<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PCE | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/pce/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-14T23:24:06-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blazing Lazers (PCE, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/18/Game--Blazing-Lazers--PCE--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/18/Game--Blazing-Lazers--PCE--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Blazing Lazers a few nights ago and tonight. This
is a shooter from 1989 on the PC Engine.</p>

<p>I found the weapons to be really cool. I particularly liked the
laser beam weapon that spread into weird shapes.</p>

<p>I found the hit box really annoying. The hit box is bigger than
the ship graphic and wider than it is vertically, so it is really
difficult to dodge properly, at least when compared to the modern
danmaku shooters I normally play.</p>

<p>I used save states before and after bosses, plus throughout the
final boss battle. In fact, my wife helped me restart a million
times through a particular explosion.</p>

<p>Overall, I thought the game was fun, but I like modern shooters
better. I didn't like it as much as the shooter that is in Retro
Game Challenge, which is supposedly based on this game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Bonk's Adventure (PCE, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/23/Game--Bonk-s-Adventure--PCE--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/23/Game--Bonk-s-Adventure--PCE--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played Bonk's Adventure for the PC Engine (or
TurboGrafx-16.) The beginning of the game was very fun and
straight-forward, but once you get to the final level the
difficulty ramps up to an insane degree. It starts with a tunnel
in the water where there are spikes on the top and the bottom and
I have no idea how to get through without just spending multiple
lives to get through it. After that, there is a huge level full of
Mega Man-style disappearing blocks. Then there's basically a boss
rush where you face all the previous bosses then two final bosses,
which are both insane. Nevertheless, the game was fun, but crazy
at the end. I got 66,080 points. Word.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (PCE, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--PCE--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--PCE--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing Akumajō Dracula X Chi no Rondo on the PC
Engine CD.</p>

<p>This game is /amazing/. The levels are all so unique and
interesting. They are all challenging and the boss are
particularly frustrating, but totally satisfying and fun. I loved
being able to play as Maria after I rescued her. I can't wait to
play Symphony of the Night again and pay attention to the
interactions with Maria. The game is definitely easier with her. I
only played with her through the alternate route and I beat
Dracula with both Richter and Maria. Naturally I also got 100%,
but I'd like to play it again sometime and go with Maria through
the primary route and Richter through the alternate route.</p></p>

<p>Update: One more thing. If you've played a Castlevania game,
you know how when you beat a boss, this magic sphere appears that
refills your health or advances you to the next level. I
/always/ jump to get it. It is so much fun!</p>

<p>I /absolutely/ recommend this game!</p>

<p>Finished with these paths:
Richter:
1 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4 -> 5 -> 6 -> 7 -> 8 -> Final
Prisoners: 2, 7</p>

<p>Maria:
1 -> 2' -> 3' -> 4' -> 5' -> 6 + Final
Prisoners: 3', 4'</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
