<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Rayman Origins | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/rayman-origins/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T21:04:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that life is too short to play games like Rayman Origins
when there are amazing games I haven't played enough. So I'm
stopping. I did everything possible in the first world and
everything possible in the first half of the second world. The
horrible controls are not worth the adorable setting of the
game... unfortunately.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half today. I did two chase
levels and a shmup level. There's so much about this game that is
admirable: the music is cool, the level design is pretty neat,
the graphics are great. But man! The controls are SOOOOOOOOOO
bad. It's like every level is the worst under-water level ever
from Mario. Rayman is just so slippery and hard to
control. Ugh. It makes me want to not play the game at all, but
I'm a masochist and can't resist. I'll definitely remove every of
Rayman game from my list though.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another level and got all the stuff in it, although I
was one second from getting the time flag. It was just because I
thought I would land on the flag, but actually had to move to the
right. Urgh.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son requested this again and I got all the awards on the second
level then got all the things on the third, except the medal and
the speed trophy. I found it un-intuitive to figure out how to do
the time course. I also find this game to control incredibly
sloppily. The character just swishes around all the time, it is
incredibly obnoxious and hard to deal with.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son picked this game out because of its box art and it is in
my "new game queue". I'd been planning on playing it co-op with
my wife, but I couldn't dissuade him from wanting to check it
out. I've never played a Rayman game before, so I didn't know
what to expect other than that it is a platformer.</p>

<p>I found the world to be really cute and the art to be awesome.</p>

<p>I think the controls are really floaty and delayed (especially
the punches). The running doesn't feel quite right either. But
I'd say it is still on par with DKCR, and not totally terrible.</p>

<p>We played two levels. The first I played twice so I could get all
the stuff and the second I was one shiny thing away from the
second bonus. The collectathon in this game seems more fun that
the collectathons in DKCR and I'm not sure if I like them more or
less than NSMBW.</p>

<p>I couldn't figure out how to play multiplayer... maybe I just
needed to have two active controllers. Nor could I understand
what the difference between the characters were. I hope to play
it with my wife eventually, but I probably won't play again for a
while unless the kids request it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
