<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Advance Wars: Dual Strike | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/advance-wars-dual-strike/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-25T23:05:59-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Dual Strike (DS, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/28/Game--Advance-Wars--Dual-Strike--DS--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/28/Game--Advance-Wars--Dual-Strike--DS--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Advance Wars: Dual Strike for the
DS. I'd never played a game in this series before and it's been a
long time since I've played a tactical game like this---although
/Devil Survivor/ was definitely tactically-inspired.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the game. I especially liked how hard it
felt. I think I only lost two or three missions (but beat them on
the second try), but for nearly all the missions after the
tutorial levels, I felt pushed to my limit and nearly losing. I
like that sensation, because it keeps the game very exciting.</p>

<p>During the majority of the time I played the game, I would make my
moves for a round, and then I would go do something else (like
practicing Japanese) and then look back when it was my turn
again. It was amazing to me how long it would often take before I
could take a turn again. I consider this a problem with the game,
although it worked out for good in my case because I was glad to
be getting something else done as well without giving it my total
focus.</p>

<p>Perhaps my favourite thing about the game was how by the end, I
was regularly using almost all the features of the combat. This
suggests to me that the mechanics are well-designed and actually
useful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
