<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Nintendo World Cup | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nintendo-world-cup/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-21T23:46:24-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Nintendo World Cup (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another five matches in the middle of the day over about
an hour. I discovered a new trick: after expending all your super
kicks (or just getting an advantage), run down the clock so you
win. I found two good ways to run down the clock: First, knock out
a member of the other team and go into the zone that only he
defends and wait. Second, continually to head-butt passes (the AI
never intercepts these). Hah!</p>

<p>At the end of the day I played again for another hour or so and
beat the game. The final few matches were really tough to keep the
ball on my side and I got scored on more than any other matches,
but I was able to win with a bit of abuse. It's a fun game to play
and I can imagine it being more difficult and interesting.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Nintendo World Cup (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These TECHNOS games feel so good. I like the dynamics in this
game and the way it feels great to tackle your opponent. I really
enjoy more abstract sports games like this. I don't know if I
wouldn't like the more modern, realistic sports games... I
presume I wouldn't, but I haven't really played them. One thing
about this game though, is that I don't think it could sustain
playing it for a long sitting. I played for a little more than
thirty minutes and that seems like the right amount of time. I
think I will keep at it and beat it... maybe?</p>

<p>Password: 30711 - Argentina 3rd match</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
