<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: New Super Mario Brothers | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/new-super-mario-brothers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-28T22:44:39-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: New Super Mario Brothers (DS, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/30/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers--DS--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/30/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers--DS--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the plane ride back from New England for Thanksgiving, I beat
New Super Mario Brothers for the Nintendo DS.</p>

<p>I started playing the game in August 2009 on a trip to Oregon
for a wedding, but I hit a wall in my progress after the second
tower in World 6. It was very frustrating, so I only played it
occasionally (less than monthly), basically whenever I was bored
and had a few moments. On the ride out to Boston this year, I did
exactly that. And again as I was sitting around with my family one
night. Then. I beat the level! I played regularly the rest of the
trip and by the flight home, I'd beaten it.</p>

<p>Most of my opinion of the game revolve around the last World
and my painful experience with the progress wall. Obviously it is
very frustrating not to make any progress. I think the biggest
problem was that even when I could beat a level, you are
restricted from saving until after a tower or castle, so you had
to have a successful string and a long time to play to make
progress. NSMBW solved this problem with the Quick Save system,
although I see no reason to not have Save anywhere unlocked from
the beginning. The final level's maze was really frustrating---I
made it there over 10 times and tried different patterns over and
over again, running out of time and then lives each time, before
looking it up online (which was a miracle, because I was on a
plane.)</p>

<p>I thought the physics in the game after more off than NSMBW. I
thought that the additional power-ups were mostly all dumb.</p>

<p>But, I love platformers and Mario in particular, so it was
really fun, especially when you're on a roll.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
