<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sweet Home | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/sweet-home/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sweet Home (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a really interesting game. It's clear to me how Resident
Evil was inspired by this. The difficulties of managing the
various members of the party and piecing together the
multi-dimensional fetch quest is a very interesting (and pretty
unique) structure for a game.</p>

<p>I played reading a walk-through that was very particular about
where you should go and what you should do. I feel like it would
be bad to play this way, because the whole point of the game is
to explore this world. However, it seems like it is pretty brutal
in terms of what your lack of knowledge means. I think I will put
this on my "revisit" pile.</p>

<p>Given my short time with the game, the main problem with it is
that it is just a puzzle and there's no good visceral feeling
associated with playing the game. The controls are pretty awkward
(knowing who is who is a pain in the beginning, but would
definitely get better as you played more) and the battle system is
uninteresting. The quick-time events are really fascinating. The
lack of an ability to see if a weapon is strong is
annoying. Overall, it's been a bit of an obtuse but really
strangely modern game. I feel like a game like this could be made
really well today. I don't think I can look past the flaws right
now though.</p>

<p>When I do play it again, I will have to re-rank it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:43</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
