<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Soma Bringer | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/soma-bringer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T00:07:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Soma Bringer (DS, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Soma-Bringer--DS--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Soma-Bringer--DS--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I was on my tour, I played Soma Bringer for the DS. At
first, I thought I would love it because it felt like Secret of
Mana. After playing through five "acts" of the game, I became too
bored with it and stopped playing.</p>

<p>I played as Millers with the Kampfs class and used claws as my
weapon.</p>

<p>Although on the surface, it is like /Secret of Mana/, there is
very little choice or customization in the battle system. There
are eight characters, but you can only play as one and have two
others for back-up. (Since only one character, it seems, can heal,
you pretty much must have them in the party.)  When your choose
your character, you can pick any of six classes, but each
character is best suited for one class. Each class can use about
three different kinds of weapons, but if you don't invest
everything in one kind of weapon, you'll be disadvantaged. Next,
you can choose to invest skill points in weapon-specific special
attacks. (If I recall there are about eight options, but they open
up in a staggered way.) For Kampfs, each special attack is
specified as either Combo 1, 2, or 3. You get bonuses for using
the combo attacks in sequence. What this all amounts to is that
once you decide your class and preferred weapon, everything is
determined for the rest of the game, because you want one of each
combo and the strongest version of it.</p>

<p>The game is too easy too. You get way to much money and can buy
whatever you want. Of course, there is rarely anything you'd want
to buy, so it just accumulates.</p>

<p>The story is interesting but there isn't anything too special
about it.</p>

<p>The game has a multi-player mode that I imagine would be fun,
but I didn't use it.</p>

<p>Overall, I can recommend the first third of the game, but
during the second third I was hoping that something new and
interesting would happen; when it didn't I quit.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
