<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lost | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/lost/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-21T08:32:24-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Lost]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/16/Lost-0/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/16/Lost-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Starting in July, <em>REDACTED</em> and I started watching Lost. Since it had
finished, we were able to watch all the episodes with only the
delays we wanted, rather than having to wait in between
seasons---the way we like it.</p>

<p>My first experience with Lost was when I went to the graduate
school recruiting visit. Someone invited a few of us over to watch
the third or fourth episode. I wasn't really interested at the
time, but when I think of Lost, I think of that first. I'm guessing
I would've been caught if I had started back then. =)</p>

<p>I liked Lost because of the interesting mythology and the detailed
characters. Lost isn't really about the "plot" or about discovering
a "mystery", it is really a character drama where the situations in
the show just serve to illustrate the personalities of the
characters. Of course, this standard of the drama genre gets
co-opted by the mythology to turn the whole island experience into
a kind of test for the characters. The mythology as a whole is
really interesting and fun to speculate about. Yet I wouldn't say
that discovering it is really what the show is about, because I
don't believe the full mythology was in the mind of the creators,
thus you can't really call it a "mystery", but rather an unfolding
revelation.</p>

<p>My favourite characters where Juliette, Richard, Ben, and the
Monster. Of the survivors, I thought <em>REDACTED</em> was very well developed
and Sawyer showed the most growth, which is interesting. I liked
Annalucia and Boone, though they were short lived, so they are
harder to appreciate.</p>

<p>I'd definitely recommend Lost. I'm excited to read fan theories and
summaries now.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
