<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Overlord | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/overlord/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-15T06:06:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Overlord (X360, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/11/Game--Overlord--X360--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/11/Game--Overlord--X360--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started playing Overlord last night and played a little more
today; I probably spent about 3 hours on it. My brother-in-law
recommended it to me and lent me his copy, but I sat on it for a
few months before getting around to it.</p>

<p>I admittedly did not play the whole game, but I found it
frustrating and boring. Some aspects of the frustration:
- It takes a few minutes to go from the Dashboard to actually
playing the game
- Getting back to what you were doing after saving is annoying,
because unlike a shmup when you play the same sections over and
over you have to pass the challenge again, in contrast you walk
through empty boringness in Overlord to get back
- There is no in-game map (period OR on the screen)
- There is no in-game record of the details of quests and no way
to talk to people, so as I wandered around in the beginning I
unlocked quests that I don't remember what they told me to do
now
- There are many times where the game is very vague about what you
should do, for example when you fight a halfling warrior your
minions start dancing and you're supposed to stop the music but
you can't hit him when you attack (I see that this an FAQ in the
walkthrough on GameFAQs. Game design: Fail!)
- You can control your minions with the right stick, but if they
get distracted they get separated and then chaos breaks
loose. It is hard to tell which group the game thinks you are
controlling and they start going crazy.</p>

<p>Now on to some stuff I find boring:
- I found myself holding down the right trigger (Minions, Go!) and
wandering around while they did stuff. This was enough to
successfully complete about 5 or 6 quests. If that's what the
rest of the game will be like, I'm not interested.
- The combat system is a single button for attacks and a single
button for spells. Yawn. Maybe there would be diversity later
on, but it didn't seem that way and it didn't seem necessary (re
the previous comment.)
- There was no risk. In addition the single way to be effective, I
quickly had hundreds of evil points to summon minions with if
they ever died so I couldn't imagine ever dying because I could
always just retreat and get some more at the last spawning pit.</p>

<p>I can see why someone might like the mechanic enough to look
behind these problems and I'm quite picky, but because I'm so
picky I was going to finish this game. Maybe the sequel fixed
these issues?</p>

<p>I don't recommend it. But I didn't finish it. Take that with
appropriate salt.</p>

<p>Frustrating, boring mechanic</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
