<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GEN | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/gen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-23T23:41:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Target Earth (GEN, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Target-Earth--GEN--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Target-Earth--GEN--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game in two chunks today. I saw the Encyclopedia
Bombastica entry about it and thought it looked neat.</p>

<p>In my first chunk, I played for about an hour and got to
stage 4. I played the first stage maybe ten times before I was
able to do anything. The game has a steep learning curve in terms
of controlling your mecha and understanding how weak the mecha
is. The key seems to be going very slowly, so that you can
recharge. I feel like it is reminiscent, in a way, to a game like
Vanquish, where it is essential to stay with your squad.</p>

<p>In my second chunk, I played for a bit more than an hour and beat
it. The story was mildly interesting and the final levels seemed
easier because you had more stuff, but still challenging.</p>

<p>I think the hardest level was the first low-gravity one where you
had to defend the ships and then get into one of them by the
end. I couldn't guard them effectively, but I realized that if I
kept one off-screen, I could continually dodge and then get into
at the last second without it being destroyed.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the game once I got into it. The chunky feel of
the game felt purposeful and interesting. The aiming system that
encouraged you to stay still was neat. The progression system was
a nice touch.</p>

<p>I think my only really problem was that most of the weapons had
such limited ammo, that I conserved them to the point of never
using them. I used the spread shot a few times in the
beginning. I used the grenade launcher once. Once I got the
missile pods, I used them to defeat the last few bosses. I think
the game could have been better by having a different special
weapon system. For example, you could decide between different
shapes and then the other weapons would be power-ups that you'd
have to find in the level and they might be permanent after that,
or have a time-limit (so you are compelled to blast with them.)
Or, they could have made it so it was essential to use them, so
you had to figure out to use them properly. As it was, they felt
so valuable that I never experimented with them enough to learn
how they worked.</p>

<p>Another thing that could have been better was providing another
way to deal with enemies that were incredibly close to you. There
were many times when I was just covered and enemies and couldn't
do anything because the bullets appeared on the screen passed the
mob. Perhaps a melee weapon would have been the trick?</p>

<p>In any case, this was a very fun game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Hang-On (GEN, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Super-Hang-On--GEN--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Super-Hang-On--GEN--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to have a Genesis day and I played a lot of games. I
started off with this one... way it is unbelievably
terrible. It's interesting that it is trying to do the same as a
game like Gran Turismo... and obviously it utterly fails.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:06</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Strider (GEN, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Strider--GEN--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Strider--GEN--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've heard a lot about this game and I thought it would be an
awesome action game like Ninja Gaiden, but with bigger and more
beautiful graphics. I was totally wrong. This is super boring and
the giant sprites do the gameplay a great dis-service by
preventing you from seeing enough of the screen to do anything
really effectively. I did not enjoy it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:12</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Streets of Rage (GEN, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Streets-of-Rage--GEN--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Streets-of-Rage--GEN--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this on Easy as Blaze and got to the final
boss. The combat feels pretty good in this game, but it has the
normal problems with beat-em-ups: the bosses are impossible unless
you use lots of special attacks, which are drastically
limited. I'm surprised I got so far. On my first continue, I got
to the end of Round 5. On my second, I got to the end of
Round 7. In the third, I got to the final boss. Definitely not
worth playing again, but it wasn't a terrible waste of an hour.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Revenge of Shinobi (GEN, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Revenge-of-Shinobi--GEN--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Revenge-of-Shinobi--GEN--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through the first level of this game. Compared to Strider
it is a lot more interesting, but the hit detection and the speed
are way too painful to really enjoy. I also greatly disliked that
the attack was limited by a small amount of ammo.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
