<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GEN | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/gen/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-08T06:52:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gunstar Heroes (GEN, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Gunstar Heroes last night and tonight. I'm a
shameless Treasure fanboy, but I'd never played this, so I thought
that I would do it. It was pretty awesome. It's really remarkable
how many many enemies they were able to get on the screen at
once. The game is really tight and fun. I was able to beat it up
until the shmup part with only one or two continues. After that, I
save-stated after each boss battle so I wouldn't have to do huge
segments over again. I really enjoyed the game. I stuck with the
flame-thrower weapon the whole time as well.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p=335">This review</a> of a different Treasure game talks a lot about Gunstar
in a way that I couldn't do better. Check that out.</p>

<p>When I was playing, my wife walked in the room and said, "This looks
cool." That's a good sign.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: World of Illusion (GEN, 1992)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/26/Game--World-of-Illusion--GEN--1992--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/26/Game--World-of-Illusion--GEN--1992--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wifey and I just beat World of Illusion Starring Mickey Mouse and
Donald Duck for the Genesis. This is a two player platformer
released in 1992 for the Sega Genesis. It is really fun that you
have to cooperate with another person: sometimes you need to stand
on each other's shoulders, pull the other player through a small
hole, or use a handcar together. There is also friendly fire in
the game, which is definitely exciting and forces you to really
communicate.</p>

<p>We played through all but the final level in one go a few weeks
ago, but we lost all our tries right near the end and waited until
tonight to finish it. We got back through all those parts and to
the final boss, but he creamed us up front. The problem was that
we didn't know where to attack him. This is typical of this game:
it does a very poor job communicating to you what you need to do
to advance. For example, there are these doors in the final area
that are very hard to open because you don't know what button to
press. Simple, but annoying.</p>

<p>Overall, the game is a nice quick platforming experience and I
think my wife liked it; and that's saying something! I can't wait to
play through the new Super Mario Brothers for the Wii with her.</p>

<p>We used Save States in the final area to conserve lives, but beat
the final boss on one try.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
