<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Acid | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-acid/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-17T23:15:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid (PSP, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Metal Gear Acid for the PSP.</p>

<p>This game is utterly insane in concept. It is a turn-based
tactical game based on the Metal Gear world, with collectible card
game elements. You need to read the Wikipedia page's (linked
above) gameplay discussion to possibly understand how it
works. After playing it through, it is brilliant. I can't believe
how great it is.</p>

<p>I love the gameplay. It is so deep. The final battle is
particularly epic.</p>

<p>The art is beautiful. There is some great 2D art, in addition to
the cool 3D in the game, but the 2D is definitely a lot better.</p>

<p>The story and characters are great and really "fit" in the Metal
Gear universe, even though it is a gaiden.</p>

<p>One of my favourite things in retrospect was the opening movie
that was an "action" video, but using the card-mechanics of the
whole game, so it felt really awkward and off-kilter, but in an
endearing way.</p>

<p>I found that the stealth-gameplay was pretty weak and it was
really optimized for combat, but I think that's appropriate for
the gameplay since that's where it really shines.</p>

<p>I think it would have a lot of replay value, although I never
played any level again, although I definitely died a lot and had
to make many attempts on some levels. In all, the game took me
19:55:01 on Normal difficulty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
