<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Battlestar Galactica | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/battlestar-galactica/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-11T00:18:36-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica - The Plan]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/Battlestar-Galactica---The-Plan-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/04/Battlestar-Galactica---The-Plan-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a neat episode. It was basically just character
development for the Cylons, but it was very neat. I think the most
meaningful thing was about the disappointment of the One and his
role as a leader from the very beginning. Cool. There were no new
plot or mythology revelations, but it was neat.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica - Season 4 - Episode 19 & 20 - Daybreak]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-19---20---Daybreak-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-19---20---Daybreak-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The flashbacks are interesting, but I wonder how they can
relevant. I don't feel like they answer big questions about the
characters, they just seem to be elaborating some of the
characters we already know about them. Even Gaius/Caprica and
Laura's things tell us new things about them, but we already
believed those characters traits. I'm kind of surprised that
Gaius would really go with Galactica and I still wonder what he
could do there. How will the story resolve what the deal is with
his "destiny" and his "angel"? I'm glad that Boomer is trying to
help Hera (even though she got her into the mess in the first
place.)  It was funny how the black guy said, "It looks like it
was wrong to trust her" and Cavil, ever the machine, says "No, it
was just a miscalculation." It was really cool to see the humans
fighting alongside Centurions (you wonder how they explained the
problem to them); and it was also neat to see the old Centurions
on the colony. I'm still not sure how they'll be able to fully
resolve the story. In my mind, they need (a) rescue Hera, (b)
destroy the Cylon threat, (c) find a place to live, and (d)
briefly explain how future integration will occur. Right now,
they are on track to (a) and I can imagine they'll be able to (b)
by destroying the colony, or something. But what'll happen with
(c) and (d)... or the other un-answered questions?</p>

<p>Well, the solution they came up with was pretty awesome. I find a
little hard to believe that they could convince everyone to put
down their technology, but it is a good solution. The connection
to real history is really cool too. It was super epic how Kara
came up with the jump coordinates and how she was really an angel
or something. Part of me wishes that they would go into more
detail with Gaius' cult, God, how the 13th (Cylon) colony was
attacked, etc, but another part of me thinks that they couldn't
do it in a non-absurd way. By the way, I found the truce from
Cavil to be very believable and I think he would have been
trustworthy. I didn't expect Tyril to be such a punk. What an
awesome show.</p>

<p><a href="http://econlog.econlib.org/archives/2009/03/you_will_know_t.html">Bryan Caplan</a> was very upset with the finale. He finds it really
unbelievable. I agree. But I think that the conclusion was safe,
in the sense that it resolved the core conflict in a meaningful
way. A few commentators make the point that it is the only way to
connect the Colonists with our past. One person on his site says
that the whole story is like a re-telling of the Flood: God is
sick of the wickness, so He destroys almost everyone and starts
over with a group of flawed people (Adama = Noah = weak to
drink). Another comment talks about how cool it would be if the
arrived in modern times and it dealt with how crazy we would feel
about them. The same guy says that they could have crash landed
to remove their equipment, rather than voluntary losing it. Re:
Kara leads people to their doom, might mean the destruction of
technology.</p>

<p><a href="http://mormonmatters.org/2009/03/21/battlestar-galactica-series-finale-critique-spoiler-alert/"><em>REDACTED</em> Matters</a> has an interesting review.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica - Season 4 - Episode 18 - Islanded in a Stream of Stars]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-18---Islanded-in-a-Stream-of-Stars-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/29/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-18---Islanded-in-a-Stream-of-Stars-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very interesting episode. I can't believe how terrible
Boomer is. Athena seems like she's in so much pain. I love the
little insight into Gaius' operation. There's now only one show
left, I have no idea how they can close it up. <em>REDACTED</em> thinks they
have to back and live on New Caprica, because that's the only
habitable place they know. Could Hera do something that will
drastically improve the situation from the Cylon Colony? What
will it be like when the Cylon Basestar is the military HQ? It's
intense.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica - Season 4 - Episode 17 - Someone to Watch Over Me]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-17---Someone-to-Watch-Over-Me-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-17---Someone-to-Watch-Over-Me-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Wow, Boomer is a low down good fer nothin'. I totally predicted
that Kara's piano playing friend was her dad and that he wasn't
real. Given that he played that song, it makes me wonder if like
her dad was the only living "Daniel" Cylon---you know, the
artist. Because if he doesn't enter the plot in some way, why
would they tell us about him in the first place, given that it
wasn't really that informative about something else. (Maybe just
that Cavil is a punk.) Also, at the beginning of this episode I
was thinking about how Cavil has been missing most of the season,
at least since the hub was destroyed, and that he doesn't really
have plans that they are getting involved in. There's only two
episodes left!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Battlestar Galactica - Season 4 - Episode 16 - Deadlock]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-16---Deadlock-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/26/Battlestar-Galactica---Season-4---Episode-16---Deadlock-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We didn't watch for as long as I hoped today... just one
episode. It was a really good episode though. I like the struggle
they are having about using support from the Cylons. I continue
to be fascinated by Gaius and what he is going to do. I love it
when he just says whatever Figment Six tells him to. I'm kind of
surprised what happened with Ellen. It seems even too low for
her. During this episode, I remembered something from the
Colonial Scriptures... it said that the 13th tribe was pursued by
demons. We were originally meant to assume that this was the
Cylons, but it appears that it was really not. I think it was
humans who later attacked them (as I said above.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
