<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2004 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2004/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-05T23:13:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Resident Evil: Apocalypse, starring Milla Jovovich (2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Movie--Resident-Evil--Apocalypse--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Movie--Resident-Evil--Apocalypse--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie is a noticeable step down from the last one. It has a
much more typical horror movie structure. It has some pretty loose
plot elements--for example, why does Jill know that zombies should
be killed by being shot in the head? How can Dr. Ashford find his
daughter on the computer but the official Umbrella people have lost
her? How does his daughter stay safe, despite being in the same
room as the zombie kids? (BTW, I'm glad they didn't kill any kids.)</p>

<p>There are some pretty funny parts that are surprisingly subtle for
a movie like this. For example, Nemesis is instructed to "Kill all
STARS" and carefully avoids the civilian (LJ) with his seemingly
un-targeted Gatling gun fire. The Nemesis' display is clearly meant
to look like a video game HUD.</p>

<p>Overall, it much more like a random action movie with zombie
elements---something that is actually kind of rare---I think the
closest analogue is something like Underworld or Van Helsing. The
Nemesis looks straight-out of Buffy or Angel... a really
low-budgeting looking costume. The super-heroism of Alice is just
like Buffy too.</p>

<p>Like the last movie, it ends setting up the sequel, where now Alice
has been revived from the dead (or something?) and has even more
super powers, as well as some strange Umbrella influence.</p>

<p>I thought the actress that played Jill looked perfect for the part
and that made it more apparent how ridiculous her outfit really
is. The real problem is that she, and no character other than LJ,
Angela (barely), and Alice have any character history or
development.</p>

<p>Overall, I can't say I like this. <a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID%3D/20040910/REVIEWS/409100304/1023">Roger Ebert's review</a> is funny;
"The movie is an utterly meaningless waste of time. There was no
reason to produce it, except to make money, and there is no reason
to see it, except to spend money. It is a dead zone, a film without
interest, wit, imagination or even entertaining violence and
special effects. [...] Parents: If you encounter teenagers who say
they liked this movie, do not let them date your children."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes (GC, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes over the course
of about a week. This is a remake of Metal Gear Solid with a bit
of new gameplay, new cinematics, and generally improved graphics.</p>

<p>I had never played this remake, but I played the original many
times when it came out. I really enjoyed playing it again. It was
very nostalgic for me.</p>

<p>I noticed a lot of homages to the first two games. For example,
you meet Meryl in a bathroom; you fist fight with Gray Fox; there
is a key that changes with the temperature; and you fight in an
elevator against an assassination squad. All these happened in
Metal Gear: Solid Snake. Naturally, the themes are the
same---especially the idea that everyone betrays Snake.</p>

<p>The one annoying thing in the game was the tortue scene. They
don't tell you in the dialogue which button resists and which
button gives up. As soon as it started, I tried to call someone on
the Codec to find that out. Of course, the give up button was the
call button. Doh! I hadn't saved in hours, so I couldn't do it
again. What a bummer. Meryl died because of it.</p>

<p>Game Level: Easy
Play Time: 10:38:12
Save: 12 times
Continue: 21 times
Alert Mode: 31 times
Enemies: 037 killed
Rations: 056 used
Code Name: Flying Squirrel
Clear Code: VHNL RGCX CH78 TBXX C5FB 79VD XB8</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Cave Story (PC, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/17/Game--Cave-Story--PC--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/17/Game--Cave-Story--PC--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few days, I've played through Cave Story on the
PC. (It has recently been re-released in an updated form for
WiiWare.)</p>

<p>It has a very unique and fun mix of Mega Man, Metroid, and
Adventure-style game play. I played through the "Hard" version of
the game where you get Booster 2.0 and I played through the "Hell"
final area as well.</p>

<p>I highly recommend it. It is free to download and it's very
fun. It inspires me to work more often on my game ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Katamari Damacy (PS2, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/15/Game--Katamari-Damacy--PS2--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/15/Game--Katamari-Damacy--PS2--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Final Fantasy 13, I wanted to play something really
light. Katamari Damacy was a good choice. It's crazy, bizarre, and
really fun. I've heard a lot about it over the past few years and
I was glad to be able to try it out.</p>

<p>I really like the way you collect countries in the ending
sequence. It's funny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metroid - Zero Mission (GBA, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/04/01/Game--Metroid---Zero-Mission--GBA--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/04/01/Game--Metroid---Zero-Mission--GBA--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't beat this; I got stuck at Mother Brain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
