<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2004 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2004/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-02T19:55:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Resident Evil: Apocalypse, starring Milla Jovovich (2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Movie--Resident-Evil--Apocalypse--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Movie--Resident-Evil--Apocalypse--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie is a noticeable step down from the last one. It has a
much more typical horror movie structure. It has some pretty loose
plot elements--for example, why does Jill know that zombies should
be killed by being shot in the head? How can Dr. Ashford find his
daughter on the computer but the official Umbrella people have lost
her? How does his daughter stay safe, despite being in the same
room as the zombie kids? (BTW, I'm glad they didn't kill any kids.)</p>

<p>There are some pretty funny parts that are surprisingly subtle for
a movie like this. For example, Nemesis is instructed to "Kill all
STARS" and carefully avoids the civilian (LJ) with his seemingly
un-targeted Gatling gun fire. The Nemesis' display is clearly meant
to look like a video game HUD.</p>

<p>Overall, it much more like a random action movie with zombie
elements---something that is actually kind of rare---I think the
closest analogue is something like Underworld or Van Helsing. The
Nemesis looks straight-out of Buffy or Angel... a really
low-budgeting looking costume. The super-heroism of Alice is just
like Buffy too.</p>

<p>Like the last movie, it ends setting up the sequel, where now Alice
has been revived from the dead (or something?) and has even more
super powers, as well as some strange Umbrella influence.</p>

<p>I thought the actress that played Jill looked perfect for the part
and that made it more apparent how ridiculous her outfit really
is. The real problem is that she, and no character other than LJ,
Angela (barely), and Alice have any character history or
development.</p>

<p>Overall, I can't say I like this. <a href="http://rogerebert.suntimes.com/apps/pbcs.dll/article?AID%3D/20040910/REVIEWS/409100304/1023">Roger Ebert's review</a> is funny;
"The movie is an utterly meaningless waste of time. There was no
reason to produce it, except to make money, and there is no reason
to see it, except to spend money. It is a dead zone, a film without
interest, wit, imagination or even entertaining violence and
special effects. [...] Parents: If you encounter teenagers who say
they liked this movie, do not let them date your children."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid (PSP, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Metal Gear Acid for the PSP.</p>

<p>This game is utterly insane in concept. It is a turn-based
tactical game based on the Metal Gear world, with collectible card
game elements. You need to read the Wikipedia page's (linked
above) gameplay discussion to possibly understand how it
works. After playing it through, it is brilliant. I can't believe
how great it is.</p>

<p>I love the gameplay. It is so deep. The final battle is
particularly epic.</p>

<p>The art is beautiful. There is some great 2D art, in addition to
the cool 3D in the game, but the 2D is definitely a lot better.</p>

<p>The story and characters are great and really "fit" in the Metal
Gear universe, even though it is a gaiden.</p>

<p>One of my favourite things in retrospect was the opening movie
that was an "action" video, but using the card-mechanics of the
whole game, so it felt really awkward and off-kilter, but in an
endearing way.</p>

<p>I found that the stealth-gameplay was pretty weak and it was
really optimized for combat, but I think that's appropriate for
the gameplay since that's where it really shines.</p>

<p>I think it would have a lot of replay value, although I never
played any level again, although I definitely died a lot and had
to make many attempts on some levels. In all, the game took me
19:55:01 on Normal difficulty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes (GC, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes over the course
of about a week. This is a remake of Metal Gear Solid with a bit
of new gameplay, new cinematics, and generally improved graphics.</p>

<p>I had never played this remake, but I played the original many
times when it came out. I really enjoyed playing it again. It was
very nostalgic for me.</p>

<p>I noticed a lot of homages to the first two games. For example,
you meet Meryl in a bathroom; you fist fight with Gray Fox; there
is a key that changes with the temperature; and you fight in an
elevator against an assassination squad. All these happened in
Metal Gear: Solid Snake. Naturally, the themes are the
same---especially the idea that everyone betrays Snake.</p>

<p>The one annoying thing in the game was the tortue scene. They
don't tell you in the dialogue which button resists and which
button gives up. As soon as it started, I tried to call someone on
the Codec to find that out. Of course, the give up button was the
call button. Doh! I hadn't saved in hours, so I couldn't do it
again. What a bummer. Meryl died because of it.</p>

<p>Game Level: Easy
Play Time: 10:38:12
Save: 12 times
Continue: 21 times
Alert Mode: 31 times
Enemies: 037 killed
Rations: 056 used
Code Name: Flying Squirrel
Clear Code: VHNL RGCX CH78 TBXX C5FB 79VD XB8</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: WarioWare: Touched! (DS, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/31/Game--WarioWare--Touched---DS--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/31/Game--WarioWare--Touched---DS--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through WarioWare: Touched! and had a chance with all of
the games. It is really fun, just like /WarioWare: Smooth Moves/
for the Wii.</p>

<p>This is the perfect game for someone with ADD, especially once
you unlock the Megamix and can sit on one screen and go through
the whole variety of games. I really enjoyed the retro games, but
I was a little annoyed when the control was really different than
the original game, because I felt stupid being so bad at them
initially. I thought the mic-based games were all very lazy and
easily the worst part of the game. my wife and I played the
Ping-Pong game, which was an incredibly clever use of the dual
screens of the DS.</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the game a lot; I'll keep it around to play
whenever I need something quick to fool around with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap (GBA, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through The Legend of Zelda: The
Minish Cap. I knew I was almost done, so I stayed up a little too
late finish it tonight.</p>

<p>The graphics in this game are beautiful and vibrant. Many games
these days are dark and muddy, so it is refreshing to have such a
bright game. The game has the same style as /Link to the Past/,
but with a bit more cudly-ness.</p>

<p>The sound is good. I caught my wife humming a few of the
tunes.</p>

<p>The story is a respectable Zelda story. I like that the title
is a double entendre.</p>

<p>The gameplay is very good. It has the same core mechanics as
the first Zelda and /Link to the Past/ (my two
favourite), but almost all the items are brand new. The Kinstone
system (wherein you collect trinkets and give them to particular
NPCs) is a nice abstraction of a quest mechanic, although I
would've liked to have been able to get to the bonuses without
using a Kinstone, somehow. The boss fights are very fun and
difficult enough---I had to repeat two of them and the final
boss's first form got me the first time. The dungeon designs are
good. The puzzles are interesting without being infuriating. I
only had a few times where I wanted to throw the control (all in
the Wind Palace, btw.) The world is big enough to make it
interesting and the teleport system is convenient.</p>

<p>I finished the game with 14 heart containers, two bottles,
without the boomerang, with the original shield, without any bomb
bag/quiver upgrades (actually I'm not sure if there are any) and
with all the sword techniques. It was a little hard to complete
with such a small amount of life and only two bottles, but it was
obviously do-able and fun.</p>

<p>I definitely still prefer /Link to the Past/, but
this is worth playing again and thus worth playing for the first
time too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
