<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1991 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1991/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T00:21:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago... I forget when... we played again, beat the first
temple and got some items in the world. My son really enjoys
watching it.</p>

<p>Today we played up to the boss in the Tower of Hera, but were
totally creamed. It is tough. I keep getting knocked off and then
his health is reset.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought my son might like this game, given how much he enjoyed
watching the beginning of Castlevania: SOTN. I also thought he
might be willing to play it because the controls are simpler. I
was right. He really enjoyed watching the beginning and then all
of sudden he said, "Dad, how do you move? How do you attack? Can I
try?" He explored the world a little and fought some enemies. He
started getting frustrated because he kept dying. His problem was
that he wouldn't move away from enemies when they came to attack
him. He would swing his sword while the enemies were on top of him
and this killed him eventually.</p>

<p>We got to the boss of the first temple, but I died during the
stomping part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 4 (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/26/Game--Final-Fantasy-4--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/26/Game--Final-Fantasy-4--SNES--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This month I played through Final Fantasy
IV on the Super Nintendo using the Japanese release and the J2e
translation.</p>

<p>I remember loving FF4 when I was younger, but I haven't played
it in a very long time. Back then, I remember hearing that the
Japanese version had more story scenes and a slightly different
story, due to the censorship Nintendo had at that point on the
SNES. Therefore, I was very excited to play a translation of the
Japanese version.</p>

<p>The new story is different in some subtle ways; the main change is
that there is a lot of risque humour, especially with Edge and
Palom. J2e kept "You Spoony Bard!", which was great to
remember. Most of the spells and items seemed to be named
differently, and something else I liked a lot was that there
seemed to be no limit put on item and character name lengths,
which made for some more pleasant reading.</p>

<p>Overall, FF4 is as good as I remember. The story is
entertaining and detailed enough, for the time. The battle system
is fun... and actually it is much more brutal than I
remembered. The non-boss battles were particularly rough rather
than the normal steam-rolling fodder. The optional content is very
detailed. The characters are interesting. A subtle thing I really
enjoy is that there is no character customization: by level 38,
Rosa always learns Reflect, with no options. This kind of thing is
no longer popular, but I liked the way it ties together the
character's personality and their battle powers. (For example,
when Rydia is encouraged by Rosa to cast a Fire spell---despite
her village being destroyed by fire---she then gains the ability
in combat as well.) Despite appearances, it actually gives you
more ability to be creative, because you have to find interesting
ways to use the abilities that you have, rather than find a boring
min-max strategy.</p>

<p>I misremembered the story a little bit, so I was pleasantly
surprised. For example, I thought that Edge would die near the end
and that FuSoYa would be in the party for the rest of the game,
but I was (obviously) wrong.</p>

<p>Definitely a great game, I think I will enjoy playing it again
in another few years.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
