<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1985 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1985/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-25T22:05:32-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Yie Ar Kung-Fu (NES, 1985)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/11/Game--Yie-Ar-Kung-Fu--NES--1985--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/11/Game--Yie-Ar-Kung-Fu--NES--1985--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played Yie Ar Kung-Fu for my Famicom tonight. I got it when I
bought the Famicom and I read that it was one of the first
fighting games.</p>

<p>It's not very good. I think the main problem I have with it is
that hit box detection is terrible. You can have your foot in the
enemy's skull and it doesn't register a hit. The diagonal jumping
control is also really off.</p>

<p>But, I can see how the principles of this game have gone on to
more developed games, and I appreciated it for that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario Bros (NES, 1985)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Super-Mario-Bros--NES--1985--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Super-Mario-Bros--NES--1985--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past month I've been playing this for the NES. Of course,
I played that game a lot when I was growing up, but I had never
beat it or experienced every level. It remains fun and challenging
to this day. When I started playing, I didn't remember that you
needed to go through particular paths in many of the castles, so
that was a really fun challenge this time around. The final castle
in particular is a pain in the neck with all the different
pipes. I was really excited to finally save Princess Toadstool;
she's been waiting a long time for me.</p>

<p>I used save states and got a score of 443900 with 23 coins and 7
extra lives. There is a save state at the start screen of the
second quest.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
