<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-29T22:03:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lumines: Electronic Symphony (Vita, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game--Lumines--Electronic-Symphony--Vita--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game&#8211;Lumines&#8211;Electronic-Symphony&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today on one run. I got a very high
score. I don&#8217;t know what it would mean to &#8220;beat&#8221; this game. In
addition, every time I play, even when I last longer, I don&#8217;t
really feel like I did anything good since you can manage to get
back down to a blank screen so often. Another thing strange about
this game is that the difficulty never really changes, I just
feel like I keep going and going and going but the soundtrack
changes. It&#8217;s odd.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to mark the game &#8220;Done&#8221; but play it whenever I need to
run down my Vita&#8217;s battery.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today. I&#8217;m trying to beat the Pro VS
match. I tried first and the match lasted 15 minutes and I
ultimately lost after a good run of wins. I decided to try &#8220;Easy
Mode&#8221; to see how easy it was&#8230; and I lost twice and then won,
but failed on 3-5 twice. Easy doesn&#8217;t really seem that much
easier and it&#8217;s not worth having the green medal on the score
icon. I feel like I&#8217;m at a bit of a wall in this game and should
play it a lot less.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m going to schedule it for a weekly session on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>Total time: 9:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for an hour and half this morning. I got stars in every
beginner event. I did 1-5 as Chang and I beat Isabella in Sudden
Death on the third hole. It was very intense. Also, in 1-5 I got
a crown. I haven&#8217;t figured out how to find out what will give you
a crown though. Everything seemed a lot easier with Change
because he had so much power, but it also seems like the
characters aren&#8217;t really supposed to be better than one-another,
but just represent different play styles. I&#8217;m not sure.</p>

<p>In the evening, I played all night while chatting and burping my
new baby. I got stars up to 3-4 and did the Pro VS match twice. In
the first one, I lost after just a few holes and in the second I
had her tied until the second to last hole, then lost by one
stroke in the last. Ouch. It&#8217;s a very fun game. But I might be
playing too much :/</p>

<p>Total time: 9:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Secretariat, starring Diane Lane (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Movie--Secretariat--starring-Diane-Lane--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Movie&#8211;Secretariat&#8211;starring-Diane-Lane&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun horse movie. I feel like all horse movies are the
same, but they&#8217;re the same and interesting. I was very impressed
by the horse after I read its Wikipedia page. I thought the
sub-plot of Penney being a &#8220;housewife&#8221; and having issues with her
family were interesting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-3&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we played for a bit more than an hour and beat the
game. I played through all of Wily&#8217;s Fortress three times. The
first time I got stuck on the level before the triplicator
because I ran out of energy for the Rush Jet. The second time I
got to Wily but after continuing I didn&#8217;t have any E-tanks or any
of the weapons I needed to kill him. The third time I won. It was
a brutal fight and I got really good at getting through the
fortress. I think this is a great game. Mega Man 2 is awesome,
but this is great too.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for two and three quarter hours. I got stars in
1-1, 1-2, and 1-3. The game is very fun and I like the abstract
way it presents golf. I feel like I know nothing about golf, but
that I can do the game pretty well and have fun. One thing I
don&#8217;t like though is that golf punishes mistakes soooo
heavily. Basically one mistake can cause you to get two or three
strokes behind and then you&#8217;ll never get back. I went from being
1st in 1-4 to 13th in one hole and then ended in 19th because I
made another single mistake. It is brutal.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Symphony of the Night (PS1, 1997) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Castlevania--Symphony-of-the-Night--PS1--1997--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game&#8211;Castlevania&#8211;Symphony-of-the-Night&#8211;PS1&#8211;1997&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I noticed today that I could download this for my Vita, since I
already bought it for the PS3 back in 2008, so I downloaded it
and showed it to my wife. I love the opening&#8230; fighting with
Richter and then the abilitease. It&#8217;s great.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-3&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little more than thirty minutes. We got to
the final boss rush, but I didn&#8217;t have enough skill to beat them,
and then when I got to the continue screen I accidentally
selected &#8220;Stage Select&#8221; rather than &#8220;Continue&#8221; so was put back at
the beginning of Wily&#8217;s Castle. In frustration, I quit. I
understand why this option is there&#8212;so you can gave E
tanks. But I was very annoyed that it was default and it took so
long to restart the game back to where I was.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gravity Rush (Vita, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/24/Game--Gravity-Rush--Vita--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/24/Game&#8211;Gravity-Rush&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like two hours tonight. The &#8220;gameplay loop&#8221; of this
game is very repetitive. I feel like my use of the fighting system
is so boring, but so effective too that it doesn&#8217;t matter. I still
like the feeling of flying through the air though. I feel like
that game is too long and I&#8217;ve already played it for so long. I
had a lot of frustrating times tonight when I needed to swing the
camera fast and couldn&#8217;t.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Lucky One, starring Zac Efron and Taylor Schilling (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Movie--The-Lucky-One--starring-Zac-Efron-and-Taylor-Schilling--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Movie&#8211;The-Lucky-One&#8211;starring-Zac-Efron-and-Taylor-Schilling&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really cute movie. Nicholas Sparks is amazing. Taylor
Schilling is super beautiful. Zac was great in the movie, but I
think he looks too young for the part, even with
scruffiness. Something neat about Sparks is that his movies always
work, but as movies, there&#8217;s nothing really special about
them. Interesting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game&#8211;Lufia&#8212;The-Fortress-Of-Doom&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that I&#8217;m not going to continue playing this game. It&#8217;s
definitely not a bad game, but it&#8217;s also not an excellent
game. Given its age, there are really some interface things that
it should have done better:</p>

<ul>
<li>attacks should not go into empty space</li>
<li>you should be able to see what equipment will improve your stats
and buy them easier</li>
<li>you should be able to see what items do</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, if I had a lot of nostalgia for this game, I would be much
more willing to play it to experience the story and world again,
but I have much more nostalgia for the second game. In terms of
story, this game basically does everything I think is cool in the
first few hours and then it&#8217;s just been standard JRPG fare.</p>

<p>I do find the concept of the Old Cave with the &#8220;task&#8221; system to be
pretty interesting, but not enough to make me want to keep doing
it.</p>

<p>Basically this game will be left aside because of the &#8220;there&#8217;s
not enough time in the world to play non-amazing games&#8221;. I guess
this means that I can&#8217;t really recommend the game either, because
there&#8217;s things you should play instead, but it&#8217;s still not a
&#8220;bad&#8221; game. For example, I prefer it to the PS3 Star Ocean or
some of the other modern junk I&#8217;ve tried to play.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Game&#8211;Lufia&#8212;The-Fortress-Of-Doom&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I got to the Old Cave and
to the Tower in the Northwest, but the enemies in the entry way
were pretty brutal. I feel like this game is almost all grind in
that way the DQ can be. There haven&#8217;t really been any cute
moments in the story since the main character and Lufia don&#8217;t
talk to each other anymore.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Pointe - Season 1 - Episode 6 - Curtain Call]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Breaking-Pointe---Season-1---Episode-6---Curtain-Call-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Breaking-Pointe&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-6&#8212;Curtain-Call-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We finished the series tonight. I thought the final episode was
pretty weak. I feel like the party for Katie was pretty
contrived; the discussion of the final performances was really
quickly cut, presumably because nothing happened; the meltdown
between Allison and Rex was really annoying because Rex seems
like such a jerk to her, but I&#8217;m glad that she reached out to
him, because it seems like if she opens up, he&#8217;ll be very good
for her; and the thing between Christiana and her husband was
touching.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game&#8211;Lufia&#8212;The-Fortress-Of-Doom&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half while we were watching a TV
show on my wife&#8217;s laptop. It was relaxing to grind a bit. I got
to the port town and met the guy who knew Guy. The story is very
simple so far, but it&#8217;s nice in a Dragon-Quest-y way.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game&#8211;Castlevania&#8211;NES&#8211;1986&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to beat this game today. I used a cheat code to give
infinite lines, so I didn&#8217;t need to worry about continues and
replaying sections over and over (at least, until I got passed
them once, or in the case of the stage before a boss battle, more
times.) However, even with that, I was able to get to
Frankenstein&#8217;s in 3 lives. I took another three to get to stage
15 (the stage that ends in Death.) I did all that in about 30
minutes. I played the stage before Death for about 25 minutes
before church. Then I had a very NES moment and left the system
running while I was at church.</p>

<p>When I got back, I played Death&#8217;s sequence over and over again
for an hour and a half. Eventually I decided to focus on not
losing any life at all during the hallway with the two axe
knights and the brutal Medusa heads, by willingly sacrificing
lots of hearts. This turned out to be a good move and I gradually
improved. It took maybe three times of getting to Death with full
health before I defeated him. It was awesome.</p>

<p>It only took about 15 minutes to get to Dracula after that. It
took another hour and a half before I beat Dracula. It got to the
point where I could get passed the first form without taking any
damage pretty reliably, but then I had to work on my moves to
fight the second form. Eventually I decided to try the potion
rather than the cross, because the cross didn&#8217;t seem to do much
damage. This was an awesome move. The potion doesn&#8217;t do any
damage, but it stunlocks him so he can&#8217;t move. Provided I didn&#8217;t
have the double shot, I was able to lay into him for two hits,
then stun, then repeat. I was triumphant!</p>

<p>Altogether, I beat the game in about four hours. It felt so good
to do it. Even though I used a code, it was a pretty weak code
because I had to do everything. It&#8217;s a good example about what
I&#8217;d like games to do&#8212;be like spaced repetition systems (like
Anki), have me do a stage until I can beat it reliably, then move
on, but don&#8217;t show me something that is now easy (or moderate,
but with random swings all the time.)</p>

<p>I&#8217;m very glad I gave this game a chance. Initially, the controls
felt so gross, but now I really love their unique stickiness.</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:58
Total time: 6:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Pointe - Season 1 - Episode 5 - Bad Dress: Good Show]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Breaking-Pointe---Season-1---Episode-5---Bad-Dress--Good-Show-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Breaking-Pointe&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-5&#8212;Bad-Dress&#8211;Good-Show-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was cool to watch this one, because we were at the opening
show. I didn&#8217;t notice anything wrong with Allison&#8217;s dancing. I&#8217;m
one of the &#8220;80% who don&#8217;t know anything about ballet&#8221;. It&#8217;s kind
of sad that she seems to have such contempt for ballet fans, like
myself, who think it&#8217;s all beautiful and can&#8217;t notice flaws. I
also felt bad for Allison when she talked with her family&#8230; she
don&#8217;t seem very supportive of her in the way she needs.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Breaking Pointe - Season 1 - Episode 4 - Tempo Tantrums]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Breaking-Pointe---Season-1---Episode-4---Tempo-Tantrums-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Breaking-Pointe&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-4&#8212;Tempo-Tantrums-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a stressful episode, because it makes you feel so bad
for Allison. She seems really great, but in a lot of pain and
Rex isn&#8217;t being the best for her.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sonic the Hedgehog (GEN, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game--Sonic-the-Hedgehog--GEN--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game&#8211;Sonic-the-Hedgehog&#8211;GEN&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game with my kids this morning. Once I played, I
got to the first Act of the Marble Zone. My daughter played and
managed to get through most of the first level, including dealing
with the jumps, but then got stuck a bit. The first zone was
pretty good and easy. The second zone was brutal.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game&#8211;Lufia&#8212;The-Fortress-Of-Doom&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this game for about an hour this morning. The beginning
is a really cool &#8220;abilitease&#8221;. I find the movement speed really
painful. I worked my way to the castle in the north and then
back. This game is one of the most Dragon-Quest-y clones I&#8217;ve
played recently. When I first played it, it had been a long time
since I played a Dragon Quest game, so I didn&#8217;t realize it. But
now, it&#8217;s quite amazing. Even down to the Dragon Quest 2 problem
of attacks against monsters that are now gone not
connecting. It&#8217;s cute so far though.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: It's Kind of a Funny Story, starring Keir Gilchrist (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie&#8211;It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story&#8211;starring-Keir-Gilchrist&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had no expectations about this movie. It was pretty cute and
interesting. I think depressed people are stupid, so I didn&#8217;t
really like the part of it that justified them, although a big part
of it didn&#8217;t (Craig&#8217;s conclusion is that depression is
self-indulgent.) I though Emma Roberts&#8217; character was very cute,
although we don&#8217;t learn anything about her, other than that she&#8217;s
cute and quirky. The final sequence in the movie where we see what
Craig does with his life is more interesting than a lot of moments
in the movie. The character of Bobby is actually sad, but again,
everyone in the movie is just a caricature with no substance, so
we don&#8217;t really know what his feels truly are. The movie is
annoying in that way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
