<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-10T23:35:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Nick and Norah's Infinite Playlist, starring Michael Cera (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie--Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist--starring-Michael-Cera--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie&#8211;Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist&#8211;starring-Michael-Cera&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn&#8217;t really know anything about this movie before watching it,
but heard it was interesting. It was really cool. It was so
nostalgic of what life was like for me when I was young&#8230; going
to shows all night, etc. That was really cool about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ziggurat (iOS, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Ziggurat--iOS--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game&#8211;Ziggurat&#8211;iOS&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve had this game on my &#8220;Queue&#8221; since I bought it, but I&#8217;ve had
to admit to myself that I just hate playing games on the iPhone
so much, I&#8217;m definitely not going to sit down and play
this. Sometimes I play it when I&#8217;m waiting for something, but I
have other things that feel more productive that I could be doing
on my phone.</p>

<p>I like the game and I think it is the best iPhone game I&#8217;ve
played, but I really dislike the iPhone interface and this game
in particular feels like it would work just as well with
buttons. I feel like the only way for me to appreciate this game
will be for me to re-implement it myself and give it buttons.</p>

<p>So, I&#8217;m retiring it from my queue, with a bit of a sad face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game tonight. The opening sequence is really cool,
especially after the battle when it pulls out and shows you how
people live on the two giant titans. It&#8217;s such a cool concept.</p>

<p>The battle system I experienced during the walk to the first
village was incredibly reminiscent of FF12, but with a bit more
action on the part of the player. When I got to the town, it was
incredibly tempting to go and find all the glowing blue things
and get all the quests, etc. I can tell that it will be hard to
not make this game a giant collect-a-thon for myself.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m finding the mechanics a bit overwhelming. There are a lot of
different options about how to equip characters, so many quests,
so many different ways to buy things. It&#8217;s very intimidating. I
think I will do the obvious thing until it hurts me rather than
trying to compute what the best solution will be.</p>

<p>I was amazed at how many different quests I unlocked so early,
though.</p>

<p>The voice acting in this game is actually really good. I almost
never like non-Japanese voice acting, because it is normally just
so horrendous. (Actually, now that I think about, Asura&#8217;s Wrath
was pretty good.) Since the actors in this game are British,
there&#8217;s something really fun and exotic about them. I like it.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m pretty excited to be playing this game. (One annoyance: I&#8217;m
using the Wii Pro controller. I hate having to have it plugged in
to the Wiimote that sits stupidly next to me on the couch.)</p>

<p>Total time: 1:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game&#8211;Punch-Out&#8212;-Wii&#8211;2009&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time&#8230; I considered restarting, but didn&#8217;t and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He&#8217;s really really hard. I&#8217;ve decided to put this as
&#8220;Scheduled&#8221; game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played again from the start for about an hour. This time I
beat Chill Penguin, then went against Flame Mammoth (because I
thought he&#8217;d be weak, but he wasn&#8217;t), then we went to Sting
Chameleon&#8217;s stage and got the Armor upgrade. I&#8217;m not sure if I
will use the password next time we play. Fighting the armor
upgrade guard was te&#8212;-dious!</p>

<p>Total time: 1:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for an hour and a half-ish. We beat the game! The
final boss and the last rocket sequence was pretty tough and my
wife was getting very frustrated, but we eventually did it.</p>

<p>The Nintendo Channel clocks our total time at 20 hours and 52
minutes (I haven&#8217;t been keeping track of our game play that long.)</p>

<p>We decided that the game is a lot more sloppy in many ways
compared to NSMBW, but that we had a lot of fun, especially once
we got infinite lives. We don&#8217;t love the game enough to try to get
all the bonuses to unlock the hidden temple, so that&#8217;s that.</p>

<p>I like platformers, but I like playing games with my wife more.</p>

<p>Time: 7:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment (N64, 2000) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game&#8211;Sin&#8212;Punishment&#8211;N64&#8211;2000&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in May, I bought a copy of S&amp;P for the N64 in Japan. On
Tuesday I bought a US N64 to play it on. Today, I got the
&#8220;GameBit&#8221; in the mail that I needed to region mod it to play
Japanese N64 games.</p>

<p>I started playing S&amp;P and it took a while to get used to the
controls again&#8230; especially because before I played on my arcade
stick (under an emulator) and now I was using the actual control
scheme. It felt a little strange but I started to get used to it
quickly.</p>

<p>I played about 14 minutes and got: 5,343,930 pts, 11m13s, and 531
enemies. I died at the final stage of the final boss of the first
level. I remember it taking a while to realize that I had to
shoot the glowing spot under water the first time too&#8230;</p>

<p>Time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game&#8211;Punch-Out&#8212;-Wii&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this in the morning and got to Great Tiger. I had a
tough time with Bear Hugger before I realized that I could duck
the Bear Hug. I only fought one round against Great Tiger, so I&#8217;m
just learning his patterns. It is interesting how this game is
almost, but not quite, identical to the NES version. There are
some things that are better and more convenient (like Saves and
Retry in the middle of a match) but other than that it&#8217;s just
tweaked on the edges. It&#8217;s cool.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son and I played for about twenty minutes. We did the
Intro stage and then Chill Penguin. We got the dash and got to
the boss, but died on the first time and were out of lives. He
wanted to play Launch Octopus again so we did that had a tough
time with the ships before it was time for breakfast.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for an hour and beat the first three levels of
World 8. There was a normal platforming level (although it had
lots of breaking platforms), then a rocket level, then a mine-cart
level. The rocket levels are so terrible because they are just
memorization mazes with an awful control scheme. It was
annoying. But eventually I got in the zone and did it. I think my
wife was a bit mad because she kept trying and dying every other
time.</p>

<p>Time: 6:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game&#8211;Asura-s-Wrath&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours this afternoon. I beat the normal
game, but I got a message about a hidden episode that requires a
certain score to play through. I&#8217;m interested in the story and I
feel duty bound to get this score myself, rather than just watch
it online. (Whereas I will watch the &#8220;True&#8221; Ending that is DLC
because that&#8217;s ridiculous.) I&#8217;ll probably get the chance to do it
later today.</p>

<p>The normal ending is crazy. The &#8220;Tarantula&#8221; earth is ridiculous. I
love that there is a title screen on the last episode of the
game. I love the crazy million exploding arms thing. The battle
with the Vlitra Core was horrific. It is incredibly hard to dodge
in this game because the frame rate will get really choppy and
then things start teleporting around. The worst thing about the
fight was that the two QTE counter-attacks would change the
prompt seemingly randomly so you couldn&#8217;t really be prepared for
what it would be. Argh.</p>

<p>I thought that Yasha&#8217;s voice actor sounded like York from Deadly
Premonition, but my wife disagreed&#8230; and she was right. As usual.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>Later in the day I tried to starting doing the S Ranks to get the
true ending. I redid level 13, did really well, but didn&#8217;t get an
S. This made me decide it wasn&#8217;t worth it to play the game
continuously to earn the S. Instead, I watched it on YouTube and
then started watching the DLC.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>In the extended ending DLC, the Demigods-are-Robots hypothesis
got a lot of strength, because Asura&#8217;s chest is opened and a new
&#8220;reactor&#8221; is put inside.</p>

<p>The space fight with the True Boss is ridiculous. Asura grows
larger than the Earth, but it is still huge. At one point, it
seems to be launching stars at Asura.</p>

<p>The ending comic sequence is nuts too. Chun-Li was in it! I love
the ridiculous time lengths&#8230; 670 million years later.</p>

<p>The Street Fighter DLC was pretty crazy too. I liked how meta it
was&#8230; Asura entering Ryu&#8217;s game and then Ryu entering Asura&#8217;s
game. And I loved that Akuma and Asura fought for 500 years
straight. Ridiculous.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>Overall, I&#8217;d say Asura&#8217;s Wrath was a fun experience. The anime
aspect of it was really great and I think the QTEs do a good job
at making that experience more tense because you&#8217;re at the edge
of your seat. I never failed during a QTE sequence, but I did
fail quite a few times at the big boss battles during the action
sequences. I felt like they were pretty bad because they were
just sloppy (which I mentioned above.) But, given the anime
package, they were pretty fun. I&#8217;d say that they should&#8217;ve been a
bit easier or shorter so that they didn&#8217;t take away from the
roller coaster. In a lot of those action sequences there was real
bad frame-rate problems and on the version I played there was
some screen tearing near the end of the game. But other than
that, things looked really good.</p>

<p>I can recommend Asura&#8217;s Wrath in the same way I&#8217;d recommend a good
movie or TV show. It&#8217;s 8 hours worth of over-the-top insanity for
a reasonable price. I doubt it would be very replayable (even
replaying the one level for a score was really unexciting) and
this speaks ill of it /as a game/. But as a unique form of new
interactive entertainment&#8230; it&#8217;s pretty good.</p>

<p>Total time: 8:06</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/Game&#8211;Asura-s-Wrath&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I think I&#8217;m basically at
the end of the game. It was cool to play as Yasha at first,
although I was kind of disappointed I didn&#8217;t get to play as
Berserker Asura. This game is totally nuts. Today I decided that
Deus looks like Ganon from Twilight Princess. Also, I think that
something I enjoy about this is how it is a lot like Bayonetta in
terms of its style and craziness. If only the action were as good
as Bayonetta, that would be awesome. But as it stands, the style
of the game is a really great substitute.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lumines: Electronic Symphony (Vita, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Lumines--Electronic-Symphony--Vita--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game&#8211;Lumines&#8211;Electronic-Symphony&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this today and played for like 27 minutes and had one of
the best runs I ever have had on a Lumines game.</p>

<p>Total time: 27:00</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for like 20 minutes. I&#8217;ve never played at Hot Shots
Golf game before, but I&#8217;ve been curious. The PS Vita bundle I
bought came with it, so I figured, what the heck. I played two
holes as Yuna. It was kind of fun.</p>

<p>Total time: 22:00</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game&#8211;Asura-s-Wrath&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for two hours tonight and got to 11.5. There were so
many absurd moments. I loved how Asura flew by punching the
ground and riding the shock wave. I loved the onsen sequence and
how Asura was denied. I loved how Augus and Asura are
inexplicably on the moon and how ridiculously huge Augus&#8217; sword
is (and how he&#8217;s never drawn it but once). I loved the gigantic
crater from the sword and how Asura always ends up with no
arms. It&#8217;s also very intriguing that Augus was robot-y too. What
could that mean?</p>

<p>Total time: 4:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for about two hours and beat the rest of the factory
levels. We discovered a way to grind for balloons but decided not
to. We traded our time for just using a cheat code that gives
infinite balloons. It&#8217;s amazing how much more fun the game is
now, because we can play a little less cautiously and give my
wife more opportunities to do the difficult platforming sequences
where she used to just climb on my back. I think that might be
why we liked Mario so much more, because the Desert Life grind is
so effective.</p>

<p>Time: 5:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game&#8211;Asura-s-Wrath&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed my wife the awesome Wyzen fight and then did the next
two episodes. The &#8220;ending&#8221; was cool and the awesome arm-less
fight. This game is just sooo ridiculous. I can tell my wife is
kind of appalled at how insane it is. I love that about it.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We tried to play again tonight and only beat one factory level
then decided to try to grind for balloons, but there&#8217;s no good
opportunities to, so we gave up that for a bit and did something
else.</p>

<p>Time: 3:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game&#8211;Asura-s-Wrath&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game on the recommendation of the Giant Bomb
podcast. Tonight I played for a little less than two hours and
played through the first five episodes. This game is insane. I
love the over-the-top-ness. I love the TV show stylings. The
combat and shooting feel interesting and like I&#8217;m doing something,
although I get the impression that I can&#8217;t lose and it&#8217;s just a
matter of smashing enough until I can Burst, although I suppose I
could simply pay attention to my score at the end. So far, I think
it&#8217;s a really unique and amazing experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game&#8211;The-Legend-of-Zelda&#8211;Link-to-the-Past&#8211;SNES&#8211;1991&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We got through Ganon&#8217;s tower today with 2 blue potions and 2
fairies. We lost the last fairy in the fight versus Agahnim, which
we entered with only three hearts. After that, I fought Ganon,
but failed to use a potion after using a fairy, then filled up
again and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Total time: 7:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
