<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-15T22:53:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game&#8211;Pac-Man-CE-DX&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today and got a lot more S-ranks and
stuff.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 2,160/248,420 &#8212; 0.86%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game&#8211;Child-of-Eden&#8211;X360&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game as a prize from Call of Podcast for writing about
my game management system. It was on my to-buy list before that,
although I was planning on buying the PS3 version. The game looked
really beautiful and I really like Genki Rockets. I played Rez for
the Dreamcast and wasn&#8217;t really blown away, but I thought that it
might be more interesting in a more modern form.</p>

<p>The game opens up with a really intriguing video and quickly shows
off its unique, beautiful world.</p>

<p>I played it for about an hour and half tonight. I beat the
first three levels on the first try, although I had to do each
twice to unlock the next level. I played the fourth level about
four times, but kept dying at the final form of the boss, because
it shoots so many tracer rounds.</p>

<p>I find the gameplay to be enjoyable and challenging, at least when
you get totally overwhelmed by bullets. I suppose I should get
better at using the screen clearing bombs. The addition of the
tracer rounds seems like it would be an insignificant change, but
it makes a huge difference compared to Rez.</p>

<p>I love the music, although I wish that there were more vocals,
like the actual Genki Rockets song. It may be that I&#8217;m not playing
well enough to unlock them though&#8230; on that note, I dislike how
it seems like I am doing the levels perfect (not getting hit,
getting mostly perfect octo-locks) but I&#8217;m only get three stars a
pop. It&#8217;s weird.</p>

<p>I love that every level is totally different visually and aurally
from the others. This game is the perfect of a game that seems
like it was made on a totally different planet. I&#8217;ve played plenty
of Japanese games that do this, but most Western games lack that
kind of creativity.</p>

<p>I intend to keep trucking at it and beat. I haven&#8217;t yet decided if
I will play through the hard mode or if I will just periodically
play through the whole game when I want to chill out to some rad
music, or show someone the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The wife and I watched two more episodes. The game continues to be
really funny. A little thing I really liked that we noticed today
was that the voice of York is different when he is hearing himself
talk than when the camera is from a third-person perspective. Very
subtle, but neat. Something I enjoy about the narrator guy is that
he talks so matter-of-factly about some of the strange stuff going
in the game. It adds to the absurdity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Removing the Condemnation, by Denver C. Snuffer, Jr. (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Book--Removing-the-Condemnation--by-Denver-C--Snuffer--Jr---2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Book&#8211;Removing-the-Condemnation&#8211;by-Denver-C&#8211;Snuffer&#8211;Jr&#8212;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading this book for a few weeks. It&#8217;s just
terrible.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s about 550 pages where every one has the text of a verse from
the Book of <em>REDACTED</em> and then a series of questions underneath it
like &#8220;What does X mean?&#8221; &#8220;What does (something tangentially related
to X) mean?&#8221; &#8220;What does Y mean?&#8221; etc. It does this over and over
and over, with almost no answers. Sometimes the questions are
incredibly obvious or trivial, like the verse will say &#8220;follow the
Prophet&#8221; and the questions will be something like &#8220;What does it
/really/ mean to follow?&#8221; &#8220;No, REALLY what does it mean?&#8221;</p>

<p>I get the impression that the author has deep, and perhaps
controversial, opinions about these things, but doesn&#8217;t want to
express them clearly because he&#8217;s afraid of being reprimanded by
the Church or being held accountable in anyway.</p>

<p>Sometimes the questions are so leading, you can see what opinion he
is trying to express, but is unwilling to do it openly. For
example, he has a list of questions related to the details of the
sacrament ordinance with all sorts of questioning about when it is
okay to change ordinances. It is pretty clear to me he&#8217;s implying
something bad about the changes in the temple ordinances. But,
again he doesn&#8217;t actually say this.</p>

<p>In addition to this frivolous questions, there&#8217;s saccharine
comments like, &#8220;Man this Book of <em>REDACTED</em> is pretty important, huh? I
can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s so great&#8221; that sound like staged humility.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s plausible that this guy&#8217;s other books contain interesting
stuff, but I don&#8217;t think he can use the commentary format effectively.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Immortals, starring Henry Cavil (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie&#8211;Immortals&#8211;starring-Henry-Cavil&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really rad movie. It had a similar amazing look as 300,
but was much more fantasy oriented. The actions of the Gods in the
movie are awesome and not quite like anything I&#8217;d ever seen
before. The actions are the humans are exciting and down to Earth
in a neat contrasting way. Mickey Rourke does an amazing job as a
crazy warlord. The movie is a really great spectacle piece and is
totally worth it just for the way the Greek Gods are presented.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Haywire, starring Gina Carano (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie&#8211;Haywire&#8211;starring-Gina-Carano&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a cool spy-action movie. I like how it emphasizes the
&#8220;soft&#8221; part of spy work (but not as much as something like
/Spygame/.) And, I think the fight scenes are really cool because
they are so slow and feel realistic. In a strange way, her
controlled fighting makes it almost less exciting, because she
seems so confident and in control all the time. There was lots of
neat camera work&#8212;mainly during the chase sequences. And, the
structuring of the story telling (in the beginning, she&#8217;s narrating
to someone else) is interesting. The one thing I think could have
been a lot better about the movie was the final reveal: the reason
for the betrayal could have been more meaningful and cooler. But,
overall, it was a pretty rad movie. I can imagine watching more
movies with Gina Carano starring.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I&#8217;m
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I&#8217;m on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I&#8217;ll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but&#8230;</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I&#8217;m not compelled by this one at all. It&#8217;s a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There&#8217;s a
&#8220;blindside&#8221; system, but it&#8217;s basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren&#8217;t ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It&#8217;s frustrating that
you can&#8217;t really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there&#8217;s no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you&#8217;ll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You&#8217;ll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it&#8217;s
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don&#8217;t think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m glad I&#8217;ve played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game&#8211;Pac-Man-CE-DX&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got another S-rank.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 3,144/248,092 &#8212; 1.26%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Contact, starring Jodie Foster (1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/12/Movie--Contact--starring-Jodie-Foster--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/12/Movie&#8211;Contact&#8211;starring-Jodie-Foster&#8211;1997&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this movie. It&#8217;s so inspirational and moving. I particularly
like the deep connection between it and the Gospel. I think it hits
the nail on the head in so many ways and is incredibly
pro-religion, of a sorts. I&#8217;ve read the book and I like both of
them for different reasons. It&#8217;s hard to say a lot about a movie I
just gush over.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game&#8211;Pac-Man-CE-DX&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today and a few weeks ago, I improved my score a bit. I am now
3,526/248,092, in the top 1.42%. I still have a few modes that are
not all As. I plan on getting all As and then eventually Ss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched the next episode where he spends a lot of time at the
Milk Barn. I loved looking at each of the different products in
the store. There was more clear Japanese translations. It was also
funny to have him role-play as York a little bit. It&#8217;s strange
that everyone talks about York&#8217;s scar.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Daybreakers, staring Ethan Hawke (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie&#8211;Daybreakers&#8211;staring-Ethan-Hawke&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie has a very unique and interesting premise: a dystopia
where vampires have become the norm and humans are rare. The
beginning of the movie, where you learn about what normal vampire
culture is like, is the best and most interesting part of the
movie. The rest of it lacks any unifying idea that brings it
weight. The cure is discovered to be controlled sunlight, but no
explanation is given why this would work. The cure turns out to be
contagious, so when a former vampire is fed from the feeder is
cured. There&#8217;s no explanation offered, although I would have liked
some pseudo-science. The rest of the movie is some pretty routine
chase and fight sequences. The movie feels very much like an
allegory about American imperialism and the ethic of kids who join
the military, combined with standard liberal concerns about oil,
etc. The other great missed opportunity is more guilt and attention
given to the main &#8220;bad guy&#8220;&#8216;s interaction with his daughter.</p>

<p>Overall, I&#8217;d say the movie was a disappointment. It wasn&#8217;t totally
terrible; I can definitely think of worse movies. But the majority
of what I got out of it, I would have had by just reading the
Wikipedia page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour tonight and mainly did story and
exploration stuff. I got the ability to go to other planets and
got to the medieval world. The game is okay so far. I haven&#8217;t
really been captured by it. I&#8217;m not sure why. The combat system
doesn&#8217;t seem as advanced as I&#8217;d like and a lot of the world is
pretty empty and samey. I&#8217;ll keep playing, but I&#8217;m a bit sad I
haven&#8217;t been totally won over by it.</p>

<p>Total: 3:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched the first two episodes of the 100% playthrough. I really
like the commentary that the guy adds and how he seems to know
everything that is interesting in the game. He hasn&#8217;t yet done
what I did in the game, but he&#8217;s done so much more. The game is
super quirky and fascinating.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: 300, directed by Zack Snyder (2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie--300--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie&#8211;300&#8211;directed-by-Zack-Snyder&#8211;2007&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an amazing movie. The visual were out of this world. The
story is so inspiring. Although it is pretty bloody, for some
reason there&#8217;s really only like two gross parts. The grossest thing
was the disfigured people, but that&#8217;s weird, mainly because it&#8217;s
actually real.</p>

<p>Looking at the guys in the movie makes you feel tiny, puny, and
weak. It&#8217;s super intense.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
&#8220;Inn&#8221; to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I&#8217;ve been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There&#8217;s just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one &#8220;episode&#8221; per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I&#8217;m looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don&#8217;t really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It&#8217;s the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful, although a little bit of the time
I felt like I was losing because I couldn&#8217;t target the thing I
wanted. The graphics are pretty good, although the characters are
verrry anime-y and from some angles their clothes really clash
with their faces. (For example, the guy on the computer screen
that Edge talks to.) The controls are responsive.  Although the
camera controls are a little too &#8220;tight&#8221; for my taste so far. I
got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I think the
problem is that the world is so &#8220;bright&#8221; that it&#8217;s hard to notice
something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of the time was
spent in videos, so I don&#8217;t really have a good feel for the game
yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided based on some consultation with forum posts, etc, that I
will watch a long play of the game, rather than play through it
myself. The gameplay is so bad and I want to see everything, but
don&#8217;t want to play with a walkthrough. It&#8217;s more efficient to just
watch it. I found two playthroughs: <a href="http://forums.somethingawful.com/showthread.php?threadid%3D3368004">a 100% playthrough</a> and [[http://www.giantbomb.com/forums/deadly-premonition/5058/endurance-run-download-urls/417644/][a
GiantBomb Endurance Run]]. I&#8217;m not sure which one will be better, so
I&#8217;ll try a little of both. I intend on writing about the game as I
watch these, as if it were me playing. We&#8217;ll see how that goes&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Transformers: Dark of the Moon, directed by Michael Bay (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie--Transformers--Dark-of-the-Moon--directed-by-Michael-Bay--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie&#8211;Transformers&#8211;Dark-of-the-Moon&#8211;directed-by-Michael-Bay&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another stupid, crazy, spectacle movie. The plot is pretty
incomprehensible, but who cares, or expects better? The visuals
were really amazing. I was kind of annoyed that Megan Fox wasn&#8217;t in
it and there was basically no explanation for why. I see why her
character wouldn&#8217;t work for what they had the girl do, but I don&#8217;t
see why that was a necessary plot point. Either way, the whole
movie was some good stupid fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today and finished the game. I got
As on the last few missions, which was pretty cool. I think I got
As on almost all of them, but I didn&#8217;t load my Clear data, so I&#8217;m
not sure if it would say what my overall statistics were, etc.</p>

<p>It was a really cool game. The ending was sweet. There were so
pretty crazy revelations about the characters, the events were
suitably epic, and the final boss was intense. I particularly
liked the sequence at the end where they showed what each
character did after the war&#8230; especially the little vignette
about Welkin and Alicia and their baby girl :) So cute!</p>

<p>The combat in the game is really interesting too. I enjoyed both
the &#8220;stealth&#8221; missions and the other ones. It makes me think a lot
about how you&#8217;d make a game like this. (And in particular,
randomly generate levels for it.)</p>

<p>I saw that there were some DLC missions, but I don&#8217;t think it is
worth it for me right now given my queue. I do like the game a
lot, but I feel like I&#8217;ve got the missions down to be a bit rote,
so it&#8217;s mainly the story pushing me to do more.</p>

<p>It was interesting to compare my final in-game timer (25:08) to my
count (33:39), because it shows how much time was taken up by
mission attempts that ultimately failed and thus weren&#8217;t counted
in the real total. Wow!</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>

<p>Total: 33:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
