<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T21:04:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Le Divorce, starring Naomi Watts and Kate Hudson (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie&#8211;Le-Divorce&#8211;starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson&#8211;2003&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting movie. I feel like the main point is that
we have two groups of people with loose morals, but vastly
different ways of reacting to them coming into conflict. The
characters are pretty complex and interesting. The environments,
food, clothes, and women all look very beautiful and elegant. It&#8217;s
a fun non-stereotyped picture of France. I particularly like the
scene where the two police flirt. It serves no purpose other than
to say, &#8220;This can&#8217;t happen in America.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Coco Before chanel, starring Audrey Tatou (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie--Coco-Before-chanel--starring-Audrey-Tatou--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie&#8211;Coco-Before-chanel&#8211;starring-Audrey-Tatou&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really neat movie. I didn&#8217;t know anything about Coco
Chanel, besides who she was and that she had a major influence on
women&#8217;s fashion. It was very interesting to learn about her life
before getting in to the fashion world. I like the subtlety of the
movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played tonight for about 20 minutes. I played two continues on
Ring Man&#8217;s stage and couldn&#8217;t get much past the Hippo. My kids
then took two continues and just stayed on the first screen
running around and climbing up the later and using the super
shot. It was cute.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 1 - Episode One]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/03/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-1---Episode-One-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/03/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-1&#8212;Episode-One-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just noticed that the next season was released in the
UK. This was a fun episode to get back with everyone again. I&#8217;m
glad that they&#8217;ve evolved the challenge to be more than just
Mary and Matthew fighting. It seems like the new challenge will
be this money problem and it will last through the whole
season. Obviously I have no clue, but they&#8217;ve actually got a
reliable problem to lean on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this today for 30 minutes at the request of my son. He
loves Mega Man a lot and always wants to play one. He&#8217;s very
interested in fighting Skull Man, but I went Toad -> Bright ->
Pharaoh and then died during Ring Man&#8217;s stage.</p>

<p>Something I dislike about Mega Man is the three lives system. On
a single level, it is a good idea, because it requires you to get
some mastery, rather than just sacrificing life to go
forward. The problem is that when you beat a boss on your last
life, the next level you start off with only the one life. This
encourages you to commit suicide at the start of the next level
(because there&#8217;s no disadvantage to doing that&#8230; you keep your E
Tanks and all your equipment.) I don&#8217;t like it when games have an
optimal strategy that is (a) un-fun, (b) trivial to execute, and
(c) trivial to have just programmed out of the game.</p>

<p>In any case, this game has lots of clever concepts in its
platforming.</p>

<p>In Toad Man&#8217;s stage, the rain&#8217;s ability to push you is very
challenging and the rushing water is also interesting. Fighting
the Giant Snail on the water-ridden platform was very nerve
racking.</p>

<p>In Bright Man&#8217;s stage, the jumping grasshoppers were cool
(although really out of place) and the enemies that shut-out the
lights when you hit them was pretty crazy. The sequence before the
boss door where you had to jump from falling/sliding platform to
the next one while the light-putter-outers where moving around and
firing. It was nuts.</p>

<p>In Pharaoh Man&#8217;s stage, the platforms then when you jump on them
start moving and then fall was cool. It was particularly
challenging because the next platform would shot at you just
before you were supposed to jump on to it and if you didn&#8217;t jump
early enough, you would be shocked and fall to your death.</p>

<p>In Ring Man&#8217;s stage (what I&#8217;ve seen so far), I like the platforms
that shift from side to side as you walk across them. In one
sequence if you dropped beneath one you could get a large health
charge, but you had to jump back up quickly or else you&#8217;d be
stuck. It&#8217;s a great idea.</p>

<p>This game is a very creative Mega Man game that really does
something quite different every stage, rather than executing the
same set of mechanics really well. (It&#8217;s not that I think the
normal Mega Man style is bad, but this is neat.) I&#8217;ve heard a lot
of griping about the charged shot, but I don&#8217;t find it to be so
powerful that I have to keep it charged all the time (and thus
slow down the action.) Whenever I&#8217;ve done that, I think it has
hurt me more than it helped.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunt for Red October, staring Sean Connery (1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie&#8211;The-Hunt-for-Red-October&#8211;staring-Sean-Connery&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun movie. I&#8217;m on a <em>REDACTED</em> Ryan kick and I want to go read
all the novels. The story is really great and I love that the
engine really exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game&#8211;Crystalis&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It&#8217;s very
fun. There&#8217;s a little too much grinding&#8230; I feel like I can&#8217;t
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it&#8217;s fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it&#8217;s a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This whole chapter seems to be about Marie Taglioni and she sounds
amazing.</p>

<p>If Vestris designed the steps that became modern ballet, she
figured out how to do them with the style expect of modern
ballerinas. She did everything that Vestris did, but she practiced
so long and hard to achieve the strength necessary to do it in an
&#8220;elegant&#8221; and &#8220;feminine&#8221; way. While the early dancers were
&#8220;sweaty&#8221; and &#8220;breathless&#8221; when they did them, she was
&#8220;angelic&#8221;. She built this technique over 6 months after a failed
start in Vienna by working for 6 hours a day and holding poses for
100 seconds.</p>

<p>Her shoes are still extant and have been studied. While she
performed full pointe, she mainly held herself at full point and
did not dance on it. We know this because her shoes were not the
boxed and hard style that allows that. Instead, by looking at the
wearing at the shoes, it looks like she danced about half-way
between half-pointe and full-pointe. Her dancing was so powerful
that she used 2 or 3 shoes per performance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Sum of All Fears, starring Ben Affleck (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie--The-Sum-of-All-Fears--starring-Ben-Affleck--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie&#8211;The-Sum-of-All-Fears&#8211;starring-Ben-Affleck&#8211;2002&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of my favourite movies. I love the early scenes of his
life as a boring analyst. Especially when his office mates are
talking about the intimate details of the lives of the people they
spy on. This is such a clever movie and it has so much great
acting. I greatly enjoy the disturbing way politics and personal
relationships get in the way of the right things happening. It&#8217;s
deliciously cynical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/28/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/28/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read one of the most interesting sections so far. It
discussed how in the 1820s, a ballet master named Vestris
dramatically changed the art.</p>

<p>He took the old three different genres of ballet and combined all
their steps into a new genre&#8212;that is modern ballet. This had lots
of big consequences. The old notation systems didn&#8217;t work any
longer and weren&#8217;t replaced because of the complexity of the new
dances.</p>

<p>The old style of practice was forgotten and replaced. Before, whole
dances were done continuously for practice, but after individual
steps were repeated dozens of times before going on to more
steps. The various steps were ranked in order of difficulty. For
example, in Vestris&#8217; notes it says there were 27 different kinds
of pirouettes.</p>

<p>In particular, the role of the male dancer changed a lot. Vestris
innovated the male dancer as acrobat doing many jumps and
turns. This was seen as very wild and distasteful. In addition,
the new style he came up with was perfected by women, so part of
his innovation led to male dancers becoming pariahs and not a
major part of ballet. In fact, in the mid 1800s, many male roles
were played by women! This is funny to me because a hundred years
before, the opposite was true.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/27/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/27/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The concept that Napolean had a major effect on the organization
of ballet companies and schools is really fascinating.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Sons of Perdition (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/26/Movie--Sons-of-Perdition--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/26/Movie&#8211;Sons-of-Perdition&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very touching movie. I would like to help these kids as
much as I can. I was most impressed that many people see all
<em>REDACTED</em>s as identical to these people, or at least as crazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a few minutes again and got two courses in. It&#8217;s
nice that is so easy to start up a game.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Adventures of Lolo 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game&#8211;Adventures-of-Lolo-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played through this whole game&#8230; throughout the day&#8230; a
total of seven hours and eleven minutes! Woah! This is a great
game. I love these escape puzzle games.</p>

<p>There are fifty puzzles, so each took an average of eight minutes,
but I&#8217;d say most were either really short&#8230; like one or two
tries&#8230; or very long. I had to seek hints about five times. The
ones that were the hardest were ones where you need to push a
block half a tile, or cover a monster spawning location with a
block so it would appear somewhere else, or where you need really
precise timing. The biggest problem with the game is when Lolo
gets stuck on edges of the grid. Nevertheless, It&#8217;s a lot of fun
to play.</p>

<p>The graphics are simple and to the point, but super adorable. I
love the way Lolo runs.</p>

<p>My son had fun helping me and giving me advice during the game.</p>

<p>There&#8217;s not much more to say about it, but it&#8217;s very enjoyable.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played three rounds and got to the boss of the first area both
times. This game is ridiculously bad. The controls are terrible
and basic mechanics are broken. For example, there&#8217;s no period of
invulnerability when you get hit and you get stunlocked in
place. There were times when I missed a jump, landed on an enemy,
and slowly lost all my health as I couldn&#8217;t move away.</p>

<p>I remember playing this game as a kid, but I don&#8217;t remember every
getting past the first stage. I guess I never will.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sweet Home (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Sweet-Home&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a really interesting game. It&#8217;s clear to me how Resident
Evil was inspired by this. The difficulties of managing the
various members of the party and piecing together the
multi-dimensional fetch quest is a very interesting (and pretty
unique) structure for a game.</p>

<p>I played reading a walk-through that was very particular about
where you should go and what you should do. I feel like it would
be bad to play this way, because the whole point of the game is
to explore this world. However, it seems like it is pretty brutal
in terms of what your lack of knowledge means. I think I will put
this on my &#8220;revisit&#8221; pile.</p>

<p>Given my short time with the game, the main problem with it is
that it is just a puzzle and there&#8217;s no good visceral feeling
associated with playing the game. The controls are pretty awkward
(knowing who is who is a pain in the beginning, but would
definitely get better as you played more) and the battle system is
uninteresting. The quick-time events are really fascinating. The
lack of an ability to see if a weapon is strong is
annoying. Overall, it&#8217;s been a bit of an obtuse but really
strangely modern game. I feel like a game like this could be made
really well today. I don&#8217;t think I can look past the flaws right
now though.</p>

<p>When I do play it again, I will have to re-rank it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:43</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Square's Tom Sawyer (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Square-s-Tom-Sawyer--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Square-s-Tom-Sawyer&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m fascinated by the existence of this game and I have been since
I heard that it existed. I played the game for about twenty
minutes in all Japanese. I was able to understand the menus, but I
didn&#8217;t do much more than sound out the dialogue. The graphics are
ridiculously racist. The concept of the game is nuts and based on
my brief playing and a glance at a walkthrough&#8230; it is
transparent fetch quest with RPG battles in between. In some way,
this can be said of all RPGs, but it would be far too transparent
for me, given my limited grasp of the language. I wasn&#8217;t able to
walk to the first fetch quest delivery point and back without
dying.</p>

<p>Grinding is really the worst thing for old RPGs. Many of them had
interesting mechanics, but were padded for their day. In more
modern times, this padding is really destructive if you want to
experience what was interesting about the game. There&#8217;s no good
way to use codes and cheats to give a challenging, but still
non-tedious experience. There are ways to just pre-load with
super powers and get infinite experience, but that&#8217;s little
better than just watching the game on YouTube.</p>

<p>As I get older I&#8217;m much more interested in games without
progression systems because from the second you start you&#8217;re
faced with a test to learn new skills and apply them. The tests
get harder, but there&#8217;s no artificial curve in the game. In other
games with internal progression systems, the progression is more
than just numeric&#8230; it requires more strategy and planning. For
example, Dragon Quest 1 is basically just about getting higher
numbers until you can get even higher numbers. There&#8217;s little
strategy involved&#8230; just a test of how much risk you&#8217;re willing
to take. In contrast, FF6 adds more party members, complicated
enemy patterns, many spells, etc as the game progresses.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t know where Tom Sawyer fits in this rubric, but I&#8217;m not
going to give it a chance. I have dipped into its existence and
found it very curious.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:18</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Rhythm-Heaven-Fever&#8211;Wii&#8211;2011&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played twenty minutes of Monkey Watch today. I couldn&#8217;t make it
out of the practice again. I was able to reliably hit the yellow
monkeys but couldn&#8217;t get the purple ones at all. Not a single
time. This game is very frustrating. I&#8217;m doing terribly, but
it doesn&#8217;t communicate to me in any way what I&#8217;m doing wrong. In
addition, I&#8217;m now blocked from doing any other of the
mini-games&#8230; even though they will definitely test different
rhythm skills than this one. I want to play this game and
experience more, but I can&#8217;t. Argh.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mother (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Mother--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Mother&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game (via the prototype ROM dump) for a bit
today. It&#8217;s clear that this was the precursor to Earthbound. The
dialogue is great and the enemies are very odd.</p>

<p>It is also clear that it is a straight Dragon Quest clone. I was
not able to make it from the front door of my house to town
without dying. It took three trips before I reached a high enough
level to make it. When I got there, I had about $250 in cash, but
the next worthwhile weapon was $500. Classic. I started walking
around and was decimated by the first zombie on the way to the
cemetery (plot point #1).</p>

<p>During my short play, I noticed a few typos. This, combined with
the anticipatory pain of grinding, has led me to decide to replay
it on the Mother 1+2 remake for the GBA with the fan translation
that adds the &#8220;Easy Ring&#8221; option. I was definitely convinced that
I want to play this game, but not convinced by the NES version.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game&#8211;Chip&#8212;Dale-Rescue-Rangers&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat three levels after about forty minutes of play. This game
is very similar to Super Mario Brothers 2. It&#8217;s focused around
picking up blocks and throwing them, although you can throw them
in more directions in this game. The co-op play is a memorable
feature, although I played by myself.</p>

<p>The platforming is pretty good, but the hit detection against
projectiles and enemies is too imprecise&#8230; you can get hits
registered that look very far away from your character. This
annoyance combined with the extreme speed of a lot of the enemies
(particularly the flying ones) leads to a lot of frustration. The
boss of the third level is really vicious because it zooms across
the screen and drops two moving creatures that have big hit
boxes.</p>

<p>The first boss fight is super easy once you realize what you need
to do and is pretty bland. The third is more interesting, but
also flawed because you can&#8217;t effective shot in mid-air because
you fall so quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, I&#8217;d say this is a C+ NES platformer. It&#8217;s not
horrific&#8230; it&#8217;s certainly playable (unlike TMNT, for instance)
but it by no means enters the canon, and I don&#8217;t feel it&#8217;s really
worth my time. If I could have used a Game Genie code to get
infinite lives, I would have done it though and taken one screen
at a time. As it stands, the three lives per continue and three
continues barrier is too high for me to go through imperfect
mechanics.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
