<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-21T23:31:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game today. I pre-ordered it and have been excited
about it since I heard that it would come out. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve
ever really been an extremely &#8220;Sakaguchi&#8221; Final Fantasy fan&#8230; I
feel like I&#8217;ve responded more to Kitase&#8217;s direction, but
nevertheless, I enjoyed Blue Dragon and LOOOVED Lost Odyssey, so
I had high expectations for this game. But, after being let down
so bad so recently by Xenoblade, I was a little skeptical.</p>

<p>When I first turned it on, the first thing I noticed was that the
language is surprisingly crass. I think the very first sentence
has a swear. It&#8217;s not the worst curses, but it&#8217;s there and it was
a little jarring.</p>

<p>After that, I really enjoyed how the game started &#8220;in media
res&#8221;. You have a really immediate connection to the action and the
characters and they reveal themselves in a pretty nice and subdued
way. I think the voice acting is really good&#8230; especially
Syrene&#8217;s voice actress. She sounds very, very cool. In general,
all the characters strike me as really interesting and cool. The
&#8220;sweet&#8221; girl seems very sweet too, which I like.</p>

<p>At this point in the story (after chapter 6), I really like how
&#8220;low-key&#8221; the story is. Coming from Xenoblade where you fight
God, it&#8217;s nice to have a story that is much more low level and
intimate (at least at the beginning, who knows what will happen
in the end?)</p>

<p>When I first got to the tavern, I was kind of amazed by the unique
voice acting and animated interactions with the group. I was
worried that I had accidentally advanced the story when I was
trying to just wander around and talk to people.</p>

<p>I feel like the sub-quest system isn&#8217;t very good, because there&#8217;s
no list of who wants what from you. This is a place where
Xenoblade was clearly superior in the interface department, but
Last Story seems to be keeping you more connected with the
characters, at the expense of forgetting about them all together.</p>

<p>The equipment system is interesting. It seems like armor isn&#8217;t
really that important because they were all equal for me, but
they seem to have different status effects after they&#8217;ve been
upgraded. There seems to be an assumption that you will be
upgrading every item, rather than reserving upgrading for the end
(as many games, in fact, assume.)</p>

<p>I bought all the weapons and armor that I could in the first town
and maxed them all out (up to getting some sort of rare item that
would be required to progress them.)</p>

<p>The concept of &#8220;local goods&#8221; seems strange. I get the inkling
that you can do arbitrage to make money&#8230; sounds tedious. I hope
it isn&#8217;t necessary.</p>

<p>The clothing dying system is difficult for me to imagine how to
use effectively. I feel like I want to look online for a gallery
of cool colourings. The &#8220;invisible&#8221; option is very intriguing.</p>

<p>When I was exploring, I found the arena. Syrene&#8217;s dialogue about
it was awesome&#8230; so funny. I had a really hard time the first
time in the arena, because I had yet grasped the combat system. I
originally felt like I needed to be up next to enemies all the
time, but now I feel like it is more important to manage the
battlefield and setup sneak attacks, etc. I think I may also want
to turn on the &#8220;Manual&#8221; attack mode, because I think it will feel
better.</p>

<p>After I died and retried in the arena, I then played through the
first Season of the arena six more times. The combat system
is <em>really</em> <em>really</em> fun. I like it a lot and it was cool to just
go at it and feel the excitement of the mechanics. What an
awesome change from Xenoblade.</p>

<p>I moved on with the story after that and met Lisa&#8230; accidentally
tried to walk in on them in the bath and got some really funny
text. Then moved on to the next area. The boss in that area was
difficult to do properly, because I didn&#8217;t realize I could do a
Slash over the railing. I was trying to get the auto-attack to
happen and it never did before I got hosed. Once I realized that
I could Slash, it was cake and I learned more about the game.</p>

<p>From this experience, I can say that I really love this game play
so far and I&#8217;ve very excited to see where the story goes too.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 12
Total time: 4:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie&#8211;G-I&#8211;Joe&#8211;The-Rise-of-Cobra&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool&#8230; although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking&#8230; I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear&#8230; and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I ended just before the final cut-off point to the final
bosses and end of the game. I finished the game today in about an
hour. Today as I started to play, I left the title screen on for a
while&#8230; it was very beautiful as the time of day changed.</p>

<p>I thought the end of the game was fun and crazy. It was so
incredibly Evangelion and so classically Japanese, like I said
before, but even more so given the ending&#8212;everyone you thought
was good is actually bad and everyone that was bad is really good,
and all that. I especially liked walking around in space and the
origin story given to Zanza. It was also neat how Dickson ended
up.</p>

<p>Total time: 26:36</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>In the end, I feel like this was a really interesting story and
world, but a pretty terrible game. The mechanics were just very
shallow and boring, lacking in meaningful choices. I think you
could do something with the concepts in the combat system, but
they didn&#8217;t really do it. One thing that I reckon WoW does that
this game lacks is that because you need to assemble large groups
with varied skills, there is an interesting meta-process of doing
that, but it is still ultimately boring for the individual
players.</p>

<p>I heard so much about how amazing this game was and how it was so
great that Japanese developers were learning from the West, but I
feel like all the Western ideas here are bad ideas that I don&#8217;t
want to see more of.</p>

<p>I really disliked that every item changed your appearance because
it was hard to look consistent while having the best
stats. Everyone just looked so stupid generally.</p>

<p>The interface was pretty terrible because it took so many clicks
to do everything and the buttons were reversed from what they
should be on the controller. Ugh.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t think I can really recommend this game&#8230; maybe I would
just recommend watching some videos and reading about the story,
but I found the mechanics to be unbearably weak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like four hours tonight. The ending of this game is
classic Japanese insanity where you fight God and conquer your
fate. The changing alliances and what not at the end of the game
are pretty crazy too. I like a lot of what went on and it is very
intriguing in its Evangelion-ness. Some of the boss battles are
getting to be very tedious slog fests.</p>

<p>Total time: 25:32</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game&#8211;Punch-Out&#8212;-Wii&#8211;2009&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played before dinner for like 10 minutes. I brought down the
Sandman three times, once per round, but died each of the two
matches. I&#8217;m getting better though!</p>

<p>Total time: 3:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tower Heist, starring Ben Stiller (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie--Tower-Heist--starring-Ben-Stiller--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie&#8211;Tower-Heist&#8211;starring-Ben-Stiller&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched this on recommendation from some friends. I had never
heard of it, so I didn&#8217;t know what to expect. I didn&#8217;t know it was
a comedy. It was funny, but a lot of it was pretty low brow. I&#8217;m
not even sure I&#8217;d give it a three, despite the funny moments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play for like two hours this morning to entertain my kids so my
wife could sleep in. It was very interesting to be down on the
Mechonis foot and get to know what happened to Fiora. Her outfits
look very cool&#8230; very similar to KOS-MOS. Dickson is ridiculous
in his ability to be everyone instantly, despite being a level 25
NPC.</p>

<p>Later in the day, we played for another hour and had an epic fight
then went on a dumb fetch quest to get bomb parts. We played again
for just thirty minutes and did a little exploring, before
watching the first war scene and calling it quits for the night.</p>

<p>Total time: 21:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game&#8211;Rhythm-Heaven-Fever&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this while my kids watched for like 40 minutes. We
played up to the Fork Lift one. I had a really hard time with it
and the See Saw. I really enjoyed the Double Date one, it was
super cute. The first Remix was fun too.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game&#8211;Rayman-Origins&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son requested this again and I got all the awards on the second
level then got all the things on the third, except the medal and
the speed trophy. I found it un-intuitive to figure out how to do
the time course. I also find this game to control incredibly
sloppily. The character just swishes around all the time, it is
incredibly obnoxious and hard to deal with.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deathsmiles (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game&#8211;Deathsmiles&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the first games that my son would specifically
request. He hasn&#8217;t in a long time, but wanted to today. I played
through it with three continues (one on Tyrannosatan). It was
fun. I didn&#8217;t do too well, but I did get the extend during the
castle stage.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like three hours tonight. There&#8217;s been lots of crazy
reveals in the game, some that have been obvious for a long time
and others that were just cool. Getting on to Mechonis was
awesome. It was crazy to see the new map screen. Rad.</p>

<p>Some of the main-line fetch quests in this game are absurd. You
walk through an area and then get to the end are given a fetch
quest where you walk all the way back across the area. It&#8217;s
totally insane.</p>

<p>Total time: 18:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours tonight. I got to the gate of Prison
Island. The whole High Entia concept is pretty cool&#8230; especially
that there is this giant civilization that&#8217;s totally disconnected
from others beneath it on the monster. The message at the Tomb was
very interesting too&#8230; I wonder what the ancestor&#8217;s plans were
regarding the genetic destiny of their people?</p>

<p>I really enjoyed seeing the waterfall in the forest. It was very
magnificent. My son was very impressed too.</p>

<p>Exploring the Entia capital was very confusing because the arrow
points in the direction of the destination, not the teleporter
that you have to use to get to it. It was very confusing. When I
was exploring these big empty places with very same-y textures and
models, it made me think how much this game is like mid to late
PS2 games in terms of what it tries to do technically. Rather than
having detailed environments, it often has very large environments
with big draw distances as a way to show, for example.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Uniracers (SNES, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Uniracers--SNES--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game&#8211;Uniracers&#8211;SNES&#8211;1994&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d never played this game before, but I thought it might be
interesting for my son because you don&#8217;t need to do very much. He
wasn&#8217;t interested in trying it and I did the first 5 races. It
was really neat. I&#8217;m excited about playing through it when it
comes up.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Tetris & Dr. Mario (SNES, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Tetris---Dr--Mario--SNES--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game&#8211;Tetris&#8212;Dr&#8211;Mario&#8211;SNES&#8211;1994&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son wanted to see an &#8220;easy&#8221; game and I thought this might be a
good choice because its input space is so limited. He didn&#8217;t
really understand it and wanted to switch to something else after
I lost.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game&#8211;Super-Mario-All-Stars&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played SMB1 and did levels 1-1 and 1-2. My son played
himself. He spend 5 lives running directly into the first Goomba
and cracking up. He thought it was sooo funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Little Nemo: The Dream Master (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Little-Nemo--The-Dream-Master--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game&#8211;Little-Nemo&#8211;The-Dream-Master&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have this cartridge and my son thinks the box art is cool. We
played today for a little and I beat the first level&#8230; which I
haven&#8217;t done any of the last four or five times he&#8217;s wanted to
see the game. I feel like it&#8217;s a pretty brutal game, because most
animals (and Nemo) have no offense abilities.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. The scenery was really
cool. It was awesome going through the swamp and the Bionis&#8217;
body. The visions that Schulk it seeing now are very cool and I
can&#8217;t wait to get to that area of the game. Dunban&#8217;s new outfit
is neat too. I still think the battle system is terrible, and I
still think the world is exciting.</p>

<p>Total time: 11:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game&#8211;Super-Mario-All-Stars&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played SMB1 in this for a while because my son wanted to see
some Mario. When I died and needed to continue in the World 2
castle, my son suggested that we move on to a different game. He
really enjoyed the water level in world 2.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Secret of Evermore (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game&#8211;Secret-of-Evermore&#8211;SNES&#8211;1995&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been telling my son the story of this game for a long time,
because he likes stories about dogs and exciting adventures by
boys. Today I suggested that he might like to see it. We played
for a bit. I forgot about how in the beginning you see the end of
the game and the various forms of the dog. Cool. We played
through to the bug boss of the pre-historic area, but I died. I
wasn&#8217;t quick enough using items. I forgot that I wouldn&#8217;t have a
checkpoint of some kind and we didn&#8217;t save, but once. So, we
moved on to a different game.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:54</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game&#8211;Rayman-Origins&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son picked this game out because of its box art and it is in
my &#8220;new game queue&#8221;. I&#8217;d been planning on playing it co-op with
my wife, but I couldn&#8217;t dissuade him from wanting to check it
out. I&#8217;ve never played a Rayman game before, so I didn&#8217;t know
what to expect other than that it is a platformer.</p>

<p>I found the world to be really cute and the art to be awesome.</p>

<p>I think the controls are really floaty and delayed (especially
the punches). The running doesn&#8217;t feel quite right either. But
I&#8217;d say it is still on par with DKCR, and not totally terrible.</p>

<p>We played two levels. The first I played twice so I could get all
the stuff and the second I was one shiny thing away from the
second bonus. The collectathon in this game seems more fun that
the collectathons in DKCR and I&#8217;m not sure if I like them more or
less than NSMBW.</p>

<p>I couldn&#8217;t figure out how to play multiplayer&#8230; maybe I just
needed to have two active controllers. Nor could I understand
what the difference between the characters were. I hope to play
it with my wife eventually, but I probably won&#8217;t play again for a
while unless the kids request it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
