<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-05T00:29:52-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Awakening, starring Kate Beckinsale (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Awakening&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was the fasted paced and immediately insane movie. It&#8217;s
practically equivalent to the insanity of the fourth Resident Evil
movie. The amount the world of the movies changes in the first five
minutes is unbelievable. Yet, they pack in lots of really
fascinating and sensible ideas and imagery. It&#8217;s spectacular.</p>

<p>The story is interesting, although it is unclear why they would
need to be studying the hybrids, but whatever. The quality of the
Lycan models continues to improve, although their heads are still
not quite right. This movie removes all sympathy for the Lycans
that was in the background of the 1st and 3rd movies. It basically
does absolutely nothing for the mythology either. Perhaps it will
be more successful because of that, because you don&#8217;t really need
to know anything about the previous movies to appreciate this
one. The mythological wankery only appeals to some, but this could
appeal to many.</p>

<p>The movie was noticeably more gory than previous movies. The only
time this bothered me was at the very beginning when Selene was
killing humans escaping. I don&#8217;t mind gore when it is directed at
monsters or aliens, but humans shouldn&#8217;t receive it. It is also
kind of uncharacteristic, because the previous movies have
established a vampire moral code that limits their consumption of
human blood.</p>

<p>I was surprised that Michael Corvin is basically not in the
movie. I was expecting him to come back and save the day in the
final fight after Selene had released him. (The actual ending
though, was supremely feminist, as the mother and daughter don&#8217;t
really need help from the father, or men in general.) But I suppose
it was based on some contractual reason.</p>

<p>The Wikipedia page contains story information that I didn&#8217;t get
from the movie. For example, the daughter&#8217;s name is Eve and the
secret of the immortals was revealed to humans by the
doctor. Weird.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today. I did a bunch of different
missions, all were done in a relatively &#8220;stealthy&#8221; style. It was
very hard though, but quite fun. The story is really interesting,
as I said. I was quite surprised by who shot Alicia. After the
next battle, I unlocked a few reports, which I am now going
through.</p>

<p>Total: 26:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Rise-of-the-Lycans&#8211;starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy&#8211;2009&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking about this movie the day after, there are some things
really strange about it:</p>

<p>All the movies more or less establish the vampires as basically in
the right, with the werewolves being too uncontrolled to be safe
for humans. Almost as if the vampires are protecting humans from
the immortals&#8212;especially given that they have a cultural
imperative to not consume human blood. (Viktor is a &#8220;bad&#8221; vampire
almost entirely because he sometimes breaks this rule.)</p>

<p>The first movie mixes this a little bit, portraying Lucian as
having been wronged and the vampires, especially Viktor, overly
prejudiced. But, it doesn&#8217;t give Lucian any motives other than
revenge on vampires. Given that he is involved in offensive action,
it&#8217;s not as if the vampires are simply out to get him. The war is
reciprocal.</p>

<p>The second movie really lays on the thick that danger of the
werewolves with the flash back sequences, but otherwise doesn&#8217;t
really develop the reason for the conflict. It&#8217;s basically just
sibling rivalry. (The movie is also weird because it makes very
little sense that Markus would act as he does now, as opposed to in
any of the previous 100 year periods where he was the sole reigning
vampire elder. It&#8217;s especially incomprehensible why he destroys his
coven.)</p>

<p>The third movie doesn&#8217;t really explain why Lucian would continue to
fight the vampires. It presents him as unassailably moral and a
freedom fighter. But once he gets his freedom, why does he have any
reason to continue fighting? Especially given that he thinks Viktor
is dead.</p>

<p>I presume that this won&#8217;t be resolved or explained in the last
movie. But maybe not? It seems like Selene is the oldest vampire
that we&#8217;ve heard of it that is still alive and there has never been
any ranking werewolves other than Lucian and William.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: In Time, starring Justin Timberlake (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--In-Time--starring-Justin-Timberlake--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie&#8211;In-Time&#8211;starring-Justin-Timberlake&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really fascinating movie. It&#8217;s a totally unique dystopia
for me (maybe Wikipedia will tell me about things that are like
it?) and that is always fascinating. The plot is basically Bonnie &amp;
Clyde after an initial glance at the prejudice and hardship in the
system.</p>

<p>The imagery is really cool and there are lots of interesting and
bizarre situations, like the way Wies introduces his female
relatives.</p>

<p>I think the movie lost some good opportunities for character
development. For example, Will gets 30 minutes for lunch at the
beginning but she dies by seconds when she can&#8217;t take the bus, and
was just 20 minutes short of being able to pay for the bus
ride. Yet, he doesn&#8217;t acknowledge this for the sake of the audience
or to show his great remorse, etc.</p>

<p>Overall, I found the movie to be very intriguing. This, however, is
also its biggest problem because it begs you to think about it
deeply and the world isn&#8217;t explained well enough.</p>

<p>For example, there&#8217;s a strong suggestion that the mantra &#8220;For few to
be immortal, many must die&#8221; has some sort of quasi-mystical and
dreadful significance. Like there is some sort of Big Brother type
that is keeping people down. However, this isn&#8217;t followed through.</p>

<p>The purpose of the Time Keepers is not explained adequately. On one
level, they are simply cops and since money is time, they are
connected to time. However, in the end, when they&#8217;re talking about
how &#8220;that much money can&#8217;t leave that zone&#8221; and many other
situations, you get the impression that there is some deeper
purpose to their actions.</p>

<p>Similarly, the movie has poor economics. For example, what effect
does birth have, given that it introduces a year of time? If the
time is a real commodity&#8212;i.e. an abstraction of some sort of
energy their bodies need, rather than a fiat system (i.e. they are
like nanomachines that keep track of the time and just kill you
when it is zero.)&#8212;then where does the new year come from? How
could there be such price controls?</p>

<p>I think the movie could have resolved this better by coming up with
some sort of origin story and pseudo-science to explain why people
would choose to live like this (and everyone!) at some point
voluntarily and how it works. I think the fiat system would have
been interesting, because it makes it so there&#8217;s actually a
solution that they could possibly reach. But, as it is, we can&#8217;t
imagine that Will and Sylvia will ever actually fix
anything&#8230; other than what communists and Robin Hoods try to do
and fail to do in the real world.</p>

<p>The movie is very confused, therefore, with what its message (and
the message of its heroes) really is. Philippe spouts
pseudo-Capitalism, so perhaps the movie is anti-Capitalism? Yet,
the corruption of the Time Keepers vis a vis Fortis is reminiscent
of the relationship between the US and e.g. African dictators. So,
is it an anti &#8220;Globalization&#8221; or &#8220;Imperialist&#8221; politic?</p>

<p>I think because they don&#8217;t foreshadow a solution or great evil
through technology or metaphysics, the world must be a &#8220;natural&#8221;
world and so the villain must be natural, and they rhetoric of the
movie leaves nothing left but a political agenda. Yet, it doesn&#8217;t
articulate what the agenda is.</p>

<p>The movie is good for making it possible to think of it like this,
but it is bad because by not answering these questions, it is
incoherent and vapid.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--10/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about 33 minutes today and basically just learned
that Alicia really is a Valkyria and she&#8217;s super tough. I lost the
battle pretty hard, because I did a stealth rush and couldn&#8217;t
defend the forward base. Now that I know where the enemy will be,
I think I will try to pre-place Lancers behind the where the tanks
appear! We&#8217;ll see tomorrow.</p>

<p>Total: 23:26</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Rise-of-the-Lycans&#8211;starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was really surprised by the quality of this movie. I assumed that
because it didn&#8217;t star Kate Beckinsale it would be a cheap version
of the world. But actually, I think it is the best yet; although it
wouldn&#8217;t be very good without the first movie, obviously. It gives
a lot better context to the first movie and makes a lot of what
seems strange about the mythology a lot more reasonable. The story
is a lot more coherent and reasonable and the action is noticeably
slower, so you can appreciate it a bit more.</p>

<p>The development of the romance between Lucian and Sonja is totally
ignored, apart from a glance when they are kids.</p>

<p>Rhona Mitra really does look like Kate Beckinsale.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s cool that the giant black werewolf from the first scene of the
first movie is one of Lucian&#8217;s oldest friends. A nice little nod to
people paying attention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a few more stealth style missions. The big battle in the
trenches was really different and dangerous, although I did it in
a stealth way. The bonus mission where you had to search through
all the grassy areas was pretty cool too.</p>

<p>The story is getting really neat and touching. I can&#8217;t believe
they killed Isara, but I like the way you return to Bruhl as a way
to &#8220;avenge&#8221; her. The development of the idea of Alicia being a
Valkyria is really neat too. I wonder if it will just be in
cut-scenes or if she&#8217;ll become some crazy new unit type? I feel
like the story is close to wrapping up, but there are a lot more
empty boxes in the R&amp;D area, so I suspect that it really isn&#8217;t
that close to being done.</p>

<p>This is still an awesome game. The best part is probably the way
they are constantly developing and adding more and more to the
story and gameplay. It&#8217;s very different than it was in the
beginning, but the path to here has made complete sense.</p>

<p>Total: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kings of Power 4 Billion %, by Paul Robertson (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie--Kings-of-Power-4-Billion----by-Paul-Robertson--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie&#8211;Kings-of-Power-4-Billion&#8212;-by-Paul-Robertson&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is totally insane and amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a very busy but ultimately unproductive day with a lot of
wasted effort, so I played games rather later to feel some
accomplishment. I played for about 2 hours. I got through all of
chapter 11 and did the skirmish that opened up three times (Easy,
Normal, Normal)&#8230; all As (2 rounds!)&#8230; to get enough money to
buy everything. The beach battle was pretty scary, but I was able
to do it in 2 rounds with only 2 restarts. It was pretty cool to
have a few &#8220;stealth&#8221; levels.</p>

<p>Total: 20:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Evolution&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2006&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn&#8217;t seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It&#8217;s a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight&#8230; the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn&#8217;t understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it&#8230; but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I&#8217;m curious about what Zaka will be
like&#8230; do I really get another vehicle? I&#8217;m running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat the game tonight after playing for about 5 hours. The final
battle was super tough. I liked all the build-up side battles
too. The best part of the final battle were the cool 2D animations
and &#8220;camera&#8221; changes. It was pretty unique, although something
similar happened a few times in earlier parts of the game.</p>

<p>Overall, I found this game to be pretty rad. The game play is
straight-forward, but quick enough to not be too tedious compared
to the first three. The lack of a job system is fine, because the
individual characters you are given are interesting enough. The
story is very quaint and cute; the way they broke up the story is
very cool, especially how people act around the Hero.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t tell how much of what I like (such as the Heal All option)
were added in the remake, but I don&#8217;t feel like I need to play the
NES version to find out.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d play it again, because I&#8217;m willing to bet that
another Dragon Quest game (maybe a SNES one?) will be a more
refined experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 23:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld, starring Kate Beckinsale (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2003&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget why, but the other day I was reminded of this series. I
decided to start watching it, similar to how I went through the
Resident Evil movies. Like that series, I saw the first one when it
came out, but never saw the others. I remember thinking the movie
was cool and that Kate Beckinsale was amazing attractive.</p>

<p>On a second viewing, significantly older, I still think some parts
of the movie are cool. The mythology is interesting and fairly
developed. The actor of Viktor is pretty awesome; while the actor
that played Kraven was unbelievably bad. The character of Erica is
really interesting and subtle. And, yes, Kate Beckinsale is
woah&#8212;except, I don&#8217;t understand the appeal of the &#8220;cat suits&#8221;,
they make all her natural curves indistinguishable, like a running
bra or something. I don&#8217;t get it, but I guess that had to because
this movie was made to be so Matrix-y. The action sequences are
very derivative of the Matrix and pretty boring overall
actually. Lots of akimbo and chunks of buildings flying off. The
best fight is probably the very first one. Even the final fight
between Viktor and Michael is pretty meh, because Michael is so
&#8220;whatever&#8221; that it doesn&#8217;t get too exciting.</p>

<p>Definitely not a classic, but I&#8217;m interested in watching the rest
of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the &#8220;reports&#8221; I&#8217;d seen showing up were&#8230; how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service&#8230; I mean, the beach vacation&#8230; one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours throughout the day today while the
kids were playing and/or sick. I explored the waterfall and used
my water soaking stone and got a rad sword. I also did a little
bit of grinding until I could be Estark&#8230; which I barely did;
Ragnar was the only one left and he would&#8217;ve only last one
hit&#8230; and he was killed in the first fight as I tried to
escape. But, alas, I did.</p>

<p>After I got the balloon, I decided to be done for the night. As I
was looking at the world map, I thought how geeky and funny it
would be to have an &#8220;accurate&#8221; polar projection map with scaling
deformation in certain regions (including on the characters &amp;
their speed.) That would be funny.</p>

<p>Shopping list:
- 35k per Liquid Metal Armor in Endor (secret shop, need 3)
- Female armor in Elf town (need 2?)</p>

<p>Total time: 19:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Rise of the Planet of the Apes, starring James Franco and Andy Seeks (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie--Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes--starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie&#8211;Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes&#8211;starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was really different than I thought it would be. I
expected that the end of the movie would be closer to ape dominance
and I expected that the character of Caesar would be more of a hero
for humans&#8212;kind of the only smart ape that loved humans, whereas
the other ones (like Koba) would just hate them. The movie was
pretty cool and Caesar was a great epic leader. There were lots of
really cool &#8220;A-hah!&#8221; moments of his progression that were super
satisfying. I&#8217;d like to see sequels to this made.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter&#8211;DS&#8211;2011&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been plugging along in the game doing one a day. I got the
train mini-game today. It&#8217;s a neat version of the car mini-game
from the last one. The idea of dealing with multiple trains at a
time sounds like it will be challenging.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out&#8212;-NES&#8211;1987&#8211;11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to show the wife this game and have her try it out. She
beat Glass Joe by decision after losing by decision and having me
show her how it was done. She lost on the next fight but I took
the continue and took it all the way to Soda Popinski. It was
pretty rad to go through the whole game up to that point and show
off to her a bit. My code this time around was different though:</p>

<p>255 113 7842</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played three levels tonight. It was pretty fun. My wife and I
had a bit of a disagreement about what was fun about the game. She
really likes collecting everything and exploring the area, trying
to do harder things. In contrast, I find that annoying and prefer
to just go through the obstacle course as fast as possible. But,
the secret of marital bliss is she tells me what to do, and I do
it, so I repented. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. The story battles are
getting pretty rough and un-cheese-able, which is really fun
because it forces me to try different things. I got a really bad
score in the second woodland battle, which was kinda sad, so I did
another skirmish so I could get the XP I missed. I really enjoyed
using the tank a lot in the woodland battle though.</p>

<p>Total: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
