<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game&#8211;Crystalis&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I had to restart because my
save was lost somehow. I got to Portoa and got the Sword of
Water. (This appears to be about half-way by glancing at the Table
of Contents of a guide.)</p>

<p>The mechanics in the game never really get much more
interesting. They definitely add a few things: like the Rabbit
Boots, and presumably you eventually are able to cross water, and
then the keys that the swords become after you get their balls,
etc. But all the things that are different in the game are on the
level of navigation annoyances (not really &#8220;puzzles&#8221;).</p>

<p>I wouldn&#8217;t say that I&#8217;m opposed to games that don&#8217;t change their
mechanics&#8212;Super Mario, for instance, doesn&#8217;t have different
mechanics through the game. But, Mario can do this because (a) the
game play is awesome and (b) the game play is rich enough that it
supports gaining mastery and then increasing the challenge.</p>

<p>In my time playing Crystalis, it was very true to the literal
definition of &#8220;Action RPG&#8221;. The individual encounters were totally
trivial (like hitting &#8220;Fight&#8221; over and over), but did require
moderate action. The challenge came from requiring a deep grind to
get resources&#8212;power to attack with and money to pay for healing
and rests. The severely limited inventory and the large number of
enemies really encourages you to go incredibly slowly and defeat
every enemy. But, it&#8217;s not fun enough to do. It feels pretty good
for about an hour, but after that it gets really aggravating, and
I feel like I want to just rush by.</p>

<p>Something I&#8217;m surprised I was annoyed by was the need to switch
weapons to fight different kinds of enemies. It just felt so
tedious to do, because you generally want to walk around with a
sword charge, only to go to the menu to change swords when you
see an enemy. It was particularly annoying that you can&#8217;t turn
off the bracelet power once you get it, so you have to either use
MP (because it&#8217;s so easy to accidentally charge to level 3 shots)
or only use level 1 (by turning off the power-up altogether.)</p>

<p>I&#8217;d say that the game is not bad, but it has been so out-done by
games like Secret of Mana that there&#8217;s no reason to play this
older Action RPG (as if Mana is really much newer!) I was hoping a
little that this would be much more Action-y because it was
older. It is interesting for me to notice that as I get older I
like more action-based games, because they cut away all that fat
from RPGs that I used to love.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 24 - Episode Eight]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-24---Episode-Eight-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-24&#8212;Episode-Eight-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m glad Thomas is okay by the end. I thought the sub-plot of
Rose was really great. I like it because it really sets up a big
contrast between Rose (who is wild) and Edith (who is not) but
both are pursued by married men. In addition, Rose is a bit of a
stand-in for Mary at the beginning of the show, when she did
things that Edith would not approve of. Mary&#8217;s comment on the
sixth episode was very striking, that she doubts that Edith and
she would get along any better. She&#8217;s very realist.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s nice that three men in the show are getting on. It will be
interesting to plot that part of the history of Downton.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 23 - Episode Seven]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-23---Episode-Seven-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-23&#8212;Episode-Seven-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mrs. Patmore says something so funny to the young people:
&#8220;You&#8217;re all in love with wrong people!&#8221; I was also very
interested in the idea of Daisy leaving and taking charge. I
like her a lot.</p>

<p>Thomas is a very interesting character: he can be very wicked,
but he&#8217;s also extremely sympathetic to modern mores that resent
the prejudice he receives.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 22 - Episode Six]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-22---Episode-Six-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-22&#8212;Episode-Six-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s exciting to see Violet plotting and I like it when she uses
her powers for good. I think Mr. Carson is so funny the way he is
more pompous than the nobles in his observance of tradition.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 21 - Episode Five]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-21---Episode-Five-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-21&#8212;Episode-Five-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very interesting episode. I think the issues about the
management of the estate are very interesting, and I&#8217;m glad they
will get coverage. It&#8217;s very sad about Sybil, but I never really
loved her character anyways. The old ways of medicine are funny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Nutcracker, performed by Ballet West (1892)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie--The-Nutcracker--performed-by-Ballet-West--1892--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie&#8211;The-Nutcracker&#8211;performed-by-Ballet-West&#8211;1892&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight we saw Ballet West perform The Nutcracker, for our second
time. I had seen it one other time (that I can remember) performed
by the Boston Ballet.</p>

<p>I was very impressed with Sayaka for her Doll and Mirlitons. I
love the Doll because the choreography seems to be so precise,
quick, and on pointe all the time. I like the Mirlitons because
there are relatively few dancers, but they have interesting lines
and there&#8217;s lots of the kind of ballet (pointe) I like.</p>

<p>Christiana was the Sugar Plum Fairy and was amazing. I love her
solo in the Grand Pas de Deux, because she shows such power and
grace by herself (i.e. without support.) I really like the cute
leg flips (I need to learn the terms) at the beginning of the
piece.</p>

<p>I really enjoy seeing this after I&#8217;ve been reading the ballet
history book. It was cool to see so many little things that I&#8217;ve
learned where they came from.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: An Education, staring Carey Mulligan (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie--An-Education--staring-Carey-Mulligan--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie&#8211;An-Education&#8211;staring-Carey-Mulligan&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re on a French &amp; infidelity kick right now, so this movie was a
natural choice.</p>

<p>I think the movie is very interesting. I feel like it&#8217;s theme is
how Jenny learns what freedom is. She initially sees nothing good
in Miss Stubbs but drudgery. The glamour in David&#8217;s life is
attractive, but it isn&#8217;t earned and it has ugliness underneath it:
Helen gets no respect and is treated like a pet by Danny and David,
not to mention the crime. Jenny learns that this kind of freedom
has those risks and the cost of integrity. She is then surprised to
learn that liars lie and is told this in a clever way by Danny. We
later she her discovering true freedom (the joy of Miss Stubbs&#8217;
independence) and becoming the boss of the boys at Oxford.</p>

<p>I feel like the creepitude of their age gap is larger avoided, but
when it comes out, is particularly weird, but not in a truly
uncomfortable way.</p>

<p>I loved Jenny&#8217;s comment in the evening in Paris. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading every day, but I haven&#8217;t read anything I&#8217;ve felt
worth commenting on. It&#8217;s a very interesting book. The Danish and
Italian sections were curious, but seem to end in a non-conclusion
because the ballet innovations there didn&#8217;t drastically change
things. I&#8217;m excited about the transition to the Russian world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 20 - Episode Four]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/10/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-20---Episode-Four-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/10/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-20&#8212;Episode-Four-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although technically just a month later, it feels like there is a
big gap between this episode and the last. It is interesting the
way they&#8217;ve driven the family back together, solved a few
problems, and created more. There&#8217;s a very fluid flow to the
show, where there are many balls in the air that get caught at
regular rates, but just as new ones go up. I&#8217;m most curious about
the Matthew and Edith plot lines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 19 - Episode Three]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-19---Episode-Three-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-19&#8212;Episode-Three-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very exciting episode with a lot of drama. Now that
the money will be coming in, they&#8217;re be saved, but there is
mounting drama downstairs, with Mr. Bates, and with
Ethel. Exciting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 18 - Episode Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-18---Episode-Two-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-18&#8212;Episode-Two-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like how subtle and slow the plots are in this show. The
characters really sink in deeply. I like it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Le Divorce, starring Naomi Watts and Kate Hudson (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie&#8211;Le-Divorce&#8211;starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson&#8211;2003&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting movie. I feel like the main point is that
we have two groups of people with loose morals, but vastly
different ways of reacting to them coming into conflict. The
characters are pretty complex and interesting. The environments,
food, clothes, and women all look very beautiful and elegant. It&#8217;s
a fun non-stereotyped picture of France. I particularly like the
scene where the two police flirt. It serves no purpose other than
to say, &#8220;This can&#8217;t happen in America.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Coco Before chanel, starring Audrey Tatou (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie--Coco-Before-chanel--starring-Audrey-Tatou--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie&#8211;Coco-Before-chanel&#8211;starring-Audrey-Tatou&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really neat movie. I didn&#8217;t know anything about Coco
Chanel, besides who she was and that she had a major influence on
women&#8217;s fashion. It was very interesting to learn about her life
before getting in to the fashion world. I like the subtlety of the
movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played tonight for about 20 minutes. I played two continues on
Ring Man&#8217;s stage and couldn&#8217;t get much past the Hippo. My kids
then took two continues and just stayed on the first screen
running around and climbing up the later and using the super
shot. It was cute.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 17 - Episode One]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/03/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-17---Episode-One-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/03/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-17&#8212;Episode-One-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We just noticed that the next season was released in the
UK. This was a fun episode to get back with everyone again. I&#8217;m
glad that they&#8217;ve evolved the challenge to be more than just
Mary and Matthew fighting. It seems like the new challenge will
be this money problem and it will last through the whole
season. Obviously I have no clue, but they&#8217;ve actually got a
reliable problem to lean on.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this today for 30 minutes at the request of my son. He
loves Mega Man a lot and always wants to play one. He&#8217;s very
interested in fighting Skull Man, but I went Toad -> Bright ->
Pharaoh and then died during Ring Man&#8217;s stage.</p>

<p>Something I dislike about Mega Man is the three lives system. On
a single level, it is a good idea, because it requires you to get
some mastery, rather than just sacrificing life to go
forward. The problem is that when you beat a boss on your last
life, the next level you start off with only the one life. This
encourages you to commit suicide at the start of the next level
(because there&#8217;s no disadvantage to doing that&#8230; you keep your E
Tanks and all your equipment.) I don&#8217;t like it when games have an
optimal strategy that is (a) un-fun, (b) trivial to execute, and
(c) trivial to have just programmed out of the game.</p>

<p>In any case, this game has lots of clever concepts in its
platforming.</p>

<p>In Toad Man&#8217;s stage, the rain&#8217;s ability to push you is very
challenging and the rushing water is also interesting. Fighting
the Giant Snail on the water-ridden platform was very nerve
racking.</p>

<p>In Bright Man&#8217;s stage, the jumping grasshoppers were cool
(although really out of place) and the enemies that shut-out the
lights when you hit them was pretty crazy. The sequence before the
boss door where you had to jump from falling/sliding platform to
the next one while the light-putter-outers where moving around and
firing. It was nuts.</p>

<p>In Pharaoh Man&#8217;s stage, the platforms then when you jump on them
start moving and then fall was cool. It was particularly
challenging because the next platform would shot at you just
before you were supposed to jump on to it and if you didn&#8217;t jump
early enough, you would be shocked and fall to your death.</p>

<p>In Ring Man&#8217;s stage (what I&#8217;ve seen so far), I like the platforms
that shift from side to side as you walk across them. In one
sequence if you dropped beneath one you could get a large health
charge, but you had to jump back up quickly or else you&#8217;d be
stuck. It&#8217;s a great idea.</p>

<p>This game is a very creative Mega Man game that really does
something quite different every stage, rather than executing the
same set of mechanics really well. (It&#8217;s not that I think the
normal Mega Man style is bad, but this is neat.) I&#8217;ve heard a lot
of griping about the charged shot, but I don&#8217;t find it to be so
powerful that I have to keep it charged all the time (and thus
slow down the action.) Whenever I&#8217;ve done that, I think it has
hurt me more than it helped.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunt for Red October, staring Sean Connery (1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie&#8211;The-Hunt-for-Red-October&#8211;staring-Sean-Connery&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun movie. I&#8217;m on a <em>REDACTED</em> Ryan kick and I want to go read
all the novels. The story is really great and I love that the
engine really exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game&#8211;Crystalis&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It&#8217;s very
fun. There&#8217;s a little too much grinding&#8230; I feel like I can&#8217;t
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it&#8217;s fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it&#8217;s a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This whole chapter seems to be about Marie Taglioni and she sounds
amazing.</p>

<p>If Vestris designed the steps that became modern ballet, she
figured out how to do them with the style expect of modern
ballerinas. She did everything that Vestris did, but she practiced
so long and hard to achieve the strength necessary to do it in an
&#8220;elegant&#8221; and &#8220;feminine&#8221; way. While the early dancers were
&#8220;sweaty&#8221; and &#8220;breathless&#8221; when they did them, she was
&#8220;angelic&#8221;. She built this technique over 6 months after a failed
start in Vienna by working for 6 hours a day and holding poses for
100 seconds.</p>

<p>Her shoes are still extant and have been studied. While she
performed full pointe, she mainly held herself at full point and
did not dance on it. We know this because her shoes were not the
boxed and hard style that allows that. Instead, by looking at the
wearing at the shoes, it looks like she danced about half-way
between half-pointe and full-pointe. Her dancing was so powerful
that she used 2 or 3 shoes per performance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Sum of All Fears, starring Ben Affleck (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie--The-Sum-of-All-Fears--starring-Ben-Affleck--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie&#8211;The-Sum-of-All-Fears&#8211;starring-Ben-Affleck&#8211;2002&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of my favourite movies. I love the early scenes of his
life as a boring analyst. Especially when his office mates are
talking about the intimate details of the lives of the people they
spy on. This is such a clever movie and it has so much great
acting. I greatly enjoy the disturbing way politics and personal
relationships get in the way of the right things happening. It&#8217;s
deliciously cynical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
