<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T22:07:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game&#8211;Ninja-Gaiden-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this game tonight. I found it to be less
ridiculously hard than the first one because I found the powerups
and ninja power recharges to be more available. The environmental
hazards (wind, darkness, etc) were really rough. The cinema
sequences are way too long. I found confirmation in this
play-through of something that James Rolfe said in AVGN: you
forget that there is a health bar in this game, because you only
normally die by being whacked off platforms when you get
hit. It&#8217;s so true. Also, the powerup that shoots fire diagonally
upwards is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Batman (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game&#8211;Batman&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about two and half hours. A little more
than the final hour was spent on the last level trying to get up
the vertical passage with the gears. It was unbearably
brutalizing. If you could just shoot up or if the jump were a
little bit more controllable, I could have done it. But I decided
that I was interested in the ending that much.</p>

<p>Overall, this game is feels really great. The different weapons
are all useful and fun. The jumping is pretty nice and the
wall-hanging works much better than in Ninja Gaiden. Surprisingly
good!</p>

<p>Total time: 2:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Phantom of the Opera, by Andrew Lloyd Webber (2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie--The-Phantom-of-the-Opera--by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie&#8211;The-Phantom-of-the-Opera&#8211;by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber&#8211;2004&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was amazing. This visuals are crazy. The actors and
actresses are beautiful. Wow. I think my favourite moments are:
- when Christine is first going down to the Phantom&#8217;s lair,
because the pull of the camera is so cool.
- the song &#8220;Masquerade&#8221; and its dance number&#8212;crazy.
Minnie Driver was great, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Skull Man&#8217;s stage tonight (my son is very
fascinated with his appearance.) It was a fun level and I managed
to get an E tank and lots of 1-UPs on it. I had 4 lives for the
boss fight but was totally destroyed. I feel like in these later
Mega Man games, it is impossible to beat bosses out of
order. It&#8217;s a bit disappointing that it isn&#8217;t as free, but it
doesn&#8217;t detract that much from the experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xexyz (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Xexyz--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game&#8211;Xexyz&#8211;NES&#8211;1988&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about 15 minutes today. This is one of those
older NES games with really spotty controls but lots of
interesting ideas, that really doesn&#8217;t work super well. On the
first level you have to wander around a whole bunch of screens
looking for which star block to shoot five times to open a secret
door. I didn&#8217;t find the controls and mechanics very appealing, so
I think that&#8217;s it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 4 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Dragon-Warrior-4--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game&#8211;Dragon-Warrior-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played the DS remake of this and it was amazing, but I
can&#8217;t play this older version. I have some memories of it because
my good friend from elementary school had it and I borrowed it. I
think I only made it to Taloon&#8217;s part when I played it then. In
situations like this, I&#8217;m worried that someone will come to my
site&#8217;s rankings and think I dislike this game, but I do
like&#8230; just not this release. Perhaps I should change my
tracking program to keep track of releases and games distinctly
so I can rank the games, not just the releases?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game&#8211;Crystalis&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I had to restart because my
save was lost somehow. I got to Portoa and got the Sword of
Water. (This appears to be about half-way by glancing at the Table
of Contents of a guide.)</p>

<p>The mechanics in the game never really get much more
interesting. They definitely add a few things: like the Rabbit
Boots, and presumably you eventually are able to cross water, and
then the keys that the swords become after you get their balls,
etc. But all the things that are different in the game are on the
level of navigation annoyances (not really &#8220;puzzles&#8221;).</p>

<p>I wouldn&#8217;t say that I&#8217;m opposed to games that don&#8217;t change their
mechanics&#8212;Super Mario, for instance, doesn&#8217;t have different
mechanics through the game. But, Mario can do this because (a) the
game play is awesome and (b) the game play is rich enough that it
supports gaining mastery and then increasing the challenge.</p>

<p>In my time playing Crystalis, it was very true to the literal
definition of &#8220;Action RPG&#8221;. The individual encounters were totally
trivial (like hitting &#8220;Fight&#8221; over and over), but did require
moderate action. The challenge came from requiring a deep grind to
get resources&#8212;power to attack with and money to pay for healing
and rests. The severely limited inventory and the large number of
enemies really encourages you to go incredibly slowly and defeat
every enemy. But, it&#8217;s not fun enough to do. It feels pretty good
for about an hour, but after that it gets really aggravating, and
I feel like I want to just rush by.</p>

<p>Something I&#8217;m surprised I was annoyed by was the need to switch
weapons to fight different kinds of enemies. It just felt so
tedious to do, because you generally want to walk around with a
sword charge, only to go to the menu to change swords when you
see an enemy. It was particularly annoying that you can&#8217;t turn
off the bracelet power once you get it, so you have to either use
MP (because it&#8217;s so easy to accidentally charge to level 3 shots)
or only use level 1 (by turning off the power-up altogether.)</p>

<p>I&#8217;d say that the game is not bad, but it has been so out-done by
games like Secret of Mana that there&#8217;s no reason to play this
older Action RPG (as if Mana is really much newer!) I was hoping a
little that this would be much more Action-y because it was
older. It is interesting for me to notice that as I get older I
like more action-based games, because they cut away all that fat
from RPGs that I used to love.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Jaredites, by Mark E. Peterson (1984)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Book--The-Jaredites--by-Mark-E--Peterson--1984--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Book&#8211;The-Jaredites&#8211;by-Mark-E&#8211;Peterson&#8211;1984&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first page of the book is the sort of unreasonable Book of
<em>REDACTED</em> historicity that gets <em>REDACTED</em>s in the biggest trouble. It
bothers me that there is simply no evidence in the Book of <em>REDACTED</em>
itself for some of his claims&#8230; such as the &#8220;untold millions&#8221; of
Jaredites and that they &#8220;trafficked in many manufactured goods.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I started the section on Marius Petipa, whose work is still
constantly performed today. Fascinating.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 24 - Episode Eight]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-24---Episode-Eight-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-24&#8212;Episode-Eight-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m glad Thomas is okay by the end. I thought the sub-plot of
Rose was really great. I like it because it really sets up a big
contrast between Rose (who is wild) and Edith (who is not) but
both are pursued by married men. In addition, Rose is a bit of a
stand-in for Mary at the beginning of the show, when she did
things that Edith would not approve of. Mary&#8217;s comment on the
sixth episode was very striking, that she doubts that Edith and
she would get along any better. She&#8217;s very realist.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s nice that three men in the show are getting on. It will be
interesting to plot that part of the history of Downton.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 23 - Episode Seven]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-23---Episode-Seven-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-23&#8212;Episode-Seven-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Mrs. Patmore says something so funny to the young people:
&#8220;You&#8217;re all in love with wrong people!&#8221; I was also very
interested in the idea of Daisy leaving and taking charge. I
like her a lot.</p>

<p>Thomas is a very interesting character: he can be very wicked,
but he&#8217;s also extremely sympathetic to modern mores that resent
the prejudice he receives.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 22 - Episode Six]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-22---Episode-Six-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-22&#8212;Episode-Six-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s exciting to see Violet plotting and I like it when she uses
her powers for good. I think Mr. Carson is so funny the way he is
more pompous than the nobles in his observance of tradition.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 21 - Episode Five]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-21---Episode-Five-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/15/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-21&#8212;Episode-Five-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very interesting episode. I think the issues about the
management of the estate are very interesting, and I&#8217;m glad they
will get coverage. It&#8217;s very sad about Sybil, but I never really
loved her character anyways. The old ways of medicine are funny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Nutcracker, performed by Ballet West (1892)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie--The-Nutcracker--performed-by-Ballet-West--1892--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie&#8211;The-Nutcracker&#8211;performed-by-Ballet-West&#8211;1892&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight we saw Ballet West perform The Nutcracker, for our second
time. I had seen it one other time (that I can remember) performed
by the Boston Ballet.</p>

<p>I was very impressed with Sayaka for her Doll and Mirlitons. I
love the Doll because the choreography seems to be so precise,
quick, and on pointe all the time. I like the Mirlitons because
there are relatively few dancers, but they have interesting lines
and there&#8217;s lots of the kind of ballet (pointe) I like.</p>

<p>Christiana was the Sugar Plum Fairy and was amazing. I love her
solo in the Grand Pas de Deux, because she shows such power and
grace by herself (i.e. without support.) I really like the cute
leg flips (I need to learn the terms) at the beginning of the
piece.</p>

<p>I really enjoy seeing this after I&#8217;ve been reading the ballet
history book. It was cool to see so many little things that I&#8217;ve
learned where they came from.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: An Education, staring Carey Mulligan (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie--An-Education--staring-Carey-Mulligan--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie&#8211;An-Education&#8211;staring-Carey-Mulligan&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We&#8217;re on a French &amp; infidelity kick right now, so this movie was a
natural choice.</p>

<p>I think the movie is very interesting. I feel like it&#8217;s theme is
how Jenny learns what freedom is. She initially sees nothing good
in Miss Stubbs but drudgery. The glamour in David&#8217;s life is
attractive, but it isn&#8217;t earned and it has ugliness underneath it:
Helen gets no respect and is treated like a pet by Danny and David,
not to mention the crime. Jenny learns that this kind of freedom
has those risks and the cost of integrity. She is then surprised to
learn that liars lie and is told this in a clever way by Danny. We
later she her discovering true freedom (the joy of Miss Stubbs&#8217;
independence) and becoming the boss of the boys at Oxford.</p>

<p>I feel like the creepitude of their age gap is larger avoided, but
when it comes out, is particularly weird, but not in a truly
uncomfortable way.</p>

<p>I loved Jenny&#8217;s comment in the evening in Paris. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book&#8211;Apollo-s-Angels&#8211;by-Jennifer-Homans&#8211;2010&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading every day, but I haven&#8217;t read anything I&#8217;ve felt
worth commenting on. It&#8217;s a very interesting book. The Danish and
Italian sections were curious, but seem to end in a non-conclusion
because the ballet innovations there didn&#8217;t drastically change
things. I&#8217;m excited about the transition to the Russian world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 20 - Episode Four]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/10/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-20---Episode-Four-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/10/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-20&#8212;Episode-Four-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Although technically just a month later, it feels like there is a
big gap between this episode and the last. It is interesting the
way they&#8217;ve driven the family back together, solved a few
problems, and created more. There&#8217;s a very fluid flow to the
show, where there are many balls in the air that get caught at
regular rates, but just as new ones go up. I&#8217;m most curious about
the Matthew and Edith plot lines.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 19 - Episode Three]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-19---Episode-Three-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-19&#8212;Episode-Three-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very exciting episode with a lot of drama. Now that
the money will be coming in, they&#8217;re be saved, but there is
mounting drama downstairs, with Mr. Bates, and with
Ethel. Exciting!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 3 - Episode 18 - Episode Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey---Season-3---Episode-18---Episode-Two-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/09/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-3&#8212;Episode-18&#8212;Episode-Two-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like how subtle and slow the plots are in this show. The
characters really sink in deeply. I like it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Le Divorce, starring Naomi Watts and Kate Hudson (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie&#8211;Le-Divorce&#8211;starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson&#8211;2003&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting movie. I feel like the main point is that
we have two groups of people with loose morals, but vastly
different ways of reacting to them coming into conflict. The
characters are pretty complex and interesting. The environments,
food, clothes, and women all look very beautiful and elegant. It&#8217;s
a fun non-stereotyped picture of France. I particularly like the
scene where the two police flirt. It serves no purpose other than
to say, &#8220;This can&#8217;t happen in America.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
