<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-16T11:12:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Majestic, starring Jim Carrey (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie&#8211;The-Majestic&#8211;starring-Jim-Carrey&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fine little romance. The most interesting thing about it
is how this, and other movies (like the Chaplin biopic) rewrite the
history of the Communist/Hollywood controversy of the 50s to play
out the way that modern Hollywood people wish that it would. It
makes me think that maybe some people wouldn&#8217;t realize that
Hollywood didn&#8217;t really &#8220;win&#8221;. There&#8217;s a lot of Hollywood
dopey-eye-ism in the movie, actually. It reminds me a lot of
Hugo.</p>

<p>I think the movie might have been improved by making it more
ambiguous about whether Jim Carrey really lost his memory.</p>

<p>The reviews are interesting. I think Roger Ebert saw what it was
going for and believed in it. The speech at the end was a bit too
dopey for my taste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Alice in Wonderland, directed by Tim Burton (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie&#8211;Alice-in-Wonderland&#8211;directed-by-Tim-Burton&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My little sister wanted to watch this movie tonight, so we watched
it together. I thought it was very cool and pretty trippy. I don&#8217;t
think Johnny Depp was very good in it though&#8230; he was too much
like <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow, but looked really weird and had a funny
voice. The slight attraction between him and Alice was creepy
too. I think I liked Helena Bonham Carter and Anne Hathaway the
best, they were just so odd. It was cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Cowboys & Aliens, starring Daniel Craig (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie--Cowboys---Aliens--starring-Daniel-Craig--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie&#8211;Cowboys&#8212;Aliens&#8211;starring-Daniel-Craig&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the blend of Western and Sci-Fi style. I was glad
that the aliens had a sensible purpose for being on Earth. I liked
that there was a deeper world in the background, but that it was
not too tantalizing (for a movie like this.) I thought the aliens
looked cool and Daniel Craig was super tough. The juxtaposition,
though, was the best part. All-around a good time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: John Carter, starring Taylor Kitsch (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie--John-Carter--starring-Taylor-Kitsch--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie&#8211;John-Carter&#8211;starring-Taylor-Kitsch&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had heard a little about this movie when it came out, but nothing
really special. My parents wanted to watch a movie together and I
saw this on Amazon and suggested it.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the movie. It&#8217;s very much unlike anything else in
its grand scheme. Maybe a little bit like Stargate. It takes a
little while to get started, but once it does, the pay-off is
great. I think what I like most about it is the way it spins a
world so well.</p>

<p>It makes me very interested in reading the series of books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: One for the Money, starring Katherine Heigl (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie--One-for-the-Money--starring-Katherine-Heigl--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie&#8211;One-for-the-Money&#8211;starring-Katherine-Heigl&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My mom recommended this movie to us, as she has been reading the
series it is based on for a long time. I found the movie charming
and cute. It was a nice light mystery with some subtle romantic and
funny moments. It makes me interested in the books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Amazing Spider-Man, starring Andrew Garfield (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--The-Amazing-Spider-Man--starring-Andrew-Garfield--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie&#8211;The-Amazing-Spider-Man&#8211;starring-Andrew-Garfield&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I rarely see movies in the theatre, but I was very interested in
seeing this, so we took the opportunity of free babysitting and
went out.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m not a Spider-Man super-fan, but I am familiar with the comic
book mythos enough to really appreciate this movie.</p>

<p>I like the structure of the plot and I really like the interaction
of Gwen and Peter. In the Toby McGuire movies, they weren&#8217;t
adorable enough together, but this movie does a good job of giving
them lots of awkward moments. I think Emma Stone really makes
it. She&#8217;s got a beautiful face too, which is nice for all the
close-ups they give the couple.</p>

<p>I quite like the development of Pete&#8217;s understanding of being
Spider-Man and I found the moment on the bridge to be really
emotional, as well as the crane scene.</p>

<p>I thought they did some good work establishing room to work in a
new franchise. There are cameos of The Daily Bugle, Peter&#8217;s
technique of taking pictures for it, Flash, as well as the central
focus of Oscorp.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the childishness of Peter: talking on his cell
phone, pranking on the villains, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: My Mom's New Boyfriend, starring Colin Hanks (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--My-Mom-s-New-Boyfriend--starring-Colin-Hanks--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie&#8211;My-Mom-s-New-Boyfriend&#8211;starring-Colin-Hanks&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched about half of this movie with my parents. I missed the
beginning. It was pretty stupid with lots of very phoned-in
dialog and plot. In some ways it is like &#8220;This Means War&#8221;, in terms
of what the basis of the jokes are. I don&#8217;t think Meg Ryan can play
an insanely &#8220;hot&#8221; lady, although she&#8217;s definitely good
looking. Selma Blair is great, but her &#8220;sexy&#8221; scene is really
forced. The finale at the museum is pretty clever, but overall I
can understand why it was direct-to-DVD.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game&#8211;Super-Meat-Boy&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For about a month I&#8217;ve been working on 5-14X (Necrosis). It was
very, very hard. You had to go down a shaft, across a wide area
with tiny platforms, then up a shaft, back down, back across, back
up, and then across the same area but now with disappearing
platforms. All while being pursued by floating monsters and all
the shafts had maggot piles getting you.</p>

<p>Today I was playing with my son and after about 15 minutes of
doing okay, I say, &#8220;Well, I think this should be the last try
before we go to church.&#8221; He says, &#8220;Okay! Let&#8217;s DO it!&#8221; Then, of
course, I do it. I just needed a cheerleader.</p>

<p>I got 38.00 seconds when the par time was 60.00 seconds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book&#8211;Mockingjay&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Katniss destroying the Holo was pretty stupid.</p>

<p>Woah, Prim dying with the same trap that Gale was talking about.</p>

<p>Katniss awakening in a hospital and not really being involved in
capturing Snow is disappointing.</p>

<p>Snow&#8217;s conversation with Katniss: very believable.</p>

<p>Appalling that Katniss would initiate more Hunger Games. Although,
since they never talked about it happening, I wonder if it did
given that Coin was killed?</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the books and thought they ended well. I thought
the second book and the first part of the third were the high
points for the series.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (19)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--18/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;18</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I played for a little less than three hours and finished
the game. I went through the Catacombs and then to the final
boss. I beat the Pinwheel boss and Nito on my first try. After I
got back to the Firelink Shrine, it took me a long time to figure
out that I just needed to jump down the pit to get back to the
Lordvessel. I did it the first time very nervously. I fought the
boss once and got creamed, then did a few of the upgrades I could
on my gear and then went back and beat him on my second try. After
I watched the ending, I had a big&#8230; that was it? Just explode
into the flame?</p>

<p>&#8211; Final Stats &#8211;</p>

<p>SL:  89</p>

<p>Vit: 40!
Att:  8!
End: 46!
Str: 28!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Fire Murakumo +7
Giant Armor +5
Eagle Shield +13</p>

<p>Total Time: 48:02</p>

<p>&#8211; Review &#8211;</p>

<p>This is a great game. The combat is fun and challenging. The world
is interesting and detailed. It&#8217;s exactly like Demon&#8217;s Souls, but
better. Read my review about that game for more gushing. At this
point, I think I can only really think about what sets it apart
from Demon&#8217;s Souls.</p>

<p>I think the graphics were improved in that invisible technical
way. The environments feel like they could&#8217;ve been in the last
game and some of them seem incredibly close. Whatever graphical
upgrades they made aren&#8217;t a significant reasons to play this
versus the older one.</p>

<p>The story of the game is worse, in a sense. I honestly had no clue
what the point of the adventure was. I&#8217;m undead, there&#8217;s a king, I
need to get as strong as him, to beat him, and do what? After
reading the wiki Lore page, I still don&#8217;t really understand what I
did in the game. In contrast, I think Demon&#8217;s Souls story was very
coherent.</p>

<p>The world of the game is better though. The world seems much more
real because it&#8217;s all interconnected. It&#8217;s very exhilarating to
see a place from many different angles and get there. In contrast,
in the previous game, it felt incredibly &#8220;level&#8221;-y.</p>

<p>I think the difficulty of the game is pretty much identical to its
predecessor, in a sense. I felt like I never really had to learn
new strategies against what I already knew from Demon&#8217;s. There
were a few tough bosses, but only one that was really a wall: the
dual bosses in Anor Londo. I enjoyed the combat a lot, but I don&#8217;t
think it really evolved that much.</p>

<p>The way that the game is more difficult, however, is in the
numbers game. In the last game I never upgraded my weapons at all
and didn&#8217;t even really go out of my way to get particular
stuff. In this game, I got the strongest armor in the game and got
incredibly powerful weapons. Until then, I got reasonable stuff
and the game was a challenge, but not impossible. Afterward, it
felt almost the same actually, although I started getting through
the bosses in one or two tries versus four or five. But, I felt
like I did less grinding in this game than the last&#8230; maybe I
just found a better farming spot.</p>

<p>The other more difficult thing in this game were the precarious
environments that I fell off a lot. There was really only one
place like that in Demon&#8217;s, but I felt like Dark has a ton. Other
than these, I felt like the game had much fewer frustrating
moments and really not that many at all. I don&#8217;t really find the
game that difficult&#8230; just a good challenge&#8230; like Mega Man.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m a bit surprised about my statistics on the game. I ended up
two levels LOWER than Demon&#8217;s. I spent about twenty MORE hours. I
spent 19 days over the course of about six weeks&#8212;about the same
amount of total days, I think.</p>

<p>Overall, I loved the game. But, I won&#8217;t be doing New Game+. I
played the last game about a year ago and I could imagine playing
a game like this in another year. I&#8217;d really like to figure out
how to make a game like this in 2D.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book&#8211;Mockingjay&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like the idea of the bargain between District 13 and the Capitol.</p>

<p>The militarism of District 13 is fascinating and reasonable, given
their past.</p>

<p>The books have always been a thin allegory for violence in media,
but having Katniss literally be a movie star is a bit
ridiculous. I&#8217;m glad that the characters realize this
too.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s funny because when she&#8217;s in the field, it&#8217;s like she&#8217;s in the
Games again, but the cameras are now obvious rather than hidden
everywhere.</p>

<p>The real moment of Katniss&#8217; catch phrase is totally epic. A little
teary.</p>

<p>The propaganda war is pretty brilliant and fits really well with
the media theme of the books.</p>

<p>I find the term &#8220;Mockingjay&#8221; used for Katniss incredibly silly and
aggravating.</p>

<p>Katniss&#8217; impassioned speech before she gets shot. :)</p>

<p>I have to admit, turning the raid on the Capitol into a recreation
of the Games is a clever way to stick to the formula.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m stopping for the day right when Peeta shows up in the
Capitol&#8230; tense!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book&#8211;Catching-Fire&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2009&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The clock concept for the arena is clever.</p>

<p>The plot dump at the end of the book is pretty absurd, although
really, what else could she have done?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (18)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--17/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;17</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played for a little less than four hours. I went from the
Duke&#8217;s Archive and through the Lost Izalith. The Bed of Chaos boss
was tricky to get the jump right. Other than that, I found most of
the bosses hard, but definitely do-able. I think I beat all the in
between ones on my second try. This final part of the game is
pretty good&#8230; still hard because you&#8217;ve got to learn the area,
but I never need to really change my equipment or stats up&#8230;
it&#8217;s all back on my playing. I think I will be able to beat the
game tomorrow&#8230; just one more Lord Soul and then the final boss.</p>

<p>I &#8220;love&#8221; seeing the shadows of enemies from below them or through
walls.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Upgrade Shield to +15
- Upgrade Black Bow to +10 fire
- Upgrade Murakumo to +10 fire
- Fight the Black Hydra in Ash Lake
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Explore the rest of Sen&#8217;s Fortress (Pit)
- Kill the Red Dragon in the Undead Burg
- Kill Poison Dragon and final girl in Painted World
- Go to Dragon Valley and kill Undead Dragon</p>

<p>SL:  83</p>

<p>Vit: 40!
Att:  8!
End: 40! (try for 46, to hold everything including Mura)
Str: 28!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 45:18</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book&#8211;The-Hunger-Games&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2008&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea that the Muttations are really the tributes is
fascinating. The magic technology of the capital is pretty
interesting overall.</p>

<p>I finished the book today. As I said the other day, I find it to be
almost perfectly captured in the movie. That disappoints me a
little because I was hoping to learn more about the world from the
book.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t imagine how the other books could continue the style of
this one. The story can definitely move, there&#8217;s no doubt about
that, but I&#8217;m not convinced that Collins could write a political
thriller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book&#8211;Catching-Fire&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first chapters do a really good job of easily recapping what
happened in the last book as a reminder.</p>

<p>The concept of the Quarter Quell is so contrived for plot
purposes. It&#8217;s as bad as Harry Potter where every year some huge
thing is revealed that couldn&#8217;t possibly have been realistically
unmentioned before.</p>

<p>I thought that the tour around the districts would be a contrived
way to give the reader a tour. But I was wrong.</p>

<p>I teared up in the District 11 scene.</p>

<p>Wow, how contrived to get Katniss back in the arena, because
Collins has written her into a state of inability to do
anything. Naturally it will be her and Peeta again?</p>

<p>It is interesting that Katniss will have an advantage the second
time, because she and Peeta will the youngest, and presumably
un-softened by living in luxury as a victor.</p>

<p>Haymitch&#8217;s story is great.</p>

<p>The amount of &#8220;food porn&#8221; in the books never gets old, strangely.</p>

<p>Katniss&#8217; private session with the Gamemakers :)</p>

<p>The pre-Games interviews were amazing.</p>

<p>The end of Part II is waaaay intense.</p>

<p>I feel like throughout the book Collins uses such sterile and bland
language to talk about Katniss&#8217; body. Yet, she seems to always be
doing it. We often hear about the showers and baths that Katniss
takes and when that happens she&#8217;ll say she&#8217;s &#8220;naked&#8221; or talk about
her &#8220;breasts&#8221; and most often she mentions her &#8220;underwear&#8221;,
&#8220;underclothes&#8221;, or &#8220;undergarment&#8221;. It&#8217;s particularly strange how
bland it is given the food orgies and descriptions of the Capitol
fashion we&#8217;re so often given.</p>

<p>The whole second book is reminiscent of bad movie sequel that was
summarized in the production notes with one word: MORE. More
violence. More romance. More intrigue. More food. More. The book
has almost an identical structure and plot, but again, and a little
bit different, but bigger. Yet, it does a good job at it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (17)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--16/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;16</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played for about two hours and beat the Four Kings (on my
first try! with only 5 healing potions! boom!) and then spent a
lot of money upgrading my shields to +10 and buying Green Shards
to begin upgrading my bow and my next sword. I got myself over to
the Duke&#8217;s Archives for the next part of the game, but I won&#8217;t
play much longer tonight, despite having the time.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Upgrade Shield to +15
- Upgrade Black Bow to +10 fire
- Upgrade Murakumo to +10 fire and get the strength (28) to use it
- Fight the Black Hydra in Ash Lake
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Explore the rest of Sen&#8217;s Fortress (Pit)
- Kill Poison Dragon and final girl in Painted World
- Go to Dragon Valley</p>

<p>SL:  73</p>

<p>Vit: 40!
Att:  8!
End: 40!
Str: 18
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 41:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Book&#8211;The-Hunger-Games&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2008&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m disappointed the movie didn&#8217;t use the plot-point about the
&#8220;traitor&#8221; that Katniss saw in the woods that time. It&#8217;s a cool
idea.</p>

<p>I find there to be a lot more making out and conflict in Katniss
about Peeta in the book than the movie. But both are incredibly
sterile&#8230; I can&#8217;t imagine the audience really being excited about
it.</p>

<p>Another point where the movie exceeds the book is that it shows
people outside the Arena reacting. It&#8217;s very interesting. Collins
tries to do that by having Katniss imagine things, but it
definitely isn&#8217;t as touching.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Chasing Ghosts: Beyond the Arcade, directed by Lincoln Ruchti (2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Movie--Chasing-Ghosts--Beyond-the-Arcade--directed-by-Lincoln-Ruchti--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Movie&#8211;Chasing-Ghosts&#8211;Beyond-the-Arcade&#8211;directed-by-Lincoln-Ruchti&#8211;2007&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an interesting movie. I think I preferred King of Kong,
however. Something I disliked about the guys in the movie is that
they were very proud of their accomplishments and built their lives
around them, but they didn&#8217;t continue to push their high scores in
the games that made them &#8220;famous&#8221; or in future games. It seemed so
stagnant. Most of the guys seemed to live really depressing lives
too. I felt bad for them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (16)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--15/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;15</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent some time grinding today (about an hour) and then got all
the Twinkling Shards I needed to fully upgrade my Giant armor and
the Giant&#8217;s Hammer. It was pretty awesome once I did that. I then
fought the two bosses&#8230; I died the first time, but the second I
was more aggressive and got them down pretty quickly. After
getting the Lordvessel, I avenged the girl and advanced the
story. I feel like the end is in sight. I played for almost three
hours.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Go through New Londo Ruins + Abyss
- Upgrade Black Bow to +10 fire
- Upgrade Shield to +15
- Upgrade Murakumo to +10 fire and get the strength (28) to use it
- Fight the Black Hydra in Ash Lake
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Explore the rest of Sen&#8217;s Fortress (Pit)
- Kill Poison Dragon and final girl in Painted World
- Go to Dragon Valley</p>

<p>SL:  73</p>

<p>Vit: 40!
Att:  8!
End: 40!
Str: 18
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 39:56</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Book&#8211;The-Hunger-Games&#8211;by-Suzanne-Collins&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the first five chapters of this. The writing is quite better
than the Twilight series. Katniss has a strong voice that can pull
the story along well and keep your attention. The world is very
interesting, with not enough detail, but perhaps just enough.</p>

<p>I find it very strange that if the Capitol is &#8220;surrounded&#8221; by the
12 districts, and it is in the Rockies, but District 12 is in
Appalachia&#8230; i.e. very far away&#8230; how is it that only eight
thousand people live there and can all gather together in a single
public square? District 12 is the size of a small town in modern
America. It strains credulity to think that the world is so
sparsely populated and this place with so few people can really
have major starvation problems, but not be totally decimated by
them.</p>

<p>Katniss did say that there were some severe natural disasters at
some point in the past (at least 74 years) that led to the world
being like this, and at this point no information has been given
about the size of other districts, but I find it very difficult to
believe at this point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
