<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-23T22:21:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/23/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/23/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a little bit tonight and started the twin sister&#8217;s
quest. So far it is intriguing. It is a little bit annoying to
take another group from level 1, especially when they don&#8217;t have
new attributes (they&#8217;re just a healer and a mage, like the
companions in Chapter 2.) There also seem to be really poor
enemies in the area, but expensive items at the towns.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:26</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started playing this today on a flight to D.C.. The graphics are
new, but the gameplay is very old. Nevertheless, it is strangely
satisfying to make ever longer &#8220;trips&#8221; as you increase your
stats. The script is simultaneously really funny and sounds
horribly translated, but it is actually the dialects they give the
characters. The plot is interesting, because I feel things slowly
coming together as you visit different people and play as them.</p>

<p>Torneko&#8217;s chapter was really strange because you&#8217;re trying to
raise money, just like normal, but you&#8217;re doing it in such a
strange way and trying to get such huge amounts. He also seems to
get treasure chest drops from enemies much more often than the
other characters. I stopped for the day after I finished the
tunnel.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: When You Reach Me, by Rebecca Stead (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book--When-You-Reach-Me--by-Rebecca-Stead--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book&#8211;When-You-Reach-Me&#8211;by-Rebecca-Stead&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife read this book for book group (I think that&#8217;s why) and
wanted me to as well. It was not the worst book ever, but I didn&#8217;t
like it that much. My main problem with was the weakness of its
plot and its predictability. Practically nothing happens in it and
the characters are strong enough to carry a story where nothing
major happens. The slice of life isn&#8217;t slicey enough because there
aren&#8217;t even interesting vignettes about the girl&#8217;s life. The
predictability is really bad. I was about half-way through the book
yesterday (long plane trip today) and I talked to my wife about it
and told her what I thought would happen&#8230; and I was exactly
correct on all counts. That&#8217;s pretty bad. It&#8217;s not even like a
standard romantic comedy where it is sticking to a formula, it&#8217;s
just that the story is so cliche and obvious that there&#8217;s basically
only one thing that <em>could</em> happen given the way she&#8217;s set it up.</p>

<p>Maybe I&#8217;m begin too hard on a Young Adult book, but eh, it wasn&#8217;t
for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/21/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/21/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today. I got to the part where
Squad 7 is officially formed and did the first Skirmish twice
(once on each difficulty level.) I think that&#8217;ll be my
method&#8230; whenever there is a new Skirmish, do it twice. Or maybe
I&#8217;ll play them until I can (a) level everyone and (b) buy every
available upgrade.</p>

<p>So far, I really like the game. The gameplay is really unique and
interesting&#8230; there&#8217;s a lot of strategy to it. The story, which
at this point is more of just a setting, is really compelling. I
can&#8217;t wait to play more. I found the opening swell as they left
Bruhl to be very heart-warming and it almost made me tear a
little. I appreciate the pacifism of the game.</p>

<p>I like it when fiction uses words without explaining them, but
that you know what they mean. For example, in this some characters
refer to the &#8220;Imps&#8221;, which I reckon means &#8220;Imperials.&#8221; Kind of
obvious, yeah, but cute.</p>

<p>Total: 2:49</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol, starring Tom Cruise (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie&#8211;Mission-Impossible&#8211;Ghost-Protocol&#8211;starring-Tom-Cruise&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a big budget popcorn summer movie, but a pretty good one
of that category. It starts off, and sounds like, it will be just
like all the other movies, with practically the same setup; but it
quickly acknowledges that and goes in a different direction. They
didn&#8217;t over use the faces, like they&#8217;ve done before, and they there
was only one real bad scene of Tom Cruise fawning over himself. I
think my major disappointments were its lack of a romantic sub-plot
and the lack of real consequences to not being able to use IMF
resources&#8212;even though they explicitly mention how that is
standing in their way at a few points, they solve the problem too
easily.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I put the disc in so I could install the game, before we watched a
movie tonight. This games is sooo beautiful, wow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today. I went through one dungeon
and got to a really hard boss fight. I&#8217;ve been on a pattern of try
the boss then go back to the beginning of the dungeon fighting
dudes and back so I can gain some levels and try again. I think
I&#8217;ve had about 5 or 6 loops so far. It&#8217;s pretty brutal too because
there&#8217;s a medium difficulty boss battle before it that you have to
go through, so each failing boss fight takes about 10 minutes.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been talking with my wife about some of the stupid stuff in
this game. The biggest problem with it is the lack of agency in
almost every aspect of the game.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Each unit has specific skills, like Smash II or Restore III, but
you don&#8217;t get to choose what skills will actually be
used. Instead, you choose between a few &#8220;baskets&#8221; of
attacks. For example, you might have the option &#8221;<em>REDACTED</em>ge&#8221; which
has your five guys just do basic attacks and then you&#8217;ll also
have &#8220;Attack &#8216;em hard, man&#8221; which has two of your guys do two
seemingly random physical attacks. There&#8217;s no option to just
determine what your units will do.</p></li>
<li><p>It&#8217;s not even possible for you to always choose each type of
basket. For example, generally there is a (1) no AP basket, (2)
physical AP basket, (3) magic AP basket, (4) healing AP basket,
and (5) hexing/buffing basket. Each one sometimes has a second
variant that uses much more AP. However, it&#8217;s not the case that
on any given round you can choose between any of the baskets. I
have no idea what algorithm it is using to determine what I am
allowed to do. This is most frustrating with healing. Suppose I
have 2k HP and I&#8217;m fighting something that I know can do 1.2k
damage sometimes. If I get hit and get knocked down past 1.5k,
I&#8217;d like to heal as insurance for the eventually big one. Last
Remnant does not allow this. It only gives you the ability to
heal (and other teams to heal you) when you are really low, for
some unknown definition of really low. In this case, it&#8217;s too
late. It is almost like the FF13 Paradigm system where all the
characters are AI controlled and you aren&#8217;t allowed to switch to
any Paradigm whenever you want.</p></li>
<li><p>Outside of combat, there&#8217;s a similar lack of agency in the
character progression system. You have a whole bunch of
characters, but not one of them gives you the ability to decide
what skills they will learn as they progress. Rush (the main
character) can sometimes choose between two options after a
battle, but you don&#8217;t really have any perspective on this
decision and it&#8217;s very micro. Some of the leaders will ask you
whether to focus on physical or magical attacks, but
repercussions of this are pretty vague. You can&#8217;t change the
equipment on your characters, except for the main one, but you
almost never need to do it (it seems) because there&#8217;s rarely
anything better than what you have or will find in a dungeon in
a little bit.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Despite these big game play problems, I find the core idea pretty
interesting and it&#8217;s tempting to keep playing and grind through it,
but I&#8217;m beginning to think it&#8217;s just not worth given the many other
great games that are available.</p>

<p>I find the story to be pretty intriguing and original. The
production values are pretty bad in a lot of places and some of the
micro-story bits are pretty lame, but it&#8217;s a reasonable package.</p>

<p>I feel real bad putting down games and not playing them to
completion, but I just can&#8217;t get behind such flawed game play.</p>

<p>I was having a discussion with someone the other day about what
makes good game play and I stated three things:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Intuition</em></li>
</ul>


<p>The challenge of the game should require some inexplicable skill
that can&#8217;t be feasibly turned into an algorithm by
humans. Tic-Tac-Toe is flawed in this way. A shmup is super easy
to imagine (algorithm: dodge bullets when they get close), but
it&#8217;s basically impossible to succeed with such a system. Most
strategy and role-playing games can get too close to the edge of
easy to axiomatize. Games that /require/ memorization are some of
the worst offenders on this category by going in the opposite
direction from Tic-Tac-Toe; rather than having a deeply
algorithmic structure, they lack any coherence at all, so you
must resort to pure memorization.</p>

<p>The Last Remnant is pretty good in this camp, I think, but the
place where the choice enters in is pretty weak&#8212;primarily in
what order your unions attack what enemy unions and to a lesser
extent how much AP you spend on any turn.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Fairness</em></li>
</ul>


<p>When you fail, it should be clear to you that it is your
fault. This doesn&#8217;t mean you should know what to do to succeed,
but rather you should believe that you did something wrong. For
example, Super Mario Brothers is very good with this, except on
the ZX Spectrum, where the lack of scrolling forced you to do
blind jumps.</p>

<p>The Last Remnant is very bad on this category because it&#8217;s lack
of player agency makes you always feel like it was the RNG that
killed you and not your lack of ability/planning/strategy/etc.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Precision</em></li>
</ul>


<p>A complement of Fairness is Precision, which means that you the
burden to communicate your intentions should be reasonable. Mario
is practically perfect here, because there is basically no delay
between your choice and the action and the set of actions (jump,
move, etc) is perfectly matched by the mechanism of choice (the
buttons on the controller.) Many games with complicated control
schemes violate the Precision principle. Many games have bad
input lag and other problems that stand in the way of
precision. Some games seem to violate Precision&#8212;like Street
Fighter, where we could imagine a 3DS style menu of the super
attacks, rather than the high-execution challenge abilities&#8212;but
some how do not, because the commands are tight and seem to flow
out of other actions you are doing anyways, and are coupled with
general tightness and precision. Sometimes a game consciously
makes the control harder as part of the challenge&#8230; DDR is
easier with four buttons that you can control with your fingers,
for example; but this is difficulty design decision to balance
and generally pushes the game from the abstract realm (the
screen) to the physical realm (dancing).</p>

<p>The Last Remnant&#8217;s lack of Fairness almost entirely comes from
its lack of Precision. It is not possible for you to choose your
actions, so you know you should heal but the game prevents
you. It&#8217;s not necessarily the case that lack of Precision leads
to lack of Fairness&#8230; the NES Castlevania games are very chunky
in their control, but somehow maintain Fairness.</p>

<p>So I guess I&#8217;ve decided to abandon The Last Remnant. I just read
the Wikipedia summary of the story and it sounds like it would
have been cool to experience, but it&#8217;s not worth the suffering. I&#8217;m
glad I played it enough to feel like I really understand the
mechanics and gave them a chance, but I think my conscious will be
clear on abandoning the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 16:06</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game&#8211;Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter&#8211;DS&#8211;2011&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did Puzzle 2 today, which was a classic example of what I love
and hate about these games. The puzzle was about how one picture
was different than three others. I initially answered wrong
because I selected the different one, rather than the three same
ones, because I didn&#8217;t read the directions clear enough. Argh. It
should have said that I didn&#8217;t select three rather than making me
answer wrong. Then, when I converted my answer (based on the
presence of what seemed to be a different un-movable object in the
background) and found out I was wrong. I tried a few different
logical (to me) ideas and was wrong. This made me frustrated like
there was going to be some out of nowhere explanation for the
similarities that I&#8217;d never have guessed. When the wrong reason
(standing still versus not) led to the right solution, it
described that the solution was really about the shadow of the
people in the photo to show the time&#8230; which made me happy again
because it was a reasonable explanation I could have thought of
but just didn&#8217;t.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I played for about four and a half hours and finished two
or three areas, then got to a big boss fight with the Conqueror&#8217;s
army at the Nest of Eagles. I died twice. So I decided to do a few
sidequests and come back. After doing two, I tried again and died
right away. I tried one more time and this time the RNG was on my
side and I got two Gae Bolg attacks from David in a row, took out
all the plebs and could focus on the two boss characters. I barely
won, however, with some pretty crazy luck. It was fun to face such
odds and win, but the game feels totally unfair with your lack of
control.</p>

<p>The cinematic fight between Emma and the Conqueror was really
awesome. I can&#8217;t believe how poorly they introduced and explained
the Emmy character, although I&#8217;m glad I&#8217;d at least run into her
before.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game&#8211;Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter&#8211;DS&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven&#8217;t been doing puzzles for about two months, so I decided to
start again today. So far, the story is very intriguing and the
Emmy character is funny. Normally these games take a while to get
to interesting puzzles, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Castle of Cagliostro, directed by Hayao Miyazaki (1979)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie--The-Castle-of-Cagliostro--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--1979--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie&#8211;The-Castle-of-Cagliostro&#8211;directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki&#8211;1979&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun anime movie. I like all the little subtle visual
jokes that they have and the general wackiness of the action. I
think you need to be a little bit older to appreciate it though, so
we didn&#8217;t watch it with the kids.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for 1:38 tonight and just got through one area. There
were a few tough enemies that got me in trouble. I&#8217;m in an area
now with just one person in my group and it&#8217;s quite hard to go at
the battles in a way that lets me survive. Kind of fun. I&#8217;m
looking forward to getting the ability to have more units and
unions in my party. It will be fun to organize a big group, I
think.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours tonight after putting kids to
bed. The game is growing on me quite a bit. I find the story to be
very interesting. It&#8217;s not cliche and not over the top. Although
it does move a little slow.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m finding the battle system to be more fun as I think a little
hard as I direct each union to attack. Occasionally I am close to
death, so I feel like it is a little difficult, although I haven&#8217;t
died since I restarted.</p>

<p>I made it through a bunch more areas (I&#8217;m about to go under the
temple) and had a lot of combat on the way. One thing I dislike
about the game is how poorly it communicates your character
progression. There is no summary level that you can look at
it. Instead after each fight, some characters increase some stats
based on something (use? I don&#8217;t know.) It&#8217;s almost like in FF13
where you get bonuses in very small steps, but here you don&#8217;t see
the global path so you don&#8217;t get that reptilian enjoyment of
increasing numbers.</p>

<p>When I got to a new city, Elysion, I explored all over but lost
track of the plot. I couldn&#8217;t find the trigger that would bring me
to the next segment, so I thought I might have to do a mandatory
&#8220;side&#8221; quest. This sent me to a whole bunch of new places&#8230; kind
of a hole&#8230; that turned out to be unnecessary. But on the way I
got to see something cool: the world map is sensibly connected,
because in an area next to a big city, I could see a feature of
the city in the background. That was a nice touch.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Geek Charming, starring Sarah Hyland (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie&#8211;Geek-Charming&#8211;starring-Sarah-Hyland&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very predicable teen comedy of the poor to riches
variety, complete with the standard dual friend abandonment and
inner growth. Nevertheless, it was a good version of this story and
had a few cute things. A lot of the characters acknowledge the
camera too much, but when they are bit more free and their perfect
teeth aren&#8217;t totally showing, it gets a little real and that&#8217;s
nice. Overall, a fun, refreshing, ray of sunshine. Like a good pop
song on a rainy day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I played for 2:15 and got far past where I was
before. I still feel the same way about most parts of the game,
but the battle system is feeling a bit more strategic, if less
active or involved than other similar systems. The story is pretty
interesting&#8230; the concept of remnants is neat. They&#8217;re basically
totally unique high magic items in a low magic world. The voice
acting in this game is totally atrocious though. It would be much
better to just turn if off and/or have Japanese.</p>

<p>In the combat setup of unions, units, etc I feel like I&#8217;m just
making random decisions though. There are so many different
numbers and combinations, I don&#8217;t understand how to optimize it,
so I&#8217;m just getting by.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--N---X360--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game&#8211;N&#8212;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Based on my last experience with the game, I think I&#8217;m basically
done with the game. I&#8217;m pretty conflicted about it, because it is
good on many levels, but a lot of it is so broken. The structure
of the game play&#8212;5 levels at a time, no saving, is probably the
worst thing about it for me, because I like to play in such small
chunks. But also, the mechanics just aren&#8217;t tight enough for me. I
know that the physics/momentum is a conscious design decision, but
I don&#8217;t think it works. Whereas in Super Meat Boy, I can do many
sequences exactly the same every time, I find N+ to be very
variable in how I perform, even though I feel like I&#8217;m doing the
same thing, because the momentum isn&#8217;t quite right. This leads to
great frustration and lack of fun. I can&#8217;t remember if the DS game
was like this and I just hadn&#8217;t noticed because I hadn&#8217;t play SMB
yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Muchi Muchi Pork & Pink Sweets (X360, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game&#8211;Muchi-Muchi-Pork&#8212;Pink-Sweets&#8211;X360&#8211;2011&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve decided to be basically done with these games. Both are not
nearly as good as Deathsmiles, ESPgaluda II, or Mushihime-sama
Futari. Pink Sweets isn&#8217;t even really good at all for me. Both
lack the insane music and really popping/flowing feel of the other
games. I think I might play MMP every once in a while to
experience it a little bit, but it&#8217;s not something I love at
all. Overall, a bit of a bad purchase, seeing as I brought it back
from Japan myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-3&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son and I played through Snake Man&#8217;s level, then started
Hard Man. He thought Snake Man was very cool. He said, at the
beginning of the level, &#8220;Is this Snake Man&#8217;s body?&#8221; because it
looked like a Snake. He&#8217;s very cute when he watches me play Mega
Man.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I just played for 1:15. I got to the end of the fourth area,
but died during the boss fight. I had not saved&#8212;I don&#8217;t know
why, I guess I assumed that there would be checkpoints before
bosses, like Blue Dragon (and many of the other RPGs I&#8217;ve played
recently have.) And so, I lost all that progress and I will have
to start again from scratch. I wouldn&#8217;t be able to bear doing it
all over again I don&#8217;t think. At least not right away, I&#8217;ll try
again tomorrow, I guess.</p>

<p>With my limited play experience, I have some thoughts about the
game.</p>

<p>First, the technical problems are super apparent. The texture
pop-in is really obvious and pretty bad. The framerate is pretty
chuggy. There is a fairly long loading screen before every fight
and between every scene (even with it installed.) In my short
time, this wasn&#8217;t unbearable, but it was very noticeable.</p>

<p>Second, the art is very pretty. They put a lot of work into most
of the textures and models. The animation is pretty basic. A lot
of the cut-scenes look really blocky and there is pretty bad &#8220;dead
eye&#8221; syndrome. This is definitely not FF13. The liquid effects in
the first cave weren&#8217;t great and there was an early scene with an
overhead view of a field where there was some pretty bad
tiling. But overall, pretty.</p>

<p>Third, the gameplay is totally overwhelming. The very first combat
sequence you get into is filed with tons of HUD elements. The
weapon/customization/etc system looks very frightening. This is
overall a good thing. I&#8217;m glad there isn&#8217;t a tedious tutorial
(although the first few areas are clearly about teaching you
different tactics.) The details of combat are really strange. A
cross between doing a lot and doing nothing.</p>

<p>On one level, it is a strategy game where you have teams on 2D
field and you direct attacks to set up flanks, back attacks,
etc. Except, you can&#8217;t actually move the units, they run in a
straight line at the enemy unit you choose. So it&#8217;s a strategy
game where positioning isn&#8217;t directly controlled. This feels like
doing nothing, compared to a strategy game, but like doing a lot
compared to a normal RPG.</p>

<p>On another level, it&#8217;s kind of like a normal Dragon Quest style
RPG where you select &#8220;Attack&#8221;, &#8220;Magic&#8221;, or &#8220;Item&#8221; and then watch
the action play out. Except that the animations are much more
involved, and there are little QTEs (slightly more complicated
than Lost Odyssey&#8217;s) sometimes during them. Except that you don&#8217;t
choose these actions on per character basis, but for a whole team
(called a union of units.) Except that you don&#8217;t actually choose
which skills you will use, like &#8220;Magic > Fire&#8221;, you just choose
&#8220;Magic&#8221;. Except that all your skills aren&#8217;t always available, for
example, you can only choose &#8220;Heal&#8221; when someone is actually hurt
and within range. This feels like doing nothing, compared to a
normal RPG, or even S/TRPG, but a lot more than an RTS or
something where you just point and they do their one thing.</p>

<p>It is really strange.</p>

<p>Obviously I just died during this fight, which means I haven&#8217;t
learned it enough. My problem in the fight was over-confidence and
not healing. But, that over-confidence came from just spamming
Attack in all the other battles (&#8220;Press A to Win&#8221;-style). Tomorrow
I&#8217;ll see how fast I can get back to this point by skipping scenes,
etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game&#8211;The-Last-Remnant&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I plan on starting this game today. I thought I&#8217;d write about my
expectations before I played it.</p>

<p>Like Blue Dragon, I&#8217;d heard of and vaguely followed this game
before it came out. It&#8217;s one of the first &#8220;next gen&#8221; games that
Square produced, so I thought that it might be cool. I&#8217;ve heard
that it has a very strange combat system. Most people who say this
mean it as a bad thing, but that sounds like a plus to me. I don&#8217;t
really know anything about the story, but from what I do know it
sounds pretty different, which sounds like it could be good. I&#8217;ve
heard there are technical problems with laggyness and pop-in, but
that some of them go away if you install to the HDD. The laggyness
could be killer for me, but I don&#8217;t really care about stuff like
pop-in, especially in slow paced games like RPGs.</p>

<p>I looked on HowLongToBeat and there are 6 playthroughs, all over
100 hours. That makes me nervous, because I&#8217;m skeptical of loving
the game that much and it suggests to me that it could be really
grind heavy, which would be terrible.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I&#8217;m pretty excited about seeing what it is like.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
