<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-31T00:25:23-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides, starring Johnny Depp (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie--Pirates-of-the-Caribbean--On-Stranger-Tides--starring-Johnny-Depp--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie&#8211;Pirates-of-the-Caribbean&#8211;On-Stranger-Tides&#8211;starring-Johnny-Depp&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the first Pirates movie and the other ones were
pretty bad. I think their biggest failure was being too fantasy and
with too many monsters, etc. This movie doesn&#8217;t have that problem,
but it is definitely not as good as previous ones.</p>

<p>There are some fun moments of <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow being <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow. A
few absurd fights and chases. It&#8217;s a fairly fun and crazy movie.
The mermaids are totally beautiful and the mermaid who serves as
the love interest has a very sweet and innocent feel to her.</p>

<p>If you stop to think about a lot of the movie, it is pretty absurd
and silly, but I&#8217;m not sure I should really expect anything
different. It&#8217;s a solid B+. I think with a few more exciting fights
and a bit more plot coherence it could have been an A-.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I spent the time
working my way through Blighttown. It was very scary and tough. I
would get repeatedly pummeled by the huge ghouls and then I kept
falling off and getting swarmed closer to the swamp. It was pretty
rough. Quite a few times, the dogs at the very beginning caught me
off guard and decimated me.</p>

<p>Probably the worst time was when I was working my way back to the
swamp the first time, I attacked and the animation pushed me over
the edge of the cliff and I lost 7.7k souls&#8230; about a level where
I am in the game. After that, it was really hard to get back to
the swamp.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s very fun in this game to slowly push through to the next area
and then the next, etc. One thing that I dislike compared to
Demon&#8217;s Souls is that, because there is no hub, you can&#8217;t get back
to a place to buy things, like arrows, if you need them
easily. It&#8217;s kind of frustrating.</p>

<p>SL: 35</p>

<p>Vit: 18
Att:  8!
End: 26
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 10:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/29/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/29/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three and half hours tonight. I went through
the rest of the Undead Parish and then Lower Undead Burg and then
I beat the Dragon in the depths. I beat the Gargoyle on my first
try tonight by spamming it real hard. The demon in the lower burg
took quite a few tries before I took him down. I just got locked
in a combo the first times and couldn&#8217;t recover, but once I got
the dogs out of the way it was easy. When I was exploring the
Depths I got surprise attacked many times and was surprised by
some traps, but eventually I got through. I fought the dragon at
the end about seven times. The third or so I tried to fight as a
human with a phantom helper, but I wasn&#8217;t skilled enough to win
that time. Eventually I got good at running away from him and then
swooping in to his back for attacking. When I finally won, I did
it by hacking off his tail and then winning by attrition.</p>

<p>I think I lost about 6k souls tonight through various hiccups.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m still enjoying the game and finding it very fun to push
through. I&#8217;m getting close to being able to diversify my equipment,
I think. That&#8217;ll be nice to experiment with.</p>

<p>SL: 34</p>

<p>Vit: 18
Att:  8!
End: 25
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 8:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/28/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/28/Game&#8211;Sin&#8212;Punishment&#8211;Star-Successor&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Got to the next boss! I played for like an hour tonight trying
over and over again&#8230; but I did it! Only two more bosses to go!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Decimation X3 (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/28/Game--Decimation-X3--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/28/Game&#8211;Decimation-X3&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New high score&#8230; a year after my last one: Level 33: 1,733,455
points.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/Game&#8211;Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter&#8211;DS&#8211;2011&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Puzzle 26 (a moving block puzzle) took me 2641 steps&#8230; the
optimal is just 30 moves.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin (DS, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game&#8211;Advance-Wars&#8211;Days-of-Ruin&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my flight back I beat the rest of the missions. They were
really, really hard. Brutally hard. Especially the one where you
couldn&#8217;t build any new units. It was rough. This game has a really
good difficulty management system&#8230; in the beginning it is pretty
tough, but do-able and then near the middle to end it is insane,
but it&#8217;s all the same rules. It&#8217;s cool.</p>

<p>The story is totally absurd. But whatever. =)</p>

<p>Total Time: 18:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin (DS, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/18/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/18/Game&#8211;Advance-Wars&#8211;Days-of-Ruin&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went on a long flight, so I started a new DS game.</p>

<p>A few years ago I played through the first DS Advance Wars game
and found it really enjoyable, so I decided to go through the next
one.</p>

<p>I played for about 11 hours on the flight! I can&#8217;t believe my
battery lasted that long&#8212;but I did stop because it was about to
die. Then I played for another 2-ish hours while waiting for the
next flight and then on it.</p>

<p>I got about chapter 21, which appears to be about 80 or 90%
through the game. I only did the challenge levels in the very
beginning, but stopped once they outstripped my patience and
focused on the campaign levels.</p>

<p>The game is pretty much exactly the same as the last one. I don&#8217;t
remember having the anti-tank guns or the bikes in the last game,
but I could be wrong. There&#8217;s no &#8220;dual strike&#8221; anymore, which is
good because it was always a pain to look at the top screen too.</p>

<p>The game is very interesting in a way, because there&#8217;s no
progression system. Although you are gradually given new units and
abilities, you don&#8217;t have any input on that process, it&#8217;s all
story based. In essence, each level is about defeating the enemy
with the endownment you&#8217;ve been given. Very similar to my ideas
for rougelike RPGs.</p>

<p>I had a few ridiculous battles. For example, mission 10 took like
73 rounds with an incredible slow push into their territory and
many failed blitz attempts. I won 12 by depleting the enemy&#8217;s last
unit&#8217;s gas after their fighter killed my last plan and I had
defeated all their ground units honestly. Mission 14 took a ton of
attempts, probably four or five, and ended up going into 47
rounds. Mission 17 took a little over an hour to beat. (Basic math
tells me that each mission has taken on average about 40 minutes.)
It&#8217;s interesting how much mileage the game provides.</p>

<p>The story is ridiculous just like the last game but in like the
totally opposite direction. The first game I played was very &#8220;Rah
rah&#8221; about world and treated it (in the story) like a silly game
with no consequences. This game is all about the evils of war and
of humanity in general with the main characters being pure divine
beings of goodness and everyone else being totally
detestable. It&#8217;s pretty absurd. If there were voice-acting, it
would be the worst. The situation they are in is actually really
similar to Battlestar Galactica, but if all the bad guys on that
show were the ones in charge and the people at the edges were
trying to be good. I&#8217;m tempted to not even watch the story scenes
they are so ridiculous, but I&#8217;m doing it anyways.</p>

<p>Total Time: 13:12</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Vow, starring Rachel McAdams and Channing Tatum (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie&#8211;The-Vow&#8211;starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cute movie. There were a lot of cute moments. I
felt like the people in it were unrealistically mean to basically
everyone. I read the Wikipedia page and it talked about the real
couple was very religious and credit God for keeping them
together. It would have been nice to acknowledge that it
someway&#8230; but the couple in the movie weren&#8217;t even married in a
church.</p>

<p>I think my favourite parts of the movie were the very subtle signs
of how much they loved each other. Such as rolling up the window
and the cat. Very cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little over an hour. I got through the next
part of the Undead Parish. The Rhino was pretty tough and got me
once. Then I weaved my way around and accidentally stumbled into
the Bell Gargoyle fight. I died the first three times and then
accidentally died on the way. So I lost about 6k souls. Ouch. This
game is definitely great.</p>

<p>SL: 21</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 18
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 4:56</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game&#8211;Dark-Souls&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today and got used to the game. I
spent a long time planning my character based on remembering what
was a good strategy in Demon&#8217;s Souls. I&#8217;ll be taking the same
approach: really fast, huge shield, melee focus, but with a good
bow.</p>

<p>The tutorial phase of the game was much shorter and so far the
game seems incredibly linear, which I thought wasn&#8217;t the case, but
maybe I&#8217;m just still in the beginning. Last time I took a very
linear approach through the game, but this time I intend to
explore a bit more.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game are basically identical. The graphics
seem a little bit better&#8230; primarily in the lightning department,
but I don&#8217;t know if I can really tell or I just have a bad
memory. It seems like this simply <em>is</em> Demon&#8217;s Souls with a little
bit of a different structure&#8212;no hub, Humanity, etc.</p>

<p>That makes it sound like I don&#8217;t like the idea of that, but I&#8217;m
actually very excited about playing it.</p>

<p>During my time tonight, I died twice. Each time against a boss on
my first fight with them. The game seems just as hard as before,
but I&#8217;m getting used to the controls again and learning how the
bosses behave. Overall, it&#8217;s a pretty awesome game.</p>

<p>Here are my current stats (where ! indicates that the stat is at
the level I intend to leave it at for the foreseeable future):</p>

<p>SL: 19</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 16
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 3:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game&#8211;Child-of-Eden&#8211;X360&#8211;2011&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for about an hour and beat the last two levels on
my first try (tonight, the second to last level took me about four
or five tries total.) The final level was basically a boss rush
plus a new boss at the end. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>I concurred with everything I said yesterday. This game is worth
everything I paid for it. ;) I would&#8217;ve probably been happy if I
paid $15 for it. I intend to gradually play through the levels
again on Hard and through the Challenge mode. Probably once a week
on Sunday. I enjoyed the game and it will be in the back of my
mind for a while, but it&#8217;s not a revelation.</p>

<p>I wonder how it is with Kinect or Move?</p>

<p>Total time: 3:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game&#8211;Pac-Man-CE-DX&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today and got a lot more S-ranks and
stuff.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 2,160/248,420 &#8212; 0.86%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game&#8211;Child-of-Eden&#8211;X360&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game as a prize from Call of Podcast for writing about
my game management system. It was on my to-buy list before that,
although I was planning on buying the PS3 version. The game looked
really beautiful and I really like Genki Rockets. I played Rez for
the Dreamcast and wasn&#8217;t really blown away, but I thought that it
might be more interesting in a more modern form.</p>

<p>The game opens up with a really intriguing video and quickly shows
off its unique, beautiful world.</p>

<p>I played it for about an hour and half tonight. I beat the
first three levels on the first try, although I had to do each
twice to unlock the next level. I played the fourth level about
four times, but kept dying at the final form of the boss, because
it shoots so many tracer rounds.</p>

<p>I find the gameplay to be enjoyable and challenging, at least when
you get totally overwhelmed by bullets. I suppose I should get
better at using the screen clearing bombs. The addition of the
tracer rounds seems like it would be an insignificant change, but
it makes a huge difference compared to Rez.</p>

<p>I love the music, although I wish that there were more vocals,
like the actual Genki Rockets song. It may be that I&#8217;m not playing
well enough to unlock them though&#8230; on that note, I dislike how
it seems like I am doing the levels perfect (not getting hit,
getting mostly perfect octo-locks) but I&#8217;m only get three stars a
pop. It&#8217;s weird.</p>

<p>I love that every level is totally different visually and aurally
from the others. This game is the perfect of a game that seems
like it was made on a totally different planet. I&#8217;ve played plenty
of Japanese games that do this, but most Western games lack that
kind of creativity.</p>

<p>I intend to keep trucking at it and beat. I haven&#8217;t yet decided if
I will play through the hard mode or if I will just periodically
play through the whole game when I want to chill out to some rad
music, or show someone the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The wife and I watched two more episodes. The game continues to be
really funny. A little thing I really liked that we noticed today
was that the voice of York is different when he is hearing himself
talk than when the camera is from a third-person perspective. Very
subtle, but neat. Something I enjoy about the narrator guy is that
he talks so matter-of-factly about some of the strange stuff going
in the game. It adds to the absurdity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Removing the Condemnation, by Denver C. Snuffer, Jr. (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Book--Removing-the-Condemnation--by-Denver-C--Snuffer--Jr---2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Book&#8211;Removing-the-Condemnation&#8211;by-Denver-C&#8211;Snuffer&#8211;Jr&#8212;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been reading this book for a few weeks. It&#8217;s just
terrible.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s about 550 pages where every one has the text of a verse from
the Book of <em>REDACTED</em> and then a series of questions underneath it
like &#8220;What does X mean?&#8221; &#8220;What does (something tangentially related
to X) mean?&#8221; &#8220;What does Y mean?&#8221; etc. It does this over and over
and over, with almost no answers. Sometimes the questions are
incredibly obvious or trivial, like the verse will say &#8220;follow the
Prophet&#8221; and the questions will be something like &#8220;What does it
/really/ mean to follow?&#8221; &#8220;No, REALLY what does it mean?&#8221;</p>

<p>I get the impression that the author has deep, and perhaps
controversial, opinions about these things, but doesn&#8217;t want to
express them clearly because he&#8217;s afraid of being reprimanded by
the Church or being held accountable in anyway.</p>

<p>Sometimes the questions are so leading, you can see what opinion he
is trying to express, but is unwilling to do it openly. For
example, he has a list of questions related to the details of the
sacrament ordinance with all sorts of questioning about when it is
okay to change ordinances. It is pretty clear to me he&#8217;s implying
something bad about the changes in the temple ordinances. But,
again he doesn&#8217;t actually say this.</p>

<p>In addition to this frivolous questions, there&#8217;s saccharine
comments like, &#8220;Man this Book of <em>REDACTED</em> is pretty important, huh? I
can&#8217;t believe it&#8217;s so great&#8221; that sound like staged humility.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s plausible that this guy&#8217;s other books contain interesting
stuff, but I don&#8217;t think he can use the commentary format effectively.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Immortals, starring Henry Cavil (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie&#8211;Immortals&#8211;starring-Henry-Cavil&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really rad movie. It had a similar amazing look as 300,
but was much more fantasy oriented. The actions of the Gods in the
movie are awesome and not quite like anything I&#8217;d ever seen
before. The actions are the humans are exciting and down to Earth
in a neat contrasting way. Mickey Rourke does an amazing job as a
crazy warlord. The movie is a really great spectacle piece and is
totally worth it just for the way the Greek Gods are presented.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Haywire, starring Gina Carano (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie&#8211;Haywire&#8211;starring-Gina-Carano&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a cool spy-action movie. I like how it emphasizes the
&#8220;soft&#8221; part of spy work (but not as much as something like
/Spygame/.) And, I think the fight scenes are really cool because
they are so slow and feel realistic. In a strange way, her
controlled fighting makes it almost less exciting, because she
seems so confident and in control all the time. There was lots of
neat camera work&#8212;mainly during the chase sequences. And, the
structuring of the story telling (in the beginning, she&#8217;s narrating
to someone else) is interesting. The one thing I think could have
been a lot better about the movie was the final reveal: the reason
for the betrayal could have been more meaningful and cooler. But,
overall, it was a pretty rad movie. I can imagine watching more
movies with Gina Carano starring.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I&#8217;m
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I&#8217;m on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I&#8217;ll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but&#8230;</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I&#8217;m not compelled by this one at all. It&#8217;s a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There&#8217;s a
&#8220;blindside&#8221; system, but it&#8217;s basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren&#8217;t ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It&#8217;s frustrating that
you can&#8217;t really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there&#8217;s no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you&#8217;ll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You&#8217;ll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it&#8217;s
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don&#8217;t think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m glad I&#8217;ve played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game&#8211;Pac-Man-CE-DX&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got another S-rank.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 3,144/248,092 &#8212; 1.26%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
