<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-03T00:18:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Rise-of-the-Lycans&#8211;starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was really surprised by the quality of this movie. I assumed that
because it didn&#8217;t star Kate Beckinsale it would be a cheap version
of the world. But actually, I think it is the best yet; although it
wouldn&#8217;t be very good without the first movie, obviously. It gives
a lot better context to the first movie and makes a lot of what
seems strange about the mythology a lot more reasonable. The story
is a lot more coherent and reasonable and the action is noticeably
slower, so you can appreciate it a bit more.</p>

<p>The development of the romance between Lucian and Sonja is totally
ignored, apart from a glance when they are kids.</p>

<p>Rhona Mitra really does look like Kate Beckinsale.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s cool that the giant black werewolf from the first scene of the
first movie is one of Lucian&#8217;s oldest friends. A nice little nod to
people paying attention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a few more stealth style missions. The big battle in the
trenches was really different and dangerous, although I did it in
a stealth way. The bonus mission where you had to search through
all the grassy areas was pretty cool too.</p>

<p>The story is getting really neat and touching. I can&#8217;t believe
they killed Isara, but I like the way you return to Bruhl as a way
to &#8220;avenge&#8221; her. The development of the idea of Alicia being a
Valkyria is really neat too. I wonder if it will just be in
cut-scenes or if she&#8217;ll become some crazy new unit type? I feel
like the story is close to wrapping up, but there are a lot more
empty boxes in the R&amp;D area, so I suspect that it really isn&#8217;t
that close to being done.</p>

<p>This is still an awesome game. The best part is probably the way
they are constantly developing and adding more and more to the
story and gameplay. It&#8217;s very different than it was in the
beginning, but the path to here has made complete sense.</p>

<p>Total: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kings of Power 4 Billion %, by Paul Robertson (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie--Kings-of-Power-4-Billion----by-Paul-Robertson--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie&#8211;Kings-of-Power-4-Billion&#8212;-by-Paul-Robertson&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is totally insane and amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a very busy but ultimately unproductive day with a lot of
wasted effort, so I played games rather later to feel some
accomplishment. I played for about 2 hours. I got through all of
chapter 11 and did the skirmish that opened up three times (Easy,
Normal, Normal)&#8230; all As (2 rounds!)&#8230; to get enough money to
buy everything. The beach battle was pretty scary, but I was able
to do it in 2 rounds with only 2 restarts. It was pretty cool to
have a few &#8220;stealth&#8221; levels.</p>

<p>Total: 20:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Evolution&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2006&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn&#8217;t seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It&#8217;s a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight&#8230; the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn&#8217;t understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it&#8230; but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I&#8217;m curious about what Zaka will be
like&#8230; do I really get another vehicle? I&#8217;m running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat the game tonight after playing for about 5 hours. The final
battle was super tough. I liked all the build-up side battles
too. The best part of the final battle were the cool 2D animations
and &#8220;camera&#8221; changes. It was pretty unique, although something
similar happened a few times in earlier parts of the game.</p>

<p>Overall, I found this game to be pretty rad. The game play is
straight-forward, but quick enough to not be too tedious compared
to the first three. The lack of a job system is fine, because the
individual characters you are given are interesting enough. The
story is very quaint and cute; the way they broke up the story is
very cool, especially how people act around the Hero.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t tell how much of what I like (such as the Heal All option)
were added in the remake, but I don&#8217;t feel like I need to play the
NES version to find out.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;d play it again, because I&#8217;m willing to bet that
another Dragon Quest game (maybe a SNES one?) will be a more
refined experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 23:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld, starring Kate Beckinsale (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2003&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget why, but the other day I was reminded of this series. I
decided to start watching it, similar to how I went through the
Resident Evil movies. Like that series, I saw the first one when it
came out, but never saw the others. I remember thinking the movie
was cool and that Kate Beckinsale was amazing attractive.</p>

<p>On a second viewing, significantly older, I still think some parts
of the movie are cool. The mythology is interesting and fairly
developed. The actor of Viktor is pretty awesome; while the actor
that played Kraven was unbelievably bad. The character of Erica is
really interesting and subtle. And, yes, Kate Beckinsale is
woah&#8212;except, I don&#8217;t understand the appeal of the &#8220;cat suits&#8221;,
they make all her natural curves indistinguishable, like a running
bra or something. I don&#8217;t get it, but I guess that had to because
this movie was made to be so Matrix-y. The action sequences are
very derivative of the Matrix and pretty boring overall
actually. Lots of akimbo and chunks of buildings flying off. The
best fight is probably the very first one. Even the final fight
between Viktor and Michael is pretty meh, because Michael is so
&#8220;whatever&#8221; that it doesn&#8217;t get too exciting.</p>

<p>Definitely not a classic, but I&#8217;m interested in watching the rest
of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the &#8220;reports&#8221; I&#8217;d seen showing up were&#8230; how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service&#8230; I mean, the beach vacation&#8230; one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours throughout the day today while the
kids were playing and/or sick. I explored the waterfall and used
my water soaking stone and got a rad sword. I also did a little
bit of grinding until I could be Estark&#8230; which I barely did;
Ragnar was the only one left and he would&#8217;ve only last one
hit&#8230; and he was killed in the first fight as I tried to
escape. But, alas, I did.</p>

<p>After I got the balloon, I decided to be done for the night. As I
was looking at the world map, I thought how geeky and funny it
would be to have an &#8220;accurate&#8221; polar projection map with scaling
deformation in certain regions (including on the characters &amp;
their speed.) That would be funny.</p>

<p>Shopping list:
- 35k per Liquid Metal Armor in Endor (secret shop, need 3)
- Female armor in Elf town (need 2?)</p>

<p>Total time: 19:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Rise of the Planet of the Apes, starring James Franco and Andy Seeks (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie--Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes--starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie&#8211;Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes&#8211;starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was really different than I thought it would be. I
expected that the end of the movie would be closer to ape dominance
and I expected that the character of Caesar would be more of a hero
for humans&#8212;kind of the only smart ape that loved humans, whereas
the other ones (like Koba) would just hate them. The movie was
pretty cool and Caesar was a great epic leader. There were lots of
really cool &#8220;A-hah!&#8221; moments of his progression that were super
satisfying. I&#8217;d like to see sequels to this made.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter&#8211;DS&#8211;2011&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been plugging along in the game doing one a day. I got the
train mini-game today. It&#8217;s a neat version of the car mini-game
from the last one. The idea of dealing with multiple trains at a
time sounds like it will be challenging.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out&#8212;-NES&#8211;1987&#8211;11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wanted to show the wife this game and have her try it out. She
beat Glass Joe by decision after losing by decision and having me
show her how it was done. She lost on the next fight but I took
the continue and took it all the way to Soda Popinski. It was
pretty rad to go through the whole game up to that point and show
off to her a bit. My code this time around was different though:</p>

<p>255 113 7842</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game&#8211;Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played three levels tonight. It was pretty fun. My wife and I
had a bit of a disagreement about what was fun about the game. She
really likes collecting everything and exploring the area, trying
to do harder things. In contrast, I find that annoying and prefer
to just go through the obstacle course as fast as possible. But,
the secret of marital bliss is she tells me what to do, and I do
it, so I repented. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. The story battles are
getting pretty rough and un-cheese-able, which is really fun
because it forces me to try different things. I got a really bad
score in the second woodland battle, which was kinda sad, so I did
another skirmish so I could get the XP I missed. I really enjoyed
using the tank a lot in the woodland battle though.</p>

<p>Total: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours and did a lot of exploring and
learning about the many quests I need to finish to get all the
Zenithian equipment. There&#8217;s a lot to keep track of and
remember. I feel like I need to write it down. I think in a modern
game there would be in-game markers of some kind that might make
it to easy or feel to &#8220;fetch questy&#8221;, but when you actually have
to remember what&#8217;s going on, it feels more real and fun. It&#8217;s an
interesting thing.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s my list:
- The sword is near a waterfall
- I have the water soaking stone
- I need to go to a mine near the French stuff</p>

<p>Total time: 16:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three and half hours tonight. I spent a very
long time on the Desert Duel against the giant tank. There was a
lot of saving and reloading as I tried different techniques and
slowly got closer to victory. It was a really tough, complicated
fight. The stealth mission was pretty tough too; I kept making
stupid mistakes and trying to kill the soldier named &#8220;Ty the
Immortal&#8221;&#8212;I couldn&#8217;t seem to land a killing hit on him&#8230; maybe
his name was a clue from the developers? I&#8217;m sad I didn&#8217;t get an A
on that fight.</p>

<p>I think it is cool how the came is slowly becoming more
&#8220;fantastical&#8221; in its setting with the discovery at the ruins,
etc. It&#8217;s neat because the earlier parts of the game are so
realistic-ish.</p>

<p>The battles tonight were especially fun because I couldn&#8217;t cheese
them, so I had to really use all the options that were
available. Nevertheless, I had some pretty brutal strategies. For
example, in the desert fight, I was able to kill all the enemy
foot soldiers on the first round with my two snipers and
Rosie. Then I was able to take out all the gun turrets on the tank
in two rounds. Then it was just a matter of waiting around while
the radiators showed up. When Selvaria surprise attacked, Rosie
was right next to where her units appeared, so she was able to
kill every single one on the first round. Then Selvaria ignored
her and just ran past. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>Total: 10:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through a boss fight with a tiny bit of grinding to get
strong enough for it. I got totally tooled the first time, but I
got about one level per character, maybe two, and then totally
destroyed the boss (Baal-something?) on the second try. It was
weird. I thought the hidden sign was pretty cool and when I went
back to the town I immediately remembered about the door I
couldn&#8217;t go to before. I like it when things like that work out.</p>

<p>Total time: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I did a whole bunch
of battles. The hardest was the Normal Skirmish that&#8217;s like the
Woodland battle. It took me quite a few tries to get an A with
Alicia. Playing the game like this makes it like Metal Gear Solid
when you are trying to get a No Alert win. It&#8217;s a very strange
optimization problem.</p>

<p>Total: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-4&#8211;Chapters-of-the-Chosen&#8211;DS&#8211;2007&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about 30 minutes today and did a dungeon and a
boss. It&#8217;s nice how bite-sized this game can be. I&#8217;m really
hurting for cash in the game though and I don&#8217;t want to grind for
it right now. I&#8217;d much rather grind to be able to go &#8220;deeper&#8221; into
some place than just fighting enemies I know I can handle so I can
get some cash.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
