<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-22T23:06:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Wreck-It Ralph, starring John C. Reily (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Movie--Wreck-It-Ralph--starring-John-C--Reily--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Movie&#8211;Wreck-It-Ralph&#8211;starring-John-C&#8211;Reily&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a brilliant movie. All the cameos, references, and jokes
related to video games were lots of fun. The story was pretty cute
too. I saw it with my two kids and they enjoyed it a lot. I liked
the music a lot, especially the AKB48 song.</p>

<p>The short at the beginning of the movie was beautiful and made me
cry. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Hang-On (GEN, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Super-Hang-On--GEN--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Super-Hang-On&#8211;GEN&#8211;1988&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to have a Genesis day and I played a lot of games. I
started off with this one&#8230; way it is unbelievably
terrible. It&#8217;s interesting that it is trying to do the same as a
game like Gran Turismo&#8230; and obviously it utterly fails.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:06</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Strider (GEN, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Strider--GEN--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Strider&#8211;GEN&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve heard a lot about this game and I thought it would be an
awesome action game like Ninja Gaiden, but with bigger and more
beautiful graphics. I was totally wrong. This is super boring and
the giant sprites do the gameplay a great dis-service by
preventing you from seeing enough of the screen to do anything
really effectively. I did not enjoy it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:12</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Streets of Rage (GEN, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Streets-of-Rage--GEN--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Streets-of-Rage&#8211;GEN&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this on Easy as Blaze and got to the final
boss. The combat feels pretty good in this game, but it has the
normal problems with beat-em-ups: the bosses are impossible unless
you use lots of special attacks, which are drastically
limited. I&#8217;m surprised I got so far. On my first continue, I got
to the end of Round 5. On my second, I got to the end of
Round 7. In the third, I got to the final boss. Definitely not
worth playing again, but it wasn&#8217;t a terrible waste of an hour.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Revenge of Shinobi (GEN, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Revenge-of-Shinobi--GEN--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Revenge-of-Shinobi&#8211;GEN&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through the first level of this game. Compared to Strider
it is a lot more interesting, but the hit detection and the speed
are way too painful to really enjoy. I also greatly disliked that
the attack was limited by a small amount of ammo.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Golden Axe (GEN, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Golden-Axe--GEN--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Golden-Axe&#8211;GEN&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through the entire beginner version of this with the
girl. This is a classic beat-em-up at their worst. There&#8217;s no
strategy to speak of and the bosses require quarters or repeated
usage of special attacks. Very boring.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Columns (GEN, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game--Columns--GEN--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/22/Game&#8211;Columns&#8211;GEN&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve never played this puzzle game before. There&#8217;s nothing too
wrong with it as a concept, but I find it very difficult to enjoy
puzzle games like this for a long time. They would really be best
as rotating little games in a larger context. This particular
version of the Columns concept, however, feels really broken.</p>

<p>As you get jewels, it gets faster and faster. It gets so fast that
you can&#8217;t think at all and the best you can do it plan one move
ahead and then rotate the blocks as they&#8217;ve just landed to make
the most of the situation. It actually feels like you&#8217;re not
really making decisions and are winning randomly.</p>

<p>I was able to make it 22 levels and there were many times I
basically gave up but randomly got triples that totally changed
my luck. Weird.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Spaceteam (iOS, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game--Spaceteam--iOS--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game&#8211;Spaceteam&#8211;iOS&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I played this for about ten minutes today. It&#8217;s a
very cute and kind of brilliant concept. I thought the names of
the stuff were great. We gave up after eight sectors because our
kids were getting upset at us yelling at each other. :)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Nintendo World Cup (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game&#8211;Nintendo-World-Cup&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another five matches in the middle of the day over about
an hour. I discovered a new trick: after expending all your super
kicks (or just getting an advantage), run down the clock so you
win. I found two good ways to run down the clock: First, knock out
a member of the other team and go into the zone that only he
defends and wait. Second, continually to head-butt passes (the AI
never intercepts these). Hah!</p>

<p>At the end of the day I played again for another hour or so and
beat the game. The final few matches were really tough to keep the
ball on my side and I got scored on more than any other matches,
but I was able to win with a bit of abuse. It&#8217;s a fun game to play
and I can imagine it being more difficult and interesting.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/21/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-4&#8211;NES&#8211;1991&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the middle of the day, I played this and beat Ring Man and
Dust Man. Ring Man&#8217;s level was quite difficult and Dust Man was
really tough to fight himself.</p>

<p>At night, I went through the rest of the game and beat it. I
found this game to be much much harder than the other ones. I
think one thing that made it so difficult was that when you died
against a boss in the Wily stages, you had to do the end of the
level again. The 2nd form of the Wily Machine was really
brutal. It took me so long to even be able to hit him at all. I
watched a few YouTube videos and still couldn&#8217;t do it. I think it
took about 45 minutes of fighting over and over again.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:34</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Parodius Da! (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Parodius-Da---NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game&#8211;Parodius-Da&#8212;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got to the boss of stage 2 after playing for about 35
minutes. I&#8217;ve heard about this game many times before and I had
much greater expectations about how crazy and silly it would
be. I thought the bosses I fought were very cool, but overall, it
wasn&#8217;t too crazy.</p>

<p>The mechanics are very reasonable for its time&#8230; it&#8217;s just
Gradius. My only problem with it is that the NES is not a good
system for it: it has really atrocious and not intentional
slow-down; the sprite flicker is really bad and makes it hard to
see enemy bullets; and, the game lacks the vibrancy that it seems
like it should have. I&#8217;m also quite spoiler by CAVE when it comes
to being able to distinguish enemy bullets from mine and seeing
the hit box of the character easily.</p>

<p>I will try the other Parodius games rather than invest any more
time in this.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Nintendo World Cup (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game&#8211;Nintendo-World-Cup&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These TECHNOS games feel so good. I like the dynamics in this
game and the way it feels great to tackle your opponent. I really
enjoy more abstract sports games like this. I don&#8217;t know if I
wouldn&#8217;t like the more modern, realistic sports games&#8230; I
presume I wouldn&#8217;t, but I haven&#8217;t really played them. One thing
about this game though, is that I don&#8217;t think it could sustain
playing it for a long sitting. I played for a little more than
thirty minutes and that seems like the right amount of time. I
think I will keep at it and beat it&#8230; maybe?</p>

<p>Password: 30711 - Argentina 3rd match</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Military Madness (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Military-Madness--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game&#8211;Military-Madness&#8211;TG16&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played the first, second, and third levels over about an
hour. I didn&#8217;t finish the last level.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the game. It is extremely similar to Advance Wars. I
find the interface in Advance Wars to be superior and the game is
more complex, but not in a way that is extremely complex. Both
are very simple, but they allow that simplicity to be used to
create interesting and challenging situations. But, because of
the similarity, I don&#8217;t feel a great compulsion to play this
game, particularly when it is so inconvenient to do so. (I have a
Japanese PC Engine, so my Hu-Card doesn&#8217;t work, so I have to
emulate it.)</p>

<p>Maybe if I got deeper into the game, there would be something
unlike about it that would be worth understanding, but after
scanning a FAQ, it doesn&#8217;t seem so.</p>

<p>I would really like a procedurally generated game like this where
I could play at incredibly small chunks overtime. Until then&#8230; I
think I&#8217;ll abandon it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gargoyle's Quest (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Gargoyle-s-Quest--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game&#8211;Gargoyle-s-Quest&#8211;GB&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour and a half. It&#8217;s a very
intriguing game.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s like a normal platforming game, but after you beat the first
level, you are thrust into a weird RPG-like world. You wander
around talking to people and getting little side-quests.</p>

<p>When you are in the overworld, you can get into random battles
that are like Zelda 2&#8212;tiny side-scrolling segments&#8212;where you
have to defeat all the enemies to escape. There&#8217;s no experience
or progress system, other than receiving items which power you
up.</p>

<p>I got about half-way through the game (according to a FAQ) and
got a lot of interesting power-ups: breaking blocks, jumping
higher, flying longer, etc.</p>

<p>It was interesting, but it is very hard to enjoy Gameboy games (my
eyes bleed), especially on the emulator I was using because it
would get laggy a bit too often. I think I will try the NES game
and definitely the SNES game in this series. I have high hopes for
the SNES game.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game&#8211;Neutopia&#8211;TG16&#8211;1989&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Later in the day, I played for almost three hours.</p>

<p>I beat up to level 5. I find the game to be so much like LoZ but
bigger in ways that don&#8217;t make it better.</p>

<p>There are some similar items (like the Rainbow Drop is the same as
the Ladder) and some unique ones (like the Glowing Moss). But
there&#8217;s a lot that isn&#8217;t there and what is added isn&#8217;t great.</p>

<p>The levels are all a lot bigger, but they look too much the same
that they are extremely confusing and kind of frustrating. Same
with the various overworlds.</p>

<p>There are upgrades to your armor and weapon, but they don&#8217;t really
feel much better because the enemies are getting stronger too. (In
contrast, in LoZ, the enemies in the overworld are all the same
and as you get stronger stuff, you see the same guys more and get
to thrash them.)</p>

<p>The bosses are huge and cool looking, but they take way too long
to kill once you&#8217;ve learned their pattern and can totally avoid
being hit.</p>

<p>Overall, the game just isn&#8217;t as refined as LoZ. I got over the
problems with the combat with a little more attention, but I feel
like the rest of the game will just be a chore. I don&#8217;t think I
will finish it.</p>

<p>I bet if I grew up with a TurboGrafx rather than a Nintendo, I
would love this game, but as it stands, it&#8217;s just meh.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:05</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game&#8211;Neutopia&#8211;TG16&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half an hour today on an emulator.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a strange game. It seems like it is trying to be Legend of
Zelda I, but it has tried to evolve, it seems. For instance, I
felt like inside every cave was a person just blathering on about
stuff that didn&#8217;t matter. The combat feels a bit&#8230; off. It&#8217;s
like it is very hard to line enemies up. In LTTP, since the sword
slices in an arc, it never really matters if you aren&#8217;t lined up
perfectly. In LoZ, you do need to be straight, but I think the
enemies are guaranteed to be in a grid, so it is easy to hit
them. It&#8217;s a strange thing to miss. It seems like the dungeons
are much more linear and I got to the end of one, but couldn&#8217;t
beat the boss (after a ton of tries)&#8230; it seems to have way too
much health.</p>

<p>I will give it another session&#8230; but I&#8217;m not impressed.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game&#8211;Ninja-Gaiden-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this game tonight. I found it to be less
ridiculously hard than the first one because I found the powerups
and ninja power recharges to be more available. The environmental
hazards (wind, darkness, etc) were really rough. The cinema
sequences are way too long. I found confirmation in this
play-through of something that James Rolfe said in AVGN: you
forget that there is a health bar in this game, because you only
normally die by being whacked off platforms when you get
hit. It&#8217;s so true. Also, the powerup that shoots fire diagonally
upwards is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Batman (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game&#8211;Batman&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about two and half hours. A little more
than the final hour was spent on the last level trying to get up
the vertical passage with the gears. It was unbearably
brutalizing. If you could just shoot up or if the jump were a
little bit more controllable, I could have done it. But I decided
that I was interested in the ending that much.</p>

<p>Overall, this game is feels really great. The different weapons
are all useful and fun. The jumping is pretty nice and the
wall-hanging works much better than in Ninja Gaiden. Surprisingly
good!</p>

<p>Total time: 2:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Phantom of the Opera, by Andrew Lloyd Webber (2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie--The-Phantom-of-the-Opera--by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie&#8211;The-Phantom-of-the-Opera&#8211;by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber&#8211;2004&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was amazing. This visuals are crazy. The actors and
actresses are beautiful. Wow. I think my favourite moments are:
- when Christine is first going down to the Phantom&#8217;s lair,
because the pull of the camera is so cool.
- the song &#8220;Masquerade&#8221; and its dance number&#8212;crazy.
Minnie Driver was great, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Imaginarium of Doctor Parnassus, starring Heath Ledger (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie--The-Imaginarium-of-Doctor-Parnassus--starring-Heath-Ledger--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie&#8211;The-Imaginarium-of-Doctor-Parnassus&#8211;starring-Heath-Ledger&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an interesting and bizarre movie. The visuals are really
crazy and intriguing. Heath Ledger&#8217;s character is neat, although I
would prefer to learn more about Doctor Parnassus. His character&#8217;s
introduction was fascinating. Reading about how they replaced
Heath Ledger was crazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
