<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T22:13:59-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Ice Age: Continental Drift (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie--Ice-Age--Continental-Drift--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie&#8211;Ice-Age&#8211;Continental-Drift&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took my son to the theatre to see this today. He really enjoyed
it. I thought there were definitely some funny parts too, although
overall the plot is incredibly weak. It&#8217;s very short and a kid&#8217;s
movie, so that&#8217;s understandable. In terms of plot, it&#8217;s basically
the same as an episode of a cartoon, but with longer scenes and big
events. I thought the finale of the Scrat subplot was awesome
though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I advanced the story quite a bit. I feel like I&#8217;m in the closing
stages: I&#8217;m going to fight Zangurak, then send the Outsider back,
and live happily ever after with Calista. I thought her wedding
dress was very cute and I liked the resolution of the wedding
plot. In the game play, there&#8217;s been a bit of a boss rush of sorts
where boss encounters similar to ones from earlier in the game
keep coming back. It&#8217;s fun though. The fight next to the Outside
was pretty exciting and difficult. That whole sequence going down
the tunnel was very difficult&#8212;I think I died three times.</p>

<p>I accidentally used the Auto-Equip feature and all my outfits
changed. It was very painful to go back to dressing all the girls
how I like.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48
Total time: 23:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;Punch-Out&#8212;-Wii&#8211;2009&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a few rounds today with the kids. I did pretty well
against Sandman&#8230; I&#8217;m getting better. But I still didn&#8217;t beat
him.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1988&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we&#8217;ve been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a short amount of time yesterday before going to
bed. I mainly just advanced the story. It turns out that Lavos is
behind Zael&#8217;s power and the destruction of the world. Bummer. I&#8217;m
excited about a cute wedding scene.</p>

<p>TODO Go back to the mysterious island and go behind the entrance
where the Lvl 40 Cave Cougars are.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played for a lot. A new arena season was opened, so I
had a lot of fun playing it over and over so I could max out all
my currently available items, etc. I did it like seven times. In
addition to that, I did some story missions, including the
haunted mansion. The best part of that was Horace&#8217;s ridiculous
comment about his wife afterwards. The stealth section escaping
from the castle was kind of odd, but worked as much as it needed
to. It was much better with Callista than with Zael alone. I&#8217;m
weirded out by Dagran being a sketch ball. I wonder where the
story is going. I presume that the Count is really the big bad in
some way, but maybe also I&#8217;ll fight &#8220;The Outsider&#8221;.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 1.0 You Are (Not) Alone, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie&#8211;Evangelion&#8211;1-0-You-Are&#8211;Not&#8211;Alone&#8211;by-Studio-Khara&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we got this from Netflix, my wife said &#8220;Ugh, Evangelion?&#8221; But
I think she enjoyed it. She commented on how the music was really
good and we were both impressed by the obviously better graphics
and effects. It is amazing how much is the same between this and
the originals though. I think it is already clearer what the
greater story is. I think there are more risque shots than before,
but, even so, they are quite tame. Not much to say other than that
I like Evangelion and this was preferred to watching the original
episodes. (Although I do miss the theme song.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a lot today as I rested from being sick. There some
pretty memorable moments: I loved the joke about why one family
had been in charge of guarding the forbidden gate for so long. I
was a bit disappointed that I wasn&#8217;t able to say &#8220;No&#8221; to the
Count or console Callista&#8230; the romantic comedy structure is
really being forced on me. I find the establishment of Mirania as
this character with a weird &#8220;food&#8221; quirk to be pretty
hilarious. I&#8217;m still really enjoying this game.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 36
Total time: 15:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Castlevania 4 (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--Super-Castlevania-4--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;Super-Castlevania-4&#8211;SNES&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed this game to my son and got to block 3-2 on one
continue. I died once on Medusa, because I had been sloppy
earlier in the level and then the rest of the deaths came from
bad platforming (mostly swinging) in the last level. My son was
getting annoyed and kept asking me to kill myself so we could do
something else. Nice :)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got past Vile, but had a heck of a time getting up the wall with
the flying platformers&#8230; it was so painful. I feel like I&#8217;m
really letting my kids down when they watch me and expect
awesomeness.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:23</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours and got back to the town. I
find it very charming how much this story is like Aladdin or a
romantic comedy. It was also neat how there was a monster
summoning spot right before a boss fight, almost like if you were
having trouble you could grind there, because the game is
normally very closed and linear. It&#8217;s a neat structure.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 25
Total time: 10:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played again for about four hours. I got to the island and did
the two side quests there and then went to the Gurak base. I&#8217;m
really enjoying the flow of the story and the development of
Zael&#8217;s &amp; Callista&#8217;s relationship. I changed the combat controls
to Manual and I find it quite a bit more fun, even though I liked
it before. It is understandable, but I don&#8217;t like that I can&#8217;t go
to the arena right now&#8230; I am really strapped for cash and I
have a lot of upgrades I&#8217;d like to do. I think the narrator is a
really fun, cute little touch.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 20
Total time: 8:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/23/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I spent a lot of time trying to get the Hadouken today. I
eventually got it, but I find it almost impossible to use because
you need to be at full health. I got to the Spider in Sigma&#8217;s
fortress, but couldn&#8217;t get past it.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: 17 Miracles, directed by T.C. Christensen (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Movie--17-Miracles--directed-by-T-C--Christensen--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Movie&#8211;17-Miracles&#8211;directed-by-T-C&#8211;Christensen&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really nice movie. I felt like crying before the title
screen was even up. I cried a lot during the movie and found it
very uplifting. There were some problems with it&#8230; mainly that I
think a lot of assumes too much pre-existing knowledge about what
happened, rather than explaining it in the movie; particularly
with regard to the rescue. But it was an awesome movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game&#8211;Rhythm-Heaven-Fever&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got up to the Monkey Watch. I couldn&#8217;t even make it out of the
practice in it. Wow, I&#8217;m terrible.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game&#8211;Rayman-Origins&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another level and got all the stuff in it, although I
was one second from getting the time flag. It was just because I
thought I would land on the flag, but actually had to move to the
right. Urgh.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played again quite a lot today. I think all that is left is
Armored Armadillo and two heart tanks (before moving on to
Sigma&#8217;s fortress.) This game is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:34</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game today. I pre-ordered it and have been excited
about it since I heard that it would come out. I don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ve
ever really been an extremely &#8220;Sakaguchi&#8221; Final Fantasy fan&#8230; I
feel like I&#8217;ve responded more to Kitase&#8217;s direction, but
nevertheless, I enjoyed Blue Dragon and LOOOVED Lost Odyssey, so
I had high expectations for this game. But, after being let down
so bad so recently by Xenoblade, I was a little skeptical.</p>

<p>When I first turned it on, the first thing I noticed was that the
language is surprisingly crass. I think the very first sentence
has a swear. It&#8217;s not the worst curses, but it&#8217;s there and it was
a little jarring.</p>

<p>After that, I really enjoyed how the game started &#8220;in media
res&#8221;. You have a really immediate connection to the action and the
characters and they reveal themselves in a pretty nice and subdued
way. I think the voice acting is really good&#8230; especially
Syrene&#8217;s voice actress. She sounds very, very cool. In general,
all the characters strike me as really interesting and cool. The
&#8220;sweet&#8221; girl seems very sweet too, which I like.</p>

<p>At this point in the story (after chapter 6), I really like how
&#8220;low-key&#8221; the story is. Coming from Xenoblade where you fight
God, it&#8217;s nice to have a story that is much more low level and
intimate (at least at the beginning, who knows what will happen
in the end?)</p>

<p>When I first got to the tavern, I was kind of amazed by the unique
voice acting and animated interactions with the group. I was
worried that I had accidentally advanced the story when I was
trying to just wander around and talk to people.</p>

<p>I feel like the sub-quest system isn&#8217;t very good, because there&#8217;s
no list of who wants what from you. This is a place where
Xenoblade was clearly superior in the interface department, but
Last Story seems to be keeping you more connected with the
characters, at the expense of forgetting about them all together.</p>

<p>The equipment system is interesting. It seems like armor isn&#8217;t
really that important because they were all equal for me, but
they seem to have different status effects after they&#8217;ve been
upgraded. There seems to be an assumption that you will be
upgrading every item, rather than reserving upgrading for the end
(as many games, in fact, assume.)</p>

<p>I bought all the weapons and armor that I could in the first town
and maxed them all out (up to getting some sort of rare item that
would be required to progress them.)</p>

<p>The concept of &#8220;local goods&#8221; seems strange. I get the inkling
that you can do arbitrage to make money&#8230; sounds tedious. I hope
it isn&#8217;t necessary.</p>

<p>The clothing dying system is difficult for me to imagine how to
use effectively. I feel like I want to look online for a gallery
of cool colourings. The &#8220;invisible&#8221; option is very intriguing.</p>

<p>When I was exploring, I found the arena. Syrene&#8217;s dialogue about
it was awesome&#8230; so funny. I had a really hard time the first
time in the arena, because I had yet grasped the combat system. I
originally felt like I needed to be up next to enemies all the
time, but now I feel like it is more important to manage the
battlefield and setup sneak attacks, etc. I think I may also want
to turn on the &#8220;Manual&#8221; attack mode, because I think it will feel
better.</p>

<p>After I died and retried in the arena, I then played through the
first Season of the arena six more times. The combat system
is <em>really</em> <em>really</em> fun. I like it a lot and it was cool to just
go at it and feel the excitement of the mechanics. What an
awesome change from Xenoblade.</p>

<p>I moved on with the story after that and met Lisa&#8230; accidentally
tried to walk in on them in the bath and got some really funny
text. Then moved on to the next area. The boss in that area was
difficult to do properly, because I didn&#8217;t realize I could do a
Slash over the railing. I was trying to get the auto-attack to
happen and it never did before I got hosed. Once I realized that
I could Slash, it was cake and I learned more about the game.</p>

<p>From this experience, I can say that I really love this game play
so far and I&#8217;ve very excited to see where the story goes too.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 12
Total time: 4:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra, starring Channing Tatum (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--starring-Channing-Tatum--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie&#8211;G-I&#8211;Joe&#8211;The-Rise-of-Cobra&#8211;starring-Channing-Tatum&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool&#8230; although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking&#8230; I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear&#8230; and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game&#8211;Xenoblade-Chronicles&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I ended just before the final cut-off point to the final
bosses and end of the game. I finished the game today in about an
hour. Today as I started to play, I left the title screen on for a
while&#8230; it was very beautiful as the time of day changed.</p>

<p>I thought the end of the game was fun and crazy. It was so
incredibly Evangelion and so classically Japanese, like I said
before, but even more so given the ending&#8212;everyone you thought
was good is actually bad and everyone that was bad is really good,
and all that. I especially liked walking around in space and the
origin story given to Zanza. It was also neat how Dickson ended
up.</p>

<p>Total time: 26:36</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>In the end, I feel like this was a really interesting story and
world, but a pretty terrible game. The mechanics were just very
shallow and boring, lacking in meaningful choices. I think you
could do something with the concepts in the combat system, but
they didn&#8217;t really do it. One thing that I reckon WoW does that
this game lacks is that because you need to assemble large groups
with varied skills, there is an interesting meta-process of doing
that, but it is still ultimately boring for the individual
players.</p>

<p>I heard so much about how amazing this game was and how it was so
great that Japanese developers were learning from the West, but I
feel like all the Western ideas here are bad ideas that I don&#8217;t
want to see more of.</p>

<p>I really disliked that every item changed your appearance because
it was hard to look consistent while having the best
stats. Everyone just looked so stupid generally.</p>

<p>The interface was pretty terrible because it took so many clicks
to do everything and the buttons were reversed from what they
should be on the controller. Ugh.</p>

<p>I don&#8217;t think I can really recommend this game&#8230; maybe I would
just recommend watching some videos and reading about the story,
but I found the mechanics to be unbearably weak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
