<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T07:35:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight and beat the game. I just
took the Sigma levels really patiently. I filled up all my tanks
and energy after every encounter and used the charged C-Sting to
get invulnerability during the painful hallway after Vile in
Sigma 1. I was able to get to the final form of Sigma on one
life. Then it took about five or six tries to beat him, but
eventually I did it. I just needed to learn how to dodge
him. This was an awesome game. Loved it so bad.</p>

<p>My final password:</p>

<p>7437
6482
1256</p>

<p>Total time: 7:04</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gravity Rush (Vita, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/Game--Gravity-Rush--Vita--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/08/Game&#8211;Gravity-Rush&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about an hour and a half. I got my house
all set up and I did all the &#8220;recharging&#8221; missions around the
first area. The style of the game is really cool and the character
has a very cute personality, despite being the typical blank
slate. The world is really strange and the gap between normal
people and the main character is reminiscent of Bayonetta. The
mechanics are very satisfying&#8230; I feel like I&#8217;m Superman first
learning to fly. I will shoot myself up into the air, aim and then
shoot down to get somewhere. I don&#8217;t feel like I can aim fast
enough though, so I&#8217;m pretty bad at fighting and all the timed
challenges. I feel like the analog nubs on the Vita aren&#8217;t precise
or fast enough for me, but this feels a little bit too excusey and
I&#8217;ll probably get used to it as I play. It&#8217;s a fun little
game&#8230; definitely beautiful and innovative. If only I didn&#8217;t have
to ever touch the screen. I hate touching screens and getting my
fingerprints all over them. I just want them to stay pristine.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game&#8211;Rayman-Origins&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that life is too short to play games like Rayman Origins
when there are amazing games I haven&#8217;t played enough. So I&#8217;m
stopping. I did everything possible in the first world and
everything possible in the first half of the second world. The
horrible controls are not worth the adorable setting of the
game&#8230; unfortunately.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/06/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/06/Game&#8211;Castlevania&#8211;NES&#8211;1986&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today at the request of my kids. I got to the horrific
part in the second level where you are trying to get passed the
Medusa heads and platforming. The kids had a lot of fun before
that trying to play and attacking the ghouls &amp; bats. It was cute.</p>

<p>I think I will play it again.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 2.0 You Can (Not) Advance, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie--Evangelion--2-0-You-Can--Not--Advance--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie&#8211;Evangelion&#8211;2-0-You-Can&#8211;Not&#8211;Advance&#8211;by-Studio-Khara&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whereas the first Rebuild movie was almost exactly the same, but
with slightly different dialogue and scenes, but otherwise the
same, except for the technology. This movie was very
different&#8230; Mari is a whole new character&#8230; and the interactions
with Asuka and how she came were totally different. I really
enjoyed the changes, especially with Asuka. I thought the ending
was crazy and much clearer than the corresponding part in the
series. Although I&#8217;m kind of surprised that this is the point it
ends at&#8230; I feel like there can&#8217;t be two more movies worth of
content, but I&#8217;m excited to find out what there&#8217;s going to be
there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game&#8211;Rayman-Origins&#8211;PS3&#8211;2011&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half today. I did two chase
levels and a shmup level. There&#8217;s so much about this game that is
admirable: the music is cool, the level design is pretty neat,
the graphics are great. But man! The controls are SOOOOOOOOOO
bad. It&#8217;s like every level is the worst under-water level ever
from Mario. Rayman is just so slippery and hard to
control. Ugh. It makes me want to not play the game at all, but
I&#8217;m a masochist and can&#8217;t resist. I&#8217;ll definitely remove every of
Rayman game from my list though.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the game tonight in about an hour. I did the Miasma
Cave, the last Arena season, and the fight against Therius. It was
a very sweet ending. Overall, I think this is one of the strongest
stories out of an RPG I&#8217;ve played. The ending is a little bit
tropey, but not incredibly and it really justifies the things that
are tropes. I was really affected by the relationship between Zael
and Calista. It felt as real as a movie. I really loved this
game. The combat system was really fun and challenging. I think
the next time I play I&#8217;ll try not to get too powerful so the game
is a bit more challenging&#8230; but it was still good
anyways. Mistwalker keeps getting better and better.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 65
Total time: 30:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gal*Gun (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--Gal-Gun--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game&#8211;Gal-Gun&#8211;PS3&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I heard of this game online as a weird Japanese rail-shooter. I
like rail-shooters, but I find the zombie aesthetic to be pretty
boring. I thought it would be cute to have the girls/Cupid/love
thing going on in the game. I wasn&#8217;t let down in that regard, but
I found the gameplay to be very easy. I was able to clear one of
the girls in a very short period of time. I only had a hard time
with the &#8220;boss fights&#8221; because they all had different mechanics. I
really didn&#8217;t get what was going on with the book shelf
situation. I got a pretty good score on my first run, it said I
got 82% of the maximum or something and I got the &#8220;Good End&#8221;. But
it wasn&#8217;t really the sort of thing with a lot of interesting depth
to it&#8230; like Sin &amp; Punishment. This is kind of disappointing, but
I didn&#8217;t pay too much for the game.</p>

<p>I was slightly nervous that the game would be too scandalous but
it&#8217;s not bad at all. The girls are all normal anime girls and
there&#8217;s no cleavage or anything like that at all. The most racy it
gets is that the girl&#8217;s skirts rustle and sometimes it flash their
underwear for a moment. I was pleased that the girls in swimsuits
were wearing sports one-pieces, like they were properly on a swim
team.</p>

<p>I think my favourite part of the game were the animations and
sounds&#8230; particularly how when the girls get close, they give
the character an invitation or if they &#8220;attack&#8221; from far away
they shout something like &#8220;Love&#8221; or &#8220;Really Like You&#8221; and the
words are coming at you.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a totally bizarre game, but not very deep. I&#8217;m not sure how
its depth compares to something like Resident Evil: Umbrella
Chronicles, which is structurally identical but with a zombie
skin. But, Gal*Gun isn&#8217;t interesting enough for me to want to
play more than a few times.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I played for about an hour. I was surprised at how
quickly the new Jirall plot line was resolved. I was also very
sad that Calista was kidnapped. The game does a really good job
of making you feel really connected to and protective of
her. During the Jirall fight, I realized that I hadn&#8217;t seen
Dagran in a long time&#8230; where is he?</p>

<p>After we got home from the day, I played again, all night (about
four hours, with some breaks for snacks, etc.) I basically beat
the game and got to the epilogue. The final sequences had some
really tough fights. I fought the final boss three times before
winning. The final reveal of the big bad was pretty intense. I
really liked the epilogue sequence with Calista&#8217;s parents. It
seemed so appropriate for the couple to go on a little adventure
together before getting married. It&#8217;s adorable. Calista&#8217;s dress
was great too. I wish you could have her wear it during normal
gameplay. I feel like there&#8217;s still a lot of stuff to do in the
game&#8230; people to talk to, weapons to continue upgrading,
etc. It&#8217;s very strange. It&#8217;s like the final sequence of Earthbound
or Dragon Warrior but amped to the max because there&#8217;s so much to
do. It&#8217;s exciting.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48 -> 56 -> 64
Total time: 28:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Ice Age: Continental Drift (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie--Ice-Age--Continental-Drift--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie&#8211;Ice-Age&#8211;Continental-Drift&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took my son to the theatre to see this today. He really enjoyed
it. I thought there were definitely some funny parts too, although
overall the plot is incredibly weak. It&#8217;s very short and a kid&#8217;s
movie, so that&#8217;s understandable. In terms of plot, it&#8217;s basically
the same as an episode of a cartoon, but with longer scenes and big
events. I thought the finale of the Scrat subplot was awesome
though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I advanced the story quite a bit. I feel like I&#8217;m in the closing
stages: I&#8217;m going to fight Zangurak, then send the Outsider back,
and live happily ever after with Calista. I thought her wedding
dress was very cute and I liked the resolution of the wedding
plot. In the game play, there&#8217;s been a bit of a boss rush of sorts
where boss encounters similar to ones from earlier in the game
keep coming back. It&#8217;s fun though. The fight next to the Outside
was pretty exciting and difficult. That whole sequence going down
the tunnel was very difficult&#8212;I think I died three times.</p>

<p>I accidentally used the Auto-Equip feature and all my outfits
changed. It was very painful to go back to dressing all the girls
how I like.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48
Total time: 23:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;Punch-Out&#8212;-Wii&#8211;2009&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a few rounds today with the kids. I did pretty well
against Sandman&#8230; I&#8217;m getting better. But I still didn&#8217;t beat
him.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1988&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we&#8217;ve been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a short amount of time yesterday before going to
bed. I mainly just advanced the story. It turns out that Lavos is
behind Zael&#8217;s power and the destruction of the world. Bummer. I&#8217;m
excited about a cute wedding scene.</p>

<p>TODO Go back to the mysterious island and go behind the entrance
where the Lvl 40 Cave Cougars are.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played for a lot. A new arena season was opened, so I
had a lot of fun playing it over and over so I could max out all
my currently available items, etc. I did it like seven times. In
addition to that, I did some story missions, including the
haunted mansion. The best part of that was Horace&#8217;s ridiculous
comment about his wife afterwards. The stealth section escaping
from the castle was kind of odd, but worked as much as it needed
to. It was much better with Callista than with Zael alone. I&#8217;m
weirded out by Dagran being a sketch ball. I wonder where the
story is going. I presume that the Count is really the big bad in
some way, but maybe also I&#8217;ll fight &#8220;The Outsider&#8221;.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 1.0 You Are (Not) Alone, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie&#8211;Evangelion&#8211;1-0-You-Are&#8211;Not&#8211;Alone&#8211;by-Studio-Khara&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we got this from Netflix, my wife said &#8220;Ugh, Evangelion?&#8221; But
I think she enjoyed it. She commented on how the music was really
good and we were both impressed by the obviously better graphics
and effects. It is amazing how much is the same between this and
the originals though. I think it is already clearer what the
greater story is. I think there are more risque shots than before,
but, even so, they are quite tame. Not much to say other than that
I like Evangelion and this was preferred to watching the original
episodes. (Although I do miss the theme song.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a lot today as I rested from being sick. There some
pretty memorable moments: I loved the joke about why one family
had been in charge of guarding the forbidden gate for so long. I
was a bit disappointed that I wasn&#8217;t able to say &#8220;No&#8221; to the
Count or console Callista&#8230; the romantic comedy structure is
really being forced on me. I find the establishment of Mirania as
this character with a weird &#8220;food&#8221; quirk to be pretty
hilarious. I&#8217;m still really enjoying this game.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 36
Total time: 15:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Castlevania 4 (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--Super-Castlevania-4--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;Super-Castlevania-4&#8211;SNES&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed this game to my son and got to block 3-2 on one
continue. I died once on Medusa, because I had been sloppy
earlier in the level and then the rest of the deaths came from
bad platforming (mostly swinging) in the last level. My son was
getting annoyed and kept asking me to kill myself so we could do
something else. Nice :)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/25/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-X1&#8211;SNES&#8211;1993&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got past Vile, but had a heck of a time getting up the wall with
the flying platformers&#8230; it was so painful. I feel like I&#8217;m
really letting my kids down when they watch me and expect
awesomeness.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:23</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/24/Game&#8211;The-Last-Story&#8211;Wii&#8211;2012&#8211;2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours and got back to the town. I
find it very charming how much this story is like Aladdin or a
romantic comedy. It was also neat how there was a monster
summoning spot right before a boss fight, almost like if you were
having trouble you could grind there, because the game is
normally very closed and linear. It&#8217;s a neat structure.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 25
Total time: 10:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
