<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-20T22:46:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game&#8211;Super-Meat-Boy&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another night of 5-19X. This level makes me hate the game.</p>

<p>Super Meat Boy is great when (a) a level has really good flow and
(b) the challenges are bite-sized, so that when you fail you don&#8217;t
have to repeat long sequences of difficulty stuff.</p>

<p>Normal games can&#8217;t be as hard as Super Meat Boy because they are
committed to long levels and don&#8217;t give instant, infinite
respawns.</p>

<p>This level (and a few other levels) totally break the design of
the game. There are basically 5 totally independent challenges
that have nothing to do with one another and almost all of the
require you to stop moving and dodge, rather than having a flow
from one thing to the next.</p>

<p>(My point here is that a reductive
view of this issue would say that every jump is a unique
challenge. The difference is that running down a hallway in SMB is
a single coherent challenge because you must have the right flow
and tempo.)</p>

<p>Super Meat Boy is a great game when it is fulfilling its design
goals, but when it forgets them&#8230; it is horrifically bad.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game&#8211;Kid-Icarus&#8211;NES&#8211;1986&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this tonight. Last time I played, I could barely
get past the first level because it is so brutal and you need to
grind, but it&#8217;s practically impossible. This time, I tried to use
a code that gave more hearts per heart icon you got, but it didn&#8217;t
really help. I used a password that gave me more levels and that
made a big difference. The hardest part of the game was the third
fortress, because it was so complex of a labyrinth. It&#8217;s a fun
game&#8230; a little too floaty jumps and the inability to scroll
backward is bit rough, but for an old game it has pretty decent
mechanics. Although it is a classic in my memory, it&#8217;s systems
don&#8217;t live up to being a real classic.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Green Lantern: Emerald Knights, by D.C. Comics (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/19/Movie--Green-Lantern--Emerald-Knights--by-D-C--Comics--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/19/Movie&#8211;Green-Lantern&#8211;Emerald-Knights&#8211;by-D-C&#8211;Comics&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw this movie advertised at the beginning of another and it
seemed pretty neat. The mythology of the Green Lantern world is
pretty cool (based on my knowledge from the live action movie) so
we decided to get it on Netflix. It was pretty bad. The plot is so
weak and most of the stories are tiny facades around a big fight
scene. The fight scenes aren&#8217;t even that interesting, because the
rings are just used as laser cannons. One of the coolest things
about the Green Lanterns is their ability to make anything with
the ring, but that wasn&#8217;t utilized very well. Overall, this was a
very disappointing movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I used Amy exclusively and
beat the third challenge. I did really good on the third full
course tournament&#8230; until the 13th hole when I went from first to
last place by the end. Ouch.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game&#8211;Hot-Shots-Golf&#8211;World-Invitational&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about twenty minutes. I bought Amy and tried to do
the third challenge again. I ran out of batteries before I could
finish though.</p>

<p>Total time: 10:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Skyfall, starring Daniel Craig (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Skyfall--starring-Daniel-Craig--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie&#8211;Skyfall&#8211;starring-Daniel-Craig&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I saw this tonight [which is why I wanted to write down
my thoughts about the other ones.] I found a lot about this movie a
lot better than QoS. I thought the movie was paced a lot better and
the new characters were quite interesting. On the other hand, there
wasn&#8217;t really an deep connections. Even the deepest connection
(between M and 007) wasn&#8217;t developed much. In addition, the goal of
the villain wasn&#8217;t at a very big scale. He was almost Bane or
Joker-ish in his abilities, but had a trivial revenge scheme
planned. There were lots of holes and missed opportunities&#8212;why
not just blow up MI6 when M was there if he wanted to kill her so
bad? Why was Severine with the guy getting killed? Why would
Patrice be necessarily working for the same guy twice? Severine&#8217;s
death was totally ignored and Bond doesn&#8217;t even acknowledge it
happens. The island is a wasted set. The best parts are the
committee hearing and the showdown at Skyfall.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Quantum of Solace, starring Daniel Craig (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Quantum-of-Solace--starring-Daniel-Craig--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie&#8211;Quantum-of-Solace&#8211;starring-Daniel-Craig&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a much more traditional Bond movie, with a ridiculous and
large scale evil plot. I felt like the feel of the movie was a lot
different and that the beginning is much better and tighter than
the end. There are lots of bombshells in the movie, but they dwell
on Bond&#8217;s ability to conquest a bit less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Casino Royale, starring Daniel Craig (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie&#8211;Casino-Royale&#8211;starring-Daniel-Craig&#8211;2006&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is such an amazing movie. The whole story-arc of Vesper is so
powerful and heart-breaking. The first half of the film has so
many super high energy exciting parts&#8230; like the opening and the
airport. The film has lots of great lines and funny parts&#8230; like
at the country club and between Bond and Vesper. This is really great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Brothers Bloom, directed by Rian Johnson (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Movie--The-Brothers-Bloom--directed-by-Rian-Johnson--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Movie&#8211;The-Brothers-Bloom&#8211;directed-by-Rian-Johnson&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun caper movie. The story is very complicated and has
lots of twists, in a way that reminiscent of Ocean&#8217;s Eleven, but
with more off-the-wall occurrences. I feel like there were a lot
of things that should have been explained, because they would have
been very interesting, that weren&#8217;t. For example, how Penelope
manages to get out of Prague. In general though, after about the
first third, the characters (which beforehand were fascinating)
all have their identities fixed and then they never change. We
learn a lot about Penelope in the beginning, but then she&#8217;s
static. Similarly, the ending just doesn&#8217;t feel right given what
we know about the character&#8217;s feelings. Nevertheless, it was a
unique and cute movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game&#8211;Sin&#8212;Punishment&#8211;Star-Successor&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for another 20 minutes. I got the boss down to
about 750&#8230; much better than I&#8217;ve done before. Before the X-RGB
I hadn&#8217;t got past 1500; after the X-RGB I got to 1200, and today
I did even better. I feel like the end is in sight.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: ESPgaluda II: Black Label (X360, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game--ESPgaluda-II--Black-Label--X360--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game&#8211;ESPgaluda-II&#8211;Black-Label&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played a run today and did really well on the first stage, but
got brutalized in the second stage. I died during the tank rush
after the mid-boss. I like this game.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 3 - The Reichenbach Fall]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-3---The-Reichenbach-Fall-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock&#8212;Season-2&#8212;Episode-3&#8212;The-Reichenbach-Fall-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a CRAZY episode. The whole plot line is pretty cool and
exciting, but I kind of wish there was more in it. For example,
Holmes doesn&#8217;t defend himself at all, but it would great for him
to do so. I loved that he was in contempt of court, but we don&#8217;t
know what he said. There were lots of clever moments like that. I
loved the way Moriarty explained that social engineering is more
effective than hacking. I thought the ending was far too obvious,
especially with regard to Holmes enlisting Molly&#8217;s help. In that
respect it is obvious, but on the other hand it is ridiculous
that there&#8217;s going to be an explanation for how he survived,
tricked the people at morgue (presumably Molly just did it?),
etc. I&#8217;m a bit pessimistic about where the show will go from
here. The ending is so &#8220;Mission Impossible&#8221; in its incredulity,
that I could imagine Moriarty not really being dead too. The show
has upped the stakes so much, it seems like they can&#8217;t really go
back to pedestrian plots.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 2 - The Hounds of Baskerville]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-2---The-Hounds-of-Baskerville-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock&#8212;Season-2&#8212;Episode-2&#8212;The-Hounds-of-Baskerville-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very interesting episode. I liked that it was a
&#8220;monster of the week&#8221; kind of episode and not an episode about
the epic story. It was neat that the interpersonal story of
James and Sherlock was explored so much as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Game&#8211;Akumajou-Dracula-X&#8211;Chi-No-Rondo&#8211;TG-16-CD&#8211;1993&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for almost three hours and beat the game. I beat
levels 6, 7, and 8 as Maria. Then, I beat 8 as Richter. Then I
beat 4&#8217; as Richter to get to 5&#8217;. I did 5&#8217; as Maria (and continued
on to beat the game on the same continue.)</p>

<p>When I finally beat Dracula as Richter, I wasn&#8217;t hit at all in his
human form, but was hit just once in his giant man-bat form (by
the blue energy wave, that I think you are supposed to duck
under.)</p>

<p>This is a very satisfying game to beat. I will definitely
continue playing it in the future&#8230; especially since I invested
in a PC Engine to be able to play it. It&#8217;s a blast.</p>

<p>Although&#8230; I&#8217;m annoyed that I only have 96% completion on the
save screen&#8230; despite having done everything in the game. I&#8217;m not
sure what I&#8217;m supposed to do to bring it to 100%.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 1 - A Scandal in Belgravia]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-1---A-Scandal-in-Belgravia-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Sherlock&#8212;Season-2&#8212;Episode-1&#8212;A-Scandal-in-Belgravia-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun episode. I liked the beginning and the montage of
sleuthing, especially the references to Holmes stories and how it
ended up being relevant for the larger story. The concept behind
The Woman was interesting and different, but I feel like time
moved way to quickly in this episode. It seems like almost 2
years of time passed, because the year they&#8217;re texting, there&#8217;s
the six months she&#8217;s pretending to be dead, the months after the
break down, plus the two months she&#8217;s actually dead, etc. It&#8217;s a
bit unreasonable, because the time table of the earlier episodes
seemed much faster pace. I thought the advancement of some of
the extra characters was fun: Watson&#8217;s girlfriends (although we
barely get a hint of why he&#8217;d be failing in love) and Molly. I
hope Sherlock shows Molly some love. This is a fun show, but I
get the impression that I&#8217;ll be very annoyed that there won&#8217;t be
any closure in the sixth episode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--10/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Game&#8211;Sin&#8212;Punishment&#8211;Star-Successor&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about 20 minutes tonight. I used the X-RGB with the
Wii to get the input lag done. It seemed to make a difference,
because I improved my performance in such a short time. This is so
tough. I can&#8217;t wait to beat it and go back to playing this game
on an easier and more enjoyable difficulty.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Arthur, starring Russel Brand (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie--Arthur--starring-Russel-Brand--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie&#8211;Arthur&#8211;starring-Russel-Brand&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a cute movie with a pretty unique plot. The main girl was
cute and wholesome. I feel like the ending was a bit empty though,
because other than going to AA there was no explanation of how
Arthur changed. Th end of the movie suggested that Arthur&#8217;s only
problem was that he drank a lot (and perhaps having so many
resources exacerbated the impact of that), but didn&#8217;t deal at all
with his lack of knowledge, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game&#8211;Akumajou-Dracula-X&#8211;Chi-No-Rondo&#8211;TG-16-CD&#8211;1993&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the morning, we played for about a half hour and beat level 4&#8217;
via the secret route&#8212;beating Camilla&#8212;but not getting to 5&#8217;. I
started on stage 5 a bit, but was pretty beat down.</p>

<p>Later, I played for about an hour and a half and beat
stage 5. Eventually I was able to use the watch to get through up
to Death without getting hit at all&#8230; by pausing the action just
before the large green monsters. Sometimes this game seems totally
impossible and brutalizing. The key seems to always be using the
sub-weapons effectively and breaking the challenges. Or, learning
pitch perfect timing and getting through unscathed&#8230; but mostly
doing the sub-weapons just right. It&#8217;s a fascinating design.</p>

<p>After I mastered that, it took about 7 tries to kill Death. I
stuck with the Cross. I used an Item Crash early and pummeled
him. I dodged the huge skulls by staying to the left and
right. The melee fight was pure stick-and-move. It is so
satisfying to win at this game.</p>

<p>After Death was dead, I fought the Vampire Bat and was killed
Medusa in the Boss rush stage. I decided to go back and fight
Camilla again, because supposedly you need to beat Death to get
the secret exit&#8230; but no luck.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 1 - Episode 3 - The Great Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-3---The-Great-Game-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-3&#8212;The-Great-Game-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really fascinating episode. I liked how there were
some many subplots and little stories. I think the Moriarty
character is really cool, but I thought the actor wasn&#8217;t a good
choice. I expected someone older and more menacing
looking. Instead, this guy looks like an angry bully
kid. Hopefully as we see him more, he&#8217;ll look more the part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 1 - Episode 2 - The Blind Banker]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-2---The-Blind-Banker-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-2&#8212;The-Blind-Banker-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a neat episode, although I think the details of the
crime was not as interesting. Watching Sherlock be Sherlock was
very fun and I thought the introduction of the Sara character
was cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
