<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T22:04:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-5&#8211;Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat the game today. (Although I used a 4x EXP and GOLD cheat so
I didn&#8217;t have to grind. Luckily it did not make the game easy
really, it just saved time.) It was very cool. I like how
heart-warming and family-oriented the game is. It is also neat how
you go a grand tour of the world so you can revisit everyone. This
has been my favourite DQ so far. I really liked 4 a lot, but I
think this one was incredible. I almost want to say they&#8217;re just
getting better, but I know that 9 is not as good as this.</p>

<p>Near the end of the game I developed an awesome strategy: have my
wife use the Sage Stone every round; use the main character and my
son to attack; and then use my daughter to buff/debuff and use
staves for other effects, including healing. It worked awesome.</p>

<p>Total time: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 1 - Episode 3 - Episode Three]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Downton-Abbey---Season-1---Episode-3---Episode-Three-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-3&#8212;Episode-Three-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This episode was appalling! I can&#8217;t believe that Mary would
really act that way, especially when her virtue had just been
established beforehand. This seems like a case of modern writers
putting modern loose morals into the past inappropriately. I do
find it very believable that Matthew would be more attracted to
Mary when he was ignored. I wonder if we are to believe that
something sinister is behind the Turk&#8217;s death?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/16/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/16/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-5&#8211;Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a little more than three hours tonight as I watched
some YouTube videos. I made a lot of progress and had a lot of
fun. I got my wife back. It is really fun to have the whole family
together in the party now&#8230; even though my wife is much weaker
than the other party members. I&#8217;d like to keep her in just for
fun. There were some more adorable puns in the last section. I get
the feeling I&#8217;m basically done with the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 19:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Sherlock Holmes: A Game of Shadows, starring Robert Downey, Jr. (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/Movie--Sherlock-Holmes--A-Game-of-Shadows--starring-Robert-Downey--Jr---2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/Movie&#8211;Sherlock-Holmes&#8211;A-Game-of-Shadows&#8211;starring-Robert-Downey&#8211;Jr&#8212;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an interesting movie. The whole plot is really loose and a
bit lifeless compared to the first. It improves a lot towards the
end. The beginning just feels like lots of stupid moments for
Downey to do his thing. It&#8217;s funny of in this universe Holmes is
this weird kung-fu master guy. There&#8217;s lots of really cool effects
and moments that I enjoyed in the movie though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-5&#8211;Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had to wait around for a long time today, so I played for about
40 minutes. It took me a while to figure out what I needed to
do. I thought I couldn&#8217;t use at the flying carpet because at first
it said I couldn&#8217;t use it (because I was on a forest square). That
was annoying. I got the Magma Staff and now I&#8217;ll try to get to the
fallen Zenithian Castle. I like how this game has so many
references to the last one.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 1 - Episode 2 - Episode Two]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Downton-Abbey---Season-1---Episode-2---Episode-Two-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-2&#8212;Episode-Two-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was fun. It felt like an example of what all the episodes
will be like because it had a very well scoped out plot. It was
interesting how they were able to communicate Matthew&#8217;s distaste
for aristocracy, but his partial acceptance of it at the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-5&#8211;Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I&#8217;ve been taking a
break from games as I catch up on some work. I went up to the part
in the game where you are reunited with your kids after being a
statue and are looking for your wife. It was a really cool
sequence to be stone and then meet your kids. This game is just
sooo adorable.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Dark Knight Rises, directed by Christopher Nolan (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie--The-Dark-Knight-Rises--directed-by-Christopher-Nolan--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie&#8211;The-Dark-Knight-Rises&#8211;directed-by-Christopher-Nolan&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cool movie. I thought they did a great job setting
up Cat Woman and Blake as interesting characters. I liked all the
tragedy and doubt that was part of the plot&#8230; it made it more
dramatic. It&#8217;s also cool how they incorporated the
Bane-destroys-Batman storyline from the comic. All around there was
cool stuff. I&#8217;m glad that they allowed the ending to really be an
ending.</p>

<p>My only complaint is that Bane&#8217;s voice was a little too hard to
understand in a few key moments&#8230; it made me want subtitles, which
of course you can&#8217;t have in a theatre.</p>

<p>Despite Nolan&#8217;s insistence that the movie is not anti-Occupy, I
think it very much is. It shows the commies for what they really
are: blood-thirsty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game&#8211;The-Legend-of-Zelda&#8211;Link-to-the-Past&#8211;SNES&#8211;1991&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago&#8230; I forget when&#8230; we played again, beat the first
temple and got some items in the world. My son really enjoys
watching it.</p>

<p>Today we played up to the boss in the Tower of Hera, but were
totally creamed. It is tough. I keep getting knocked off and then
his health is reset.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Lockout, starring Guy Pearce (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie&#8211;Lockout&#8211;starring-Guy-Pearce&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun, fast-paced action movie. I liked how the world of
the future was very different, but there was no explanation of why
or how or in what way. It just looked really foreign, which was
pretty cool. The two lead villains were very crazy and
interesting. The main character, Snow, was very wise-cracking and
fun. Overall, the movie was a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Downton Abbey - Season 1 - Episode 1 - Episode One]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/08/Downton-Abbey---Season-1---Episode-1---Episode-One-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/08/Downton-Abbey&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-1&#8212;Episode-One-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve been hearing a lot about this show and my wife was very
interested in it. Normally I try to stay away from shows that are
not completed, but I made an exception because she was so
interested.</p>

<p>The first episode was very cool. They&#8217;ve laid out a lot of thick
plot and interesting characters. I quite like it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Muppets, starring Jason Segel (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie&#8211;The-Muppets&#8211;starring-Jason-Segel&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a hilarious movie with lots of really subtle and clever
moments. It&#8217;s really amazing and hard to express all the crazy,
funny things in it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game&#8211;The-Legend-of-Zelda&#8211;Link-to-the-Past&#8211;SNES&#8211;1991&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought my son might like this game, given how much he enjoyed
watching the beginning of Castlevania: SOTN. I also thought he
might be willing to play it because the controls are simpler. I
was right. He really enjoyed watching the beginning and then all
of sudden he said, &#8220;Dad, how do you move? How do you attack? Can I
try?&#8221; He explored the world a little and fought some enemies. He
started getting frustrated because he kept dying. His problem was
that he wouldn&#8217;t move away from enemies when they came to attack
him. He would swing his sword while the enemies were on top of him
and this killed him eventually.</p>

<p>We got to the boss of the first temple, but I died during the
stomping part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game&#8211;Mega-Man-3&#8211;NES&#8211;1990&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The kids and I played this for a bit today. We did Needle Man and
couldn&#8217;t do enough damage to the boss. Then we did Top Man, and
won. Then we did Hard Man (couldn&#8217;t get past the second monkey)
and Gemini Man and then they got bored so we switched to a different
game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dear John, starring Channing Tatum (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie&#8211;Dear-John&#8211;starring-Channing-Tatum&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was suggested by Netflix and I wasn&#8217;t sure I would like
it. As we watched it, it was pretty cute and touching. It was very
reminiscent of how my wife and I were when we first met&#8230; fell in
love over the course of 10 days and then didn&#8217;t see each for
months. I was really surprised when she dumped him and then years
and years past&#8230; it was a very depressing and unhappy ending.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Avengers, directed by Joss Whedon (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie&#8211;The-Avengers&#8211;directed-by-Joss-Whedon&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a great movie. Every character was very exciting and they
did a great job spreading out the interesting scenes for the
different characters. The only characters that weren&#8217;t totally
awesome were Hawkeye and Black Widow, because they weren&#8217;t really
super heroes&#8230; more &#8220;super spys&#8221; and that didn&#8217;t seem to fit as
well. Also, I thought Hawkeye was a bit too shallow of a
character&#8230; the actor played him too &#8220;cool&#8221; and above-it-all.</p>

<p>There were some awesome jokes and funny moments. One of my
favourites was when Captain America, reacting to hearing that Thor
and Loki are gods, says, &#8220;Ma&#8217;am, there&#8217;s only one God, and I don&#8217;t
think He dresses like that.&#8221; Not only was it delivered really well,
but it&#8217;s such a great comment for his character as the epitome of
America.</p>

<p>Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk was great too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Night Lights - Season 1 - Episode 2 - Eyes Wide Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-2---Eyes-Wide-Open-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-2&#8212;Eyes-Wide-Open-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were curious how much of the documentary-style of the pilot
would continue to the show. It is very similar. I&#8217;m surprised
that in this episode they didn&#8217;t show a football game. I get the
impression that every episode will be one week of time,
culminating in the game.</p>

<p>The &#8220;rally girl&#8221; thing was funny. And it was very sweet when
Jason got his treat even though he wasn&#8217;t playing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Night Lights - Season 1 - Episode 1 - Pilot]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-1---Pilot-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-1&#8212;Pilot-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife has been wanting to watch this show for a while, based on
the recommendation of her good friend. I can&#8217;t think of that many
things that I care less about than football, so I&#8217;ve been
dragging my feet about watching it.</p>

<p>I found the first episode to be interesting. It is very
predictable in the plot development. The characters mostly play
to type, but they have a very real quality to them&#8230; like they
could be real people out there in a world that I know nothing
about (Texas, and Football.)</p>

<p>I really like the movie Varsity Blues and this is very
reminiscent of it. The small-town quaintness is cute and it is
interesting to learn about something I know nothing about.</p>

<p>I was very disappointed that no character in the show expressed
the idea that Jason&#8217;s sacrifice was not worth it and that one
game or football itself is not worth ruining your life
over. Hopefully that will come up later.</p>

<p>I very much like the amount of faith in the show.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Jane Eyre, starring Mia Wasikowska (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie--Jane-Eyre--starring-Mia-Wasikowska--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie&#8211;Jane-Eyre&#8211;starring-Mia-Wasikowska&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;d never read Jane Eyre before, but didn&#8217;t have very big
expectations for this movie. It was very well done and pretty
fascinating. I found the story to go very slowly and have a really
unpredictable structure. I expected to learn more about the
boarding school, but did not. I expected to learn more about her
job after meeting the Rivers, but did not. It seemed like it was
going to be a horror story before the old wife is revealed. After
getting through my expectations, it was very enjoyable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game&#8211;Dragon-Quest-5&#8211;Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride&#8211;DS&#8211;2008&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a long drive today, so I played for almost four hours. I&#8217;ve
had lots of cute experiences in the game. I really like the towns
in this game&#8230; they feel much more fleshed out and real than
towns in most RPGs. I decided to marry Deborah because I think her
sprite is really cool and I thought she&#8217;d be funny. So far she has
been really hilarious with all her little comments. I like it a
lot. The wedding voes were really funny because they said &#8220;until
you stop getting resurrected at church when you die&#8221; instead of
&#8220;until death do you part&#8221;&#8230; thus acknowledging that the
characters really do die and get resurrected in the story. It was
really funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
