<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T23:19:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phineas and Ferb - Season 1 - Episode 4 - Are You My Mummy? / Flop Starz]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Phineas-and-Ferb---Season-1---Episode-4---Are-You-My-Mummy----Flop-Starz-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Phineas-and-Ferb&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-4&#8212;Are-You-My-Mummy&#8212;-Flop-Starz-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Flop Starz was so funny because it was so true.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap (SMS, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game&#8211;Wonder-Boy-III&#8211;The-Dragon-s-Trap&#8211;SMS&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a bit. It&#8217;s definitely better than the
last one. It seems a lot more deep and complex. It&#8217;s got this
non-linear-ness to it which is interesting, but the controls are
still pretty sloppy. There were many times when I just couldn&#8217;t
line up with an enemy and it was on top of me doing damage every
time it was possible. I&#8217;m still hopeful for the next sequel. But
this game doesn&#8217;t do it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario Land (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Super-Mario-Land--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game&#8211;Super-Mario-Land&#8211;GB&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for one run of about ten minutes. I got to 1-3. I
could very easily tell that this game was a novelty of its day:
Mario in Portable form! Today, there&#8217;s no reason to play
this. It&#8217;s not like it&#8217;s bad&#8230; but the limitations of the Game
Boy are way too awkward to really enjoy it. There are some cool
things though, such as the rolling boulders and the different
enemy types, but there&#8217;s no reason to play this when you&#8217;re at
home (or even with the hand-held options that are available
today.)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy Legend (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game&#8211;Final-Fantasy-Legend&#8211;GB&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half-hour. I was a Human Female,
Human Male, Mutant Female, and Human Male. I sold my Saber, bought
some armor and went out to fight. It took the whole thirty minutes
to be able to afford one more piece of armor. I went out to fight
again and got into a fight with a Red Bull, during the course of
the fight, all my weapons broke and two of my characters died,
then the monster fled, so I didn&#8217;t get to kill and didn&#8217;t get any
gold. Now I don&#8217;t have the money to replace the weapons or revive
the fallen characters. This game seems like it will be nothing
but Kawazu brutalization and grinding. No thank you.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Bugs Bunny in The Crazy Castle (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game&#8211;Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle&#8211;GB&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for almost an hour tonight. It is brilliant in
its simple setup, but complex puzzles. The controls are
horrible&#8212;you can&#8217;t turn in mid-step, you can&#8217;t stop on stairs,
and you don&#8217;t always use a special attack when you think you
will. The graphics are horrific. The music is about 4 notes
repeated. But nevertheless, it&#8217;s a really addicting and satisfying
game. It&#8217;s neat that you can watch replays of your last
attempt. This game is very similar to Lolo-style games, but
different enough that it feels unique. I was very impressed.</p>

<p>On the Game Boy, apparently it has 80 levels, and I did 31. I
think I burnt myself out on it in the one sitting I did. I will
definitely play this again, and probably pick up where I was
before, but I&#8217;ll mark it as done because I think I understand the
game pretty thoroughly and (like the Crush games) I can&#8217;t really
binge on it.</p>

<p>Stage 31: XPAZ</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phineas and Ferb - Season 1 - Episode 3 - The Magnificent Few / S'Winter]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb---Season-1---Episode-3---The-Magnificent-Few---S-Winter-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-3&#8212;The-Magnificent-Few&#8212;S-Winter-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Western themed one wasn&#8217;t as good as the past ones, but the
S&#8217;Winter one was pretty funny. Especially when Candace wins the
Limbo.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phineas and Ferb - Season 1 - Episode 2 - The Fast and the Phineas / Lawn Gnome Beach Party of Terror]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb---Season-1---Episode-2---The-Fast-and-the-Phineas---Lawn-Gnome-Beach-Party-of-Terror-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-2&#8212;The-Fast-and-the-Phineas&#8212;Lawn-Gnome-Beach-Party-of-Terror-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought the memory of Doof&#8217;s childhood as a lawn gnome was
priceless.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Phineas and Ferb - Season 1 - Episode 1 - Rollercoaster / Candace Loses Her Head]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb---Season-1---Episode-1---Rollercoaster---Candace-Loses-Her-Head-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Phineas-and-Ferb&#8212;Season-1&#8212;Episode-1&#8212;Rollercoaster&#8212;Candace-Loses-Her-Head-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These episodes are great. One of the memorable gags was Parry
needing to go back to the house through the tubes&#8230; getting in
traffic&#8230; and then having to go back. Also, the snakes part of
the rollercoaster was crazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy in Monster Land (SMS, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game&#8211;Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land&#8211;SMS&#8211;1987&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour today. I used an emulator and
couldn&#8217;t resist save states. In the beginning, I worked my way
through on my own, using saves at each screen. I had no sense of
what the items would do, so I didn&#8217;t really buy any. After a
while, I looked at a walkthrough (which basically just recommended
which items to buy) and learned that I missed a few essential
hidden items. I restarted and made it to stage 4 following the
guide. I went away to eat, paused, and when I came back, the game
had reset itself.</p>

<p>This game looks and sounds really good, especially for its
age. It&#8217;s cute and has some interesting mechanics. I think of it
as a lot like Zelda 2, but with a less interesting combat system,
sloppier mechanics, and a more advanced inventory system. I found
the jumps to feel really wrong and the combat delays to be pretty
painful. The inventory system, once you realize what things are,
is neat.</p>

<p>Overall, I&#8217;d say that this is a pretty amazing game for its age,
but that a lot about it works against it. The biggest problem is
the lack of continues. The game is too deep on a customization
level to make sense as an arcade game. I presume that later
version of the game change this, because they were designed for
consoles. Secondly, the sprites are a bit too big and they make
it hard to see what&#8217;s going on. Third, the jumps and fighting
don&#8217;t feel quite right.</p>

<p>I won&#8217;t play this, but I&#8217;m excited to investigate other games in
this series.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game&#8211;Super-Meat-Boy&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played a few runs of 5-19X. No progress.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:55</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game&#8211;Ikaruga&#8211;X360&#8211;2008&#8211;6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about twenty minutes to show my dad some of the Dot
Eater techniques I needed to master.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:26</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Devil's Crush (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game&#8211;Devil-s-Crush&#8211;TG16&#8211;1990&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like Alien Crush, this game is a very exciting and interesting
pinball table. I feel like this game is a lot crazier because
after the initial ideas in Alien Crush, they were able to go all
out. There&#8217;s lots moving around on the course, there&#8217;s three
layers, and many complicated dependencies between
pieces. In that sense, it&#8217;s much better. Plus, they added a
pass-the-controller 2-player option, which is pretty neat.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the ball physics feel much worse and the ball seems
totally outside of your control. I think part of it is that the
board is broken into three screens and each one is squatter (and
thus more detailed) than any screen was in Alien Crush. At the end
of the day, the game feels worse, despite looking much cooler.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I could imagine playing this game a lot&#8230; if not
for the interface friction.</p>

<p>When I played, my dad and I did the pass-the-controller for a
bit. My best score was 3.7 mil. I got this by getting the castle
on the bottom and then just being super cautious whenever I was
on the bottom screen. It worked like a charm!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Alien Crush (TG16, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Alien-Crush--TG16--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game&#8211;Alien-Crush&#8211;TG16&#8211;1988&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while today on an emulator. This game is
gorgeous and amazingly detailed. I love the &#8220;living&#8221; board
concept and it works really well. The hit detection on the bottom
on the paddles seems a bit off, but it&#8217;s not too hard to get used
to.</p>

<p>I got a 1.3 mil score and my dad got 4.7 mil. It was fun to pass
the game back and forth. But, for me, there&#8217;s not enough of a
carrot to chase after, because I don&#8217;t really have a good concept
of what scores are possible and most of my deaths felt random &amp;
weren&#8217;t learning experiences.</p>

<p>I enjoy the game a lot, although I&#8217;m not sure how much I
like <em>this</em> game and how much I just like pinball. In any case,
the problem with the game is the amount of friction it takes to
setup and play for how long would be optimal. I can imagine
playing this for 10 minutes at a time, but it would take at least
5 to get everything ready to play it. This game (with what is
available today to be entertained with) needs some external
scheduling and a speedy front-end.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (13)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--12/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Sin&#8212;Punishment&#8211;Star-Successor&#8211;Wii&#8211;2010&#8211;12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played about five or six rounds today. I got him down to 797
but did pretty miserably every other time.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: River City Ransom (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--River-City-Ransom--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;River-City-Ransom&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while tonight and destroyed it. I&#8217;ve played
this many many times with other people&#8230; like my friends when I
was young, my brother, my wife, my dad, etc. But I&#8217;ve never
actually beat it, perhaps because we could never have the patience
and time to actually go through the whole thing. This time, it
was pretty simple to do. I just got Dragon Feet, and lined myself
up to hit the bosses after they were downed. The main problem is
the twins and the random hit you get on you as you&#8217;re traveling
through the map. The game play mechanics in this game feel really
really good, but it&#8217;s really broken because you can abuse it so
much. I&#8217;ll definitely play this in the future in co-op, but I
don&#8217;t think it&#8217;s strong enough to last on its own&#8230; but then
again, it&#8217;s has a fun flow to it; like I can just roll through a
few levels of Mega Man 2.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mushihime-sama Futari (X360, 2009) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Mushihime-sama-Futari--X360--2009--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Mushihime-sama-Futari&#8211;X360&#8211;2009&#8211;4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played a round tonight&#8230; I did really good against the stage 2
boss, but died early in stage 2 and twice in stage 3 (before the
mid-boss.)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gravity Rush (Vita, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Gravity-Rush--Vita--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Gravity-Rush&#8211;Vita&#8211;2012&#8211;3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been about a month since I&#8217;ve played this game and I&#8217;m not
really interested in trying it again. It&#8217;s a cute concept and the
world is pretty interesting, but the controls and gameplay just
aren&#8217;t compelling enough to last much longer than I&#8217;ve
played. It&#8217;s too imprecise and the touch controls are
obnoxious. I almost feel like if this game were on PS3 I would
enjoy it a lot more. It also has a Portal-esque quality to it in
the way you move around (there aren&#8217;t gravity puzzles, as far as
I&#8217;ve seen.)</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 2 (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-2--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Final-Fantasy-2&#8211;NES&#8211;1988&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for two and half hours. I found it unbearable. I
couldn&#8217;t find any codes, so I decided to use the exploits with
canceling commands. That was actually a bad idea because it meant
I couldn&#8217;t effectively do the &#8220;hit yourself&#8221; trick to get HP and
MP. The next big problem was that I couldn&#8217;t do that because I
didn&#8217;t have enough money to pay for the inn to heal after I used
all my MP. The thing that is so annoying about this game is that
you don&#8217;t feel like you&#8217;re getting anything from battles. At
least in Dragon Quest, you are making progress. In this, I feel
like I was either cheating or wasting my time. In the average
random battle, I would barely make 10 GP, but I needed around 100
to 200 to use the inn and then over 400 to pay for a spell. I&#8217;m
curious about the story, but I&#8217;ll have to play one of the
re-releases that put in a traditional experience system.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Duck-Tales&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today and gave it another chance. This time, it was a
total breeze. I did die in the Amazon after spending $300k, which
was really painful, but I realized that if you just hold bounce
next to the statue, guys come and die under you without a chance
of getting hurt. This was totally boring and stupid (it took
a few minutes), but it wasn&#8217;t horrific. After that, there was no
more grinding. The whole game was really short&#8230; just about an
hour from start to finish. The best part was the unique challenge
of not being able to directly jump on enemies and the way you
sometimes needed to whack things with your cane. (For example,
the mummy ducks in the mansion where fun to fight when you had to
whack their ball &amp; chain.)</p>

<p>Overall, the game was fun&#8230; good music, cute monsters&#8230; and
it&#8217;s classic in a certain sense, but I don&#8217;t feel it is worth
replaying, because it is sooo easy.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Clash at Demonhead (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Clash-at-Demonhead--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game&#8211;Clash-at-Demonhead&#8211;NES&#8211;1989&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played again today and gave a bigger chance. I was able to
accomplish somethings, including killing one of the bosses. I
still think the core gameplay is really sloppy&#8212;the hit boxes
are bad, the shot control isn&#8217;t great, and the interface is
pretty whack. But, I can see why some people might have loved it
when it was released. I&#8217;m done with it though.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
