<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-10T00:20:47-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: 300, directed by Zack Snyder (2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie--300--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie&#8211;300&#8211;directed-by-Zack-Snyder&#8211;2007&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an amazing movie. The visual were out of this world. The
story is so inspiring. Although it is pretty bloody, for some
reason there&#8217;s really only like two gross parts. The grossest thing
was the disfigured people, but that&#8217;s weird, mainly because it&#8217;s
actually real.</p>

<p>Looking at the guys in the movie makes you feel tiny, puny, and
weak. It&#8217;s super intense.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
&#8220;Inn&#8221; to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I&#8217;ve been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There&#8217;s just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one &#8220;episode&#8221; per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game&#8211;Star-Ocean&#8211;The-Last-Hope-International&#8211;PS3&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;ve played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I&#8217;m looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don&#8217;t really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It&#8217;s the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful, although a little bit of the time
I felt like I was losing because I couldn&#8217;t target the thing I
wanted. The graphics are pretty good, although the characters are
verrry anime-y and from some angles their clothes really clash
with their faces. (For example, the guy on the computer screen
that Edge talks to.) The controls are responsive.  Although the
camera controls are a little too &#8220;tight&#8221; for my taste so far. I
got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I think the
problem is that the world is so &#8220;bright&#8221; that it&#8217;s hard to notice
something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of the time was
spent in videos, so I don&#8217;t really have a good feel for the game
yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided based on some consultation with forum posts, etc, that I
will watch a long play of the game, rather than play through it
myself. The gameplay is so bad and I want to see everything, but
don&#8217;t want to play with a walkthrough. It&#8217;s more efficient to just
watch it. I found two playthroughs: <a href="http://forums.somethingawful.com/showthread.php?threadid%3D3368004">a 100% playthrough</a> and [[http://www.giantbomb.com/forums/deadly-premonition/5058/endurance-run-download-urls/417644/][a
GiantBomb Endurance Run]]. I&#8217;m not sure which one will be better, so
I&#8217;ll try a little of both. I intend on writing about the game as I
watch these, as if it were me playing. We&#8217;ll see how that goes&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Transformers: Dark of the Moon, directed by Michael Bay (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie--Transformers--Dark-of-the-Moon--directed-by-Michael-Bay--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie&#8211;Transformers&#8211;Dark-of-the-Moon&#8211;directed-by-Michael-Bay&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another stupid, crazy, spectacle movie. The plot is pretty
incomprehensible, but who cares, or expects better? The visuals
were really amazing. I was kind of annoyed that Megan Fox wasn&#8217;t in
it and there was basically no explanation for why. I see why her
character wouldn&#8217;t work for what they had the girl do, but I don&#8217;t
see why that was a necessary plot point. Either way, the whole
movie was some good stupid fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today and finished the game. I got
As on the last few missions, which was pretty cool. I think I got
As on almost all of them, but I didn&#8217;t load my Clear data, so I&#8217;m
not sure if it would say what my overall statistics were, etc.</p>

<p>It was a really cool game. The ending was sweet. There were so
pretty crazy revelations about the characters, the events were
suitably epic, and the final boss was intense. I particularly
liked the sequence at the end where they showed what each
character did after the war&#8230; especially the little vignette
about Welkin and Alicia and their baby girl :) So cute!</p>

<p>The combat in the game is really interesting too. I enjoyed both
the &#8220;stealth&#8221; missions and the other ones. It makes me think a lot
about how you&#8217;d make a game like this. (And in particular,
randomly generate levels for it.)</p>

<p>I saw that there were some DLC missions, but I don&#8217;t think it is
worth it for me right now given my queue. I do like the game a
lot, but I feel like I&#8217;ve got the missions down to be a bit rote,
so it&#8217;s mainly the story pushing me to do more.</p>

<p>It was interesting to compare my final in-game timer (25:08) to my
count (33:39), because it shows how much time was taken up by
mission attempts that ultimately failed and thus weren&#8217;t counted
in the real total. Wow!</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>

<p>Total: 33:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game&#8211;Deadly-Premonition&#8211;X360&#8211;2010&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game because I heard so many good things about it on
podcasts, particularly the &#8220;WARNING: A Huge Podcast&#8221;
special. Before playing it, I&#8217;m slightly worried that the gameplay
will be too bad for me to deal with and the M rating will be too
appropriate so I won&#8217;t want to. (I don&#8217;t want to play M games
where you kill humans and where there is really bad language or
nudity. Games like Bayonetta don&#8217;t bother me because there&#8217;s just
inhuman gore, and while it and Vanquish had a few curse words, it
was pretty tame. I almost didn&#8217;t finish Battlefield 3 because of
all the bad language.) Anyways, I bought it pretty cheap, so I&#8217;m
giving it a chance, but if it doesn&#8217;t take me in one night, I
don&#8217;t think I&#8217;ll keep playing it.</p>

<p>&#8211;</p>

<p>I played for about an hour. The world of the game is incredibly
charming. The talking in the car is genius. The realistic scale of
the world is really bizarre, but neat. There are many flourishes
on top of things that other games would have and not really think
about. For example, you can shave in the bathroom, the
conversation over breakfast where the lady couldn&#8217;t hear you
correctly, the strange comments about every person York meets,
it&#8217;s all fascinating and surreal. My wife sat with me and was
entranced by the characters.</p>

<p>The production value is so bad though. The modeling and texture
work has tons of problems and there is severe dead face. The
crying is atrocious. The translation is pretty poor with some
strange too literal phrases. (For example, a gas station is called
as ガソリンスタンド(ga-so-re-n su-ta-n-do, i.e. gasoline stand)
and someone in town tells you where the &#8220;gas stand&#8221; is.)</p>

<p>The game play is bad so far. The walking is really awkward. You
don&#8217;t really have camera control, but can almost turn your head or
something, but it is so fast, it&#8217;s disorienting. The combat is
incredibly boring so far but also really hard to control. The
lock-on is necessary because the reticule movement is so chunky,
but it&#8217;s also not very effective. There&#8217;s not a good system for
keeping you informed of what enemies are around you. Based on
advice from the aforementioned podcasts, I put it on Easy mode to
avoid these. problems.</p>

<p>The quick time events with the ax guy were weird. The driving
instructions were totally over the top. My wife and I looked at
each other aghast when we saw them. It took a long time to get out
of the parking lot and get used to driving with the controls.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s a strange, surreal game. The fidelity is so bad, I don&#8217;t
think I&#8217;ll be grossed out. I get the impression there will be a
lot of jump scares. I&#8217;m slightly nervous that there will be too
much to do and explore and I&#8217;ll get bogged down and intimidated
doing it. But I&#8217;ll give it more time.</p>

<p>Total: 01:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Baxter, starring Michael Showalter (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--The-Baxter--starring-Michael-Showalter--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie&#8211;The-Baxter&#8211;starring-Michael-Showalter&#8211;2005&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very funny movie. It magnifies standard romantic comedy
cliches to a whole new level and is almost a &#8220;reductio ad absurdum&#8221;
of the concept of a &#8220;Baxter&#8221;. I quite enjoyed it. Michelle Williams
was adorable in it, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (13)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--12/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today, split across watching a
movie. The battles were pretty tough. The once against Selvaria
was insane, because she dodges practically everything. I
eventually realized I should use a unit with the &#8220;Undodgeable
Shot&#8221; ability, then it was all over. The one where you have to
blow up the canyon walls, I kept doing it wrong because I didn&#8217;t
realize there were two things to blow up to force it to
turn. D&#8217;oh. I wasted like 30 minutes because of that.</p>

<p>I can&#8217;t believe that Welkin proposed to Alicia&#8212;he even had a
ring! This game is so grown up compared to other RPGs, especially
Japanese ones. The story is really cool, still.</p>

<p>Total: 30:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Awakening, starring Kate Beckinsale (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Awakening&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2012&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was the fasted paced and immediately insane movie. It&#8217;s
practically equivalent to the insanity of the fourth Resident Evil
movie. The amount the world of the movies changes in the first five
minutes is unbelievable. Yet, they pack in lots of really
fascinating and sensible ideas and imagery. It&#8217;s spectacular.</p>

<p>The story is interesting, although it is unclear why they would
need to be studying the hybrids, but whatever. The quality of the
Lycan models continues to improve, although their heads are still
not quite right. This movie removes all sympathy for the Lycans
that was in the background of the 1st and 3rd movies. It basically
does absolutely nothing for the mythology either. Perhaps it will
be more successful because of that, because you don&#8217;t really need
to know anything about the previous movies to appreciate this
one. The mythological wankery only appeals to some, but this could
appeal to many.</p>

<p>The movie was noticeably more gory than previous movies. The only
time this bothered me was at the very beginning when Selene was
killing humans escaping. I don&#8217;t mind gore when it is directed at
monsters or aliens, but humans shouldn&#8217;t receive it. It is also
kind of uncharacteristic, because the previous movies have
established a vampire moral code that limits their consumption of
human blood.</p>

<p>I was surprised that Michael Corvin is basically not in the
movie. I was expecting him to come back and save the day in the
final fight after Selene had released him. (The actual ending
though, was supremely feminist, as the mother and daughter don&#8217;t
really need help from the father, or men in general.) But I suppose
it was based on some contractual reason.</p>

<p>The Wikipedia page contains story information that I didn&#8217;t get
from the movie. For example, the daughter&#8217;s name is Eve and the
secret of the immortals was revealed to humans by the
doctor. Weird.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today. I did a bunch of different
missions, all were done in a relatively &#8220;stealthy&#8221; style. It was
very hard though, but quite fun. The story is really interesting,
as I said. I was quite surprised by who shot Alicia. After the
next battle, I unlocked a few reports, which I am now going
through.</p>

<p>Total: 26:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Rise-of-the-Lycans&#8211;starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy&#8211;2009&#8211;1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking about this movie the day after, there are some things
really strange about it:</p>

<p>All the movies more or less establish the vampires as basically in
the right, with the werewolves being too uncontrolled to be safe
for humans. Almost as if the vampires are protecting humans from
the immortals&#8212;especially given that they have a cultural
imperative to not consume human blood. (Viktor is a &#8220;bad&#8221; vampire
almost entirely because he sometimes breaks this rule.)</p>

<p>The first movie mixes this a little bit, portraying Lucian as
having been wronged and the vampires, especially Viktor, overly
prejudiced. But, it doesn&#8217;t give Lucian any motives other than
revenge on vampires. Given that he is involved in offensive action,
it&#8217;s not as if the vampires are simply out to get him. The war is
reciprocal.</p>

<p>The second movie really lays on the thick that danger of the
werewolves with the flash back sequences, but otherwise doesn&#8217;t
really develop the reason for the conflict. It&#8217;s basically just
sibling rivalry. (The movie is also weird because it makes very
little sense that Markus would act as he does now, as opposed to in
any of the previous 100 year periods where he was the sole reigning
vampire elder. It&#8217;s especially incomprehensible why he destroys his
coven.)</p>

<p>The third movie doesn&#8217;t really explain why Lucian would continue to
fight the vampires. It presents him as unassailably moral and a
freedom fighter. But once he gets his freedom, why does he have any
reason to continue fighting? Especially given that he thinks Viktor
is dead.</p>

<p>I presume that this won&#8217;t be resolved or explained in the last
movie. But maybe not? It seems like Selene is the oldest vampire
that we&#8217;ve heard of it that is still alive and there has never been
any ranking werewolves other than Lucian and William.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: In Time, starring Justin Timberlake (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--In-Time--starring-Justin-Timberlake--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie&#8211;In-Time&#8211;starring-Justin-Timberlake&#8211;2011&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really fascinating movie. It&#8217;s a totally unique dystopia
for me (maybe Wikipedia will tell me about things that are like
it?) and that is always fascinating. The plot is basically Bonnie &amp;
Clyde after an initial glance at the prejudice and hardship in the
system.</p>

<p>The imagery is really cool and there are lots of interesting and
bizarre situations, like the way Wies introduces his female
relatives.</p>

<p>I think the movie lost some good opportunities for character
development. For example, Will gets 30 minutes for lunch at the
beginning but she dies by seconds when she can&#8217;t take the bus, and
was just 20 minutes short of being able to pay for the bus
ride. Yet, he doesn&#8217;t acknowledge this for the sake of the audience
or to show his great remorse, etc.</p>

<p>Overall, I found the movie to be very intriguing. This, however, is
also its biggest problem because it begs you to think about it
deeply and the world isn&#8217;t explained well enough.</p>

<p>For example, there&#8217;s a strong suggestion that the mantra &#8220;For few to
be immortal, many must die&#8221; has some sort of quasi-mystical and
dreadful significance. Like there is some sort of Big Brother type
that is keeping people down. However, this isn&#8217;t followed through.</p>

<p>The purpose of the Time Keepers is not explained adequately. On one
level, they are simply cops and since money is time, they are
connected to time. However, in the end, when they&#8217;re talking about
how &#8220;that much money can&#8217;t leave that zone&#8221; and many other
situations, you get the impression that there is some deeper
purpose to their actions.</p>

<p>Similarly, the movie has poor economics. For example, what effect
does birth have, given that it introduces a year of time? If the
time is a real commodity&#8212;i.e. an abstraction of some sort of
energy their bodies need, rather than a fiat system (i.e. they are
like nanomachines that keep track of the time and just kill you
when it is zero.)&#8212;then where does the new year come from? How
could there be such price controls?</p>

<p>I think the movie could have resolved this better by coming up with
some sort of origin story and pseudo-science to explain why people
would choose to live like this (and everyone!) at some point
voluntarily and how it works. I think the fiat system would have
been interesting, because it makes it so there&#8217;s actually a
solution that they could possibly reach. But, as it is, we can&#8217;t
imagine that Will and Sylvia will ever actually fix
anything&#8230; other than what communists and Robin Hoods try to do
and fail to do in the real world.</p>

<p>The movie is very confused, therefore, with what its message (and
the message of its heroes) really is. Philippe spouts
pseudo-Capitalism, so perhaps the movie is anti-Capitalism? Yet,
the corruption of the Time Keepers vis a vis Fortis is reminiscent
of the relationship between the US and e.g. African dictators. So,
is it an anti &#8220;Globalization&#8221; or &#8220;Imperialist&#8221; politic?</p>

<p>I think because they don&#8217;t foreshadow a solution or great evil
through technology or metaphysics, the world must be a &#8220;natural&#8221;
world and so the villain must be natural, and they rhetoric of the
movie leaves nothing left but a political agenda. Yet, it doesn&#8217;t
articulate what the agenda is.</p>

<p>The movie is good for making it possible to think of it like this,
but it is bad because by not answering these questions, it is
incoherent and vapid.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--10/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about 33 minutes today and basically just learned
that Alicia really is a Valkyria and she&#8217;s super tough. I lost the
battle pretty hard, because I did a stealth rush and couldn&#8217;t
defend the forward base. Now that I know where the enemy will be,
I think I will try to pre-place Lancers behind the where the tanks
appear! We&#8217;ll see tomorrow.</p>

<p>Total: 23:26</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Rise-of-the-Lycans&#8211;starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy&#8211;2009&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was really surprised by the quality of this movie. I assumed that
because it didn&#8217;t star Kate Beckinsale it would be a cheap version
of the world. But actually, I think it is the best yet; although it
wouldn&#8217;t be very good without the first movie, obviously. It gives
a lot better context to the first movie and makes a lot of what
seems strange about the mythology a lot more reasonable. The story
is a lot more coherent and reasonable and the action is noticeably
slower, so you can appreciate it a bit more.</p>

<p>The development of the romance between Lucian and Sonja is totally
ignored, apart from a glance when they are kids.</p>

<p>Rhona Mitra really does look like Kate Beckinsale.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s cool that the giant black werewolf from the first scene of the
first movie is one of Lucian&#8217;s oldest friends. A nice little nod to
people paying attention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a few more stealth style missions. The big battle in the
trenches was really different and dangerous, although I did it in
a stealth way. The bonus mission where you had to search through
all the grassy areas was pretty cool too.</p>

<p>The story is getting really neat and touching. I can&#8217;t believe
they killed Isara, but I like the way you return to Bruhl as a way
to &#8220;avenge&#8221; her. The development of the idea of Alicia being a
Valkyria is really neat too. I wonder if it will just be in
cut-scenes or if she&#8217;ll become some crazy new unit type? I feel
like the story is close to wrapping up, but there are a lot more
empty boxes in the R&amp;D area, so I suspect that it really isn&#8217;t
that close to being done.</p>

<p>This is still an awesome game. The best part is probably the way
they are constantly developing and adding more and more to the
story and gameplay. It&#8217;s very different than it was in the
beginning, but the path to here has made complete sense.</p>

<p>Total: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kings of Power 4 Billion %, by Paul Robertson (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie--Kings-of-Power-4-Billion----by-Paul-Robertson--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Movie&#8211;Kings-of-Power-4-Billion&#8212;-by-Paul-Robertson&#8211;2008&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is totally insane and amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a very busy but ultimately unproductive day with a lot of
wasted effort, so I played games rather later to feel some
accomplishment. I played for about 2 hours. I got through all of
chapter 11 and did the skirmish that opened up three times (Easy,
Normal, Normal)&#8230; all As (2 rounds!)&#8230; to get enough money to
buy everything. The beach battle was pretty scary, but I was able
to do it in 2 rounds with only 2 restarts. It was pretty cool to
have a few &#8220;stealth&#8221; levels.</p>

<p>Total: 20:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie&#8211;Underworld&#8211;Evolution&#8211;starring-Kate-Beckinsale&#8211;2006&#8211;0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn&#8217;t seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It&#8217;s a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game&#8211;Valkyria-Chronicles&#8211;PS3&#8211;2008&#8211;7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight&#8230; the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn&#8217;t understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it&#8230; but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I&#8217;m curious about what Zaka will be
like&#8230; do I really get another vehicle? I&#8217;m running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
