<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GC | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/gc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-05T23:13:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes (GC, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/12/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--The-Twin-Snakes--GC--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid: The Twin Snakes over the course
of about a week. This is a remake of Metal Gear Solid with a bit
of new gameplay, new cinematics, and generally improved graphics.</p>

<p>I had never played this remake, but I played the original many
times when it came out. I really enjoyed playing it again. It was
very nostalgic for me.</p>

<p>I noticed a lot of homages to the first two games. For example,
you meet Meryl in a bathroom; you fist fight with Gray Fox; there
is a key that changes with the temperature; and you fight in an
elevator against an assassination squad. All these happened in
Metal Gear: Solid Snake. Naturally, the themes are the
same---especially the idea that everyone betrays Snake.</p>

<p>The one annoying thing in the game was the tortue scene. They
don't tell you in the dialogue which button resists and which
button gives up. As soon as it started, I tried to call someone on
the Codec to find that out. Of course, the give up button was the
call button. Doh! I hadn't saved in hours, so I couldn't do it
again. What a bummer. Meryl died because of it.</p>

<p>Game Level: Easy
Play Time: 10:38:12
Save: 12 times
Continue: 21 times
Alert Mode: 31 times
Enemies: 037 killed
Rations: 056 used
Code Name: Flying Squirrel
Clear Code: VHNL RGCX CH78 TBXX C5FB 79VD XB8</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
