<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1994 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1994/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-12T22:37:15-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Top Hunter - Roddy & Cathy (MAME, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/14/Game--Top-Hunter---Roddy---Cathy--MAME--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/14/Game--Top-Hunter---Roddy---Cathy--MAME--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy. I found out about
the game through <a href="http://www.racketboy.com/retro/2007/02/best-undiscovered-neo-geo-games.html">Racketboy's Undiscovered Neo-Geo Games</a> list.</p>

<p>The game is a side-scrolling action game with two planes of
movement. You can jump from one plane to the other and most of the
action in the game revolves around quickly and accurately getting
on the correct plane. Even though there is jumping, this isn't
really a platforming game, because it stays on one path mostly and
there are rarely obstacles to jump over. There are four
worlds---each with two levels, one mid-boss, and one main boss;
followed by a final level with only a boss---which is actually a
six boss rush.</p>

<p>There are some interesting mechanics in the game. You can grab
things from a distance by stretching your arm. This allows you to
grab things from far away, as well as punch from a distance. Most
of the "puzzles" are about doing this effectively. There is a very
low time limit on the game and there are items that allow increase
it by 5, 10, or 20 seconds. I thought this would be stressful, but
I didn't notice it at all. (That might have been because I
credit-fed.)</p>

<p>The animation is not nearly as good as Metal Slug, but it is
decent. There is a little bit of quirkiness. For example, there is
a funny animal in the final stage... the enemies will often wave
white flags at you... etc. There are some good details too: for
example, most vehicles are destructible and you can throw their
parts at the enemies once they are destroyed.</p>

<p>Overall, the game had a very basic and repetitive design. Most of
the enemies and bosses were dealt with in the same way. I didn't
feel it was very deep. I could imagine feeling it was a bit deeper
if I restricted my credit usage. I would typically use 2 on a boss
and .5 on a level. I assume that most of the challenge of getting
credit usage down would be very much luck: enemies hit for a
lot.</p>

<p>I played through it in under an hour. I'd say it was worth
it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Snatcher (SCD, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/03/05/Game--Snatcher--SCD--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/03/05/Game--Snatcher--SCD--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I played Snatcher, Hideo Kojima's second video game, for
the Sega CD. I'm a huge fan of his Metal Gear series and I've
always heard of how cool /Snatcher/ was, so I finally got around
to playing it.</p>

<p>The gameplay isn't very deep. The puzzles and adventure game-style
fetching is pretty basic. The shooting scenes are trivial and
mostly unnecessary. But, the story and presentation is pretty
amazing, particularly if you can put your mind back in the late
80s/early 90s. You can really see how it fits into his overall
career in terms of the style, some of the core ideas, and the
"feel" of the story. For example, Kojima is very good at
suggesting that there is a deeper interesting world behind his
games; a few instances of this I liked were the subtle references
to genetically modified pets and Martian mining. A few other
things I really enjoyed were the references to other video games
at the time in the night club and to pop-culture, e.g. talking
about "Michael Jaxson" and how he is strange. The game also makes
me appreciate /Metal Gear Solid 4/'s Metal Gear Mk.II---in
/Snatcher/ your assistant has the same name and looks roughly the
same too.</p>

<p>It was a good history lesson and I enjoyed it, but I shouldn't
have stayed up so late. :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 6 (SNES, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/07/15/Game--Final-Fantasy-6--SNES--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/07/15/Game--Final-Fantasy-6--SNES--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Final_Fantasy_VI">Final Fantasy VI</a> (GBA version) on the DS</p>

<p>I /loved/ this game when it first came out. I remember getting a
SNES for my birthday, but not having any games until Christmas
when I asked for /Final Fantasy III/ (as it was called in the
US... not that I knew that at the time.) When I finally got it, I
remember talking to a friend later on in the night about how I had
played all day and was already half way through.</p>

<p>I hadn't played the game in over ten years, but before then I
played it through many times. Well, this time it was just as
awesome. But rather than just gloat, I'll mention some things I
like about it:
- The characters have real depth and it matters who is in your
party in most situations as they react differently.
- The characters have unique battle personas for most of the game,
due to their useful special commands; although sadly this
degrades a little bit in the end game when magic is essential
for everything.
- The world is interesting with many connections that you don't
need to notice unless you care to look. For example, the woman
in love with the fallen soldier in Mobliz or Shadow's dreams in
the World of Ruin.
- The final battle is very unique with multiple parties and
different tiers with different status effect carry overs.
- <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hgZXiHfNt0M">The Opera Scene</a> (and portions of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fGpIWD39Ngw">remake</a> and a [[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7NC45S948ss][live version
with the New Japan Philharmonic]]---definitely watch the live
version and after the original.)
- Speaking of that scene, the music is amazing.
- <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KCXGVNvtxkc">Imp</a>
- The multiple party dungeon system is neat, but see below.
- The split-up at the beginning of the game is very neat as well.</p>

<p>However, there are something I don't like (and unfortunately not
many games have got them right either):
- In the end game, it feels like any party is just as good as
another because of magic.
- The multiple party dungeons are tedious when characters aren't
equally leveled and the only way to get them there is to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grinding_(gaming">grind</a>),
which sucks.
- Gau, Mog, Relm, and Strago's special commands are very cool when
you think about them but are very hard to use well. Gau in
particular requires <a href="http://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/gbadvance/file/930370/50814">PhD to use well</a>.
- You can play the entire game and never see a [[http://finalfantasy.wikia.com/wiki/Desperation_Attack][desperation
attack]]. (Before I read the FAQs, I had played the game three or
four times and only seen them twice.)</p>

<p>I didn't do Dragon's Den. I primarily used
Terra/Celes/Sabin/Mog->Umaro->Gogo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Earthbound (SNES, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/08/01/Game--Earthbound--SNES--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2008-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/08/01/Game--Earthbound--SNES--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat this for the second time (for sure); playing it on an
emulator. So good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
