<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2000 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2000/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T22:07:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment (N64, 2000) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in May, I bought a copy of S&amp;P for the N64 in Japan. On
Tuesday I bought a US N64 to play it on. Today, I got the
"GameBit" in the mail that I needed to region mod it to play
Japanese N64 games.</p>

<p>I started playing S&amp;P and it took a while to get used to the
controls again... especially because before I played on my arcade
stick (under an emulator) and now I was using the actual control
scheme. It felt a little strange but I started to get used to it
quickly.</p>

<p>I played about 14 minutes and got: 5,343,930 pts, 11m13s, and 531
enemies. I died at the final stage of the final boss of the first
level. I remember it taking a while to realize that I had to
shoot the glowing spot under water the first time too...</p>

<p>Time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Puzzle Bobble 4 (DC, 2000)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Puzzle-Bobble-4--DC--2000--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Puzzle-Bobble-4--DC--2000--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another game that my son and I played today. He was very
fascinated by the different characters---especially the baby
wearing the frog costume. He didn't get the concept of aiming the
shooter, but he got that he was shooting out bubbles. For a while,
he would press the A button and I would aim, but then he'd get
bored and just smash it to cause a failure so he could pick a new
character. We primarily played it because he saw the Dreamcast
controller and wanted to try it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear: Ghost Babel (GBC, 2000)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/17/Game--Metal-Gear--Ghost-Babel--GBC--2000--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/17/Game--Metal-Gear--Ghost-Babel--GBC--2000--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid: Ghost Babel over the past three
days. This is a Game Boy Color game. At first, I assumed it would
basically be just like the first two Metal Gear games for the
MSX. It is, but it has clearly greatly evolved. This is the
perfect 2D Metal Gear. It makes me think (like I think for so many
series) how much better the series would be if it stuck in 2D but
got bigger, better, and more beautiful.</p>

<p>I'm amazed at how many of the mechanics from MGS they were able to
integrate into the game. For example, looking around walls is done
brilliantly. Tapping on walls works great. All the weapons
return. It's really a spectacular game. In some ways I'd say it is
better than MGS because many mechanics actually appear multiple
times. For example, there's really only one time you need to use
the Nikita Missiles in MGS (when you destroy the only electrical
panel in the game), but there are many instances in this
game. Same thing with the C4; there's one occurrences in MGS, but
many in this. I like the richness of that.</p>

<p>This game is technically linear and broken into stages, but in
many ways that is totally fine and a little inaccurate. It's a bit
inaccurate because there are many stages where you revisit areas
from previous stages (but that's a severe minority.) It's totally
fine because if you really break it down, MGS was linear too:
there is very sparse back-tracking. For example, once you go to
Otacon's lab, there's no reason to ever go back, even though you
could. This game just turns that admission into something enforced
by the game. Still though, each stage is really large and they
individually contain a lot of back-tracking. But really,
back-tracking (the need to go to old areas) and open world (the
technical ability to revisit old areas) are not valuable in and of
themselves. What is valuable is when the world feels "real" and
not artificial like a traditional stage-based game. This game
really makes the world feel real because of the way that things
connect and the size of the areas generally. In fact, I really see
a lot of this game in MGS4, which has a similar open-world
stage-based setup, where many areas have internal sections that
don't allow back-tracking.</p>

<p>I really want to think about this game as the basis for another 2D
Metal Gear-style game.</p>

<p>Here are the stats that I got:</p>

<p>Play Time: 02:56:07
Being Found: 001 times
Enemies: 000 killed
Rations: 008 used
Code Name: Spider</p>

<p>I was able to get such scores by using save states and always
restarting a room if I got caught. I don't feel this is cheating
because I still had to overcome the obstacle myself. It's really
an efficient way to do the traditional MGS Extreme mode where you
get a Game Over when you get caught. If I made an MGS-style game,
it would have this be an option and have it really stream-lined
(maybe Super Meat Boy streamlined.)</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment (N64, 2000) - High scores]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/16/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--1/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/16/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Easy - 44,214,705pts - 46m41s - 2,033enm</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment (N64, 2000)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/16/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/16/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For almost the past two months, I have been playing Sin and
Punishment: Hoshi no Keishōsha every day. In the beginning, I
could only get through about 15 minutes of the game, so it fit
well into my rotation. As I got towards the end, I would play
every day, get to right before the final boss and die, losing
about 45 minutes of my life every time. But! I loved it so much!
It is so satisfying to play this game and slowly get better at
getting through each boss, each segment; learning how to get more
and more enemies and points. At times I feel like I'm playing a
beautiful piano piece that I've practiced for so long.</p>

<p>When I started playing, I didn't know about the sword or that you
could knock back projectiles at enemies, so once I learned I
quickly got past some of my previous bottlenecks. My favourite
part of the game is when you control Airan: running through the
ship with her, fighting Leda, going on the chase, and destroying
the fleet is just so... EPIC! Then, the subway sequence is really
fun, but honestly, not as cool as the ship sequence. The first and
second parts with Saki are fine, but the side-scrolling final
stage is awesome. The difficulty in the game is perfect. Even
though I got through the final boss on my first try, it was insane
and frenetic. I ended with about 564 hit points left on the Earth,
which started around 30k, so I clearly didn't do an amazing
job. But it was awesome.</p>

<p>The music is great for its era (although wifey reports that she
got pretty tired of it.) The visuals hold up very well actually,
because everything is so big. Ya, the textures in the backgrounds
are really blurry, but it actually gives an apocalyptic and fast
paced feel. The controls are really smooth... although I didn't
play on a N64 controller. (I used the best controller ever aka
arcade stick. I mapped the top three buttons to: strafe left,
fire, strafe right, lock-on/manual. Then the bottom left button to
jump so that I just laid my hand down and never had to move it. I
feel like the game was easier this way because I used more digits
than the N64 controller would "fit.") I love the pacing and the
simple (but interesting) scoring system.</p>

<p>I cannot wait for the sequel, Sin and Punishment: Sora no Kōkeisha
to come out. If it doesn't make it over, I'll definitely have to
import a Japanese Wii or something to play it. I heart it.</p>

<p>Now the final business: My score. I played on Easy for this first
play-through. (I will do Normal soon.) I got 44,214,705 points,
spent 46 minutes and 41 seconds and got 2033 enemies. This is all
on one credit, of course.</p>

<p>Love it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
