<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Final Fantasy 6 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/final-fantasy-6/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-07T22:16:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 6 (SNES, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/07/15/Game--Final-Fantasy-6--SNES--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/07/15/Game--Final-Fantasy-6--SNES--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Final_Fantasy_VI">Final Fantasy VI</a> (GBA version) on the DS</p>

<p>I /loved/ this game when it first came out. I remember getting a
SNES for my birthday, but not having any games until Christmas
when I asked for /Final Fantasy III/ (as it was called in the
US... not that I knew that at the time.) When I finally got it, I
remember talking to a friend later on in the night about how I had
played all day and was already half way through.</p>

<p>I hadn't played the game in over ten years, but before then I
played it through many times. Well, this time it was just as
awesome. But rather than just gloat, I'll mention some things I
like about it:
- The characters have real depth and it matters who is in your
party in most situations as they react differently.
- The characters have unique battle personas for most of the game,
due to their useful special commands; although sadly this
degrades a little bit in the end game when magic is essential
for everything.
- The world is interesting with many connections that you don't
need to notice unless you care to look. For example, the woman
in love with the fallen soldier in Mobliz or Shadow's dreams in
the World of Ruin.
- The final battle is very unique with multiple parties and
different tiers with different status effect carry overs.
- <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hgZXiHfNt0M">The Opera Scene</a> (and portions of the <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fGpIWD39Ngw">remake</a> and a [[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7NC45S948ss][live version
with the New Japan Philharmonic]]---definitely watch the live
version and after the original.)
- Speaking of that scene, the music is amazing.
- <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=KCXGVNvtxkc">Imp</a>
- The multiple party dungeon system is neat, but see below.
- The split-up at the beginning of the game is very neat as well.</p>

<p>However, there are something I don't like (and unfortunately not
many games have got them right either):
- In the end game, it feels like any party is just as good as
another because of magic.
- The multiple party dungeons are tedious when characters aren't
equally leveled and the only way to get them there is to <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grinding_(gaming">grind</a>),
which sucks.
- Gau, Mog, Relm, and Strago's special commands are very cool when
you think about them but are very hard to use well. Gau in
particular requires <a href="http://www.gamefaqs.com/portable/gbadvance/file/930370/50814">PhD to use well</a>.
- You can play the entire game and never see a [[http://finalfantasy.wikia.com/wiki/Desperation_Attack][desperation
attack]]. (Before I read the FAQs, I had played the game three or
four times and only seen them twice.)</p>

<p>I didn't do Dragon's Den. I primarily used
Terra/Celes/Sabin/Mog->Umaro->Gogo</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
