<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dark Souls | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/dark-souls/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-22T20:29:23-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little over an hour. I got through the next
part of the Undead Parish. The Rhino was pretty tough and got me
once. Then I weaved my way around and accidentally stumbled into
the Bell Gargoyle fight. I died the first three times and then
accidentally died on the way. So I lost about 6k souls. Ouch. This
game is definitely great.</p>

<p>SL: 21</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 18
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 4:56</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today and got used to the game. I
spent a long time planning my character based on remembering what
was a good strategy in Demon's Souls. I'll be taking the same
approach: really fast, huge shield, melee focus, but with a good
bow.</p>

<p>The tutorial phase of the game was much shorter and so far the
game seems incredibly linear, which I thought wasn't the case, but
maybe I'm just still in the beginning. Last time I took a very
linear approach through the game, but this time I intend to
explore a bit more.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game are basically identical. The graphics
seem a little bit better... primarily in the lightning department,
but I don't know if I can really tell or I just have a bad
memory. It seems like this simply <em>is</em> Demon's Souls with a little
bit of a different structure---no hub, Humanity, etc.</p>

<p>That makes it sound like I don't like the idea of that, but I'm
actually very excited about playing it.</p>

<p>During my time tonight, I died twice. Each time against a boss on
my first fight with them. The game seems just as hard as before,
but I'm getting used to the controls again and learning how the
bosses behave. Overall, it's a pretty awesome game.</p>

<p>Here are my current stats (where ! indicates that the stat is at
the level I intend to leave it at for the foreseeable future):</p>

<p>SL: 19</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 16
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 3:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
