<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Square's Tom Sawyer | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/square-s-tom-sawyer/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Square's Tom Sawyer (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Square-s-Tom-Sawyer--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Square-s-Tom-Sawyer--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm fascinated by the existence of this game and I have been since
I heard that it existed. I played the game for about twenty
minutes in all Japanese. I was able to understand the menus, but I
didn't do much more than sound out the dialogue. The graphics are
ridiculously racist. The concept of the game is nuts and based on
my brief playing and a glance at a walkthrough... it is
transparent fetch quest with RPG battles in between. In some way,
this can be said of all RPGs, but it would be far too transparent
for me, given my limited grasp of the language. I wasn't able to
walk to the first fetch quest delivery point and back without
dying.</p>

<p>Grinding is really the worst thing for old RPGs. Many of them had
interesting mechanics, but were padded for their day. In more
modern times, this padding is really destructive if you want to
experience what was interesting about the game. There's no good
way to use codes and cheats to give a challenging, but still
non-tedious experience. There are ways to just pre-load with
super powers and get infinite experience, but that's little
better than just watching the game on YouTube.</p>

<p>As I get older I'm much more interested in games without
progression systems because from the second you start you're
faced with a test to learn new skills and apply them. The tests
get harder, but there's no artificial curve in the game. In other
games with internal progression systems, the progression is more
than just numeric... it requires more strategy and planning. For
example, Dragon Quest 1 is basically just about getting higher
numbers until you can get even higher numbers. There's little
strategy involved... just a test of how much risk you're willing
to take. In contrast, FF6 adds more party members, complicated
enemy patterns, many spells, etc as the game progresses.</p>

<p>I don't know where Tom Sawyer fits in this rubric, but I'm not
going to give it a chance. I have dipped into its existence and
found it very curious.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:18</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
