<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Eternal Sonata | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/eternal-sonata/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T22:21:06-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Eternal Sonata (X360, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/10/Game--Eternal-Sonata--X360--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/10/Game--Eternal-Sonata--X360--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Eternal Sonata on the Xbox from October 17th to
last night. I remember downloading the PS3 demo when I was sick
one day when the <em>REDACTED</em> was very very young. It seemed pretty cool,
and I like Tri- games, so I've had on my list since then. I saw a
Craigslist posting about it and grabbed it for ten bucks. I
finished the game with 23:59:46 on the game clock and my A-team
was around level 53 (significantly lower than a FAQ I glanced at
recommended) and the other characters on the bench were around the
low 40s.</p>

<p>The story and setting of this game is really bizarre. It takes
place inside the mind of Chopin, the composer, on his death bed
and is about a group of people kinda fighting the big bad empire,
but at the end it takes an even more bizarre turn and loses all
comprehensibility. But it doesn't really matter. The end was even
worse for me because I used Japanese language with English
subtitles during the game and the ending had no subtitles. (Really
weird actually.) I don't regret it though because the few times I
heard the English voices was horrific.</p>

<p>The graphics are beautiful and cartoony. There are many tiny
details in the background which really give flair to the world. In
a word, the graphics are "lush"... in colour, in detail, in
scope... it's great. However it is incredibly unrealistic, unlike
say FF13 which is fantastic in a realistic way. One thing strange
about the art is how the characters look mostly like action
figures, but then there is uncanny shading on a nose, or under
eyes, or on cleavage, or even on the edge of their hair. I think
the worst part of most characters is how "stuck on" their hair
looks. In particular, Allegretto looks like a bald man wearing a
wig.</p>

<p>When I started I assumed that the music would have been amazing,
but it was just good. Nothing really special about it, but
definitely serviceable and a solid "good".</p>

<p>Now, let me comment on the mechanics.</p>

<p>It has a really weak meta-game, outside the combat. There is very
little constraint on your resources. Well, if you rely on battles
to give you money, you'll be struggling. However, Beat can take
pictures and sell even bad pictures for about 10k, where the best
weapons and items cost far less than even 3k. Since you can store
12 photos, this means that every time you visit a shop you can get
over 100k. This basically means you have infinite money. The real
constraint on your resources is that you always need to back-track
(the game is a straight line) to get to a shop, so you need to
make sure you stock up beforehand.</p>

<p>Other parts of the meta-game are a little annoying. For example,
you have an incredibly large party and balancing their levels
becomes very frustrating and I gave up around 15 hours in and just
stuck with one group. The exploration of dungeons can be very
annoying too. One of the prices of the lushness is that almost
every area of a big dungeon looks identical and every one is
either a literal maze or puzzle. These are fine in moderation, but
this game does it too much and rewards the exploration too
little. (There are very useful items in chests, for example.)</p>

<p>The largest part of the game is the battle system.</p>

<p>They do a good job unfolding the battle system with the Party
Level system that advances at fixed story parts and gives you new
challenges and options. In a nutshell, it works like this: each
character has their own turn that lasts a fixed amount of time,
they have some amount of Tactical Time before their clock ticks,
and movement/attacks take certain amounts of time. Time is
essentially your MP-like resource that controls what you
do. Special attacks are divided into dark and light categories
which you can only join when you are in light or dark
areas. Enemies are affect by the light too. It's a neat little
thing. As your party level goes up, some of these get more
complicated. For example, at the beginning tactical time is
infinite and at the end it is zero. At the end, the speed of your
characters just goes up a lot so you can get things done faster. I
would said it is almost too fast at the end... I accidentally ran
past enemies a lot.</p>

<p>Overall, the battle system was satisfying, but it has a lot of
flaws. First, there are things that are too cumbersome to actually
use, like switching special attack sets in battle. I'm amazed they
didn't bind that to the triggers. Second, the layout of the
characters, enemies, and arena are few in number in each area of
the game... on the order of two or three. This means once you
discover how to beat that enemy configuration, you can do the
exact same thing again. It gets old and makes you want to just run
past the enemies so you don't have to fight them. Third, there is
a single strategy that works for all random encounters and one
that is almost the same that works for all bosses. For normal
enemies, just do lots of little combos and take them out one by
one. For bosses, build up Harmony Chains (big combos) with two
characters and have the other one on healing duty. This makes lots
of fights incredibly rote and frankly a little
boring. Nevertheless, each session of playing had a significant
section where I enjoyed the smashing of buttons and increasing of
numbers.</p>

<p>I actually fell asleep during this game more than once. One time I
was even in battle and fell asleep briefly, then woke up and
survived the battle with the one character that wasn't dead yet. I
think in that case it says more about me than the game.</p>

<p>I thought about quitting the game a few times, but ultimately
decided to continue. I'd say it was worth it, but would have been
better if the game were shorter (or just better, of course.) I
doubt I will play this again. And so, I can't recommend it very
highly, despite being a reasonable game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
