<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Assassin's Creed | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/assassin-s-creed/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-16T22:42:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Assassin's Creed (X360, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/20/Game--Assassin-s-Creed--X360--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/20/Game--Assassin-s-Creed--X360--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played this for the Xbox 360. What a disappointment. The
most interesting part of the game were the twenty-ish minutes of
cutscenes, and even they weren't that great. The best thing about
the game is the fiction that isn't even in the game, but mentioned
and <a href="http://www.computerandvideogames.com/article.php?id=175552">explained elsewhere</a>.</p>

<p>The main problem with the game is that the story and scenario are
totally inconsistent with the gameplay. Altair is supposed be a
stealthy assassin who doesn't resort to crude violence, but the
game requires it from you. There are many times where to advance
you must either fight a half-dozen guards to unlock some scholars
to get through something "stealthily" or fight a dozen guards to
get through violently. There is often no way to actually sneak in
or save the citizen that unlocks the scholars (which doesn't make
sense anyway, btw) non-violently. But it doesn't even matter
anyways, because there would be no reward for doing that. The
combat is mindlessly easy, so you can just blaze through dozens of
guards. If you listen to the advice of the game or the story, you
will be tempted to act cautiously, walk rather than run, flee from
guards, etc, but that just makes the game slow and painful; you
can get the same things accomplished easier by ignoring that
advice. It's not even as if you could create a challenge for
yourself by playing it the "real" way, because the game forces you
out of the assassin's mindset many times. The ending is the most
absurd form of this where you have to battle through multiple
armies.</p>

<p>An equally big problem with the game is that the main mechanics
are just not fun. The combat is so easy that it isn't fun. The
things that are designed to make it fun (the different moves)
aren't necessary and the controls are terrible for them
anyway. You can counter every single attack and you never need to
use any weapon other than the sword. Saving citizens is annoying
because they all say the same thing and you have to use the stupid
combat system. Interrogation is lame because you just slam the
punch button. The races are frustrating because the movement
controls are so horrible.</p>

<p>The only fun parts to me were climbing up viewpoints and the
pickpocketing. Yet, both were ruined in some way. The climbing
controls are horrendous. First, you just hold two buttons and
point. Second, you wiggle endlessly because half of the time
Altair just hangs on in one spot because the camera isn't angled
just the right way for him to move. Third, Altair jumps off the
wall for no reason because obviously you meant to jump off the
building, not to the next ledge. Fourth, every building was
basically the same after a while. Nevertheless, I can honestly say
I enjoyed looking for a good way up to a view point then getting
the spin once I was on top. The pickpocketing was just as bad. I
would've liked it to have been hard because there were guards
watching, or complicated paths, or something. But they were all
either mindlessly easy or hard because stupid beggars and crazy
people were in your way. Ugh!</p>

<p>Let me nitpick more. Beggars! I hate them. They are begging for
you to break the Assassin's Creed and just kill them. Crazy people
punching you and breaking your cover for no reason! They make no
sense! Why don't they attack normal people? Why are they even
there?  Such a ridiculous "gamey" thing in an otherwise reasonable
world. Flags! Pfff!</p>

<p>One final complaint. The game robs you of your agency in an
obscene way. The game asks you to follow the Assassin's Creed and
be discrete, but of course you can't follow that to win because of
the mechanics as mentioned above. But similarly, there are many
times when you control Altair, but you don't control whether he
follows the Creed in your opinion. For example, after every
interrogation he murders the person interrogated. There is almost
never a reason to do this and it seems to violate the rules about
killing innocents, but you can't have a say, because it is a
cut-scene. My wife was sitting by me when this happened and I
complained and she said, "Well, you're in the simulation anyways,
so it's already decided." That's true and it is exactly the
problem. If this is really a simulation, then it should just be a
"ride", but once you can control Altair, you should be able to
control everything. At first, I thought that the Animus concept
would be a great way to explain the gamey things, but it just
became absurd.</p>

<p>I do /not/ recommend this game. You will get what is good out of
it by watching the cut scenes or reading the story online.</p>

<p>Repetitive, boring slog.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
