<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-16T11:12:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Majestic, starring Jim Carrey (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fine little romance. The most interesting thing about it
is how this, and other movies (like the Chaplin biopic) rewrite the
history of the Communist/Hollywood controversy of the 50s to play
out the way that modern Hollywood people wish that it would. It
makes me think that maybe some people wouldn't realize that
Hollywood didn't really "win". There's a lot of Hollywood
dopey-eye-ism in the movie, actually. It reminds me a lot of
Hugo.</p>

<p>I think the movie might have been improved by making it more
ambiguous about whether Jim Carrey really lost his memory.</p>

<p>The reviews are interesting. I think Roger Ebert saw what it was
going for and believed in it. The speech at the end was a bit too
dopey for my taste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Alice in Wonderland, directed by Tim Burton (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My little sister wanted to watch this movie tonight, so we watched
it together. I thought it was very cool and pretty trippy. I don't
think Johnny Depp was very good in it though... he was too much
like <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow, but looked really weird and had a funny
voice. The slight attraction between him and Alice was creepy
too. I think I liked Helena Bonham Carter and Anne Hathaway the
best, they were just so odd. It was cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For about a month I've been working on 5-14X (Necrosis). It was
very, very hard. You had to go down a shaft, across a wide area
with tiny platforms, then up a shaft, back down, back across, back
up, and then across the same area but now with disappearing
platforms. All while being pursued by floating monsters and all
the shafts had maggot piles getting you.</p>

<p>Today I was playing with my son and after about 15 minutes of
doing okay, I say, "Well, I think this should be the last try
before we go to church." He says, "Okay! Let's DO it!" Then, of
course, I do it. I just needed a cheerleader.</p>

<p>I got 38.00 seconds when the par time was 60.00 seconds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Katniss destroying the Holo was pretty stupid.</p>

<p>Woah, Prim dying with the same trap that Gale was talking about.</p>

<p>Katniss awakening in a hospital and not really being involved in
capturing Snow is disappointing.</p>

<p>Snow's conversation with Katniss: very believable.</p>

<p>Appalling that Katniss would initiate more Hunger Games. Although,
since they never talked about it happening, I wonder if it did
given that Coin was killed?</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the books and thought they ended well. I thought
the second book and the first part of the third were the high
points for the series.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like the idea of the bargain between District 13 and the Capitol.</p>

<p>The militarism of District 13 is fascinating and reasonable, given
their past.</p>

<p>The books have always been a thin allegory for violence in media,
but having Katniss literally be a movie star is a bit
ridiculous. I'm glad that the characters realize this
too.</p>

<p>It's funny because when she's in the field, it's like she's in the
Games again, but the cameras are now obvious rather than hidden
everywhere.</p>

<p>The real moment of Katniss' catch phrase is totally epic. A little
teary.</p>

<p>The propaganda war is pretty brilliant and fits really well with
the media theme of the books.</p>

<p>I find the term "Mockingjay" used for Katniss incredibly silly and
aggravating.</p>

<p>Katniss' impassioned speech before she gets shot. :)</p>

<p>I have to admit, turning the raid on the Capitol into a recreation
of the Games is a clever way to stick to the formula.</p>

<p>I'm stopping for the day right when Peeta shows up in the
Capitol... tense!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
