<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-04T23:17:08-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played 5-19X for 35 minutes today. It was brutal, but I got
further than ever before... I got to the top of the tower of
disappearing blocks.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read most of the first chapter today, although I decided it was
a bit long and I should break my reading into smaller chunks. It
was very interesting to read about the philosophical origins of
the art. The idea that entertainment before was more loud and that
ballet was distinguished by silence is cool. The Feuillet notation
is crazy to read... it looks so meaningless to me. The debate
about whether dance should be considered part of music is curious,
especially given modern university organization. Finally, reading
about all the ways male dance was preferred to female dance is
very strange to a modern, such as myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the introduction today. I was very interested to learn that
the current ballet canon is very Russian, but made by a French guy,
and very late in the life of ballet. The concept of there being
very little data about the past of ballet is curious. I like the
idea that the story of this book will focus on the steps and forms
themselves. It seems like a style I would be most intrigued by.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: It's Kind of a Funny Story, starring Keir Gilchrist (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had no expectations about this movie. It was pretty cute and
interesting. I think depressed people are stupid, so I didn't
really like the part of it that justified them, although a big part
of it didn't (Craig's conclusion is that depression is
self-indulgent.) I though Emma Roberts' character was very cute,
although we don't learn anything about her, other than that she's
cute and quirky. The final sequence in the movie where we see what
Craig does with his life is more interesting than a lot of moments
in the movie. The character of Bobby is actually sad, but again,
everyone in the movie is just a caricature with no substance, so
we don't really know what his feels truly are. The movie is
annoying in that way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deathsmiles (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the first games that my son would specifically
request. He hasn't in a long time, but wanted to today. I played
through it with three continues (one on Tyrannosatan). It was
fun. I didn't do too well, but I did get the extend during the
castle stage.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
