<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T22:04:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dear John, starring Channing Tatum (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was suggested by Netflix and I wasn't sure I would like
it. As we watched it, it was pretty cute and touching. It was very
reminiscent of how my wife and I were when we first met... fell in
love over the course of 10 days and then didn't see each for
months. I was really surprised when she dumped him and then years
and years past... it was a very depressing and unhappy ending.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We finished watching it.</p>

<p>The LP was done really really well. I appreciated
SuperGreatFriend's commentary as he went, livening up the slow
moments, like long combat sequences. He had some really funny
things too... like singing into the mic at the Galaxy of
Terror. Priceless! He was very thoughtful in other things, like
not showing cards with spoilers until the end, etc.</p>

<p>The game itself was really fascinating. The reveals at the end
were wild. As crazy as this game is in the beginning... it is SO
Japanese in the insanity that takes place at the end of the
game. Awesome.</p>

<p>I listened to the WAHP interview with SWERY again and found it
cool. I also noticed during the credits that there is a character
for every letter in the alphabet! Cool!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the best moments was when he finds the card of York's
father, Brian Xander Morgan, and nonchalantly says "But you can
call him Xander, that's what everyone calls him." My wife and I
burst out laughing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Majestic, starring Jim Carrey (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fine little romance. The most interesting thing about it
is how this, and other movies (like the Chaplin biopic) rewrite the
history of the Communist/Hollywood controversy of the 50s to play
out the way that modern Hollywood people wish that it would. It
makes me think that maybe some people wouldn't realize that
Hollywood didn't really "win". There's a lot of Hollywood
dopey-eye-ism in the movie, actually. It reminds me a lot of
Hugo.</p>

<p>I think the movie might have been improved by making it more
ambiguous about whether Jim Carrey really lost his memory.</p>

<p>The reviews are interesting. I think Roger Ebert saw what it was
going for and believed in it. The speech at the end was a bit too
dopey for my taste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Alice in Wonderland, directed by Tim Burton (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My little sister wanted to watch this movie tonight, so we watched
it together. I thought it was very cool and pretty trippy. I don't
think Johnny Depp was very good in it though... he was too much
like <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow, but looked really weird and had a funny
voice. The slight attraction between him and Alice was creepy
too. I think I liked Helena Bonham Carter and Anne Hathaway the
best, they were just so odd. It was cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
