<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-10T00:20:47-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
"Inn" to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I've been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There's just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one "episode" per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I'm looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don't really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It's the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful, although a little bit of the time
I felt like I was losing because I couldn't target the thing I
wanted. The graphics are pretty good, although the characters are
verrry anime-y and from some angles their clothes really clash
with their faces. (For example, the guy on the computer screen
that Edge talks to.) The controls are responsive.  Although the
camera controls are a little too "tight" for my taste so far. I
got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I think the
problem is that the world is so "bright" that it's hard to notice
something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of the time was
spent in videos, so I don't really have a good feel for the game
yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided based on some consultation with forum posts, etc, that I
will watch a long play of the game, rather than play through it
myself. The gameplay is so bad and I want to see everything, but
don't want to play with a walkthrough. It's more efficient to just
watch it. I found two playthroughs: <a href="http://forums.somethingawful.com/showthread.php?threadid%3D3368004">a 100% playthrough</a> and [[http://www.giantbomb.com/forums/deadly-premonition/5058/endurance-run-download-urls/417644/][a
GiantBomb Endurance Run]]. I'm not sure which one will be better, so
I'll try a little of both. I intend on writing about the game as I
watch these, as if it were me playing. We'll see how that goes...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game because I heard so many good things about it on
podcasts, particularly the "WARNING: A Huge Podcast"
special. Before playing it, I'm slightly worried that the gameplay
will be too bad for me to deal with and the M rating will be too
appropriate so I won't want to. (I don't want to play M games
where you kill humans and where there is really bad language or
nudity. Games like Bayonetta don't bother me because there's just
inhuman gore, and while it and Vanquish had a few curse words, it
was pretty tame. I almost didn't finish Battlefield 3 because of
all the bad language.) Anyways, I bought it pretty cheap, so I'm
giving it a chance, but if it doesn't take me in one night, I
don't think I'll keep playing it.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour. The world of the game is incredibly
charming. The talking in the car is genius. The realistic scale of
the world is really bizarre, but neat. There are many flourishes
on top of things that other games would have and not really think
about. For example, you can shave in the bathroom, the
conversation over breakfast where the lady couldn't hear you
correctly, the strange comments about every person York meets,
it's all fascinating and surreal. My wife sat with me and was
entranced by the characters.</p>

<p>The production value is so bad though. The modeling and texture
work has tons of problems and there is severe dead face. The
crying is atrocious. The translation is pretty poor with some
strange too literal phrases. (For example, a gas station is called
as ガソリンスタンド(ga-so-re-n su-ta-n-do, i.e. gasoline stand)
and someone in town tells you where the "gas stand" is.)</p>

<p>The game play is bad so far. The walking is really awkward. You
don't really have camera control, but can almost turn your head or
something, but it is so fast, it's disorienting. The combat is
incredibly boring so far but also really hard to control. The
lock-on is necessary because the reticule movement is so chunky,
but it's also not very effective. There's not a good system for
keeping you informed of what enemies are around you. Based on
advice from the aforementioned podcasts, I put it on Easy mode to
avoid these. problems.</p>

<p>The quick time events with the ax guy were weird. The driving
instructions were totally over the top. My wife and I looked at
each other aghast when we saw them. It took a long time to get out
of the parking lot and get used to driving with the controls.</p>

<p>It's a strange, surreal game. The fidelity is so bad, I don't
think I'll be grossed out. I get the impression there will be a
lot of jump scares. I'm slightly nervous that there will be too
much to do and explore and I'll get bogged down and intimidated
doing it. But I'll give it more time.</p>

<p>Total: 01:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played three levels tonight. It was pretty fun. My wife and I
had a bit of a disagreement about what was fun about the game. She
really likes collecting everything and exploring the area, trying
to do harder things. In contrast, I find that annoying and prefer
to just go through the obstacle course as fast as possible. But,
the secret of marital bliss is she tells me what to do, and I do
it, so I repented. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
