<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:16:43-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game because I heard so many good things about it on
podcasts, particularly the "WARNING: A Huge Podcast"
special. Before playing it, I'm slightly worried that the gameplay
will be too bad for me to deal with and the M rating will be too
appropriate so I won't want to. (I don't want to play M games
where you kill humans and where there is really bad language or
nudity. Games like Bayonetta don't bother me because there's just
inhuman gore, and while it and Vanquish had a few curse words, it
was pretty tame. I almost didn't finish Battlefield 3 because of
all the bad language.) Anyways, I bought it pretty cheap, so I'm
giving it a chance, but if it doesn't take me in one night, I
don't think I'll keep playing it.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour. The world of the game is incredibly
charming. The talking in the car is genius. The realistic scale of
the world is really bizarre, but neat. There are many flourishes
on top of things that other games would have and not really think
about. For example, you can shave in the bathroom, the
conversation over breakfast where the lady couldn't hear you
correctly, the strange comments about every person York meets,
it's all fascinating and surreal. My wife sat with me and was
entranced by the characters.</p>

<p>The production value is so bad though. The modeling and texture
work has tons of problems and there is severe dead face. The
crying is atrocious. The translation is pretty poor with some
strange too literal phrases. (For example, a gas station is called
as ガソリンスタンド(ga-so-re-n su-ta-n-do, i.e. gasoline stand)
and someone in town tells you where the "gas stand" is.)</p>

<p>The game play is bad so far. The walking is really awkward. You
don't really have camera control, but can almost turn your head or
something, but it is so fast, it's disorienting. The combat is
incredibly boring so far but also really hard to control. The
lock-on is necessary because the reticule movement is so chunky,
but it's also not very effective. There's not a good system for
keeping you informed of what enemies are around you. Based on
advice from the aforementioned podcasts, I put it on Easy mode to
avoid these. problems.</p>

<p>The quick time events with the ax guy were weird. The driving
instructions were totally over the top. My wife and I looked at
each other aghast when we saw them. It took a long time to get out
of the parking lot and get used to driving with the controls.</p>

<p>It's a strange, surreal game. The fidelity is so bad, I don't
think I'll be grossed out. I get the impression there will be a
lot of jump scares. I'm slightly nervous that there will be too
much to do and explore and I'll get bogged down and intimidated
doing it. But I'll give it more time.</p>

<p>Total: 01:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played three levels tonight. It was pretty fun. My wife and I
had a bit of a disagreement about what was fun about the game. She
really likes collecting everything and exploring the area, trying
to do harder things. In contrast, I find that annoying and prefer
to just go through the obstacle course as fast as possible. But,
the secret of marital bliss is she tells me what to do, and I do
it, so I repented. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finished getting As or above on every event in Pac-Man CE
DX. My ranking across the whole game is 5,100/245,281 or in the
top 2.07%. It's a really fun game. I think I like the normal mode
the most. The time trial is fun, but I think it's too easy to
cheese out and ignore the ghosts and just take shortcuts, so it
eliminates a bit of the unique fun of CE-DX. Such an awesome game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/01/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/01/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got the Championship I Ghost Combo... but I got LAST place:
9,483/9,483!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I still need to get a gold on the Formula GT expert race (I
currently have a silver) and the rest of the special events. I've
decided to not do the A-Spec Endurance races at all, because they
are insulting. I tried doing the GT race this morning, but had
monkeys climbing all over me... which was very difficult.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
