<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T00:07:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/20/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/20/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about forty minutes tonight. I tried using the
Gamecube controller because I thought it would be easier to make
small movements when dodging and I could aim the cross-hair at the
center once and for all (given that the boss doesn't move much)
and then dodge. I was able to do about as well as usual, but not
better. I don't think it was worth it, so I went back to the
normal method. This is a very hard battle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I beat the level---The Coil. It was horrible. The first time
I beat it---after almost an hour---I was 1.02 seconds too late to
get an A+. I gave it another 15 minutes and got about 7 seconds
under the required time. Go!</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for another hour and a half later in the day beat a few
more levels. 5-19X was destroying me though. I have 5-19X, 5-20X,
Four Letter Word in Cotton Alley, and all the Dark World of
Dr. Fetus' castle and Cotton Alley left before I do everything in
the game. Exhausting. This game makes my hands hurt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to retire this game for a while. I haven't really
been playing that much even though I have it scheduled and kind of
want to. I think I need to start again from the beginning with no
assists. I only have the Endurance Races, the Formula GT races,
and the Special Events to get Golds on, but I don't want to spend
the time on the Endurance ones and the Formula/Special events are
so technical, I think my skills just aren't up to the task. I
think I need to re-learn to play. I'm going to put it on my
schedule to play it again in January and give it another try. I
can't believe how much and how long I've played this game. It's
sooo good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dear John, starring Channing Tatum (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was suggested by Netflix and I wasn't sure I would like
it. As we watched it, it was pretty cute and touching. It was very
reminiscent of how my wife and I were when we first met... fell in
love over the course of 10 days and then didn't see each for
months. I was really surprised when she dumped him and then years
and years past... it was a very depressing and unhappy ending.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We finished watching it.</p>

<p>The LP was done really really well. I appreciated
SuperGreatFriend's commentary as he went, livening up the slow
moments, like long combat sequences. He had some really funny
things too... like singing into the mic at the Galaxy of
Terror. Priceless! He was very thoughtful in other things, like
not showing cards with spoilers until the end, etc.</p>

<p>The game itself was really fascinating. The reveals at the end
were wild. As crazy as this game is in the beginning... it is SO
Japanese in the insanity that takes place at the end of the
game. Awesome.</p>

<p>I listened to the WAHP interview with SWERY again and found it
cool. I also noticed during the credits that there is a character
for every letter in the alphabet! Cool!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
