<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-06T22:58:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for about two hours and beat the rest of the factory
levels. We discovered a way to grind for balloons but decided not
to. We traded our time for just using a cheat code that gives
infinite balloons. It's amazing how much more fun the game is
now, because we can play a little less cautiously and give my
wife more opportunities to do the difficult platforming sequences
where she used to just climb on my back. I think that might be
why we liked Mario so much more, because the Desert Life grind is
so effective.</p>

<p>Time: 5:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We tried to play again tonight and only beat one factory level
then decided to try to grind for balloons, but there's no good
opportunities to, so we gave up that for a bit and did something
else.</p>

<p>Time: 3:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played a few levels tonight and finished Area 6. I found a lot
of the levels to be really difficult to have two people, because
they use forced scrolling and the timed barrel jumps, which
require a lot more synchronization than is reasonable between two
people. Overall, the game seems to have multiplayer as an after
thought, especially with the varied capabilities of the two
players. The boss of Area 6 was very exciting to beat with my
wife, we were yelling and jumping out of our seats as we
recognized tells of the boss.</p>

<p>Time: 2:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/20/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/20/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about forty minutes tonight. I tried using the
Gamecube controller because I thought it would be easier to make
small movements when dodging and I could aim the cross-hair at the
center once and for all (given that the boss doesn't move much)
and then dodge. I was able to do about as well as usual, but not
better. I don't think it was worth it, so I went back to the
normal method. This is a very hard battle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I beat the level---The Coil. It was horrible. The first time
I beat it---after almost an hour---I was 1.02 seconds too late to
get an A+. I gave it another 15 minutes and got about 7 seconds
under the required time. Go!</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for another hour and a half later in the day beat a few
more levels. 5-19X was destroying me though. I have 5-19X, 5-20X,
Four Letter Word in Cotton Alley, and all the Dark World of
Dr. Fetus' castle and Cotton Alley left before I do everything in
the game. Exhausting. This game makes my hands hurt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
