<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-21T22:28:01-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: It's Kind of a Funny Story, starring Keir Gilchrist (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had no expectations about this movie. It was pretty cute and
interesting. I think depressed people are stupid, so I didn't
really like the part of it that justified them, although a big part
of it didn't (Craig's conclusion is that depression is
self-indulgent.) I though Emma Roberts' character was very cute,
although we don't learn anything about her, other than that she's
cute and quirky. The final sequence in the movie where we see what
Craig does with his life is more interesting than a lot of moments
in the movie. The character of Bobby is actually sad, but again,
everyone in the movie is just a caricature with no substance, so
we don't really know what his feels truly are. The movie is
annoying in that way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deathsmiles (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the first games that my son would specifically
request. He hasn't in a long time, but wanted to today. I played
through it with three continues (one on Tyrannosatan). It was
fun. I didn't do too well, but I did get the extend during the
castle stage.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for an hour and a half-ish. We beat the game! The
final boss and the last rocket sequence was pretty tough and my
wife was getting very frustrated, but we eventually did it.</p>

<p>The Nintendo Channel clocks our total time at 20 hours and 52
minutes (I haven't been keeping track of our game play that long.)</p>

<p>We decided that the game is a lot more sloppy in many ways
compared to NSMBW, but that we had a lot of fun, especially once
we got infinite lives. We don't love the game enough to try to get
all the bonuses to unlock the hidden temple, so that's that.</p>

<p>I like platformers, but I like playing games with my wife more.</p>

<p>Time: 7:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for an hour and beat the first three levels of
World 8. There was a normal platforming level (although it had
lots of breaking platforms), then a rocket level, then a mine-cart
level. The rocket levels are so terrible because they are just
memorization mazes with an awful control scheme. It was
annoying. But eventually I got in the zone and did it. I think my
wife was a bit mad because she kept trying and dying every other
time.</p>

<p>Time: 6:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for about two hours and beat the rest of the factory
levels. We discovered a way to grind for balloons but decided not
to. We traded our time for just using a cheat code that gives
infinite balloons. It's amazing how much more fun the game is
now, because we can play a little less cautiously and give my
wife more opportunities to do the difficult platforming sequences
where she used to just climb on my back. I think that might be
why we liked Mario so much more, because the Desert Life grind is
so effective.</p>

<p>Time: 5:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
