<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2010 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2010/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-28T22:39:53-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like the idea of the bargain between District 13 and the Capitol.</p>

<p>The militarism of District 13 is fascinating and reasonable, given
their past.</p>

<p>The books have always been a thin allegory for violence in media,
but having Katniss literally be a movie star is a bit
ridiculous. I'm glad that the characters realize this
too.</p>

<p>It's funny because when she's in the field, it's like she's in the
Games again, but the cameras are now obvious rather than hidden
everywhere.</p>

<p>The real moment of Katniss' catch phrase is totally epic. A little
teary.</p>

<p>The propaganda war is pretty brilliant and fits really well with
the media theme of the books.</p>

<p>I find the term "Mockingjay" used for Katniss incredibly silly and
aggravating.</p>

<p>Katniss' impassioned speech before she gets shot. :)</p>

<p>I have to admit, turning the raid on the Capitol into a recreation
of the Games is a clever way to stick to the formula.</p>

<p>I'm stopping for the day right when Peeta shows up in the
Capitol... tense!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Chronicles of Narnia: The Voyage of the Dawn Treader (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/17/Movie--The-Chronicles-of-Narnia--The-Voyage-of-the-Dawn-Treader--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/17/Movie--The-Chronicles-of-Narnia--The-Voyage-of-the-Dawn-Treader--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie is like a video game: lots of sets with a few scenes set
there before they move on to the next, fairly disconnected
event. It has very high production value. The acting can be a bit
bad. Eustace is pretty terrible, especially in the
beginning. Caspian is quite hammy. Lucy is probably the best player
in the film.</p>

<p>I think the story of this movie/book is not as strong as the other
ones, because the ending is very uneventful. You think they're
fighting fear itself, but there's no real pay-off because the enemy
is never really named or described in a meaningful way.</p>

<p>The movie's version of Eustace during back from being a dragon was
much less epic than I remember it being in the book, which was my
favourite part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/07/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/07/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The pot lady is so ridiculous!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>New overall ranking: 2,035/249,990 --- 0.81%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The episode we watched tonight was amazing because he said that he
played through the entire game again because he forgot to record
the last segment and so lost the progress. It's amazing that he's
so patient and dedicated enough to do that. Also, last time he
showed some really funny clips from Attack of the Killer Tomatoes,
including a really great scene where a whole bunch of people were
squeezing into a tiny room. It was hilarious!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
