<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1998 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1998/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-11T13:12:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Tomba! (PS1, 1998)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/09/Game--Tomba---PS1--1998--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/09/Game--Tomba---PS1--1998--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've recently played through Tomba! over the past few weeks as my
"main" game.</p>

<p>This game defies categorization.</p>

<p>It's primarily a platforming game with a few accoutrements to
that basic experience: you get a number of different weapons, some
speed bonuses in form of new pants, and some utility items like a
grappling hook and a parasol (so you fall slower.) While the world
and gameplay in primarily 2D, you often need to jump into the
"background" and onto a different plane. Sometimes when you go
into the background the camera rotates to a different slice of a
3D area you're exploring. It's very neat mechanically.</p>

<p>The other aspect of the game is the mission system. As you
interact with the world and individuals in it, they inform you of
a problem. If and when you solve it, you gain AP and unlock
potentially more missions. Some of them are required, but
definitely not all of them. There are 130 in the game; I found 106
and cleared 87 of them. (I ended with 755,900 AP. I reckon this
isn't very much.)</p>

<p>Overall the game is very fun and unique. I imagine that Zelda II:
The Adventure of Link could have been like this game and moved the
Zelda series in a good direction rather the dead-end /Zelda II/
was. /Tomba!/ took me 4 hours and 27 minutes on the clock to beat,
but I would guess I probably spent closer to 2.5 times that amount
of time due to the difficulty of the platforming and bosses that
required reloading my save file.</p>

<p>I easily recommend it. Despite having typical PS1 loading time
problems, it's definitely worth it. I'm excited to play the sequel
eventually.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kuch Kuch Hota Hai (1998)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/23/Movie--Kuch-Kuch-Hota-Hai--1998--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-23T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/23/Movie--Kuch-Kuch-Hota-Hai--1998--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kuch Kuch Hota Hai, from the team that created Kabhi Kushi Kabhie
Gham..., is an exceedingly cute movie. Starring is Shahrukh Khan,
Kajol, and Rani Mukherjee.</p>

<p>I thought the story, acting, and songs were great. Actually, the
songs were fabulous. I have a collection of CDs with songs from
Shahrukh movies, and I loved all the songs from this movie before I
saw it.</p>

<p>Shahrukh is handsome and well dressed in the movie, although he
reminds me a frog in general. Kajol was beautiful in the second
half and her wedding gowns were amazing. Rani was beautiful in the
beginning, although I think she looks better without her "modern
ideas."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
