<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Radilgy | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/radilgy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-30T00:46:00-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Radilgy (DC, 2006) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/26/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--1/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/26/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>As I mentioned, I've been playing Radilgy on my Dreamcast. In my
last post, I wrote about how I wasn't sure how much longer I would
play it. Well, I think I'm pretty satisfied now.</p>

<p>I know that I /could/ get better, but I think I would rather move
on. In the past week, since my first win, I've beaten it three
more times. My first win was on Easy with 5 lives per continue. My
second was on Normal with 5 lives per continue. My third was on
Normal with 4 lives per continue. And my fourth (completed about 5
minutes ago) was on Normal with 3 lives per continue (the default
setting.)</p>

<p>I started keeping records of each play-through:
- Feb 19 - E-123, 6 continues, 5 lives per
- Feb 21 - N-W, 8 continues, 5 lives per
- Feb 21 - N-W, 8 continues, 4 lives per --- Died on last boss
(final form)
- Feb 21 - N-W, 8 continues, 4 lives per --- Died on last boss
(one hit before final form)
- Feb 22 - N-W, 8 continues, 4 lives per, 3 left
- Feb 23 - N-W, 8 continues, 3 lives per --- Died on last
mini-boss [after controller breaking for a bit! arghh!]
- Feb 23 - N-W, 1:3 boss, 2:4 pre-mini, 3:4 mini, 4:4 post-mini,
5:4 hell, 6:4 boss, 7:5 mini, 8:5 post-mini, D:5 final-first
- Feb 24 - N-W, 1:3 boss, 2:4 mini, 3:4 hell, 4:4 boss, 5:5 mini,
6:5 post-mini, 7:5 final-first, 8:5 final-second, D:5
final-second (1/3 health)
- Feb 25 - N-W, 8:3 mini, 7:3 boss, 6:3 boss, 5:4 mini, 4:4 hell,
3:4 boss, 2:4 boss, 1:5 mini, D:5 post-mini
- Feb 25 - N-W, 8:2 boss, 7:3 post-mini, 6:3 post-mini, 5:3 boss,
4:4 mini, 3:4 boss, 2:4 boss, 1:5 post-mini, D:5 post-mini
- Feb 25 - N-W, 8:3 post-mini, 7:3 boss, 6:4 mini, 5:4 boss, 4:4
boss, 3:5 mini, 2:5 post-mini, 1:5 final-first, D:5 final-second
(2/3 health)
- Feb 25 - N-W, 8:3 boss, 7:4 mini, 6:4 mini, 5:4 pre-boss, 4:4
boss, 3:5 mini, 2:5 pre-boss, 1:5 final-first, D:5 final-second
- Feb 26 - N-W, [L] 9-1:1 boss, 9-2:3 post-mini, 9-3:3 post-mini,
8-1:3 post-mini, 8-2:3 boss, 8-3:3 boss, 7-1:3 boss, 7-2:4 mini,
7-3:4 mini, 6-1:4 mini, 6-2:4 post-mini, 6-3:4 post-mini, 5-1:4
post-mini, 5-2:4 boss, 5-3:4 boss, 4-1:4 boss, 4-2:5 mini, 4-3:5
mini, 3-1:5 mini, 3-2:5 post-mini, 3-3:5 post-mini, 2-1:5
post-mini, 2-2:5 final-first, 2-3:5 final-first, 1-1:5
final-first, 1-2: 5 final-second, 1-3: 5 final-second
- Feb 26 - N-123, [L] 9-1:1 pre-boss, 9-2:1 boss, 9-3:3 mini,
8-1:3 mini, 8-2:3 boss, 8-3:3 boss, 7-1:4 mini, 7-2:4 mini,
7-3:4 mini, 6-1:4 mini, 6-2:4 post-mini, 6-3:4 post-mini, 5-1:4
boss, 5-2:4 boss, 5-3:5 mini, 4-1:5 mini, 4-2:5 post-mini, 4-3:5
post-mini, 3-1:5 final-first, 3-2:5 final-first, 3-3:5
final-first, 2-1:5 final-second, 2-2:5 final-second, 2-3:5
final-second, 1-1:5 final-second, 1-2:5 final-second, 1-3:5
final-second [sliver left]
- Feb 26 - N-123, [L] 9-1:2 pre-boss, 9-2:3 mini, 9-3:3 pre-boss,
8-1:3 boss, 8-2:3 boss, 8-3:4 mini, 7-1:4 mini, 7-2:4 post,
7-3:4 post, 6-1:4 boss, 6-2:4 boss, 6-3:4 boss, 5-1:4 boss,
5-2:4 boss, 5-3:5 pre, 4-1:5 mini, 4-2:5 mini, 4-3:5 post-mini,
3-1:5 post-mini, 3-2:5 final1, 3-3:5 final1, 2-1:5 final1, 2-2:5
final2, 2-3:5 final2, 1-1:5 final2, 1-2:5 final2, WIN!</p>

<p>I started recording just wins with the configuration. Then I added
when I died. Then I tracked when I spent each /i/th
continue. (I switched to when I spent continue number /i/,
because it was easier to eye-ball.) I recorded particularly
depressing losses when the final form of the final boss was almost
dead. Finally today, I kept track of when I lost each life. Also
today I switched from using the Wide shot to using the 123
Laser. My impression is that one weapon isn't more powerful than
another, but that they represent different play styles. I realized
today that I was focusing my shots at a single enemy typically, so
I might as well use the weapon that corresponds to that style. The
main difference I observed was being able to take care of the boss
a little faster.</p>

<p>This process I've just gone through---training and recording
performance---makes me think about features I would like in a
shooter. Here's a few:
- <em>Data!</em> I wish the game would keep track of all the data I was
tracking by hand so I could find out where I was dying a lot and
where I needed to practice. It would even be nicer if the
granularity of this data was very fine; for example, I'd like to
know that I always die on the third attack of the fourth
mini-boss.
- <em>Progress-based Scoreboard</em> I'd like to be able to sort my
scoreboard (+ the public one in modern games) by how far in the
game/level the score was completed at. For example, I'm
currently working on 1cc-ing Ikaruga and doing chapter 3
Dot-Eater style. I'm not playing for score, so I'd like to be
able to (at a glance) see if I've gotten further than I have
before.
- <em>Practice modes</em> Most games are pretty good about allowing you
to practice chapters you've unlocked and some (Ikaruga on
Gamecube, for example) allow you to practice individual chapter
stages. I'd like this to be more common and with finer
granularity.
- <em>Trainer</em> Even better than a practice mode would be a mode where
the game planned your practice regime based on your previous
game performance. It would be rad also if you could loop bosses
or bullet patterns until you got through them without having to
go through all of the surrounding game.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, there's something very satisfying about playing the
beginning of a game so many times you can destroy it without
mercy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Radilgy (DC, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/19/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/19/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently bought a Dreamcast. The very first game I played was
The Typing of the Dead, but I only played it for a few minutes to
show to Wifey. The very first game I played in depth is &lt;a
Radilgy, a shmup.</p>

<p>The art style is really unique and good looking. The controllers
are quite tight. The weapons are fun. (I really like the lasers
and the bubbles. I play most of the time with the lasers though.)
The shield, sword, and force field are nice touches.</p>

<p>The fourth and fifth levels have these segments that require
spamming the force field over and over and over. (At least, that's
how I do it!) It is pretty insane. Each of the end bosses is
really fun. The mid-level bosses are a little repetitive, because
they have the same core attacks, but they fit well and create a
nice feel for the game. (As I understand from the Wikipedia story,
those are the terrorists and the end bosses are warped
robots.)</p>

<p>My one complaint with the game is that the graphics are so
bright and there is so much flashing that it becomes hard to look
at after a while. I've been playing in 20-ish minute chunks then
doing something else.</p>

<p>I just beat it on Easy with 6 credits and 5 life credits using the
laser. I've been working on a number of different
configurations. I don't like it when shmups have so many options,
because I don't have a good grasp of what the "right" options
are. There is also a big temptation to make it easier, etc. I
wonder, should I try to 1cc it on Easy, then Normal, then Hard? Or
just got right to a different difficulty, etc? I can use 1 credit
to get to the middle of stage 3 (the mini-boss) on Normal. I've
gotten through stages 1 and 2 without ever dying as well. How
should I go about it? I plan on definitely playing for a little
while, but I don't want to make it a permanent pursuit like
/Ikaruga/.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Radilgy (DC, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/01/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/01/Game--Radilgy--DC--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Beat on Easy-123 5 lives per
Beat on Normal-Wide 5 lives per
Beat on Normal-Wide 4 lives per
Beat on Normal-123 3 lives per</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
