<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dragon Warrior 2 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/dragon-warrior-2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T22:21:06-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 2 (NES, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/13/Game--Dragon-Warrior-2--NES--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/13/Game--Dragon-Warrior-2--NES--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Dragon Warrior 2 yesterday and today. Again, I
used codes to improve experience and gold acquisition. The gold
one was too effective, so I could get whatever I wanted
easily. The experience one was better, because it required me to
grind a tiny bit. At the very end, I used another code that
disabled random battles to go directly to the final 6 bosses
without getting in fights along the way.</p>

<p>This is a major jump in the sophistication of the series. There
are multiple characters, a ship, multiple enemies in battles, a
wide array of spells, and a much more expansive quest. It is
interesting that it was developed at the same time as Final
Fantasy, which had many similar advances over Dragon Quest 1.</p>

<p>Overall, it was an enjoyable game and much better to play for
modern players. However, there are a lot of insane secrets that I
would have given up in frustration trying to find if not for the
walkthrough I used. I doubt I will play it again, but I'm glad I
played it.</p>

<p>Final stats: 31/29/23; used two codes: easy xp, easy money, and
then at the end, no random battles</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
