<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Solid: VR Missions | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-solid-vr-missions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T00:21:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: VR Missions (PS1, 1999)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/13/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--VR-Missions--PS1--1999--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/13/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--VR-Missions--PS1--1999--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I thought I was going to play Metal Gear Solid: VR Missions. I
got it all ready and played it... but it wasn't at all what I
expected.</p>

<p>First, a little background. My favourite part about Metal Gear is
sneaking without being noticed and without interacting with the
guards in any direct way. I dislike using weapons and I dislike
using chokes or throws. My least favourite parts of Metal Gear
games are when you are forced to interact---such as running up the
stairs in the 2nd and 3rd games in the series or the boss battles
in general.</p>

<p>I was expecting VR Missions to be hundreds of bite-sized
guard/room configurations I had to get through in this way. It is
sort of that, except that the vast majority of the content
revolves crucially around using weapons to kill the
enemies---going so far as to prevent the goal from appearing until
you destroy them.</p>

<p>I did all the No Weapon Sneaking mode missions in about twenty
minutes... looked through the other options... and decided to
ignore them and move on to the next game in the Metal Gear
series. I wonder if the MGS2 VR missions will be better?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
