<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1997 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1997/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-08T22:23:39-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mischief Makers (N64, 1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/12/Game--Mischief-Makers--N64--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/12/Game--Mischief-Makers--N64--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few nights, I've played through the first two worlds
of Mischief Makers on the N64. Overall, I found the game very fun
and interesting. It has a totally unique mechanic: grabbing,
catching, and throwing enemies. And, although it is a 2D
platformer, it is rendered in 3D and Treasure clearly had a lot of
fun with 3D tricks and depth tricks. These aren't done perfectly,
but I can imagine an alternate history where games like this are
the ones that became popular, rather than games like Super Mario
64 (which I dislike(d).)</p>

<p>I'm stopping playing the game because my emulator is too flakey
with it. The sound is really messed up, some of the textures
aren't displaying (so that platforms are just invisible), and the
controls are really unresponsive. Even if all that were perfect,
I'm not sure this is the best game for me to playing. From what
I've seen, it isn't Treasure's best work, but I'm glad to have
experienced it to know what the deal is with it.</p>

<p>I heard about it from <a href="http://www.hardcoregaming101.net/mischiefmakers/mischiefmakers.htm">Hardcore Gaming 101</a>; I recommend reading
their article.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super God Trooper Zeroigar (PCFX, 1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/28/Game--Super-God-Trooper-Zeroigar--PCFX--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/28/Game--Super-God-Trooper-Zeroigar--PCFX--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through most of Super God Trooper Zeroigar, a shmup for
the PC-FX, tonight. It was pretty rad, but got a little bland
towards the end, which is why I stopped playing. I don't
understand Japanese, so the long Anime cutscenes and conversations
didn't have a big impact on me, but I appreciated their
presence. The shmuping was good, but the controls are way too
sensitive, which led to many stupid deaths.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 7 (PS1, 1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/09/Game--Final-Fantasy-7--PS1--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/09/Game--Final-Fantasy-7--PS1--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this on the PS3 and played through up to the final
dungeon, but didn't want to grind to be able to get through it.</p>

<p>At the beginning of August, I played through FF7 for the first
time in a long time. It definitely is /not/ preserved as well as
Final Fantasy 6. The graphics are just ugly and
distracting. Additionally the game is filled with really annoying
minigames. Ugh. Nevertheless, the game is still pretty good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Symphony of the Night (PS1, 1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Castlevania--Symphony-of-the-Night--PS1--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Castlevania--Symphony-of-the-Night--PS1--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this game. I'd like to beat it as Richter eventually.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dil To Pagal Hai (1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2004/12/27/Movie--Dil-To-Pagal-Hai--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2004-12-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2004/12/27/Movie--Dil-To-Pagal-Hai--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched another good Bollywood movie, Dil To Pagal Hai. It stars
Karishma Kapoor, Kareena's older sister, and Madhuri Dixit who
reminds me of Rani Mukherjee.</p>

<p>The movie is a fairly clever. The biggest disappointment with it
was that there was little tradition style outfits and dancing,
which has become my favourite aspect of these movies. Still it was
very cute, and Amanda cried at the end.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
