<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ikaruga | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ikaruga/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-09T23:52:46-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/27/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/27/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since my last post about Ikaruga, I've continued my daily
training. I've made a few new accomplishments:
- <em>Grade of A on Easy - Chapter 2.</em> I've been working on this
since November 2009 and I finally did it this morning.</p>

<p>Here's (roughly) my technique ([[http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=6sow_bw4iq4][here's a video of someone doing
it much better than me]] to following along): chain the first few
popcorn strands and then dodge the kamikaze planes while getting
two to three more chains in the process, if I get hit then just
shot everything but try to end in a white enemy, then get the
six black enemies on the left, then get three white (not four!)
in the middle, then get the six white on the right, then go back
to the middle and get the black as they fly by, ending by
switching to black and firing lasers to destroy everything
remaining. By the end of the prologue, I've had a 12 chain
stretch and I'm on a 14 chain stretch. If I'm imbalanced because
I didn't have enough laser energy for the whites, an immediate
bullet will kill a white and a quick second shot after moving to
the right a little will get another white. Now I kill the blacks
two at a time as they rotate around, then kill all the white. If
I've been fast enough, the ring of white will appear and I'll
get them, then get all the floating white blocks. Now I destroy
the left black block on top, then the right, then I get the two
popcorn that come on the left, then go back and get the
right. By this time I should have a little more than 30
chains. Now I destroy the white blocks by firing then move
forward and blow black lasers to get the incoming whites. Now I
go back and forth chaining every single enemy, then I blast the
white stream of popcorn until I have to get out. I tap to the
left and switch black then kill the 3 black on the left, then
the 3 white on the right, then I get the rotating popcorn. I
ignore the laser shooting enemies and kill the six white popcorn
on the left, then three on right (I often die if I go for all
six so I play it safe.) Then I destroy the left 6 black and use
lasers to destroy the central blocks, now I chain everything
that comes through until I get to the popcorn emitters. I
destroy the black generators then start taking out white streams
until the bottom one is off-screen. Then I destroy the black
popcorn in the circle as the come past the bottom, then I blast
all the white and chain the laser-shooters and their
options. Now it's time for the boss and I've got almost 90
chains. I take down the boss by shooting black lasers
immediately, opening the white hatch, destroying it, opening the
black hatch, then sitting right next to it dodging. I can take
down the boss in about 15 seconds and only opening the hatches
once each.</p>

<p>I'm not writing down my strategy so that you can learn or
because it's that important, but I'd like you to understand that
I have the entire level in my brain and I have planned out my
attack to the letter.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Easy - Chapter 4 - Dot Eater.</em> This took about five weeks of
playing (but, of course, for two I was on a trip so I caught up
on a single night last week.) I wouldn't say it was much easier
than Chapter 3, but rather doing Chapter 3 taught me so much
about Ikaruga that I was able to do it easier. Chapter 4 is
probably a little bit easier though because it has such a strong
theme: oppositely spinning beams of black and white so you must
be one color to go one direction and the other to go the
opposite. One thing I'm a bit proud of is that I got through the
boss on my first try ever and didn't get hit once (which is good
because I didn't have any extra lives by the time I go to the
boss.) <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=D0PlVm5n0zk">Here's a video of someone else.</a></li>
</ul>


<p>I still love this game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/12/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/12/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Since I bought Ikaruga back in August, I've <em>still</em> been playing
every day. I've played for 38 hours, 42 minutes, and 28 seconds
according to the game clock. I've recently made a nice
achievement, so I thought I would make a progress report.</p>

<p>My accomplishments to date:
- <em>Credit-feeding through the game on Easy, Normal, and Hard.</em>
This was the first thing I did by October. (It's not totally
brain-dead because you have to beat the bosses within the time
limit.) I was able to get through Easy before unlocking
free-play.
- <em>Grade of A on Easy - Chapter 1.</em> I did this by the end of
November. It was really hard to get to that point, but now I get
an A without even thinking about it.
- <em>Easy - Chapter 1 - Dot Eater.</em> This only took a few tries and
was relatively easy. Done in November.
- <em>Easy - Chapter 2 - Dot Eater.</em> This was very hard, because it
requires pixel-perfect control to get through the blocks at the
beginning of the level. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LtIDc04e79M">Here's a video of someone else.</a> But it
only took about two months, maybe a little less. Done in
December.
- <em>Easy - Chapter 3 - Dot Eater.</em> This was /very hard/. I've been
working on this since December, but I just did it tonight. For
comparison, there are over a thousand people who've done Chapter
1 - Dot Eater, 103 who've done Chapter 2, and only 44 who've
done Chapter 3. (FWIW, 24 for Chapter 4 and 25 for the Final
Chapter.) There are four main challenges to this: first, getting
through the moving block lasers that push you into obstacles,
then getting through rows of enemies and moving spears, then
getting chased by/dealing with Shigi, then dealing with the
spinning boss Uzura. Yikes. <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Gk5iefdDhvs">Here's a video of someone else.</a>
- <em>Easy and Normal - One credit to Chapter 3's Boss.</em> Not much to
say here, except that doing these levels Dot Eater helps train
for the normal mode well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/11/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/11/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought Ikaruga last August and I have been playing every single
day since then (except for when I was away on trips...)  It is
unbelievably amazing. The more I play the more I realize what a
masterpiece it is. I just want to talk about one part of it right
now:</p>

<p>/metaphor/</p>

<p>The whole game is a metaphor for life. As you play it, the
mechanics of the game force you to put yourself into the mind of
Shinra (the pilot of the Ikaruga.) The game starts with this
quote:</p>

<p>"I will not die until I achieve something.
Even though the ideal is high, I never give in.
Therefore, I never die with regrets."</p>

<p>Is this about Shinra?: The single surviving member of the army
that fought against the Horai; the man who has been nursed back to
health by the defeated people of the island town of Ikaruga; the
man who will fight against "The Power of the Gods"; (SPOILER) the
man who dies to destroy the Ubusunagami Okinokai?</p>

<p>Is this about the player playing the game?: The game acknowledges
its difficulty and how it cannot be casually won; even though it
"only" lasts 29 minutes, I've played for over 20 hours and am not
even close to conquering it; I practice every day so I can achieve
something and I never give in.</p>

<p>Or is this about the player in his normal life?: We all face
adversity, but we must achieve something and fight for our ideals
or else we will die with regrets.</p>

<p>By teaching the player about Shinra, teaching the player about
himself as player, the game teaches the player about himself as a
person.</p>

<p>I have a hard time thinking of other games that do this.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008) - High scores]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ikaruga - Easy - Chapter 1: 2,790,680 points. #384 #hiscore
Ikaruga - Easy - Chapter 2: 3,155,770 points. #535 #hiscore
Ikaruga - Easy - Final Chapter: 3,777,260 points. Grade B+. #392 #hiscore
Ikaruga - Easy: Died @ Final Chapter, Boss 1: 7,219,430 points. #548 #hiscore</p>

<p>Ikaruga - Easy - Final Chapter: 1,309,100 points. Dot Eater! #32/32 #hiscore</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikaruga (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Ikaruga--X360--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently bought Ikaruga for the Xbox 360. This game is
/amazing/. I can't believe how beautiful and epic it is. I even
set up my TV to rotate into portrait so I could play it as it was
meant to be played.</p>

<p>The game is so difficult, but so rewarding at the same time. Every
new screen is totally different, yet totally builds on the simple
controls of the earlier parts of the game. I'm really impressed by
this game and can't wait to try out some of the other shmups from
Treasure.</p>

<p>There are some amazing videos of it online: <a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=z5JAnfdaU_Y">level 3 (perfect)</a> and
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5ZEGyrEnXrk">1 player 2 player</a>. And <a href="http://www.destructoid.com/the-thinking-man-s-ikaruga-stop-and-smell-the-duality-60929.phtml">here's a description of the story</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
