<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blaster Master | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/blaster-master/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T22:13:59-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blaster Master (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/Game--Blaster-Master--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/24/Game--Blaster-Master--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Blaster Master tonight after getting home from
Thanksgiving in SLC.</p>

<p>I had fond memories of reading about this game in Nintendo Power
and seeing the box art many many times. However, I don't remember
ever playing it. It's funny, I've always thought of it as a game I
played, but when I stretch, I realize I can't remember any
details. Another funny thing happened related to this game
recently. Just last night a student asked me if I knew the name of
the game with the kid and his frog that jumps in a
hole. Naturally, I said "Blaster Master!" And then I played it the
next day.</p>

<p>The game was very fun. The platforming is very simple. It's more
of a combat game. However, the combat is not really twitchy or
skillful. It is more a matter of being patient and taking each
enemy one at a time. I thought that I would appreciate the
"Metroid"-ness about it. But, although there is a back-tracking
and an open world. The upgrades you get feel like "keys" that are
only used once, rather than enhancements of your abilities that
you use all the time. That's a weak way to have a system like
this. Perhaps the worst part is that the final upgrade makes the
jumping feel totally off, wrong, and hard to do right because you
accidentally go under the platform you are on. The bosses are
really really hard and in most cases I resorted to dirty tricks to
get them... like going into a place where I could hit them but
they couldn't hit me. Some it was pure luck.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I do stick by the game being fun, and although I
don't think I'd play it again, I would recommend it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
