<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1993 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1993/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-03T00:18:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played again today. He didn't want to play as much, but I
showed him each of the games on it and he thought SMB2 was really
cool. He got over 1 pit in SMB1!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son and I played this today; specifically SMB1. In the past he
has been able to get to the first pit, but rarely, because he is
still getting used to platforming. Today he did great and got to
it 5 times in row, but couldn't get past. It is interesting to
watch him play, because it makes you think about the game
differently. Avoiding a Goomba just requires jumping, because they
come to you. Getting over the pipes just requires jumping and
holding Right against it. But, a pit requires a little bit of a
run and jump at the right time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gunstar Heroes (GEN, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Gunstar Heroes last night and tonight. I'm a
shameless Treasure fanboy, but I'd never played this, so I thought
that I would do it. It was pretty awesome. It's really remarkable
how many many enemies they were able to get on the screen at
once. The game is really tight and fun. I was able to beat it up
until the shmup part with only one or two continues. After that, I
save-stated after each boss battle so I wouldn't have to do huge
segments over again. I really enjoyed the game. I stuck with the
flame-thrower weapon the whole time as well.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p=335">This review</a> of a different Treasure game talks a lot about Gunstar
in a way that I couldn't do better. Check that out.</p>

<p>When I was playing, my wife walked in the room and said, "This looks
cool." That's a good sign.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Dracula (GB, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/19/Game--Kid-Dracula--GB--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/19/Game--Kid-Dracula--GB--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played Kid Dracula for the Gameboy. It's a very straight-forward
platformer with a shooting mechanic. It has a little bonus
mechanic of different kinds of magic that let Kid Dracula turn
into a bat, walk on the ceiling, use a protective umbrella,
etc. Most of these things are only useful in a few places in the
eight level game, but they are present enough to make it fun to
use them. The best part about the game, however, is the clever cut
parody of the Castlevania series. Most of the common enemies show
up in super-cute form.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (PCE, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--PCE--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/11/25/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--PCE--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing Akumajō Dracula X Chi no Rondo on the PC
Engine CD.</p>

<p>This game is /amazing/. The levels are all so unique and
interesting. They are all challenging and the boss are
particularly frustrating, but totally satisfying and fun. I loved
being able to play as Maria after I rescued her. I can't wait to
play Symphony of the Night again and pay attention to the
interactions with Maria. The game is definitely easier with her. I
only played with her through the alternate route and I beat
Dracula with both Richter and Maria. Naturally I also got 100%,
but I'd like to play it again sometime and go with Maria through
the primary route and Richter through the alternate route.</p></p>

<p>Update: One more thing. If you've played a Castlevania game,
you know how when you beat a boss, this magic sphere appears that
refills your health or advances you to the next level. I
/always/ jump to get it. It is so much fun!</p>

<p>I /absolutely/ recommend this game!</p>

<p>Finished with these paths:
Richter:
1 -> 2 -> 3 -> 4 -> 5 -> 6 -> 7 -> 8 -> Final
Prisoners: 2, 7</p>

<p>Maria:
1 -> 2' -> 3' -> 4' -> 5' -> 6 + Final
Prisoners: 3', 4'</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
