<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1993 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1993/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-08T09:45:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son and I played for about twenty minutes. We did the
Intro stage and then Chill Penguin. We got the dash and got to
the boss, but died on the first time and were out of lives. He
wanted to play Launch Octopus again so we did that had a tough
time with the ships before it was time for breakfast.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son and I played this for about 15 minutes and played the
Launch Octopus level. The Sea Dragon got me and put me back at the
second miniboss.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played again today. He didn't want to play as much, but I
showed him each of the games on it and he thought SMB2 was really
cool. He got over 1 pit in SMB1!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son and I played this today; specifically SMB1. In the past he
has been able to get to the first pit, but rarely, because he is
still getting used to platforming. Today he did great and got to
it 5 times in row, but couldn't get past. It is interesting to
watch him play, because it makes you think about the game
differently. Avoiding a Goomba just requires jumping, because they
come to you. Getting over the pipes just requires jumping and
holding Right against it. But, a pit requires a little bit of a
run and jump at the right time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gunstar Heroes (GEN, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/13/Game--Gunstar-Heroes--GEN--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Gunstar Heroes last night and tonight. I'm a
shameless Treasure fanboy, but I'd never played this, so I thought
that I would do it. It was pretty awesome. It's really remarkable
how many many enemies they were able to get on the screen at
once. The game is really tight and fun. I was able to beat it up
until the shmup part with only one or two continues. After that, I
save-stated after each boss battle so I wouldn't have to do huge
segments over again. I really enjoyed the game. I stuck with the
flame-thrower weapon the whole time as well.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p=335">This review</a> of a different Treasure game talks a lot about Gunstar
in a way that I couldn't do better. Check that out.</p>

<p>When I was playing, my wife walked in the room and said, "This looks
cool." That's a good sign.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
