<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1993 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1993/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-22T23:06:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/13/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for almost three hours and beat the game. I beat
levels 6, 7, and 8 as Maria. Then, I beat 8 as Richter. Then I
beat 4' as Richter to get to 5'. I did 5' as Maria (and continued
on to beat the game on the same continue.)</p>

<p>When I finally beat Dracula as Richter, I wasn't hit at all in his
human form, but was hit just once in his giant man-bat form (by
the blue energy wave, that I think you are supposed to duck
under.)</p>

<p>This is a very satisfying game to beat. I will definitely
continue playing it in the future... especially since I invested
in a PC Engine to be able to play it. It's a blast.</p>

<p>Although... I'm annoyed that I only have 96% completion on the
save screen... despite having done everything in the game. I'm not
sure what I'm supposed to do to bring it to 100%.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the morning, we played for about a half hour and beat level 4'
via the secret route---beating Camilla---but not getting to 5'. I
started on stage 5 a bit, but was pretty beat down.</p>

<p>Later, I played for about an hour and a half and beat
stage 5. Eventually I was able to use the watch to get through up
to Death without getting hit at all... by pausing the action just
before the large green monsters. Sometimes this game seems totally
impossible and brutalizing. The key seems to always be using the
sub-weapons effectively and breaking the challenges. Or, learning
pitch perfect timing and getting through unscathed... but mostly
doing the sub-weapons just right. It's a fascinating design.</p>

<p>After I mastered that, it took about 7 tries to kill Death. I
stuck with the Cross. I used an Item Crash early and pummeled
him. I dodged the huge skulls by staying to the left and
right. The melee fight was pure stick-and-move. It is so
satisfying to win at this game.</p>

<p>After Death was dead, I fought the Vampire Bat and was killed
Medusa in the Boss rush stage. I decided to go back and fight
Camilla again, because supposedly you need to beat Death to get
the secret exit... but no luck.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I played this game with my son for about an hour. We
beat level 2 the normal way after getting Maria. Now I have
unlocked up to 4 and 4'. We tried 4 but were totally brutalized by
the boss playing as Maria (she's really weak.) We also rescued two
of the non-playable girls. Still... amazing game.</p>

<p>Later in the day we played for about thirty minutes and beat level
4' via the normal route and got to stage 5. I wish the game a
better way of tracking which levels/exits you have done.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a PC Engine and got this game. It is really fun to play
it again, especially without an emulator and save states, so I
have to do it better. Additionally, I've had a lot more
experience with the other early Castlevania games so I'm just
better at playing it. It's really fun and smooth feeling, despite
having classic Casltevania stickiness.</p>

<p>I played only as Richter today and I did all secret exits. I went
from 0 to 1 to 2' to 3' to 4'. I fought the Serpent, the Minotaur,
the Werewolf, and the floaty head thing. It's a lot of fun.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that I'm not going to continue playing this game. It's
definitely not a bad game, but it's also not an excellent
game. Given its age, there are really some interface things that
it should have done better:</p>

<ul>
<li>attacks should not go into empty space</li>
<li>you should be able to see what equipment will improve your stats
and buy them easier</li>
<li>you should be able to see what items do</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, if I had a lot of nostalgia for this game, I would be much
more willing to play it to experience the story and world again,
but I have much more nostalgia for the second game. In terms of
story, this game basically does everything I think is cool in the
first few hours and then it's just been standard JRPG fare.</p>

<p>I do find the concept of the Old Cave with the "task" system to be
pretty interesting, but not enough to make me want to keep doing
it.</p>

<p>Basically this game will be left aside because of the "there's
not enough time in the world to play non-amazing games". I guess
this means that I can't really recommend the game either, because
there's things you should play instead, but it's still not a
"bad" game. For example, I prefer it to the PS3 Star Ocean or
some of the other modern junk I've tried to play.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
