<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-solid-portable-ops/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T19:11:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through Metal
Gear Solid: Portable Ops.</p>

<p>I really liked that this is a canonical game and features Naked
Snake. I find his character really fascinating.</p>

<p>In general, I found the gameplay great. The controls on the PSP
were really hard to work with, so I played on Easy. I find that
very interesting, because the first three Metal Gear Solid games
had fixed cameras. If this game were just made in that style, then
the lack of a second analog stick on the PSP would not have been a
problem. I found it very painful.</p>

<p>The recruiting and squad concept was interesting, but ultimately
very unfulfilling for me. I want to play as Snake. I only used
other people in one boss fight where Snake died and then when I
wanted to get a box closer to capture someone.</p>

<p>The comic book style cutscenes in this game were really great. I
think they looked better than MGS1 cut-scenes, so I don't feel
like it was a cop-out.</p>

<p>The storyline revelations were very cool and the general concept
for the action was rad. I found that the game had the same great
Metal Gear themes, even though it was portable.</p>

<p>Great game!</p>

<p>Stats:
Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 11:25
Times Saved: 8
Restarts: 18
Times Alert Mode Triggered: 76
Humans Killed: 41
Comrades Secured: 53
Comrades Killed: 16
Codename: Scorpion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
