<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-07T22:53:07-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Green Lantern, starring Ryan Reynolds (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/06/Movie--Green-Lantern--starring-Ryan-Reynolds--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/06/Movie--Green-Lantern--starring-Ryan-Reynolds--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a pretty cheesy comic book movie. The story was quite
different than others, with its god-like characters and its vast
universe.</p>

<p>On one hand, I liked that it didn't really dwell on the fact that
aliens exist, etc. But on the hand, that was the most interesting
part of the movie, but it was also totally unfulfilled.</p>

<p>The characters all play totally to type and lots of character
development consists of almost a single scene to establish the type
and then the movie moves on. (Most of the scenes with Blake
Lively.)</p>

<p>My other favourite scene was the opening dog fight with the
experimental planes. It was interesting how it foreshadowed the
ending. It was unfortunate that an otherwise heroic moment was
shattered by a cliche character reveal.</p>

<p>And one more... when Blake saw through the disguise. Brilliant.</p>

<p>But despite a few high moments, it's a pretty vapid movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Atlas Shrugged: Part I, starring Taylor Schilling (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-I--starring-Taylor-Schilling--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-I--starring-Taylor-Schilling--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an amazing movie. Unbelievably good. The final scene is
totally epic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides, starring Johnny Depp (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie--Pirates-of-the-Caribbean--On-Stranger-Tides--starring-Johnny-Depp--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie--Pirates-of-the-Caribbean--On-Stranger-Tides--starring-Johnny-Depp--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the first Pirates movie and the other ones were
pretty bad. I think their biggest failure was being too fantasy and
with too many monsters, etc. This movie doesn't have that problem,
but it is definitely not as good as previous ones.</p>

<p>There are some fun moments of <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow being <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow. A
few absurd fights and chases. It's a fairly fun and crazy movie.
The mermaids are totally beautiful and the mermaid who serves as
the love interest has a very sweet and innocent feel to her.</p>

<p>If you stop to think about a lot of the movie, it is pretty absurd
and silly, but I'm not sure I should really expect anything
different. It's a solid B+. I think with a few more exciting fights
and a bit more plot coherence it could have been an A-.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Vow, starring Rachel McAdams and Channing Tatum (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cute movie. There were a lot of cute moments. I
felt like the people in it were unrealistically mean to basically
everyone. I read the Wikipedia page and it talked about the real
couple was very religious and credit God for keeping them
together. It would have been nice to acknowledge that it
someway... but the couple in the movie weren't even married in a
church.</p>

<p>I think my favourite parts of the movie were the very subtle signs
of how much they loved each other. Such as rolling up the window
and the cat. Very cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Immortals, starring Henry Cavil (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really rad movie. It had a similar amazing look as 300,
but was much more fantasy oriented. The actions of the Gods in the
movie are awesome and not quite like anything I'd ever seen
before. The actions are the humans are exciting and down to Earth
in a neat contrasting way. Mickey Rourke does an amazing job as a
crazy warlord. The movie is a really great spectacle piece and is
totally worth it just for the way the Greek Gods are presented.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
