<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-21T22:28:01-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: It's Kind of a Funny Story, starring Keir Gilchrist (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/19/Movie--It-s-Kind-of-a-Funny-Story--starring-Keir-Gilchrist--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had no expectations about this movie. It was pretty cute and
interesting. I think depressed people are stupid, so I didn't
really like the part of it that justified them, although a big part
of it didn't (Craig's conclusion is that depression is
self-indulgent.) I though Emma Roberts' character was very cute,
although we don't learn anything about her, other than that she's
cute and quirky. The final sequence in the movie where we see what
Craig does with his life is more interesting than a lot of moments
in the movie. The character of Bobby is actually sad, but again,
everyone in the movie is just a caricature with no substance, so
we don't really know what his feels truly are. The movie is
annoying in that way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Last Emperor, starring John Lone (1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Movie--The-Last-Emperor--starring-John-Lone--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Movie--The-Last-Emperor--starring-John-Lone--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wasn't sure what to think of this movie before seeing it, but
I'd heard it was very good. I enjoyed it a great deal. I felt very
bad for the guy... it must have been hard to grow up like that and
to be used to so badly your whole life...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Atlas Shrugged: Part II, directed by John Putch (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/12/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-II--directed-by-John-Putch--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/12/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-II--directed-by-John-Putch--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the first Atlas Shrugged movie, so I decided to
support this by seeing it in the theatre. This felt like it had a
smaller budget, despite having the same budget. I feel like because
this part of the book is so depressing, the movie lacks a lot of
excitement. But, I enjoyed it and hope there can be a conclusion. I
feel like total cast swap was really bad... my wife was very
confused by who people were and I thought that this Dagny was much
worse that Taylor Schilling, who was beautiful and powerful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Snow White and the Hunstman, staring Kristen Stewart (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Movie--Snow-White-and-the-Hunstman--staring-Kristen-Stewart--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Movie--Snow-White-and-the-Hunstman--staring-Kristen-Stewart--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really cool movie. The effects were awesome and the
embellishments of the story, particularly the relationship of the
Evil Queen and her brother, were really cool. Kristen Stewart was
beautiful in it and played the part very well. I thought she was
awkward fighting, but feel like it was purposeful. Definitely a
fun movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 2.0 You Can (Not) Advance, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie--Evangelion--2-0-You-Can--Not--Advance--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie--Evangelion--2-0-You-Can--Not--Advance--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whereas the first Rebuild movie was almost exactly the same, but
with slightly different dialogue and scenes, but otherwise the
same, except for the technology. This movie was very
different... Mari is a whole new character... and the interactions
with Asuka and how she came were totally different. I really
enjoyed the changes, especially with Asuka. I thought the ending
was crazy and much clearer than the corresponding part in the
series. Although I'm kind of surprised that this is the point it
ends at... I feel like there can't be two more movies worth of
content, but I'm excited to find out what there's going to be
there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
