<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-16T22:42:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Super 8, directed by J. J. Abrams (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Movie--Super-8--directed-by-J--J--Abrams--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Movie--Super-8--directed-by-J--J--Abrams--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an /awesome/ movie. At one moment, my wife and I looked at
each other and said: "This movie is like the Goonies, but
AMAZING!" It starts so chill and then gets crazy. The young actors
are awesome and Elle Fanning is really cute with the kid. The
story was pretty neat... a kind of myth of the pure native, but in
a different way. The concept of the ship was really cool. The
meta-arc of the kids making the film was really neat too. Overall,
it was very cool and nostalgic. I liked all the ironic references
to what was exciting in technology during the early 80s.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Nick and Norah's Infinite Playlist, starring Michael Cera (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie--Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist--starring-Michael-Cera--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie--Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist--starring-Michael-Cera--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't really know anything about this movie before watching it,
but heard it was interesting. It was really cool. It was so
nostalgic of what life was like for me when I was young... going
to shows all night, etc. That was really cool about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Wrath of the Titans, starring Sam Worthington (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was fun, but definitely not as good as the first one. I
think the plot was much weaker and the cast was kind of thrown
together for no good reason---whereas the first one had a very
nice progression of how people joined the group.</p>

<p>Rosamund Pike was very beautiful, but it was very weird that the
actress from the previous movie was replaced and because she acted
so differently than the character before I didn't realize it was
supposed to be the same person.</p>

<p>Overall, I don't feel like the sequel was really necessary, which
is unfortunate, because I thought the first one was so good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tron: Legacy, starring Jeff Bridges (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/27/Movie--Tron--Legacy--starring-Jeff-Bridges--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/27/Movie--Tron--Legacy--starring-Jeff-Bridges--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a much better movie than the last one. I think my
favourite part of it was how it is basically the story of Catholic
theology: God enters the Void and creates Angels to assist Him in
creating perfection, but later finds (or creates) Humans, who are
imperfect, but have agency and can therefore grow and experience
love, but this upsets His chief Angel who fights against Him out of
jealousy. This particular story takes an approach very similar to
His Dark Materials, where God loses and someone has to come and
save him. The film is very cool throughout.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tron, starring Jeff Bridges (1982)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/23/Movie--Tron--starring-Jeff-Bridges--1982--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/23/Movie--Tron--starring-Jeff-Bridges--1982--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I watched this in preparation for the sequel. It was
very interesting, especially by putting ourselves in the mindset of
someone from the 1980s. It's fascinating how just 10 or so years
after the movie came out, consumer computers would have been able
to render the graphics in real-time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
