<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-27T23:30:24-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol, starring Tom Cruise (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a big budget popcorn summer movie, but a pretty good one
of that category. It starts off, and sounds like, it will be just
like all the other movies, with practically the same setup; but it
quickly acknowledges that and goes in a different direction. They
didn't over use the faces, like they've done before, and they there
was only one real bad scene of Tom Cruise fawning over himself. I
think my major disappointments were its lack of a romantic sub-plot
and the lack of real consequences to not being able to use IMF
resources---even though they explicitly mention how that is
standing in their way at a few points, they solve the problem too
easily.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Castle of Cagliostro, directed by Hayao Miyazaki (1979)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie--The-Castle-of-Cagliostro--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--1979--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie--The-Castle-of-Cagliostro--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--1979--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun anime movie. I like all the little subtle visual
jokes that they have and the general wackiness of the action. I
think you need to be a little bit older to appreciate it though, so
we didn't watch it with the kids.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Geek Charming, starring Sarah Hyland (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very predicable teen comedy of the poor to riches
variety, complete with the standard dual friend abandonment and
inner growth. Nevertheless, it was a good version of this story and
had a few cute things. A lot of the characters acknowledge the
camera too much, but when they are bit more free and their perfect
teeth aren't totally showing, it gets a little real and that's
nice. Overall, a fun, refreshing, ray of sunshine. Like a good pop
song on a rainy day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kagemusha, directed by Akira Kurosawa (1980)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Movie--Kagemusha--directed-by-Akira-Kurosawa--1980--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Movie--Kagemusha--directed-by-Akira-Kurosawa--1980--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second Kurosawa film that I've seen. I thought it was
done very well and the story was incredibly interesting, but
definitely not exciting. It was well acted. A lot of the movie went
on too long. The battle scenes are very long and drag without much
interesting stuff going on. Additionally, there are a few
"psychedelic" scenes that really date the movie. All that aside, I
think it was pretty cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: My Life in Ruins, starring Nia Vardalos (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a pretty bad movie, but bad in that way that Pringles are,
where you think they are good while you're eating them, but every
so often you think "What am I doing?" and afterward as you reflect
on it, you regret. You should read the Wikipedia page on the
Critical Reception. I very much agree. There are a few funny
moments, but overall it feels so fake. The best part is how
realistic the tour members are. I direct tours, actually, and I
find a lot of it to be true to life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
