<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-17T08:05:33-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Majestic, starring Jim Carrey (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--The-Majestic--starring-Jim-Carrey--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fine little romance. The most interesting thing about it
is how this, and other movies (like the Chaplin biopic) rewrite the
history of the Communist/Hollywood controversy of the 50s to play
out the way that modern Hollywood people wish that it would. It
makes me think that maybe some people wouldn't realize that
Hollywood didn't really "win". There's a lot of Hollywood
dopey-eye-ism in the movie, actually. It reminds me a lot of
Hugo.</p>

<p>I think the movie might have been improved by making it more
ambiguous about whether Jim Carrey really lost his memory.</p>

<p>The reviews are interesting. I think Roger Ebert saw what it was
going for and believed in it. The speech at the end was a bit too
dopey for my taste.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Alice in Wonderland, directed by Tim Burton (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/15/Movie--Alice-in-Wonderland--directed-by-Tim-Burton--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My little sister wanted to watch this movie tonight, so we watched
it together. I thought it was very cool and pretty trippy. I don't
think Johnny Depp was very good in it though... he was too much
like <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow, but looked really weird and had a funny
voice. The slight attraction between him and Alice was creepy
too. I think I liked Helena Bonham Carter and Anne Hathaway the
best, they were just so odd. It was cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Cowboys & Aliens, starring Daniel Craig (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie--Cowboys---Aliens--starring-Daniel-Craig--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie--Cowboys---Aliens--starring-Daniel-Craig--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the blend of Western and Sci-Fi style. I was glad
that the aliens had a sensible purpose for being on Earth. I liked
that there was a deeper world in the background, but that it was
not too tantalizing (for a movie like this.) I thought the aliens
looked cool and Daniel Craig was super tough. The juxtaposition,
though, was the best part. All-around a good time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: John Carter, starring Taylor Kitsch (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie--John-Carter--starring-Taylor-Kitsch--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie--John-Carter--starring-Taylor-Kitsch--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had heard a little about this movie when it came out, but nothing
really special. My parents wanted to watch a movie together and I
saw this on Amazon and suggested it.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the movie. It's very much unlike anything else in
its grand scheme. Maybe a little bit like Stargate. It takes a
little while to get started, but once it does, the pay-off is
great. I think what I like most about it is the way it spins a
world so well.</p>

<p>It makes me very interested in reading the series of books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: One for the Money, starring Katherine Heigl (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie--One-for-the-Money--starring-Katherine-Heigl--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie--One-for-the-Money--starring-Katherine-Heigl--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My mom recommended this movie to us, as she has been reading the
series it is based on for a long time. I found the movie charming
and cute. It was a nice light mystery with some subtle romantic and
funny moments. It makes me interested in the books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
