<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-16T21:43:32-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Skyfall, starring Daniel Craig (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Skyfall--starring-Daniel-Craig--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Skyfall--starring-Daniel-Craig--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife and I saw this tonight [which is why I wanted to write down
my thoughts about the other ones.] I found a lot about this movie a
lot better than QoS. I thought the movie was paced a lot better and
the new characters were quite interesting. On the other hand, there
wasn't really an deep connections. Even the deepest connection
(between M and 007) wasn't developed much. In addition, the goal of
the villain wasn't at a very big scale. He was almost Bane or
Joker-ish in his abilities, but had a trivial revenge scheme
planned. There were lots of holes and missed opportunities---why
not just blow up MI6 when M was there if he wanted to kill her so
bad? Why was Severine with the guy getting killed? Why would
Patrice be necessarily working for the same guy twice? Severine's
death was totally ignored and Bond doesn't even acknowledge it
happens. The island is a wasted set. The best parts are the
committee hearing and the showdown at Skyfall.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Quantum of Solace, starring Daniel Craig (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Quantum-of-Solace--starring-Daniel-Craig--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Quantum-of-Solace--starring-Daniel-Craig--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a much more traditional Bond movie, with a ridiculous and
large scale evil plot. I felt like the feel of the movie was a lot
different and that the beginning is much better and tighter than
the end. There are lots of bombshells in the movie, but they dwell
on Bond's ability to conquest a bit less.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Casino Royale, starring Daniel Craig (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is such an amazing movie. The whole story-arc of Vesper is so
powerful and heart-breaking. The first half of the film has so
many super high energy exciting parts... like the opening and the
airport. The film has lots of great lines and funny parts... like
at the country club and between Bond and Vesper. This is really great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Brothers Bloom, directed by Rian Johnson (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Movie--The-Brothers-Bloom--directed-by-Rian-Johnson--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Movie--The-Brothers-Bloom--directed-by-Rian-Johnson--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun caper movie. The story is very complicated and has
lots of twists, in a way that reminiscent of Ocean's Eleven, but
with more off-the-wall occurrences. I feel like there were a lot
of things that should have been explained, because they would have
been very interesting, that weren't. For example, how Penelope
manages to get out of Prague. In general though, after about the
first third, the characters (which beforehand were fascinating)
all have their identities fixed and then they never change. We
learn a lot about Penelope in the beginning, but then she's
static. Similarly, the ending just doesn't feel right given what
we know about the character's feelings. Nevertheless, it was a
unique and cute movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Arthur, starring Russel Brand (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie--Arthur--starring-Russel-Brand--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie--Arthur--starring-Russel-Brand--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a cute movie with a pretty unique plot. The main girl was
cute and wholesome. I feel like the ending was a bit empty though,
because other than going to AA there was no explanation of how
Arthur changed. Th end of the movie suggested that Arthur's only
problem was that he drank a lot (and perhaps having so many
resources exacerbated the impact of that), but didn't deal at all
with his lack of knowledge, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
