<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-28T22:39:53-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Chasing Ghosts: Beyond the Arcade (2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Movie--Chasing-Ghosts--Beyond-the-Arcade--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Movie--Chasing-Ghosts--Beyond-the-Arcade--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an interesting movie. I think I preferred King of Kong,
however. Something I disliked about the guys in the movie is that
they were very proud of their accomplishments and built their lives
around them, but they didn't continue to push their high scores in
the games that made them "famous" or in future games. It seemed so
stagnant. Most of the guys seemed to live really depressing lives
too. I felt bad for them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: This Means War (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/Movie--This-Means-War--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/Movie--This-Means-War--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a totally over the top movie. It's silly, kind of stupid,
but fun at the same time.</p>

<p>There are some funny moments and characters---like the way the CIA
teams act on the "case" and Lauren's friend Trish. The action
scenes are of the "super fast" type without much impact.</p>

<p>There a few moments of real romance---when FDR takes Lauren home or
when he's watching Titantic and the look on Tuck's ex-wife's face
at the end. The main problem with the romantic plot is that
everyone is being so dishonest with each other, there's no meaning
behind their actions.</p>

<p>But overall, I feel like a lot of the actors aren't really acting
together, just in the same room. It feels very
forced. (Particularly Trish actually, she's doesn't look at Lauren
enough when they're talking... it's very unnatural.)</p>

<p>Reese Witherspoon looks really good in the movie. However,
sometimes it feels like she's trying too hard to look
sexy... particularly in the sex scene with FDR. The way the
characters are connect to each other... it's like ballroom dancing
where FDR is the frame to show off her legs and stomach. Yet
another example of the unnaturalness in the movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Chronicles of Narnia: The Voyage of the Dawn Treader (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/17/Movie--The-Chronicles-of-Narnia--The-Voyage-of-the-Dawn-Treader--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/17/Movie--The-Chronicles-of-Narnia--The-Voyage-of-the-Dawn-Treader--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie is like a video game: lots of sets with a few scenes set
there before they move on to the next, fairly disconnected
event. It has very high production value. The acting can be a bit
bad. Eustace is pretty terrible, especially in the
beginning. Caspian is quite hammy. Lucy is probably the best player
in the film.</p>

<p>I think the story of this movie/book is not as strong as the other
ones, because the ending is very uneventful. You think they're
fighting fear itself, but there's no real pay-off because the enemy
is never really named or described in a meaningful way.</p>

<p>The movie's version of Eustace during back from being a dragon was
much less epic than I remember it being in the book, which was my
favourite part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Green Lantern, starring Ryan Reynolds (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/06/Movie--Green-Lantern--starring-Ryan-Reynolds--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/06/Movie--Green-Lantern--starring-Ryan-Reynolds--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a pretty cheesy comic book movie. The story was quite
different than others, with its god-like characters and its vast
universe.</p>

<p>On one hand, I liked that it didn't really dwell on the fact that
aliens exist, etc. But on the hand, that was the most interesting
part of the movie, but it was also totally unfulfilled.</p>

<p>The characters all play totally to type and lots of character
development consists of almost a single scene to establish the type
and then the movie moves on. (Most of the scenes with Blake
Lively.)</p>

<p>My other favourite scene was the opening dog fight with the
experimental planes. It was interesting how it foreshadowed the
ending. It was unfortunate that an otherwise heroic moment was
shattered by a cliche character reveal.</p>

<p>And one more... when Blake saw through the disguise. Brilliant.</p>

<p>But despite a few high moments, it's a pretty vapid movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Atlas Shrugged: Part I, starring Taylor Schilling (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-I--starring-Taylor-Schilling--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Movie--Atlas-Shrugged--Part-I--starring-Taylor-Schilling--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an amazing movie. Unbelievably good. The final scene is
totally epic.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
