<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-10T00:20:47-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: 300, directed by Zack Snyder (2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie--300--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Movie--300--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an amazing movie. The visual were out of this world. The
story is so inspiring. Although it is pretty bloody, for some
reason there's really only like two gross parts. The grossest thing
was the disfigured people, but that's weird, mainly because it's
actually real.</p>

<p>Looking at the guys in the movie makes you feel tiny, puny, and
weak. It's super intense.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Transformers: Dark of the Moon, directed by Michael Bay (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie--Transformers--Dark-of-the-Moon--directed-by-Michael-Bay--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/07/Movie--Transformers--Dark-of-the-Moon--directed-by-Michael-Bay--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another stupid, crazy, spectacle movie. The plot is pretty
incomprehensible, but who cares, or expects better? The visuals
were really amazing. I was kind of annoyed that Megan Fox wasn't in
it and there was basically no explanation for why. I see why her
character wouldn't work for what they had the girl do, but I don't
see why that was a necessary plot point. Either way, the whole
movie was some good stupid fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Baxter, starring Michael Showalter (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--The-Baxter--starring-Michael-Showalter--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--The-Baxter--starring-Michael-Showalter--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very funny movie. It magnifies standard romantic comedy
cliches to a whole new level and is almost a "reductio ad absurdum"
of the concept of a "Baxter". I quite enjoyed it. Michelle Williams
was adorable in it, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Awakening, starring Kate Beckinsale (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was the fasted paced and immediately insane movie. It's
practically equivalent to the insanity of the fourth Resident Evil
movie. The amount the world of the movies changes in the first five
minutes is unbelievable. Yet, they pack in lots of really
fascinating and sensible ideas and imagery. It's spectacular.</p>

<p>The story is interesting, although it is unclear why they would
need to be studying the hybrids, but whatever. The quality of the
Lycan models continues to improve, although their heads are still
not quite right. This movie removes all sympathy for the Lycans
that was in the background of the 1st and 3rd movies. It basically
does absolutely nothing for the mythology either. Perhaps it will
be more successful because of that, because you don't really need
to know anything about the previous movies to appreciate this
one. The mythological wankery only appeals to some, but this could
appeal to many.</p>

<p>The movie was noticeably more gory than previous movies. The only
time this bothered me was at the very beginning when Selene was
killing humans escaping. I don't mind gore when it is directed at
monsters or aliens, but humans shouldn't receive it. It is also
kind of uncharacteristic, because the previous movies have
established a vampire moral code that limits their consumption of
human blood.</p>

<p>I was surprised that Michael Corvin is basically not in the
movie. I was expecting him to come back and save the day in the
final fight after Selene had released him. (The actual ending
though, was supremely feminist, as the mother and daughter don't
really need help from the father, or men in general.) But I suppose
it was based on some contractual reason.</p>

<p>The Wikipedia page contains story information that I didn't get
from the movie. For example, the daughter's name is Eve and the
secret of the immortals was revealed to humans by the
doctor. Weird.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking about this movie the day after, there are some things
really strange about it:</p>

<p>All the movies more or less establish the vampires as basically in
the right, with the werewolves being too uncontrolled to be safe
for humans. Almost as if the vampires are protecting humans from
the immortals---especially given that they have a cultural
imperative to not consume human blood. (Viktor is a "bad" vampire
almost entirely because he sometimes breaks this rule.)</p>

<p>The first movie mixes this a little bit, portraying Lucian as
having been wronged and the vampires, especially Viktor, overly
prejudiced. But, it doesn't give Lucian any motives other than
revenge on vampires. Given that he is involved in offensive action,
it's not as if the vampires are simply out to get him. The war is
reciprocal.</p>

<p>The second movie really lays on the thick that danger of the
werewolves with the flash back sequences, but otherwise doesn't
really develop the reason for the conflict. It's basically just
sibling rivalry. (The movie is also weird because it makes very
little sense that Markus would act as he does now, as opposed to in
any of the previous 100 year periods where he was the sole reigning
vampire elder. It's especially incomprehensible why he destroys his
coven.)</p>

<p>The third movie doesn't really explain why Lucian would continue to
fight the vampires. It presents him as unassailably moral and a
freedom fighter. But once he gets his freedom, why does he have any
reason to continue fighting? Especially given that he thinks Viktor
is dead.</p>

<p>I presume that this won't be resolved or explained in the last
movie. But maybe not? It seems like Selene is the oldest vampire
that we've heard of it that is still alive and there has never been
any ranking werewolves other than Lucian and William.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
