<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-11T10:31:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Lockout, starring Guy Pearce (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun, fast-paced action movie. I liked how the world of
the future was very different, but there was no explanation of why
or how or in what way. It just looked really foreign, which was
pretty cool. The two lead villains were very crazy and
interesting. The main character, Snow, was very wise-cracking and
fun. Overall, the movie was a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Muppets, starring Jason Segel (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a hilarious movie with lots of really subtle and clever
moments. It's really amazing and hard to express all the crazy,
funny things in it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dear John, starring Channing Tatum (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was suggested by Netflix and I wasn't sure I would like
it. As we watched it, it was pretty cute and touching. It was very
reminiscent of how my wife and I were when we first met... fell in
love over the course of 10 days and then didn't see each for
months. I was really surprised when she dumped him and then years
and years past... it was a very depressing and unhappy ending.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Avengers, directed by Joss Whedon (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a great movie. Every character was very exciting and they
did a great job spreading out the interesting scenes for the
different characters. The only characters that weren't totally
awesome were Hawkeye and Black Widow, because they weren't really
super heroes... more "super spys" and that didn't seem to fit as
well. Also, I thought Hawkeye was a bit too shallow of a
character... the actor played him too "cool" and above-it-all.</p>

<p>There were some awesome jokes and funny moments. One of my
favourites was when Captain America, reacting to hearing that Thor
and Loki are gods, says, "Ma'am, there's only one God, and I don't
think He dresses like that." Not only was it delivered really well,
but it's such a great comment for his character as the epitome of
America.</p>

<p>Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk was great too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Jane Eyre, starring Mia Wasikowska (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie--Jane-Eyre--starring-Mia-Wasikowska--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie--Jane-Eyre--starring-Mia-Wasikowska--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'd never read Jane Eyre before, but didn't have very big
expectations for this movie. It was very well done and pretty
fascinating. I found the story to go very slowly and have a really
unpredictable structure. I expected to learn more about the
boarding school, but did not. I expected to learn more about her
job after meeting the Rivers, but did not. It seemed like it was
going to be a horror story before the old wife is revealed. After
getting through my expectations, it was very enjoyable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
