<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-02T22:11:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Ice Age: Continental Drift (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie--Ice-Age--Continental-Drift--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Movie--Ice-Age--Continental-Drift--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took my son to the theatre to see this today. He really enjoyed
it. I thought there were definitely some funny parts too, although
overall the plot is incredibly weak. It's very short and a kid's
movie, so that's understandable. In terms of plot, it's basically
the same as an episode of a cartoon, but with longer scenes and big
events. I thought the finale of the Scrat subplot was awesome
though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 1.0 You Are (Not) Alone, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we got this from Netflix, my wife said "Ugh, Evangelion?" But
I think she enjoyed it. She commented on how the music was really
good and we were both impressed by the obviously better graphics
and effects. It is amazing how much is the same between this and
the originals though. I think it is already clearer what the
greater story is. I think there are more risque shots than before,
but, even so, they are quite tame. Not much to say other than that
I like Evangelion and this was preferred to watching the original
episodes. (Although I do miss the theme song.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: 17 Miracles, directed by T.C. Christensen (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Movie--17-Miracles--directed-by-T-C--Christensen--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Movie--17-Miracles--directed-by-T-C--Christensen--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really nice movie. I felt like crying before the title
screen was even up. I cried a lot during the movie and found it
very uplifting. There were some problems with it... mainly that I
think a lot of assumes too much pre-existing knowledge about what
happened, rather than explaining it in the movie; particularly
with regard to the rescue. But it was an awesome movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra, starring Channing Tatum (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--starring-Channing-Tatum--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--starring-Channing-Tatum--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool... although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking... I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear... and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tower Heist, starring Ben Stiller (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie--Tower-Heist--starring-Ben-Stiller--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie--Tower-Heist--starring-Ben-Stiller--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched this on recommendation from some friends. I had never
heard of it, so I didn't know what to expect. I didn't know it was
a comedy. It was funny, but a lot of it was pretty low brow. I'm
not even sure I'd give it a three, despite the funny moments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
