<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T15:43:44-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Phantom of the Opera, by Andrew Lloyd Webber (2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie--The-Phantom-of-the-Opera--by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Movie--The-Phantom-of-the-Opera--by-Andrew-Lloyd-Webber--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was amazing. This visuals are crazy. The actors and
actresses are beautiful. Wow. I think my favourite moments are:
- when Christine is first going down to the Phantom's lair,
because the pull of the camera is so cool.
- the song "Masquerade" and its dance number---crazy.
Minnie Driver was great, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Nutcracker, performed by Ballet West (1892)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie--The-Nutcracker--performed-by-Ballet-West--1892--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/14/Movie--The-Nutcracker--performed-by-Ballet-West--1892--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight we saw Ballet West perform The Nutcracker, for our second
time. I had seen it one other time (that I can remember) performed
by the Boston Ballet.</p>

<p>I was very impressed with Sayaka for her Doll and Mirlitons. I
love the Doll because the choreography seems to be so precise,
quick, and on pointe all the time. I like the Mirlitons because
there are relatively few dancers, but they have interesting lines
and there's lots of the kind of ballet (pointe) I like.</p>

<p>Christiana was the Sugar Plum Fairy and was amazing. I love her
solo in the Grand Pas de Deux, because she shows such power and
grace by herself (i.e. without support.) I really like the cute
leg flips (I need to learn the terms) at the beginning of the
piece.</p>

<p>I really enjoy seeing this after I've been reading the ballet
history book. It was cool to see so many little things that I've
learned where they came from.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: An Education, staring Carey Mulligan (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie--An-Education--staring-Carey-Mulligan--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-13T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/13/Movie--An-Education--staring-Carey-Mulligan--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We're on a French &amp; infidelity kick right now, so this movie was a
natural choice.</p>

<p>I think the movie is very interesting. I feel like it's theme is
how Jenny learns what freedom is. She initially sees nothing good
in Miss Stubbs but drudgery. The glamour in David's life is
attractive, but it isn't earned and it has ugliness underneath it:
Helen gets no respect and is treated like a pet by Danny and David,
not to mention the crime. Jenny learns that this kind of freedom
has those risks and the cost of integrity. She is then surprised to
learn that liars lie and is told this in a clever way by Danny. We
later she her discovering true freedom (the joy of Miss Stubbs'
independence) and becoming the boss of the boys at Oxford.</p>

<p>I feel like the creepitude of their age gap is larger avoided, but
when it comes out, is particularly weird, but not in a truly
uncomfortable way.</p>

<p>I loved Jenny's comment in the evening in Paris. =)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Le Divorce, starring Naomi Watts and Kate Hudson (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting movie. I feel like the main point is that
we have two groups of people with loose morals, but vastly
different ways of reacting to them coming into conflict. The
characters are pretty complex and interesting. The environments,
food, clothes, and women all look very beautiful and elegant. It's
a fun non-stereotyped picture of France. I particularly like the
scene where the two police flirt. It serves no purpose other than
to say, "This can't happen in America."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Coco Before chanel, starring Audrey Tatou (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie--Coco-Before-chanel--starring-Audrey-Tatou--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Movie--Coco-Before-chanel--starring-Audrey-Tatou--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really neat movie. I didn't know anything about Coco
Chanel, besides who she was and that she had a major influence on
women's fashion. It was very interesting to learn about her life
before getting in to the fashion world. I like the subtlety of the
movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
