<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-22T02:03:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Vow, starring Rachel McAdams and Channing Tatum (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cute movie. There were a lot of cute moments. I
felt like the people in it were unrealistically mean to basically
everyone. I read the Wikipedia page and it talked about the real
couple was very religious and credit God for keeping them
together. It would have been nice to acknowledge that it
someway... but the couple in the movie weren't even married in a
church.</p>

<p>I think my favourite parts of the movie were the very subtle signs
of how much they loved each other. Such as rolling up the window
and the cat. Very cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Immortals, starring Henry Cavil (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really rad movie. It had a similar amazing look as 300,
but was much more fantasy oriented. The actions of the Gods in the
movie are awesome and not quite like anything I'd ever seen
before. The actions are the humans are exciting and down to Earth
in a neat contrasting way. Mickey Rourke does an amazing job as a
crazy warlord. The movie is a really great spectacle piece and is
totally worth it just for the way the Greek Gods are presented.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Haywire, starring Gina Carano (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a cool spy-action movie. I like how it emphasizes the
"soft" part of spy work (but not as much as something like
/Spygame/.) And, I think the fight scenes are really cool because
they are so slow and feel realistic. In a strange way, her
controlled fighting makes it almost less exciting, because she
seems so confident and in control all the time. There was lots of
neat camera work---mainly during the chase sequences. And, the
structuring of the story telling (in the beginning, she's narrating
to someone else) is interesting. The one thing I think could have
been a lot better about the movie was the final reveal: the reason
for the betrayal could have been more meaningful and cooler. But,
overall, it was a pretty rad movie. I can imagine watching more
movies with Gina Carano starring.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Contact, starring Jodie Foster (1997)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/12/Movie--Contact--starring-Jodie-Foster--1997--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/12/Movie--Contact--starring-Jodie-Foster--1997--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love this movie. It's so inspirational and moving. I particularly
like the deep connection between it and the Gospel. I think it hits
the nail on the head in so many ways and is incredibly
pro-religion, of a sorts. I've read the book and I like both of
them for different reasons. It's hard to say a lot about a movie I
just gush over.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Daybreakers, staring Ethan Hawke (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie has a very unique and interesting premise: a dystopia
where vampires have become the norm and humans are rare. The
beginning of the movie, where you learn about what normal vampire
culture is like, is the best and most interesting part of the
movie. The rest of it lacks any unifying idea that brings it
weight. The cure is discovered to be controlled sunlight, but no
explanation is given why this would work. The cure turns out to be
contagious, so when a former vampire is fed from the feeder is
cured. There's no explanation offered, although I would have liked
some pseudo-science. The rest of the movie is some pretty routine
chase and fight sequences. The movie feels very much like an
allegory about American imperialism and the ethic of kids who join
the military, combined with standard liberal concerns about oil,
etc. The other great missed opportunity is more guilt and attention
given to the main "bad guy"'s interaction with his daughter.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say the movie was a disappointment. It wasn't totally
terrible; I can definitely think of worse movies. But the majority
of what I got out of it, I would have had by just reading the
Wikipedia page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
