<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-20T23:06:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool... although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking... I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear... and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tower Heist, starring Ben Stiller (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie--Tower-Heist--starring-Ben-Stiller--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Movie--Tower-Heist--starring-Ben-Stiller--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched this on recommendation from some friends. I had never
heard of it, so I didn't know what to expect. I didn't know it was
a comedy. It was funny, but a lot of it was pretty low brow. I'm
not even sure I'd give it a three, despite the funny moments.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Super 8, directed by J. J. Abrams (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Movie--Super-8--directed-by-J--J--Abrams--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Movie--Super-8--directed-by-J--J--Abrams--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an /awesome/ movie. At one moment, my wife and I looked at
each other and said: "This movie is like the Goonies, but
AMAZING!" It starts so chill and then gets crazy. The young actors
are awesome and Elle Fanning is really cute with the kid. The
story was pretty neat... a kind of myth of the pure native, but in
a different way. The concept of the ship was really cool. The
meta-arc of the kids making the film was really neat too. Overall,
it was very cool and nostalgic. I liked all the ironic references
to what was exciting in technology during the early 80s.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Nick and Norah's Infinite Playlist, starring Michael Cera (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie--Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist--starring-Michael-Cera--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Movie--Nick-and-Norah-s-Infinite-Playlist--starring-Michael-Cera--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I didn't really know anything about this movie before watching it,
but heard it was interesting. It was really cool. It was so
nostalgic of what life was like for me when I was young... going
to shows all night, etc. That was really cool about it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Wrath of the Titans, starring Sam Worthington (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was fun, but definitely not as good as the first one. I
think the plot was much weaker and the cast was kind of thrown
together for no good reason---whereas the first one had a very
nice progression of how people joined the group.</p>

<p>Rosamund Pike was very beautiful, but it was very weird that the
actress from the previous movie was replaced and because she acted
so differently than the character before I didn't realize it was
supposed to be the same person.</p>

<p>Overall, I don't feel like the sequel was really necessary, which
is unfortunate, because I thought the first one was so good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
