<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-12T22:37:15-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Dark Knight Rises, directed by Christopher Nolan (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie--The-Dark-Knight-Rises--directed-by-Christopher-Nolan--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie--The-Dark-Knight-Rises--directed-by-Christopher-Nolan--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cool movie. I thought they did a great job setting
up Cat Woman and Blake as interesting characters. I liked all the
tragedy and doubt that was part of the plot... it made it more
dramatic. It's also cool how they incorporated the
Bane-destroys-Batman storyline from the comic. All around there was
cool stuff. I'm glad that they allowed the ending to really be an
ending.</p>

<p>My only complaint is that Bane's voice was a little too hard to
understand in a few key moments... it made me want subtitles, which
of course you can't have in a theatre.</p>

<p>Despite Nolan's insistence that the movie is not anti-Occupy, I
think it very much is. It shows the commies for what they really
are: blood-thirsty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Lockout, starring Guy Pearce (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun, fast-paced action movie. I liked how the world of
the future was very different, but there was no explanation of why
or how or in what way. It just looked really foreign, which was
pretty cool. The two lead villains were very crazy and
interesting. The main character, Snow, was very wise-cracking and
fun. Overall, the movie was a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Muppets, starring Jason Segel (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a hilarious movie with lots of really subtle and clever
moments. It's really amazing and hard to express all the crazy,
funny things in it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Dear John, starring Channing Tatum (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/02/Movie--Dear-John--starring-Channing-Tatum--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was suggested by Netflix and I wasn't sure I would like
it. As we watched it, it was pretty cute and touching. It was very
reminiscent of how my wife and I were when we first met... fell in
love over the course of 10 days and then didn't see each for
months. I was really surprised when she dumped him and then years
and years past... it was a very depressing and unhappy ending.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Avengers, directed by Joss Whedon (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a great movie. Every character was very exciting and they
did a great job spreading out the interesting scenes for the
different characters. The only characters that weren't totally
awesome were Hawkeye and Black Widow, because they weren't really
super heroes... more "super spys" and that didn't seem to fit as
well. Also, I thought Hawkeye was a bit too shallow of a
character... the actor played him too "cool" and above-it-all.</p>

<p>There were some awesome jokes and funny moments. One of my
favourites was when Captain America, reacting to hearing that Thor
and Loki are gods, says, "Ma'am, there's only one God, and I don't
think He dresses like that." Not only was it delivered really well,
but it's such a great comment for his character as the epitome of
America.</p>

<p>Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk was great too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
