<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-01T08:00:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn't seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It's a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld, starring Kate Beckinsale (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget why, but the other day I was reminded of this series. I
decided to start watching it, similar to how I went through the
Resident Evil movies. Like that series, I saw the first one when it
came out, but never saw the others. I remember thinking the movie
was cool and that Kate Beckinsale was amazing attractive.</p>

<p>On a second viewing, significantly older, I still think some parts
of the movie are cool. The mythology is interesting and fairly
developed. The actor of Viktor is pretty awesome; while the actor
that played Kraven was unbelievably bad. The character of Erica is
really interesting and subtle. And, yes, Kate Beckinsale is
woah---except, I don't understand the appeal of the "cat suits",
they make all her natural curves indistinguishable, like a running
bra or something. I don't get it, but I guess that had to because
this movie was made to be so Matrix-y. The action sequences are
very derivative of the Matrix and pretty boring overall
actually. Lots of akimbo and chunks of buildings flying off. The
best fight is probably the very first one. Even the final fight
between Viktor and Michael is pretty meh, because Michael is so
"whatever" that it doesn't get too exciting.</p>

<p>Definitely not a classic, but I'm interested in watching the rest
of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Rise of the Planet of the Apes, starring James Franco and Andy Seeks (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie--Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes--starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Movie--Rise-of-the-Planet-of-the-Apes--starring-James-Franco-and-Andy-Seeks--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was really different than I thought it would be. I
expected that the end of the movie would be closer to ape dominance
and I expected that the character of Caesar would be more of a hero
for humans---kind of the only smart ape that loved humans, whereas
the other ones (like Koba) would just hate them. The movie was
pretty cool and Caesar was a great epic leader. There were lots of
really cool "A-hah!" moments of his progression that were super
satisfying. I'd like to see sequels to this made.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol, starring Tom Cruise (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a big budget popcorn summer movie, but a pretty good one
of that category. It starts off, and sounds like, it will be just
like all the other movies, with practically the same setup; but it
quickly acknowledges that and goes in a different direction. They
didn't over use the faces, like they've done before, and they there
was only one real bad scene of Tom Cruise fawning over himself. I
think my major disappointments were its lack of a romantic sub-plot
and the lack of real consequences to not being able to use IMF
resources---even though they explicitly mention how that is
standing in their way at a few points, they solve the problem too
easily.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Castle of Cagliostro, directed by Hayao Miyazaki (1979)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie--The-Castle-of-Cagliostro--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--1979--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Movie--The-Castle-of-Cagliostro--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--1979--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun anime movie. I like all the little subtle visual
jokes that they have and the general wackiness of the action. I
think you need to be a little bit older to appreciate it though, so
we didn't watch it with the kids.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
