<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Movies | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/movies/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-12T19:30:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kagemusha, directed by Akira Kurosawa (1980)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Movie--Kagemusha--directed-by-Akira-Kurosawa--1980--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Movie--Kagemusha--directed-by-Akira-Kurosawa--1980--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second Kurosawa film that I've seen. I thought it was
done very well and the story was incredibly interesting, but
definitely not exciting. It was well acted. A lot of the movie went
on too long. The battle scenes are very long and drag without much
interesting stuff going on. Additionally, there are a few
"psychedelic" scenes that really date the movie. All that aside, I
think it was pretty cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: My Life in Ruins, starring Nia Vardalos (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a pretty bad movie, but bad in that way that Pringles are,
where you think they are good while you're eating them, but every
so often you think "What am I doing?" and afterward as you reflect
on it, you regret. You should read the Wikipedia page on the
Critical Reception. I very much agree. There are a few funny
moments, but overall it feels so fake. The best part is how
realistic the tour members are. I direct tours, actually, and I
find a lot of it to be true to life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Avatar, starring Sam Worthington (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Movie--Avatar--starring-Sam-Worthington--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Movie--Avatar--starring-Sam-Worthington--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched this movie tonight. I heard a lot about it when it came
out, suggesting that it was a lame movie, but with some cool 3D
effects. Obviously I didn't watch it in 3D, but I found the normal
effects and the story to actually be pretty cool. I was
impressed. Obviously it is very Fern Gully, but there a lot of
other cool stuff going on to. It's the good kind of science fiction
where you know there is a lot more to the world than you can
see. The concept of the electrical connection between all the
different creatures is really cool. The plot, and a lot of specific
actions, are both really predicable and telegraphed clearly, but
hey, it's pretty fun. Wikipedia claims there will be sequels. That
could be cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Ponyo, directed by Hayao Miyazaki (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/25/Movie--Ponyo--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/25/Movie--Ponyo--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My three year old loved this movie when he was two and it was on
Netflix. I think it is very cute and does a great job with the
visuals and in particular the expressiveness of the characters. I
think the kids act <em>just</em> like little kids. I don't like the plot
as much as other Miyazaki movies because almost nothing
happens. It's very meh. But it is still good because of how cool
the characters are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunger Games, starring Jennifer Lawrence (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Movie--The-Hunger-Games--starring-Jennifer-Lawrence--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Movie--The-Hunger-Games--starring-Jennifer-Lawrence--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw this on opening day, because my wife was going with some
friends and someone fell through, so I took the last ticket. I have
never read the books, so I don't really have opinions or
predilections about it. I thought the world was neat. They did a
good job showing the opulence of the people in the capitol, but I
don't think they really made the oppression disgusting enough. The
action was fun and she was pretty heroic---I found myself tearing
up a few times. I find the world to be pretty unbelievable
though. I don't understand how the people in the capitol could be
supportive of the oppression, when they don't seem to be kept in
the dark or otherwise "brainwashed" into thinking that they are
doing great things for the districts. Similarly, I don't understand
why they would not take better care of the districts or why the
districts would not have already gone on strike. The idea that this
could go on for 74 years strains credulity. I don't think Katniss
is a very consistent character. The movie communicated to me that
she was all about doing the right thing and would rather die than
not do that; yet, she doesn't do a whole lot against "the man". For
example, when she talks to Peter at night before the games start,
he says he wants to show that he is not "owned" and she agrees, but
says she'd like to go home. The way this scene plays out and how
she is so non-aggressive during the games said to me that she
really agreed with him. Yet, she never actually does anything to go
against them. Dying together at the end is a little bit like that,
but you get the impression that she knew they wouldn't let her do
it, and therefore it was an empty calculation rather than a
confident objection. Overall, I really enjoyed the movie, but I
felt like it could be more. My wife says that it is part one of a
trilogy and my wishes will come true in some way in the
future. That's fine... but... it's annoying when you need to know
something about the real world to appreciate a movie... when it
can't satisfy you on its own.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
