<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: A Boy and His Blob | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/a-boy-and-his-blob/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-12T19:30:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: A Boy and His Blob (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/13/Game--A-Boy-and-His-Blob--Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/10/13/Game--A-Boy-and-His-Blob--Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through A Boy and His Blob for the Wii. I'd been
watching this game since it was announced because it was 2D,
looked beautiful, and looked really cute too.</p>

<p>When I first started playing, I was very thorough: getting
every treasure and going through every challenge level, but
eventually (as you read below) the challenge levels became
incredibly painful and I started to hate the game because of
them. After that I just raced through the game and didn't even get
many chests in the final world.</p>

<h1>Things I loved</h1>

<p>The 2D graphics are really pretty. I like the brightness and
the fluidity of them in particular. I like that the levels reflect
what the world map implies about them and sometimes you can see
the later landmarks on the map from inside them.  For example,
seeing the tower from the middle of the final world was epic.</p>

<p>The whole style is incredibly cute and heartwarming. The boy is
the best five year old I've ever seen in a game and I love the hug
animation. Even the enemies are kind of pudgy and cute.</p>

<p>The vast variety of beans is very entertaining. Only a few of
them overlap in functionality, so the puzzles are not necessarily
"non-linear", but the variety of different kinds of puzzles keeps
it fresh. I would've liked a mode where I could play a level with
a custom selection of beans (perhaps after I beat it or got all
the chests.)</p>

<p>The puzzles are clever enough. There are a few places where you
can really break things with creativity, but that is fun. For
example, you can get birds to hit mine blobs and just walk out of
some otherwise difficult things; the Zorb bean can survive any
fall and is invulnerable, so you can just jump in it and then jump
off a cliff rather than blob-achute down. I think the final areas
(in the castles) had the best puzzles in terms of difficulty and
interestingatude.</p>

<p>I was very surprised when I got to the first boss battle. I
thought the worked really well as multi-part puzzles. Although,
I'll complain about them more later... that they exist is
definitely a plus.</p>

<p>I was impressed with the lack of text and the way the game
communicated to you what you were supposed to do and the
intentions of the blob, etc. This is best illustrated by the lack
of a menu. I love that you turn the game on and are almost
instantly controlling the boy.</p>

<p>MECHA BLOB!</p>

<h1>Things I hated</h1>

<p>Although the puzzles were clever and interesting, there was not
enough mystery because almost every stage has a sign instructing
you which of the four beans is the correct one to use for that
segment. This really kills a lot of the enjoyment, because you're
not so much "solving the puzzle" as "executing the solution". I
will complain below about the tools you have for "executing", so
this turns out to be a big problem.</p>

<p>Unlike the rest of the game, the challenge levels don't have
checkpoints. This makes playing them really jarring because it
doesn't fit with the general feel. Since the challenge levels have
the hardest "reflex" challenges (more below), this is particularly
annoying. Some of the challenge levels are just stupid-cheap
too. For example, I quit playing them after one where you had to
drop a Trampobean down a pit and then jump hoping you landed on it
correctly. You then had to do this four more times, restarting
from the beginning when you missed. Since the beans bounce and
have physics applied to them, it is frustrating and unsatisfying
to make the jump correctly.</p>

<p>There are a few annoying bugs. Level 4-1 sticks in my mind
because you don't have the blob with you, so he doesn't eat the
chests. Instead, you drop them into the ground level where the
blob will get them later. I dropped every chest and made it to the
next checkpoint, yet only two chests were there at the
end. Arggh.</p>

<h1>The biggest most "shoot myself in the face" problem</h1>

<p>The controls are unimaginably bad. They are sluggish and
inaccurate. It is like trying to push an anvil with a wet
noodle. I've read the developers talk about how this is partly
because the boy is supposed to be a clumsy kid but that seems like
a total cop-out. This just plain sucks. I think the sluggish-ness
would not be as bad if you could use the D-pad to control the boy,
but even on the Classic controller (where most buttons duplicate
what another button does), you cannot. This is especially dumb
because the game is 2D.</p>

<p>In general, this horrible control would be much more passable
if the game did not require reflexes. Yet, there are many reflex
sections that require exact platforming control yet the mechanics
do not give the ability to do it. I don't mind restarting levels,
etc (I play shmups after all), but that's because the games I play
that require that always make clear that it is /your fault/
when you die and it never feels like the game's fault. I can
honestly say that almost all the time, I felt like I was dying
because the controls were so bad. There is nothing more
frustrating than this.</p>

<p>The bad controls are made worse by some of the custom bean
controls. The Zorb, Rocket, and Bouncer are the biggest offenders,
because they are the most mobile beans. The Blobachute is bad
too.</p>

<p>This problem is why the challenge levels were so bad. They were
almost all reflex based and had a higher than normal restart
penalty. The bosses were frustrating for the same reason. The
third boss was one of the worst gaming experiences of my life. I
wanted to blow my brains out. Ugh.</p>

<h1>The verdict</h1>

<p>This is a good game, but not a classic. I only want to play
classics. I don't think I'll be playing this much more, but if I
have a young friend in the near future I may point them at this or
donate the game to them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
