<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: SNES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/snes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-25T23:32:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 7 (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mega-Man-7--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mega-Man-7--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son asked for this game today (rather than the next game in our
sequence, Mega Man 4.) So I played it for about an hour. I
couldn't beat any levels, but I fought Freeze Man and Cloud Man a
few times and got all the secret items on their stages. I think I
need to invest in Energy Tanks prior to a boss battle.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/23/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that I'm not going to continue playing this game. It's
definitely not a bad game, but it's also not an excellent
game. Given its age, there are really some interface things that
it should have done better:</p>

<ul>
<li>attacks should not go into empty space</li>
<li>you should be able to see what equipment will improve your stats
and buy them easier</li>
<li>you should be able to see what items do</li>
</ul>


<p>Now, if I had a lot of nostalgia for this game, I would be much
more willing to play it to experience the story and world again,
but I have much more nostalgia for the second game. In terms of
story, this game basically does everything I think is cool in the
first few hours and then it's just been standard JRPG fare.</p>

<p>I do find the concept of the Old Cave with the "task" system to be
pretty interesting, but not enough to make me want to keep doing
it.</p>

<p>Basically this game will be left aside because of the "there's
not enough time in the world to play non-amazing games". I guess
this means that I can't really recommend the game either, because
there's things you should play instead, but it's still not a
"bad" game. For example, I prefer it to the PS3 Star Ocean or
some of the other modern junk I've tried to play.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/22/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I got to the Old Cave and
to the Tower in the Northwest, but the enemies in the entry way
were pretty brutal. I feel like this game is almost all grind in
that way the DQ can be. There haven't really been any cute
moments in the story since the main character and Lufia don't
talk to each other anymore.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half while we were watching a TV
show on my wife's laptop. It was relaxing to grind a bit. I got
to the port town and met the guy who knew Guy. The story is very
simple so far, but it's nice in a Dragon-Quest-y way.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lufia & The Fortress Of Doom (SNES, 1993)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/20/Game--Lufia---The-Fortress-Of-Doom--SNES--1993--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this game for about an hour this morning. The beginning
is a really cool "abilitease". I find the movement speed really
painful. I worked my way to the castle in the north and then
back. This game is one of the most Dragon-Quest-y clones I've
played recently. When I first played it, it had been a long time
since I played a Dragon Quest game, so I didn't realize it. But
now, it's quite amazing. Even down to the Dragon Quest 2 problem
of attacks against monsters that are now gone not
connecting. It's cute so far though.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
