<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: TG16 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/tg16/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-23T23:41:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Military Madness (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Military-Madness--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Military-Madness--TG16--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played the first, second, and third levels over about an
hour. I didn't finish the last level.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the game. It is extremely similar to Advance Wars. I
find the interface in Advance Wars to be superior and the game is
more complex, but not in a way that is extremely complex. Both
are very simple, but they allow that simplicity to be used to
create interesting and challenging situations. But, because of
the similarity, I don't feel a great compulsion to play this
game, particularly when it is so inconvenient to do so. (I have a
Japanese PC Engine, so my Hu-Card doesn't work, so I have to
emulate it.)</p>

<p>Maybe if I got deeper into the game, there would be something
unlike about it that would be worth understanding, but after
scanning a FAQ, it doesn't seem so.</p>

<p>I would really like a procedurally generated game like this where
I could play at incredibly small chunks overtime. Until then... I
think I'll abandon it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Later in the day, I played for almost three hours.</p>

<p>I beat up to level 5. I find the game to be so much like LoZ but
bigger in ways that don't make it better.</p>

<p>There are some similar items (like the Rainbow Drop is the same as
the Ladder) and some unique ones (like the Glowing Moss). But
there's a lot that isn't there and what is added isn't great.</p>

<p>The levels are all a lot bigger, but they look too much the same
that they are extremely confusing and kind of frustrating. Same
with the various overworlds.</p>

<p>There are upgrades to your armor and weapon, but they don't really
feel much better because the enemies are getting stronger too. (In
contrast, in LoZ, the enemies in the overworld are all the same
and as you get stronger stuff, you see the same guys more and get
to thrash them.)</p>

<p>The bosses are huge and cool looking, but they take way too long
to kill once you've learned their pattern and can totally avoid
being hit.</p>

<p>Overall, the game just isn't as refined as LoZ. I got over the
problems with the combat with a little more attention, but I feel
like the rest of the game will just be a chore. I don't think I
will finish it.</p>

<p>I bet if I grew up with a TurboGrafx rather than a Nintendo, I
would love this game, but as it stands, it's just meh.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:05</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half an hour today on an emulator.</p>

<p>It's a strange game. It seems like it is trying to be Legend of
Zelda I, but it has tried to evolve, it seems. For instance, I
felt like inside every cave was a person just blathering on about
stuff that didn't matter. The combat feels a bit... off. It's
like it is very hard to line enemies up. In LTTP, since the sword
slices in an arc, it never really matters if you aren't lined up
perfectly. In LoZ, you do need to be straight, but I think the
enemies are guaranteed to be in a grid, so it is easy to hit
them. It's a strange thing to miss. It seems like the dungeons
are much more linear and I got to the end of one, but couldn't
beat the boss (after a ton of tries)... it seems to have way too
much health.</p>

<p>I will give it another session... but I'm not impressed.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Devil's Crush (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like Alien Crush, this game is a very exciting and interesting
pinball table. I feel like this game is a lot crazier because
after the initial ideas in Alien Crush, they were able to go all
out. There's lots moving around on the course, there's three
layers, and many complicated dependencies between
pieces. In that sense, it's much better. Plus, they added a
pass-the-controller 2-player option, which is pretty neat.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the ball physics feel much worse and the ball seems
totally outside of your control. I think part of it is that the
board is broken into three screens and each one is squatter (and
thus more detailed) than any screen was in Alien Crush. At the end
of the day, the game feels worse, despite looking much cooler.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I could imagine playing this game a lot... if not
for the interface friction.</p>

<p>When I played, my dad and I did the pass-the-controller for a
bit. My best score was 3.7 mil. I got this by getting the castle
on the bottom and then just being super cautious whenever I was
on the bottom screen. It worked like a charm!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Alien Crush (TG16, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Alien-Crush--TG16--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Alien-Crush--TG16--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while today on an emulator. This game is
gorgeous and amazingly detailed. I love the "living" board
concept and it works really well. The hit detection on the bottom
on the paddles seems a bit off, but it's not too hard to get used
to.</p>

<p>I got a 1.3 mil score and my dad got 4.7 mil. It was fun to pass
the game back and forth. But, for me, there's not enough of a
carrot to chase after, because I don't really have a good concept
of what scores are possible and most of my deaths felt random &amp;
weren't learning experiences.</p>

<p>I enjoy the game a lot, although I'm not sure how much I
like <em>this</em> game and how much I just like pinball. In any case,
the problem with the game is the amount of friction it takes to
setup and play for how long would be optimal. I can imagine
playing this for 10 minutes at a time, but it would take at least
5 to get everything ready to play it. This game (with what is
available today to be entertained with) needs some external
scheduling and a speedy front-end.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
