<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-31T00:25:23-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Pirates of the Caribbean: On Stranger Tides, starring Johnny Depp (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie--Pirates-of-the-Caribbean--On-Stranger-Tides--starring-Johnny-Depp--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Movie--Pirates-of-the-Caribbean--On-Stranger-Tides--starring-Johnny-Depp--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the first Pirates movie and the other ones were
pretty bad. I think their biggest failure was being too fantasy and
with too many monsters, etc. This movie doesn't have that problem,
but it is definitely not as good as previous ones.</p>

<p>There are some fun moments of <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow being <em>REDACTED</em> Sparrow. A
few absurd fights and chases. It's a fairly fun and crazy movie.
The mermaids are totally beautiful and the mermaid who serves as
the love interest has a very sweet and innocent feel to her.</p>

<p>If you stop to think about a lot of the movie, it is pretty absurd
and silly, but I'm not sure I should really expect anything
different. It's a solid B+. I think with a few more exciting fights
and a bit more plot coherence it could have been an A-.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I spent the time
working my way through Blighttown. It was very scary and tough. I
would get repeatedly pummeled by the huge ghouls and then I kept
falling off and getting swarmed closer to the swamp. It was pretty
rough. Quite a few times, the dogs at the very beginning caught me
off guard and decimated me.</p>

<p>Probably the worst time was when I was working my way back to the
swamp the first time, I attacked and the animation pushed me over
the edge of the cliff and I lost 7.7k souls... about a level where
I am in the game. After that, it was really hard to get back to
the swamp.</p>

<p>It's very fun in this game to slowly push through to the next area
and then the next, etc. One thing that I dislike compared to
Demon's Souls is that, because there is no hub, you can't get back
to a place to buy things, like arrows, if you need them
easily. It's kind of frustrating.</p>

<p>SL: 35</p>

<p>Vit: 18
Att:  8!
End: 26
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 10:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/29/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/29/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three and half hours tonight. I went through
the rest of the Undead Parish and then Lower Undead Burg and then
I beat the Dragon in the depths. I beat the Gargoyle on my first
try tonight by spamming it real hard. The demon in the lower burg
took quite a few tries before I took him down. I just got locked
in a combo the first times and couldn't recover, but once I got
the dogs out of the way it was easy. When I was exploring the
Depths I got surprise attacked many times and was surprised by
some traps, but eventually I got through. I fought the dragon at
the end about seven times. The third or so I tried to fight as a
human with a phantom helper, but I wasn't skilled enough to win
that time. Eventually I got good at running away from him and then
swooping in to his back for attacking. When I finally won, I did
it by hacking off his tail and then winning by attrition.</p>

<p>I think I lost about 6k souls tonight through various hiccups.</p>

<p>I'm still enjoying the game and finding it very fun to push
through. I'm getting close to being able to diversify my equipment,
I think. That'll be nice to experiment with.</p>

<p>SL: 34</p>

<p>Vit: 18
Att:  8!
End: 25
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 8:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/27/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Puzzle 26 (a moving block puzzle) took me 2641 steps... the
optimal is just 30 moves.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little over an hour. I got through the next
part of the Undead Parish. The Rhino was pretty tough and got me
once. Then I weaved my way around and accidentally stumbled into
the Bell Gargoyle fight. I died the first three times and then
accidentally died on the way. So I lost about 6k souls. Ouch. This
game is definitely great.</p>

<p>SL: 21</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 18
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 4:56</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
