<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-17T07:11:54-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Geek Charming, starring Sarah Hyland (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very predicable teen comedy of the poor to riches
variety, complete with the standard dual friend abandonment and
inner growth. Nevertheless, it was a good version of this story and
had a few cute things. A lot of the characters acknowledge the
camera too much, but when they are bit more free and their perfect
teeth aren't totally showing, it gets a little real and that's
nice. Overall, a fun, refreshing, ray of sunshine. Like a good pop
song on a rainy day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Muchi Muchi Pork & Pink Sweets (X360, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to be basically done with these games. Both are not
nearly as good as Deathsmiles, ESPgaluda II, or Mushihime-sama
Futari. Pink Sweets isn't even really good at all for me. Both
lack the insane music and really popping/flowing feel of the other
games. I think I might play MMP every once in a while to
experience it a little bit, but it's not something I love at
all. Overall, a bit of a bad purchase, seeing as I brought it back
from Japan myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Muchi Muchi Pork & Pink Sweets (X360, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/12/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Pink Sweets - 364,870 points. 1-2 #562 #hiscore</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Paradise Kiss, starring Keiko Kitagawa (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Movie--Paradise-Kiss--starring-Keiko-Kitagawa--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Movie--Paradise-Kiss--starring-Keiko-Kitagawa--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really loved this movie. The plot is great. The story is very
subtle. For example, in an early scene George pressures Yukari into
a love hotel, seemingly to rape her, but I found it to be
incredibly clear that his real intentions were to force her to
stand up for herself by ensuring that inaction would lead to
something she definitely couldn't accept. It's got all the elements
of a great movie: fun, cute people, drama, love, beautiful
costumes, etc. At many times in the movie, I thought it was going
to go one way, but was wrong. For example, at one point their
consignment clothes are returned and they give up working together;
I assumed that Yukari---with her school skills---would create some
sort of advertising campaign and make their business work. Nope. I
like being surprised though. =) The music was also awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Hugo, directed by Martin Scorsese (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/Movie--Hugo--directed-by-Martin-Scorsese--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/09/Movie--Hugo--directed-by-Martin-Scorsese--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a neat movie. It reminds me a lot of Amelie---both in its
Frenchness and that there are slightly fantastical things going on
in an otherwise mundane plot. There was some pretty bad CG
work---the people on the platform in the opening sequence. The
characters were very funny and memorable. It was neat to learn
about Meilies---I read his Wikipedia page afterward. Nevertheless,
it seemed pretty shameless in its appeal to the Academy for awards:
it's a movie about how awesome movies are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
