<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T19:11:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Arthur, starring Russel Brand (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie--Arthur--starring-Russel-Brand--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Movie--Arthur--starring-Russel-Brand--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a cute movie with a pretty unique plot. The main girl was
cute and wholesome. I feel like the ending was a bit empty though,
because other than going to AA there was no explanation of how
Arthur changed. Th end of the movie suggested that Arthur's only
problem was that he drank a lot (and perhaps having so many
resources exacerbated the impact of that), but didn't deal at all
with his lack of knowledge, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Crazy, Stupid, Love., starring Steve Carell (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/07/Movie--Crazy--Stupid--Love---starring-Steve-Carell--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/07/Movie--Crazy--Stupid--Love---starring-Steve-Carell--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a great movie. It was very clever all over the place and
had a great cast. I was totally oblivious to the central twice and
it made for a really fun ending. Highly recommended!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Sucker Punch, directed by Zack Snyder (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Movie--Sucker-Punch--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Movie--Sucker-Punch--directed-by-Zack-Snyder--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a crazy movie. It is very disturbing, but in a way that is
always beneath the surface in a hidden way. The double layered
fantasy world that the girls live in is terrible, but what's most
disturbing is that it is hiding a worse world. The fantasy within
that is really insane and feels very Japanese in its absurdity. I
liked that about it a lot. The visual effects and photography were
really interesting and different---particularly the beginning
sequence was crazy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that life is too short to play games like Rayman Origins
when there are amazing games I haven't played enough. So I'm
stopping. I did everything possible in the first world and
everything possible in the first half of the second world. The
horrible controls are not worth the adorable setting of the
game... unfortunately.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half today. I did two chase
levels and a shmup level. There's so much about this game that is
admirable: the music is cool, the level design is pretty neat,
the graphics are great. But man! The controls are SOOOOOOOOOO
bad. It's like every level is the worst under-water level ever
from Mario. Rayman is just so slippery and hard to
control. Ugh. It makes me want to not play the game at all, but
I'm a masochist and can't resist. I'll definitely remove every of
Rayman game from my list though.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
