<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-25T22:05:32-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Mission Impossible: Ghost Protocol, starring Tom Cruise (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/19/Movie--Mission-Impossible--Ghost-Protocol--starring-Tom-Cruise--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a big budget popcorn summer movie, but a pretty good one
of that category. It starts off, and sounds like, it will be just
like all the other movies, with practically the same setup; but it
quickly acknowledges that and goes in a different direction. They
didn't over use the faces, like they've done before, and they there
was only one real bad scene of Tom Cruise fawning over himself. I
think my major disappointments were its lack of a romantic sub-plot
and the lack of real consequences to not being able to use IMF
resources---even though they explicitly mention how that is
standing in their way at a few points, they solve the problem too
easily.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did Puzzle 2 today, which was a classic example of what I love
and hate about these games. The puzzle was about how one picture
was different than three others. I initially answered wrong
because I selected the different one, rather than the three same
ones, because I didn't read the directions clear enough. Argh. It
should have said that I didn't select three rather than making me
answer wrong. Then, when I converted my answer (based on the
presence of what seemed to be a different un-movable object in the
background) and found out I was wrong. I tried a few different
logical (to me) ideas and was wrong. This made me frustrated like
there was going to be some out of nowhere explanation for the
similarities that I'd never have guessed. When the wrong reason
(standing still versus not) led to the right solution, it
described that the solution was really about the shadow of the
people in the photo to show the time... which made me happy again
because it was a reasonable explanation I could have thought of
but just didn't.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven't been doing puzzles for about two months, so I decided to
start again today. So far, the story is very intriguing and the
Emmy character is funny. Normally these games take a while to get
to interesting puzzles, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Geek Charming, starring Sarah Hyland (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Movie--Geek-Charming--starring-Sarah-Hyland--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very predicable teen comedy of the poor to riches
variety, complete with the standard dual friend abandonment and
inner growth. Nevertheless, it was a good version of this story and
had a few cute things. A lot of the characters acknowledge the
camera too much, but when they are bit more free and their perfect
teeth aren't totally showing, it gets a little real and that's
nice. Overall, a fun, refreshing, ray of sunshine. Like a good pop
song on a rainy day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Muchi Muchi Pork & Pink Sweets (X360, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Muchi-Muchi-Pork---Pink-Sweets--X360--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to be basically done with these games. Both are not
nearly as good as Deathsmiles, ESPgaluda II, or Mushihime-sama
Futari. Pink Sweets isn't even really good at all for me. Both
lack the insane music and really popping/flowing feel of the other
games. I think I might play MMP every once in a while to
experience it a little bit, but it's not something I love at
all. Overall, a bit of a bad purchase, seeing as I brought it back
from Japan myself.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
