<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-17T00:06:57-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today and got used to the game. I
spent a long time planning my character based on remembering what
was a good strategy in Demon's Souls. I'll be taking the same
approach: really fast, huge shield, melee focus, but with a good
bow.</p>

<p>The tutorial phase of the game was much shorter and so far the
game seems incredibly linear, which I thought wasn't the case, but
maybe I'm just still in the beginning. Last time I took a very
linear approach through the game, but this time I intend to
explore a bit more.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game are basically identical. The graphics
seem a little bit better... primarily in the lightning department,
but I don't know if I can really tell or I just have a bad
memory. It seems like this simply <em>is</em> Demon's Souls with a little
bit of a different structure---no hub, Humanity, etc.</p>

<p>That makes it sound like I don't like the idea of that, but I'm
actually very excited about playing it.</p>

<p>During my time tonight, I died twice. Each time against a boss on
my first fight with them. The game seems just as hard as before,
but I'm getting used to the controls again and learning how the
bosses behave. Overall, it's a pretty awesome game.</p>

<p>Here are my current stats (where ! indicates that the stat is at
the level I intend to leave it at for the foreseeable future):</p>

<p>SL: 19</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 16
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 3:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for about an hour and beat the last two levels on
my first try (tonight, the second to last level took me about four
or five tries total.) The final level was basically a boss rush
plus a new boss at the end. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>I concurred with everything I said yesterday. This game is worth
everything I paid for it. ;) I would've probably been happy if I
paid $15 for it. I intend to gradually play through the levels
again on Hard and through the Challenge mode. Probably once a week
on Sunday. I enjoyed the game and it will be in the back of my
mind for a while, but it's not a revelation.</p>

<p>I wonder how it is with Kinect or Move?</p>

<p>Total time: 3:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game as a prize from Call of Podcast for writing about
my game management system. It was on my to-buy list before that,
although I was planning on buying the PS3 version. The game looked
really beautiful and I really like Genki Rockets. I played Rez for
the Dreamcast and wasn't really blown away, but I thought that it
might be more interesting in a more modern form.</p>

<p>The game opens up with a really intriguing video and quickly shows
off its unique, beautiful world.</p>

<p>I played it for about an hour and half tonight. I beat the
first three levels on the first try, although I had to do each
twice to unlock the next level. I played the fourth level about
four times, but kept dying at the final form of the boss, because
it shoots so many tracer rounds.</p>

<p>I find the gameplay to be enjoyable and challenging, at least when
you get totally overwhelmed by bullets. I suppose I should get
better at using the screen clearing bombs. The addition of the
tracer rounds seems like it would be an insignificant change, but
it makes a huge difference compared to Rez.</p>

<p>I love the music, although I wish that there were more vocals,
like the actual Genki Rockets song. It may be that I'm not playing
well enough to unlock them though... on that note, I dislike how
it seems like I am doing the levels perfect (not getting hit,
getting mostly perfect octo-locks) but I'm only get three stars a
pop. It's weird.</p>

<p>I love that every level is totally different visually and aurally
from the others. This game is the perfect of a game that seems
like it was made on a totally different planet. I've played plenty
of Japanese games that do this, but most Western games lack that
kind of creativity.</p>

<p>I intend to keep trucking at it and beat. I haven't yet decided if
I will play through the hard mode or if I will just periodically
play through the whole game when I want to chill out to some rad
music, or show someone the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Immortals, starring Henry Cavil (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Immortals--starring-Henry-Cavil--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really rad movie. It had a similar amazing look as 300,
but was much more fantasy oriented. The actions of the Gods in the
movie are awesome and not quite like anything I'd ever seen
before. The actions are the humans are exciting and down to Earth
in a neat contrasting way. Mickey Rourke does an amazing job as a
crazy warlord. The movie is a really great spectacle piece and is
totally worth it just for the way the Greek Gods are presented.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Haywire, starring Gina Carano (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Movie--Haywire--starring-Gina-Carano--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a cool spy-action movie. I like how it emphasizes the
"soft" part of spy work (but not as much as something like
/Spygame/.) And, I think the fight scenes are really cool because
they are so slow and feel realistic. In a strange way, her
controlled fighting makes it almost less exciting, because she
seems so confident and in control all the time. There was lots of
neat camera work---mainly during the chase sequences. And, the
structuring of the story telling (in the beginning, she's narrating
to someone else) is interesting. The one thing I think could have
been a lot better about the movie was the final reveal: the reason
for the betrayal could have been more meaningful and cooler. But,
overall, it was a pretty rad movie. I can imagine watching more
movies with Gina Carano starring.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
