<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2011 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2011/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T22:50:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Sherlock Holmes: A Game of Shadows, starring Robert Downey, Jr. (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/Movie--Sherlock-Holmes--A-Game-of-Shadows--starring-Robert-Downey--Jr---2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/15/Movie--Sherlock-Holmes--A-Game-of-Shadows--starring-Robert-Downey--Jr---2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was an interesting movie. The whole plot is really loose and a
bit lifeless compared to the first. It improves a lot towards the
end. The beginning just feels like lots of stupid moments for
Downey to do his thing. It's funny of in this universe Holmes is
this weird kung-fu master guy. There's lots of really cool effects
and moments that I enjoyed in the movie though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Muppets, starring Jason Segel (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/06/Movie--The-Muppets--starring-Jason-Segel--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a hilarious movie with lots of really subtle and clever
moments. It's really amazing and hard to express all the crazy,
funny things in it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Jane Eyre, starring Mia Wasikowska (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie--Jane-Eyre--starring-Mia-Wasikowska--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/29/Movie--Jane-Eyre--starring-Mia-Wasikowska--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'd never read Jane Eyre before, but didn't have very big
expectations for this movie. It was very well done and pretty
fascinating. I found the story to go very slowly and have a really
unpredictable structure. I expected to learn more about the
boarding school, but did not. I expected to learn more about her
job after meeting the Rivers, but did not. It seemed like it was
going to be a horror story before the old wife is revealed. After
getting through my expectations, it was very enjoyable.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Captain America, starring Chris Evans (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/20/Movie--Captain-America--starring-Chris-Evans--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/20/Movie--Captain-America--starring-Chris-Evans--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For some reason I had lower expectations for this movie than recent
super hero movies I've seen. It turned out to be very good. I think
my favourite parts were the bravery of Steve in the
beginning... like when he jumped on the grenade... and then the
great way they sold the crazy Captain America costume. I think it
worked really well. It was kind of disappointing that the romance
didn't really get anywhere, but it was very romantic the way he had
her picture in his compass. The thing in the promo film was super
cute. Overall, a good movie. I'm excited to see The Avengers!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Cowboys & Aliens, starring Daniel Craig (2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie--Cowboys---Aliens--starring-Daniel-Craig--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/Movie--Cowboys---Aliens--starring-Daniel-Craig--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really enjoyed the blend of Western and Sci-Fi style. I was glad
that the aliens had a sensible purpose for being on Earth. I liked
that there was a deeper world in the background, but that it was
not too tantalizing (for a movie like this.) I thought the aliens
looked cool and Daniel Craig was super tough. The juxtaposition,
though, was the best part. All-around a good time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
