<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Duck Tales | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/duck-tales/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T21:04:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today and gave it another chance. This time, it was a
total breeze. I did die in the Amazon after spending $300k, which
was really painful, but I realized that if you just hold bounce
next to the statue, guys come and die under you without a chance
of getting hurt. This was totally boring and stupid (it took
a few minutes), but it wasn't horrific. After that, there was no
more grinding. The whole game was really short... just about an
hour from start to finish. The best part was the unique challenge
of not being able to directly jump on enemies and the way you
sometimes needed to whack things with your cane. (For example,
the mummy ducks in the mansion where fun to fight when you had to
whack their ball &amp; chain.)</p>

<p>Overall, the game was fun... good music, cute monsters... and
it's classic in a certain sense, but I don't feel it is worth
replaying, because it is sooo easy.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played the Amazon and got to the boss, but died and then I had
to pay the 300k to get to the boss again. That is unbelievably
unfair and I'm not interested in grinding a platform game. This is
a fun game, but that's too lame in my mind.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
