<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metroid | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metroid/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T21:04:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metroid (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/14/Game--Metroid--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/14/Game--Metroid--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metroid over the past few days. (I started on the
10th, got the majority of the items and killed Kraid. Then the
next day I got two missile tanks and got to Ridley's zone. Then
today I finished Ridley's zone and finished the game.)</p>

<p>This is another game that I remember very fondly as a kid. I
remember using my dad's maps and playing through it a lot, and
then discovering the JUSTIN BAILEY code and using it a lot too. I
don't remember ever beating it though, or even really doing very
good or getting very far.</p>

<p>I think the problem when I was young is that I didn't have the
patience to grind out health to refill all the tanks that I got;
whereas playing through the game this time, I spent a lot of time
doing that to be prepared for the enemies. If you are willing to
do that, the game gets a lot easier.</p>

<p>The final area with the Metroids and Mother Brain is brutal
though. Much much harder than any other part of the game. The
Metroids practically instantly kill you if they catch you. I had
to play through it quite a few times.</p>

<p>Overall, this game totally survived replaying and remains as
awesome in my mind as I've always thought.</p>

<p>7?--?- -t-u1Y
T?a3GS 005WCE</p>

<p>Got every item but didn't kill Mother Brain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metroid (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/10/Game--Metroid--NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/10/Game--Metroid--NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's hard to "save" because you have to kill yourself.  It
requires great patience to grind out health</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
