<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Etrian Odyssey | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/etrian-odyssey/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-22T21:48:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Etrian Odyssey (DS, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/09/26/Game--Etrian-Odyssey--DS--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-09-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/09/26/Game--Etrian-Odyssey--DS--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I went to visit my parents, I started playing Etrian Odyssey
based on a discussion on Active Time Babble.</p>

<p>I was able to get to the 20th floor. I had 34k in money with
nothing to buy at the time. I completed every quest that was
available. My party was: Landsknecht (57), Protector (57), Samurai
(53), Medic (57), and an Alchemist (57).</p>

<h1>Things I liked</h1>

<p>I like mapping. It is really satisfying to enter an empty
screen and slowly fill in all the corners and corridors on your
map.</p>

<p>I like the art style.</p>

<p>I like the combat. Since the game is entirely combat
(seriously, the story in its entirety is: "There is a dungeon
outside the town."), it's natural that it will be fun and
complex. It wasn't often that I could "phone it in" and just slam
A. The way that attacks would build on each and the way that the
Protector class worked were particularly cool.</p>

<p>I like the grind. By my definition, an analogy for good grinding
is when there is a wall, you know how to get over it, but you're
not quite ready to jump it yet, so you need to practice jumping
slightly smaller walls. In the context of the game, the wall is a
boss or the normal monsters on the next level of the dungeon and
you simply can't defeat them. The smaller walls are other monsters
that actually require some plan or strategy to defeat. (For
example, if you can just press A to defeat the next most difficult
monsters before the boss, then it is boring grinding, but if the
other fights will be difficult, than it is good grinding.) I think
I liked this game so much because it was almost entirely good
grinding. (In retrospect, Final Fantasy XIII did this really
well.)</p>

<p>I liked the flow of the game. Since there is no story, there is
no interruption from the action. This means that there is always
something to do and get better at. This really hits my pleasure
receptors. =)</p>

<h1>Things I didn't like</h1>

<p>The mapping system isn't advanced enough. There were many times
where I wanted to express something---like the link between a
portal's entrance and exit, or the fact that a corridor/door was
one-way---where there was no way to do it. I could always encode
the property some way, but it was unsatisfying that someone else
wouldn't be able to read my map. It was also annoying that there
is a limit to the number of certain elements on each map floor. In
one case, I had to use the trap symbol to indicate the absence of
a trap because there were so many.</p>

<p>The character customization didn't have enough feedback on what
would be different in combat. This is particularly relevant, IMHO,
because you couldn't upgrade everything (there just aren't enough
levels.) But it was often the case that I wasn't exactly sure what
upgrading a skill would really do in practice.</p>

<p>I stopped playing because I got to a point where the difficulty
curve steepened drastically and I couldn't bear the slog
through. Basically, it got to the point where the only grinding I
could do was boring grinding because I was too powerful for the
second worst enemy but not powerful enough to clear the worst
enemy and I wasn't making enough improvement after a few weeks of
sporadic play.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
