<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Lost Odyssey | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/lost-odyssey/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-07T23:16:43-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Lost Odyssey (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/01/31/Game--Lost-Odyssey--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/01/31/Game--Lost-Odyssey--X360--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing Lost Odyssey last night. While playing
this game, it was hard to not compare it to Final Fantasy 13, a
game I loved a ton.</p>

<p>My completed game save reads: "43,521G; 047:09 play time; Kaim
54/Seth 54/Ming 42/Sarah 51/Jansen 51/Cooke 42/Mack 42/Sed
43/Tolten 50". During the majority of the game, I rotated through
all the characters, replacing characters with whoever was lowest
level, although I kept Kaim and Seth in the party always (if I was
allowed to.) However, right at the end, I fought the final battle
once (and mercilessly died), so I spent some time grinding with a
Kaim/Seth/Sarah/Jansen/Tolten party and got them up many levels
above everyone else. That was probably a bad idea, because Ming
ended up so weak comparatively in the final FINAL battle.</p>

<p>As I played, I wrote down some notes, which I will expand on
below, in the order I wrote them originally.</p>

<p>The battle animations in this game are laughable compared to
FF13. The characters stand almost motionless looking at each other
waiting to be attacked. This is particularly bad when you (or the
enemies) have status effects, like Blind, which cause them to
miss, because you watch an animation of your character running up,
hitting the enemy, the enemy recoiling in pain, and then the word
"Miss" appears over them. I understand the LO has a turn-based
system (which was definitely good for strategy), but they could
have implemented some of "time is frozen" style while commands
were input, and had some more movement during the battle. The idle
animations on the characters were great though; particular Cooke
and Mack with their adjusting for packs and taunting the
enemy.</p>

<p>The most amazing part of this game were the "Thousand Years of
Dreams" segments. There were some nights when all I would do was
find and "watch" these. For a little background, as Kaim (and the
other immortals) have experiences, they are reminded of past
events in their life. Those "dreams" are audio/visual/textual
presentations of a short story. Rather than just bland text on the
screen, like the FF13 Datalog, interesting music plays while the
text slows appears on screen. The text is synchronized with light
audio (like a door opening or a baby's cry) and sometimes the text
itself is moving (like dropping in from above, etc.) This style is
AMAZING. It makes reading the story very interesting and the use
of silence and sound makes it really evocative of emotions. In
addition, the stories themselves are incredibly interesting. You
really get to know and understand Kaim's character. The message of
the game is unmistakable and perfectly shown through these: the
despair of Kaim's loneliness, anti-war/violence, the beauty of the
small things in human life, the importance of family, etc. I read
on Wikipedia about these and here's what it said:</p>

<p><blockquote><p></p></p><p><p>Lost Odyssey's "Thousand Years of Dreams" were penned by an<br/>award-winning Japanese short story writer, Kiyoshi Shigematsu, who<br/>worked directly with the game's producer Hironobu Sakaguchi on<br/>Kaim's backstory, while Sakaguchi alone wrote the game's main<br/>story. The memory sequences were translated into English by<br/><em>REDACTED</em> Rubin, a respected Harvard professor who also translated the<br/>works of novelist Haruki Murakami. While Rubin originally<br/>objected to what he perceived as "adding to the world's supply of<br/>senseless violence," he relented after viewing the material and<br/>being "shocked" at its pacifist message and "vivid<br/>imagery".</p></p><p><p></p></blockquote></p>

<p>I want to give my save file to others so they can just watch these
segments.</p>

<p>On the subject of sound and music, the audio in this game is
really good. The game does a really good job of having ambient
music and sound appropriate to the areas you are in. For example,
on a mountain you can hear a light breeze, in a forest you can
here birds, in a factory you can hear machinery, etc. In addition,
the actual music for battles and cinematics is really good. One
part that was particularly interesting was a sequence between Sed
and Seth that was funny and this music played that was a riff on
the "chocobo" music from FF6. It was really interesting to hear
Uematsu riff on himself like that.</p>

<p>The geometry and texture work on the environments is really
high-class. Apart from FF13, I haven't played anything with better
looking environments.</p>

<p>There were some gameplay segments that really sucked
though. For example, it felt like you were escaping from an
exploding (or freezing) building half a dozen times in the game
and that got old. The freezing one was actually the worst because
you had to stay in front of the fringe of cold, rather than fight
an actual timer. There were a few annoying "mini-games": escaping
from monsters in a ship by doing a long QTE was annoying;
defending a city by defeating 4 bosses in a restricted amount of
time (I think I had to do it 15 times before I won; the worst was
when I only had one left once and it triggered the "losing"
animation just as I was about to touch it and when it was nowhere
near the city); etc.</p>

<p>The character models aren't very good (compared to FF13),
particular with regard to the eyes and mouths of the
characters. However, the textures on them are really
good---especially on the faces actually. The textures have some
really strange details though. For example, two characters (Ming
and Sarah) have ridiculous cleavage-revealing outfits and there
are quite a few shots where attention is given to them. Now that's
pretty standard, but even a casual glance at Ming will make you
notice that she has near-translucent skin and you can clearly see
veins on chest. It's really weird. Sarah has another strange
breast detail: she has a small birthmark-ish bump on the
right-side of her left breast. I think what made me remember this
is that so often in video games women are purely sex symbols and
their bodies are exaggerated to "perfect" male fantasies, but in
this game, while their outfits are clearly cut from the same
cloth, their actual bodies are reasonably realistic. (Actually
Ming's body is NOT realistic, her breasts are almost as large as
her head.)</p>

<p>On the subject of the models, the cinematic models are
/really/ different and really good.</p>

<p>On the subject of Ming's outfit, once thing interesting about it
is how it looks like her palace in a weird way. What I mean is, it
looks like the type of person who would design her palace to look
like /that/ would clearly wear something with /those/
elements. Compare <a href="http://www.google.com/images?q=lost+odyssey+ming&amp;um=1&amp;ie=UTF-8&amp;source=univ&amp;ei=2gNHTZOlDJKCsQPRlP3tCg&amp;sa=X&amp;oi=image_result_group&amp;ct=title&amp;resnum=1&amp;ved=0CCIQsAQwAA&amp;biw=1050&amp;bih=803">pictures of Ming</a> and [[http://www.google.com/images?hl=en&amp;biw=1050&amp;bih=803&amp;tbs=isch:1&amp;sa=1&amp;q=lost+odyssey+numara+palace&amp;aq=f&amp;aqi=&amp;aql=&amp;oq=][pictures of the
palace]]. Both have a "wispy" and "tendrily" style about them.</p>

<p>Another graphical thing: The "liquid" in the game looks
unbelievable bad. Especially when it is on the characters
(e.g. tears.) Wow. So bad.</p>

<p>I loved the part of the game when the party split up. It
reminded me so much of FF6. Very cool.</p>

<p>I had a really frustrating time in the second-to-last
dungeon. I walked around for 10 minutes, then died from
petrify. So I re-specced and tried again. I walked around for 20
minutes and pressed a button that released an enemy much more
powerful than any boss I'd ever fought that was optional, but that
you couldn't run from, so I died. I noted not to press those
buttons and tried again. I walked around for a little until 2
hours, then I accidentally pressed one of those buttons (because
it didn't look the same from the angle I approached it at) and
died again. I gave up for the night with that, having made no
progress after almost 3 hours.</p>

<p>Overall, I loved the story of this game. The combat was not
spectacular, although the ring system kept you involved. The
character progression was fun to build up skills. But the real
thing that kept me interested in the game was the awesome story
and characters. I guess I really mean characters, because the plot
is pretty standard, but it really comes alive through the
characters. Even the world is mostly a nameless backdrop, although
there are quite a few cool details---like the different scripts
used by the different countries, the common architectural styles,
etc. The characters themselves are, in part, great because of
their connections (often familial) with each other and their
growth (particular Jansen.) I highly recommend the game for
that.</p>

<p>In a word, I'd call the game "meaningful". There's a big
message and it is communicated very effectively. There were many
strong emotional pulls and every time there was tragedy for the
characters, you had been prepared to care, so that it was tragedy
for you too. (Especially with the ending.) The epilogue is very
nice as well, I really like the new outfits too.</p>

<p>One final thing: I found the final battle disappointing in a
strange way. In the first part of the battle, I felt good because
I was doing huge amounts of damage, but it was also difficult
because I had to careful plan my actions. I felt powerful, but it
was not easy. In the second part though, it was a lot
different. Very quickly, basically all the characters except Kaim
were killed and every round was a single attack from Kaim for less
than a thousand damage and then healing for everyone else. Some
rounds Kaim wouldn't be able to attack. Eventually I just stopped
keeping some of the characters alive because they weren't really
contributing. After over an hour of this, I won with Kaim and Seth
left standing, Seth using a healing item every round and Kaim
doing a dinky attack. On one hand, I should feel proud and happy
that I was able to do it with few resources and at the bare edge
of survival, but on the other it felt really unsatisfying to win
in such a simple, weak way.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
