<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1989 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1989/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-01T09:01:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played three rounds and got to the boss of the first area both
times. This game is ridiculously bad. The controls are terrible
and basic mechanics are broken. For example, there's no period of
invulnerability when you get hit and you get stunlocked in
place. There were times when I missed a jump, landed on an enemy,
and slowly lost all my health as I couldn't move away.</p>

<p>I remember playing this game as a kid, but I don't remember every
getting past the first stage. I guess I never will.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sweet Home (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a really interesting game. It's clear to me how Resident
Evil was inspired by this. The difficulties of managing the
various members of the party and piecing together the
multi-dimensional fetch quest is a very interesting (and pretty
unique) structure for a game.</p>

<p>I played reading a walk-through that was very particular about
where you should go and what you should do. I feel like it would
be bad to play this way, because the whole point of the game is
to explore this world. However, it seems like it is pretty brutal
in terms of what your lack of knowledge means. I think I will put
this on my "revisit" pile.</p>

<p>Given my short time with the game, the main problem with it is
that it is just a puzzle and there's no good visceral feeling
associated with playing the game. The controls are pretty awkward
(knowing who is who is a pain in the beginning, but would
definitely get better as you played more) and the battle system is
uninteresting. The quick-time events are really fascinating. The
lack of an ability to see if a weapon is strong is
annoying. Overall, it's been a bit of an obtuse but really
strangely modern game. I feel like a game like this could be made
really well today. I don't think I can look past the flaws right
now though.</p>

<p>When I do play it again, I will have to re-rank it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:43</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Square's Tom Sawyer (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Square-s-Tom-Sawyer--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Square-s-Tom-Sawyer--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm fascinated by the existence of this game and I have been since
I heard that it existed. I played the game for about twenty
minutes in all Japanese. I was able to understand the menus, but I
didn't do much more than sound out the dialogue. The graphics are
ridiculously racist. The concept of the game is nuts and based on
my brief playing and a glance at a walkthrough... it is
transparent fetch quest with RPG battles in between. In some way,
this can be said of all RPGs, but it would be far too transparent
for me, given my limited grasp of the language. I wasn't able to
walk to the first fetch quest delivery point and back without
dying.</p>

<p>Grinding is really the worst thing for old RPGs. Many of them had
interesting mechanics, but were padded for their day. In more
modern times, this padding is really destructive if you want to
experience what was interesting about the game. There's no good
way to use codes and cheats to give a challenging, but still
non-tedious experience. There are ways to just pre-load with
super powers and get infinite experience, but that's little
better than just watching the game on YouTube.</p>

<p>As I get older I'm much more interested in games without
progression systems because from the second you start you're
faced with a test to learn new skills and apply them. The tests
get harder, but there's no artificial curve in the game. In other
games with internal progression systems, the progression is more
than just numeric... it requires more strategy and planning. For
example, Dragon Quest 1 is basically just about getting higher
numbers until you can get even higher numbers. There's little
strategy involved... just a test of how much risk you're willing
to take. In contrast, FF6 adds more party members, complicated
enemy patterns, many spells, etc as the game progresses.</p>

<p>I don't know where Tom Sawyer fits in this rubric, but I'm not
going to give it a chance. I have dipped into its existence and
found it very curious.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:18</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mother (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Mother--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Mother--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game (via the prototype ROM dump) for a bit
today. It's clear that this was the precursor to Earthbound. The
dialogue is great and the enemies are very odd.</p>

<p>It is also clear that it is a straight Dragon Quest clone. I was
not able to make it from the front door of my house to town
without dying. It took three trips before I reached a high enough
level to make it. When I got there, I had about $250 in cash, but
the next worthwhile weapon was $500. Classic. I started walking
around and was decimated by the first zombie on the way to the
cemetery (plot point #1).</p>

<p>During my short play, I noticed a few typos. This, combined with
the anticipatory pain of grinding, has led me to decide to replay
it on the Mother 1+2 remake for the GBA with the fan translation
that adds the "Easy Ring" option. I was definitely convinced that
I want to play this game, but not convinced by the NES version.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap (SMS, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a bit. It's definitely better than the
last one. It seems a lot more deep and complex. It's got this
non-linear-ness to it which is interesting, but the controls are
still pretty sloppy. There were many times when I just couldn't
line up with an enemy and it was on top of me doing damage every
time it was possible. I'm still hopeful for the next sequel. But
this game doesn't do it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
