<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1989 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1989/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T07:26:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: River City Ransom (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--River-City-Ransom--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--River-City-Ransom--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while tonight and destroyed it. I've played
this many many times with other people... like my friends when I
was young, my brother, my wife, my dad, etc. But I've never
actually beat it, perhaps because we could never have the patience
and time to actually go through the whole thing. This time, it
was pretty simple to do. I just got Dragon Feet, and lined myself
up to hit the bosses after they were downed. The main problem is
the twins and the random hit you get on you as you're traveling
through the map. The game play mechanics in this game feel really
really good, but it's really broken because you can abuse it so
much. I'll definitely play this in the future in co-op, but I
don't think it's strong enough to last on its own... but then
again, it's has a fun flow to it; like I can just roll through a
few levels of Mega Man 2.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today and gave it another chance. This time, it was a
total breeze. I did die in the Amazon after spending $300k, which
was really painful, but I realized that if you just hold bounce
next to the statue, guys come and die under you without a chance
of getting hurt. This was totally boring and stupid (it took
a few minutes), but it wasn't horrific. After that, there was no
more grinding. The whole game was really short... just about an
hour from start to finish. The best part was the unique challenge
of not being able to directly jump on enemies and the way you
sometimes needed to whack things with your cane. (For example,
the mummy ducks in the mansion where fun to fight when you had to
whack their ball &amp; chain.)</p>

<p>Overall, the game was fun... good music, cute monsters... and
it's classic in a certain sense, but I don't feel it is worth
replaying, because it is sooo easy.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Clash at Demonhead (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Clash-at-Demonhead--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Clash-at-Demonhead--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played again today and gave a bigger chance. I was able to
accomplish somethings, including killing one of the bosses. I
still think the core gameplay is really sloppy---the hit boxes
are bad, the shot control isn't great, and the interface is
pretty whack. But, I can see why some people might have loved it
when it was released. I'm done with it though.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Dodge Ball (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Super-Dodge-Ball--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Super-Dodge-Ball--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a match. I've heard a lot about how awesome
this game was, but I never played it when I was younger and I
don't really get the appeal. I didn't beat the match and maybe it
would be more exciting if you were any good, but it was very basic
but not the "simple control but complex depth" that defines so
many great NES games. I don't think I play it again. I think if it
was a bit faster and maybe with more fluid/intuitive controls it
could be really awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Idol Hakkenden (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Idol-Hakkenden--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Idol-Hakkenden--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Too much Japanese and a lame adventure game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
