<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1989 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1989/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T23:19:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap (SMS, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a bit. It's definitely better than the
last one. It seems a lot more deep and complex. It's got this
non-linear-ness to it which is interesting, but the controls are
still pretty sloppy. There were many times when I just couldn't
line up with an enemy and it was on top of me doing damage every
time it was possible. I'm still hopeful for the next sequel. But
this game doesn't do it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario Land (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Super-Mario-Land--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Super-Mario-Land--GB--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for one run of about ten minutes. I got to 1-3. I
could very easily tell that this game was a novelty of its day:
Mario in Portable form! Today, there's no reason to play
this. It's not like it's bad... but the limitations of the Game
Boy are way too awkward to really enjoy it. There are some cool
things though, such as the rolling boulders and the different
enemy types, but there's no reason to play this when you're at
home (or even with the hand-held options that are available
today.)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy Legend (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half-hour. I was a Human Female,
Human Male, Mutant Female, and Human Male. I sold my Saber, bought
some armor and went out to fight. It took the whole thirty minutes
to be able to afford one more piece of armor. I went out to fight
again and got into a fight with a Red Bull, during the course of
the fight, all my weapons broke and two of my characters died,
then the monster fled, so I didn't get to kill and didn't get any
gold. Now I don't have the money to replace the weapons or revive
the fallen characters. This game seems like it will be nothing
but Kawazu brutalization and grinding. No thank you.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: River City Ransom (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--River-City-Ransom--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--River-City-Ransom--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while tonight and destroyed it. I've played
this many many times with other people... like my friends when I
was young, my brother, my wife, my dad, etc. But I've never
actually beat it, perhaps because we could never have the patience
and time to actually go through the whole thing. This time, it
was pretty simple to do. I just got Dragon Feet, and lined myself
up to hit the bosses after they were downed. The main problem is
the twins and the random hit you get on you as you're traveling
through the map. The game play mechanics in this game feel really
really good, but it's really broken because you can abuse it so
much. I'll definitely play this in the future in co-op, but I
don't think it's strong enough to last on its own... but then
again, it's has a fun flow to it; like I can just roll through a
few levels of Mega Man 2.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today and gave it another chance. This time, it was a
total breeze. I did die in the Amazon after spending $300k, which
was really painful, but I realized that if you just hold bounce
next to the statue, guys come and die under you without a chance
of getting hurt. This was totally boring and stupid (it took
a few minutes), but it wasn't horrific. After that, there was no
more grinding. The whole game was really short... just about an
hour from start to finish. The best part was the unique challenge
of not being able to directly jump on enemies and the way you
sometimes needed to whack things with your cane. (For example,
the mummy ducks in the mansion where fun to fight when you had to
whack their ball &amp; chain.)</p>

<p>Overall, the game was fun... good music, cute monsters... and
it's classic in a certain sense, but I don't feel it is worth
replaying, because it is sooo easy.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
