<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1989 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1989/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T22:55:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Later in the day, I played for almost three hours.</p>

<p>I beat up to level 5. I find the game to be so much like LoZ but
bigger in ways that don't make it better.</p>

<p>There are some similar items (like the Rainbow Drop is the same as
the Ladder) and some unique ones (like the Glowing Moss). But
there's a lot that isn't there and what is added isn't great.</p>

<p>The levels are all a lot bigger, but they look too much the same
that they are extremely confusing and kind of frustrating. Same
with the various overworlds.</p>

<p>There are upgrades to your armor and weapon, but they don't really
feel much better because the enemies are getting stronger too. (In
contrast, in LoZ, the enemies in the overworld are all the same
and as you get stronger stuff, you see the same guys more and get
to thrash them.)</p>

<p>The bosses are huge and cool looking, but they take way too long
to kill once you've learned their pattern and can totally avoid
being hit.</p>

<p>Overall, the game just isn't as refined as LoZ. I got over the
problems with the combat with a little more attention, but I feel
like the rest of the game will just be a chore. I don't think I
will finish it.</p>

<p>I bet if I grew up with a TurboGrafx rather than a Nintendo, I
would love this game, but as it stands, it's just meh.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:05</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half an hour today on an emulator.</p>

<p>It's a strange game. It seems like it is trying to be Legend of
Zelda I, but it has tried to evolve, it seems. For instance, I
felt like inside every cave was a person just blathering on about
stuff that didn't matter. The combat feels a bit... off. It's
like it is very hard to line enemies up. In LTTP, since the sword
slices in an arc, it never really matters if you aren't lined up
perfectly. In LoZ, you do need to be straight, but I think the
enemies are guaranteed to be in a grid, so it is easy to hit
them. It's a strange thing to miss. It seems like the dungeons
are much more linear and I got to the end of one, but couldn't
beat the boss (after a ton of tries)... it seems to have way too
much health.</p>

<p>I will give it another session... but I'm not impressed.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Batman (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about two and half hours. A little more
than the final hour was spent on the last level trying to get up
the vertical passage with the gears. It was unbearably
brutalizing. If you could just shoot up or if the jump were a
little bit more controllable, I could have done it. But I decided
that I was interested in the ending that much.</p>

<p>Overall, this game is feels really great. The different weapons
are all useful and fun. The jumping is pretty nice and the
wall-hanging works much better than in Ninja Gaiden. Surprisingly
good!</p>

<p>Total time: 2:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played three rounds and got to the boss of the first area both
times. This game is ridiculously bad. The controls are terrible
and basic mechanics are broken. For example, there's no period of
invulnerability when you get hit and you get stunlocked in
place. There were times when I missed a jump, landed on an enemy,
and slowly lost all my health as I couldn't move away.</p>

<p>I remember playing this game as a kid, but I don't remember every
getting past the first stage. I guess I never will.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sweet Home (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Sweet-Home--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a really interesting game. It's clear to me how Resident
Evil was inspired by this. The difficulties of managing the
various members of the party and piecing together the
multi-dimensional fetch quest is a very interesting (and pretty
unique) structure for a game.</p>

<p>I played reading a walk-through that was very particular about
where you should go and what you should do. I feel like it would
be bad to play this way, because the whole point of the game is
to explore this world. However, it seems like it is pretty brutal
in terms of what your lack of knowledge means. I think I will put
this on my "revisit" pile.</p>

<p>Given my short time with the game, the main problem with it is
that it is just a puzzle and there's no good visceral feeling
associated with playing the game. The controls are pretty awkward
(knowing who is who is a pain in the beginning, but would
definitely get better as you played more) and the battle system is
uninteresting. The quick-time events are really fascinating. The
lack of an ability to see if a weapon is strong is
annoying. Overall, it's been a bit of an obtuse but really
strangely modern game. I feel like a game like this could be made
really well today. I don't think I can look past the flaws right
now though.</p>

<p>When I do play it again, I will have to re-rank it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:43</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
