<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1989 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1989/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-26T21:48:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Dodge Ball (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Super-Dodge-Ball--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Super-Dodge-Ball--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a match. I've heard a lot about how awesome
this game was, but I never played it when I was younger and I
don't really get the appeal. I didn't beat the match and maybe it
would be more exciting if you were any good, but it was very basic
but not the "simple control but complex depth" that defines so
many great NES games. I don't think I play it again. I think if it
was a bit faster and maybe with more fluid/intuitive controls it
could be really awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Idol Hakkenden (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Idol-Hakkenden--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Idol-Hakkenden--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Too much Japanese and a lame adventure game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played the Amazon and got to the boss, but died and then I had
to pay the 300k to get to the boss again. That is unbelievably
unfair and I'm not interested in grinding a platform game. This is
a fun game, but that's too lame in my mind.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania 3 (NES, 1989) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/16/Game--Castlevania-3--NES--1989--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/16/Game--Castlevania-3--NES--1989--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was in Japan, I bought a copy of Akumajou Densetsu for the
Famicom. I knew that it did not work on my PowerPak and I had
heard that due to its special chip the game was much much better
in the Japanese version. I got it very cheap too, so it was a nice
buy.</p>

<p>This is a great game. I find it much much more playable than the
other two NES Castlevania games. It is still quite clunky, but not
terribly obtuse compared to those games. I gave it a
play-through.</p>

<p>The first night I got the first level with a great deal of
frustration as I got used to the controls. The next night I went
through the clock tower and got Grant "DaNasty". The next night I
escaped from the clock tower, went through the next level, and
went through the pirate ship. The day I went through 4 and 5 and
then at night I went through 6, 7, and I got to the end of 8.</p>

<p>I played through stage 8 so many times I could get through it
perfectly without getting hit at all---up until the boss that
is. I could beat the first form of Death about a fifth of the
time, but I wasn't able to beat the second form. I probably fought
him about 30 or 40 times that night with no luck. So I decided to
use a password and skip to the next level.</p>

<p>However, in the next level I could barely even make it to the
second block. It got to the point where the screen is just
swarming with enemies that slowly suck your life away... and you
need to make it through 3 blocks and then fight
bosses. Insanity. It's too much for me and it's not rewarding
enough.</p>

<p>I do like the game and I will definitely play parts of it again,
but it got to an insane point that wasn't fun... just unfair.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania 3 (NES, 1989) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/Game--Castlevania-3--NES--1989--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/15/Game--Castlevania-3--NES--1989--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Stage 9 is way too brutal. I can't do it.</p>

<p><em>W_W
H</em><em><em>
</em>WH</em>
WC_H</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
