<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: (New) Ninja Gaiden II | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/-new-ninja-gaiden-ii/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T22:07:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: (New) Ninja Gaiden II (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/15/Game---New--Ninja-Gaiden-II--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/15/Game---New--Ninja-Gaiden-II--X360--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played it for about a week and got to Chapter 7. Each day I
played it, I completely exactly one chapter. Each chapter took
about 30 to 40 minutes of play-time, although I don't think the
in-game clock counted deaths, which I estimate added another 15
minutes on average.</p>

<p>As I played, I took little notes. Unfortunately, almost all of
them are about bad things. But before I say the bad things, I
should say that if this game didn't have such stiff competition,
it would probably be very good.</p>

<p>It's competition, is, of course, Bayonetta---a.k.a. pure gaming
amazingness.</p>

<p>At it's core, Ninja Gaiden and Bayonetta are the same kind of
game: 3D action/brawler. Thus, it's very fair to compare them.</p>

<p>Ninja is cut from really different cloth though. For example, in
Hideki Kamiya's commentary of Bayonetta, he talked about how he
didn't like blocking in action games because they were too slow
and emphasized static resistance, rather than fluid
dodging. Bayonetta's dodging is a brilliant counter to
blocking. Ninja, however, has really static blocking, that
actually hardly ever feels effective.</p>

<p>In the same commentary, Kamiya talked about how it was important
to him that Bayonetta could not be knocked down, unless she is
killed. In addition to promoting feminist power, this ensures that
the player never has to wait for her to get up for the action to
start again.</p>

<p>There are many, many, many times in Ninja where you feel like you
are frustratedly waiting for Ryu to get up from being knocked
down, finish a "strong" attack so you can move and dodge (which,
of course, you can't, so you get clobbered), or waiting for an
enemy that has trapped you to finish its animation. This is a very
unfulfilling and frustrating time. I found the Skull Boss in
Venice to be a particularly bad offender on this point.</p>

<p>One of the worst experiences in all dynamic games is the dreaded
turret sequence where you must stand still, shoot at things with a
different (i.e., uncomfortable) mechanic, and get knocked back
when you get hit. Even the wonderful Bayonetta has such a sequence
(although, it's really not that bad because it's so fast and you
basically can't fail.)</p>

<p>Ninja does not have a proper turret sequence (at least in the part
I got to.) Instead, every time you have to use a missile weapon,
it becomes one. It is unbelievably bad and drastically slows down
the game and your ability to dodge as you painful readjust the
camera to the target.</p>

<p>On that note, in general the camera in Ninja is pretty bad. FWIW,
I think a camera is bad when you have to think about it "as a
camera" rather than becoming a natural part of your motion. I
think the reason is that the camera is too tight on Ryu. It looks
perfect when it is directly behind him, a little above his
shoulder, looking out at the stage with Ryu in the bottom middle
of the screen; but this angle/placement becomes really bad when
you are jumping around fighting. In contrast, in Bayonetta the
camera is at a much higher vantage point with Bayonetta in the
center and the stage around her; this placement is much harder to
mess up and I don't recall it ever happening.</p>

<p>But now, these are relatively minor problems. I wouldn't have such
high standards if not for the masterpiece, Bayonetta. So, why did
I quit Ninja Gaiden II after about 6 hours of play and completing
about half the game? Crashes.</p>

<p>The game crashed in chapter 5. I gave it another chance.</p>

<p>The game crashed in chapter 7. I gave it another chance.</p>

<p>This time it crashed again in chapter 7, at the same spot, the
very next time I tried.</p>

<p>I cannot believe that people can sell video games that crash like
this. Old games had flaws and buggy behavior, but I don't remember
experiencing any crashes. I think that the possibility of
releasing patches has made developers sloppy and decreased the
objective quality of modern games.</p>

<p>I wish there was a way to monetarily punish Team Ninja for this
infraction.</p>

<p>By the way, here are my end-of-chapter statistics:</p>

<p>Chapter 1:
Kills: 147
Essence: 15465
Ninpo: 2
Play Time: 000:37:58
Karma: 731559</p>

<p>Chapter 2:
Kills: 121
Essence: 14400
Ninpo: 3
Play Time: 000:33:05
Karma: 1493816</p>

<p>Chapter 3:
Kills: 239
Essence: 26468
Ninpo: 3
Play Time: 000:43:19
Karma: 2704203</p>

<p>Chapter 4:
Kills: 132
Essence: 20340
Ninpo: 3
Play Time: 000:32:24
Karma: 3415814</p>

<p>Chapter 5:
Kills: 92
Essence: 12640
Ninpo: 4
Play Time: 000:30:43
Karma: 4177470</p>

<p>Chapter 6:
Kills: 232
Essence: 57099
Ninpo: 4
Play Time: 001:02:07
Karma: 5099027</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
