<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-solid-peace-walker/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-09T22:55:18-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker (PSP, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Peace-Walker--PSP--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Peace-Walker--PSP--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started on the July 12th and beat the main game on the 19th. I
continued playing the optional content until today. I did all the
extra "Search" missions, but I didn't want to invest the time to
do every other mission to unlock the /Final/ mission. (So I
watched it on YouTube.) In the end, I cleared 86 missions in
36:22:53.</p>

<p>I thought the game was amazing. It's beautiful and the controls
actually feel really nice (unlike Portable Ops, where the controls
were atrocious.) The story is really cool too. The main thing I
didn't like about the game is how a lot of the extra content
revolved around incredibly difficult boss fights. (It was about
half that and half stealth missions... which were all really
fun.)</p>

<p>I thought the pace of unlocking new content was really nice. A big
problem with some games like this is that you feel drowned in the
number of possible options. This has a nice slow drip that feels
rewarding to unlock more. Eventually though, it became too much
for me when there were so many combat missions on the docket.</p>

<p>There were many funny in-jokes in the Metal Gear Universe that I
enjoyed.</p>

<p>The biggest problem with the game though was the disgusting Che
worship. Ugh.</p>

<p>Highly recommended.</p>

<p>I have now played and beat every Metal Gear game that has been
released!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
