<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2009 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2009/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-26T21:48:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: When You Reach Me, by Rebecca Stead (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book--When-You-Reach-Me--by-Rebecca-Stead--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book--When-You-Reach-Me--by-Rebecca-Stead--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife read this book for book group (I think that's why) and
wanted me to as well. It was not the worst book ever, but I didn't
like it that much. My main problem with was the weakness of its
plot and its predictability. Practically nothing happens in it and
the characters are strong enough to carry a story where nothing
major happens. The slice of life isn't slicey enough because there
aren't even interesting vignettes about the girl's life. The
predictability is really bad. I was about half-way through the book
yesterday (long plane trip today) and I talked to my wife about it
and told her what I thought would happen... and I was exactly
correct on all counts. That's pretty bad. It's not even like a
standard romantic comedy where it is sticking to a formula, it's
just that the story is so cliche and obvious that there's basically
only one thing that <em>could</em> happen given the way she's set it up.</p>

<p>Maybe I'm begin too hard on a Young Adult book, but eh, it wasn't
for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: My Life in Ruins, starring Nia Vardalos (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Movie--My-Life-in-Ruins--starring-Nia-Vardalos--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a pretty bad movie, but bad in that way that Pringles are,
where you think they are good while you're eating them, but every
so often you think "What am I doing?" and afterward as you reflect
on it, you regret. You should read the Wikipedia page on the
Critical Reception. I very much agree. There are a few funny
moments, but overall it feels so fake. The best part is how
realistic the tour members are. I direct tours, actually, and I
find a lot of it to be true to life.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Avatar, starring Sam Worthington (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Movie--Avatar--starring-Sam-Worthington--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/30/Movie--Avatar--starring-Sam-Worthington--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched this movie tonight. I heard a lot about it when it came
out, suggesting that it was a lame movie, but with some cool 3D
effects. Obviously I didn't watch it in 3D, but I found the normal
effects and the story to actually be pretty cool. I was
impressed. Obviously it is very Fern Gully, but there a lot of
other cool stuff going on to. It's the good kind of science fiction
where you know there is a lot more to the world than you can
see. The concept of the electrical connection between all the
different creatures is really cool. The plot, and a lot of specific
actions, are both really predicable and telegraphed clearly, but
hey, it's pretty fun. Wikipedia claims there will be sequels. That
could be cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: BlazBlue: Calamity Trigger (X360, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--BlazBlue--Calamity-Trigger--X360--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--BlazBlue--Calamity-Trigger--X360--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game in Arcade mode today (normally, I play it once
a month and I've been doing Ragnar's story) and got to the end. I
think I will try some of the other characters over the next little
bit, but I'll practically consider it mostly done. I like Street
Fighter much more given my experience with this game. The story is
super super Anime. The graphics are gorgeous. But, the systems are
not as appealing or intuitive to me, but I have more experience
with SF, so I like it better.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Invention of Lying, starring Ricky Gervais (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Movie--The-Invention-of-Lying--starring-Ricky-Gervais--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Movie--The-Invention-of-Lying--starring-Ricky-Gervais--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The wife and I watched this tonight. It's a very funny premise: a
world where no one can lie and the first instance thereof. They do
a good job world-building and making the setting seem real. I love
how all the waiters and waitresses say horrible things to the
guests. The religious sub-plot is much cooler than the romantic
sub-plot, and I think they could have/should have followed that
further---with Marc having to invent more and more rules as he
attempts to give people good morals and get them
happy. Nevertheless, as it stands, it's just a normal romcom with a
really fascinating premise at its core.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
