<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2009 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2009/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-11T22:21:06-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time... I considered restarting, but didn't and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He's really really hard. I've decided to put this as
"Scheduled" game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I'm kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this in the morning and got to Great Tiger. I had a
tough time with Bear Hugger before I realized that I could duck
the Bear Hug. I only fought one round against Great Tiger, so I'm
just learning his patterns. It is interesting how this game is
almost, but not quite, identical to the NES version. There are
some things that are better and more convenient (like Saves and
Retry in the middle of a match) but other than that it's just
tweaked on the edges. It's cool.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The clock concept for the arena is clever.</p>

<p>The plot dump at the end of the book is pretty absurd, although
really, what else could she have done?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first chapters do a really good job of easily recapping what
happened in the last book as a reminder.</p>

<p>The concept of the Quarter Quell is so contrived for plot
purposes. It's as bad as Harry Potter where every year some huge
thing is revealed that couldn't possibly have been realistically
unmentioned before.</p>

<p>I thought that the tour around the districts would be a contrived
way to give the reader a tour. But I was wrong.</p>

<p>I teared up in the District 11 scene.</p>

<p>Wow, how contrived to get Katniss back in the arena, because
Collins has written her into a state of inability to do
anything. Naturally it will be her and Peeta again?</p>

<p>It is interesting that Katniss will have an advantage the second
time, because she and Peeta will the youngest, and presumably
un-softened by living in luxury as a victor.</p>

<p>Haymitch's story is great.</p>

<p>The amount of "food porn" in the books never gets old, strangely.</p>

<p>Katniss' private session with the Gamemakers :)</p>

<p>The pre-Games interviews were amazing.</p>

<p>The end of Part II is waaaay intense.</p>

<p>I feel like throughout the book Collins uses such sterile and bland
language to talk about Katniss' body. Yet, she seems to always be
doing it. We often hear about the showers and baths that Katniss
takes and when that happens she'll say she's "naked" or talk about
her "breasts" and most often she mentions her "underwear",
"underclothes", or "undergarment". It's particularly strange how
bland it is given the food orgies and descriptions of the Capitol
fashion we're so often given.</p>

<p>The whole second book is reminiscent of bad movie sequel that was
summarized in the production notes with one word: MORE. More
violence. More romance. More intrigue. More food. More. The book
has almost an identical structure and plot, but again, and a little
bit different, but bigger. Yet, it does a good job at it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Daybreakers, staring Ethan Hawke (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie has a very unique and interesting premise: a dystopia
where vampires have become the norm and humans are rare. The
beginning of the movie, where you learn about what normal vampire
culture is like, is the best and most interesting part of the
movie. The rest of it lacks any unifying idea that brings it
weight. The cure is discovered to be controlled sunlight, but no
explanation is given why this would work. The cure turns out to be
contagious, so when a former vampire is fed from the feeder is
cured. There's no explanation offered, although I would have liked
some pseudo-science. The rest of the movie is some pretty routine
chase and fight sequences. The movie feels very much like an
allegory about American imperialism and the ethic of kids who join
the military, combined with standard liberal concerns about oil,
etc. The other great missed opportunity is more guilt and attention
given to the main "bad guy"'s interaction with his daughter.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say the movie was a disappointment. It wasn't totally
terrible; I can definitely think of worse movies. But the majority
of what I got out of it, I would have had by just reading the
Wikipedia page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
