<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2009 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2009/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-20T23:06:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool... although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking... I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear... and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played before dinner for like 10 minutes. I brought down the
Sandman three times, once per round, but died each of the two
matches. I'm getting better though!</p>

<p>Total time: 3:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this morning for a little bit... a couple rounds against
Mr. Sandman. I got a few hits in, but don't have a reliable
pattern down. I really let my kids down who were hoping for an
amazing display by Dad.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mushihime-sama Futari (X360, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Mushihime-sama-Futari--X360--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Mushihime-sama-Futari--X360--2009--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played a round of Black Label normal and then played through all
of Novice Normal for my son. He really enjoys the animations and
all the enemies. It is so much fun to just blast away in this
game.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time... I considered restarting, but didn't and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He's really really hard. I've decided to put this as
"Scheduled" game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I'm kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
