<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2009 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2009/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-02T22:22:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The clock concept for the arena is clever.</p>

<p>The plot dump at the end of the book is pretty absurd, although
really, what else could she have done?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first chapters do a really good job of easily recapping what
happened in the last book as a reminder.</p>

<p>The concept of the Quarter Quell is so contrived for plot
purposes. It's as bad as Harry Potter where every year some huge
thing is revealed that couldn't possibly have been realistically
unmentioned before.</p>

<p>I thought that the tour around the districts would be a contrived
way to give the reader a tour. But I was wrong.</p>

<p>I teared up in the District 11 scene.</p>

<p>Wow, how contrived to get Katniss back in the arena, because
Collins has written her into a state of inability to do
anything. Naturally it will be her and Peeta again?</p>

<p>It is interesting that Katniss will have an advantage the second
time, because she and Peeta will the youngest, and presumably
un-softened by living in luxury as a victor.</p>

<p>Haymitch's story is great.</p>

<p>The amount of "food porn" in the books never gets old, strangely.</p>

<p>Katniss' private session with the Gamemakers :)</p>

<p>The pre-Games interviews were amazing.</p>

<p>The end of Part II is waaaay intense.</p>

<p>I feel like throughout the book Collins uses such sterile and bland
language to talk about Katniss' body. Yet, she seems to always be
doing it. We often hear about the showers and baths that Katniss
takes and when that happens she'll say she's "naked" or talk about
her "breasts" and most often she mentions her "underwear",
"underclothes", or "undergarment". It's particularly strange how
bland it is given the food orgies and descriptions of the Capitol
fashion we're so often given.</p>

<p>The whole second book is reminiscent of bad movie sequel that was
summarized in the production notes with one word: MORE. More
violence. More romance. More intrigue. More food. More. The book
has almost an identical structure and plot, but again, and a little
bit different, but bigger. Yet, it does a good job at it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Daybreakers, staring Ethan Hawke (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Movie--Daybreakers--staring-Ethan-Hawke--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie has a very unique and interesting premise: a dystopia
where vampires have become the norm and humans are rare. The
beginning of the movie, where you learn about what normal vampire
culture is like, is the best and most interesting part of the
movie. The rest of it lacks any unifying idea that brings it
weight. The cure is discovered to be controlled sunlight, but no
explanation is given why this would work. The cure turns out to be
contagious, so when a former vampire is fed from the feeder is
cured. There's no explanation offered, although I would have liked
some pseudo-science. The rest of the movie is some pretty routine
chase and fight sequences. The movie feels very much like an
allegory about American imperialism and the ethic of kids who join
the military, combined with standard liberal concerns about oil,
etc. The other great missed opportunity is more guilt and attention
given to the main "bad guy"'s interaction with his daughter.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say the movie was a disappointment. It wasn't totally
terrible; I can definitely think of worse movies. But the majority
of what I got out of it, I would have had by just reading the
Wikipedia page.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Thinking about this movie the day after, there are some things
really strange about it:</p>

<p>All the movies more or less establish the vampires as basically in
the right, with the werewolves being too uncontrolled to be safe
for humans. Almost as if the vampires are protecting humans from
the immortals---especially given that they have a cultural
imperative to not consume human blood. (Viktor is a "bad" vampire
almost entirely because he sometimes breaks this rule.)</p>

<p>The first movie mixes this a little bit, portraying Lucian as
having been wronged and the vampires, especially Viktor, overly
prejudiced. But, it doesn't give Lucian any motives other than
revenge on vampires. Given that he is involved in offensive action,
it's not as if the vampires are simply out to get him. The war is
reciprocal.</p>

<p>The second movie really lays on the thick that danger of the
werewolves with the flash back sequences, but otherwise doesn't
really develop the reason for the conflict. It's basically just
sibling rivalry. (The movie is also weird because it makes very
little sense that Markus would act as he does now, as opposed to in
any of the previous 100 year periods where he was the sole reigning
vampire elder. It's especially incomprehensible why he destroys his
coven.)</p>

<p>The third movie doesn't really explain why Lucian would continue to
fight the vampires. It presents him as unassailably moral and a
freedom fighter. But once he gets his freedom, why does he have any
reason to continue fighting? Especially given that he thinks Viktor
is dead.</p>

<p>I presume that this won't be resolved or explained in the last
movie. But maybe not? It seems like Selene is the oldest vampire
that we've heard of it that is still alive and there has never been
any ranking werewolves other than Lucian and William.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Rise of the Lycans, starring Michael Sheen and Bill Nighy (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Movie--Underworld--Rise-of-the-Lycans--starring-Michael-Sheen-and-Bill-Nighy--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I was really surprised by the quality of this movie. I assumed that
because it didn't star Kate Beckinsale it would be a cheap version
of the world. But actually, I think it is the best yet; although it
wouldn't be very good without the first movie, obviously. It gives
a lot better context to the first movie and makes a lot of what
seems strange about the mythology a lot more reasonable. The story
is a lot more coherent and reasonable and the action is noticeably
slower, so you can appreciate it a bit more.</p>

<p>The development of the romance between Lucian and Sonja is totally
ignored, apart from a glance when they are kids.</p>

<p>Rhona Mitra really does look like Kate Beckinsale.</p>

<p>It's cool that the giant black werewolf from the first scene of the
first movie is one of Lucian's oldest friends. A nice little nod to
people paying attention.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
