<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2009 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2009/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T07:35:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 2.0 You Can (Not) Advance, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie--Evangelion--2-0-You-Can--Not--Advance--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/04/Movie--Evangelion--2-0-You-Can--Not--Advance--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Whereas the first Rebuild movie was almost exactly the same, but
with slightly different dialogue and scenes, but otherwise the
same, except for the technology. This movie was very
different... Mari is a whole new character... and the interactions
with Asuka and how she came were totally different. I really
enjoyed the changes, especially with Asuka. I thought the ending
was crazy and much clearer than the corresponding part in the
series. Although I'm kind of surprised that this is the point it
ends at... I feel like there can't be two more movies worth of
content, but I'm excited to find out what there's going to be
there.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a few rounds today with the kids. I did pretty well
against Sandman... I'm getting better. But I still didn't beat
him.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Evangelion: 1.0 You Are (Not) Alone, by Studio Khara (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/26/Movie--Evangelion--1-0-You-Are--Not--Alone--by-Studio-Khara--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When we got this from Netflix, my wife said "Ugh, Evangelion?" But
I think she enjoyed it. She commented on how the music was really
good and we were both impressed by the obviously better graphics
and effects. It is amazing how much is the same between this and
the originals though. I think it is already clearer what the
greater story is. I think there are more risque shots than before,
but, even so, they are quite tame. Not much to say other than that
I like Evangelion and this was preferred to watching the original
episodes. (Although I do miss the theme song.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: G.I. Joe: The Rise of Cobra, starring Channing Tatum (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--starring-Channing-Tatum--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Movie--G-I--Joe--The-Rise-of-Cobra--starring-Channing-Tatum--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had low expectations for this movie, other than it having crazy
special effects and action sequences. It exceeded my
expectations. There were some badly composed and lighted effects,
but overall it was pretty awesome. The chase in Paris was really
cool... although I thought the Acceleration Suits were kind of
dumb looking... I would have preferred something that looked more
like the suit in Vanquish; something less bulky.</p>

<p>I described the movie to my wife as taking place in the same
universe as Metal Gear... and it was pretty accurate, especially
because in this movie nanomachines play such a large role.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played before dinner for like 10 minutes. I brought down the
Sandman three times, once per round, but died each of the two
matches. I'm getting better though!</p>

<p>Total time: 3:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
