<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1987 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1987/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T23:19:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy in Monster Land (SMS, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour today. I used an emulator and
couldn't resist save states. In the beginning, I worked my way
through on my own, using saves at each screen. I had no sense of
what the items would do, so I didn't really buy any. After a
while, I looked at a walkthrough (which basically just recommended
which items to buy) and learned that I missed a few essential
hidden items. I restarted and made it to stage 4 following the
guide. I went away to eat, paused, and when I came back, the game
had reset itself.</p>

<p>This game looks and sounds really good, especially for its
age. It's cute and has some interesting mechanics. I think of it
as a lot like Zelda 2, but with a less interesting combat system,
sloppier mechanics, and a more advanced inventory system. I found
the jumps to feel really wrong and the combat delays to be pretty
painful. The inventory system, once you realize what things are,
is neat.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that this is a pretty amazing game for its age,
but that a lot about it works against it. The biggest problem is
the lack of continues. The game is too deep on a customization
level to make sense as an arcade game. I presume that later
version of the game change this, because they were designed for
consoles. Secondly, the sprites are a bit too big and they make
it hard to see what's going on. Third, the jumps and fighting
don't feel quite right.</p>

<p>I won't play this, but I'm excited to investigate other games in
this series.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania 2 (NES, 1987) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this game today using a walkthrough, maps, and
an infinite lives/hearts code. I feel like the hearts code was
essential so I didn't have to grind. The lives code didn't seem
to make much of a difference, because the game is pretty easy
(re: Egoraptor's dissection of its layout problems.) The
walkthrough and maps were definitely essential because it is so
confusing and backwards. I feel like there wasn't really anything
valuable in this game, although the mechanics felt good, but it
just wasn't anywhere near as challenging as Castlevania 1.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (15)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--14/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this today for a little more than half and hour. I sped
through up to Soda Popinski, although Bald Bull got me once and
Piston Honda got me another time. This game is so fun. I also
played it with my new XRGB Framemeister... so beautiful!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Last Emperor, starring John Lone (1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Movie--The-Last-Emperor--starring-John-Lone--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Movie--The-Last-Emperor--starring-John-Lone--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wasn't sure what to think of this movie before seeing it, but
I'd heard it was very good. I enjoyed it a great deal. I felt very
bad for the guy... it must have been hard to grow up like that and
to be used to so badly your whole life...</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing this regularly for so long and I've never gotten
past Soda Popinski. I think I will retire it for a
while. Definitely an awesome game, but it has shattered me for a
while. A part of me suspects that I need to get a TV setup with
lower lag to be successful. But that's probably just being a sore
loser.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
