<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/shin-megami-tensei-persona-3-portable/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-29T22:56:30-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable (PSP, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/02/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/02/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played Persona 3 again. This time I played a female character
named Buffy Summers. That was the best part. I maxed all the
social links with a walkthrough and got all the remaining Personas
(there were five more I needed.) I just played 30 minutes a day
and really really rushed through it. I never fought any enemies
except bosses, because my MC was soooo powerful. Overall, it
wasn't as good as the first time. I can't tell if it is because
I'd done it before, or because being a girl wasn't as exciting. I
can't really get excited about wooing boys. :) There are
definitely some good jokes if you know what happens to the guy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable (PSP, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/10/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/10/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just beat Persona 3 Portable. It was awesome. I'd never played a
Persona game before and the other Megaten game I played was a lot
different. This game was amazing.</p>

<p>I loved the collecting of Personas and the deep social link
system. I got all but 4 MAX Social Links and 5 Personas. (I didn't
MAX Aeon, Fortune, Temperance, or Priestess.)</p>

<p>I took me 87 hours and 36 minutes to play through the game. I
haven't played a game for so long in a while.</p>

<p>I really liked the way understanding your enemy's weaknesses was
crucial to beating them. I was a little annoyed at how spikey the
difficulty of bosses was in the middle of the game. I had to do
more grinding than I would've preferred.</p>

<p>I played as the Male main character. I'd like to do it again and
get MAX everything. I'd also like to play as the Female MC. My
Male MC was named after me; it's fun to have the characters
talk about you. I plan on naming my Female MC "Buffy
Summers". =)</p>

<p>I wrote a little program to compute the optimal way to make my
Personas. It was neat to do.</p>

<p>I <em>highly</em> recommend this game. I intend to play it two more times
and play Persona 4.</p>

<ul>
<li>Male MC: Aeon 8 / Fortune 5 / Temper. 5 / Priestess 1</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shin Megami Tensei: Persona 3 Portable (PSP, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/03/01/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/03/01/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Persona-3-Portable--PSP--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Started</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
