<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T22:55:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Parodius Da! (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Parodius-Da---NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Parodius-Da---NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got to the boss of stage 2 after playing for about 35
minutes. I've heard about this game many times before and I had
much greater expectations about how crazy and silly it would
be. I thought the bosses I fought were very cool, but overall, it
wasn't too crazy.</p>

<p>The mechanics are very reasonable for its time... it's just
Gradius. My only problem with it is that the NES is not a good
system for it: it has really atrocious and not intentional
slow-down; the sprite flicker is really bad and makes it hard to
see enemy bullets; and, the game lacks the vibrancy that it seems
like it should have. I'm also quite spoiler by CAVE when it comes
to being able to distinguish enemy bullets from mine and seeing
the hit box of the character easily.</p>

<p>I will try the other Parodius games rather than invest any more
time in this.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Nintendo World Cup (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Nintendo-World-Cup--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>These TECHNOS games feel so good. I like the dynamics in this
game and the way it feels great to tackle your opponent. I really
enjoy more abstract sports games like this. I don't know if I
wouldn't like the more modern, realistic sports games... I
presume I wouldn't, but I haven't really played them. One thing
about this game though, is that I don't think it could sustain
playing it for a long sitting. I played for a little more than
thirty minutes and that seems like the right amount of time. I
think I will keep at it and beat it... maybe?</p>

<p>Password: 30711 - Argentina 3rd match</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Military Madness (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Military-Madness--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Military-Madness--TG16--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played the first, second, and third levels over about an
hour. I didn't finish the last level.</p>

<p>I enjoyed the game. It is extremely similar to Advance Wars. I
find the interface in Advance Wars to be superior and the game is
more complex, but not in a way that is extremely complex. Both
are very simple, but they allow that simplicity to be used to
create interesting and challenging situations. But, because of
the similarity, I don't feel a great compulsion to play this
game, particularly when it is so inconvenient to do so. (I have a
Japanese PC Engine, so my Hu-Card doesn't work, so I have to
emulate it.)</p>

<p>Maybe if I got deeper into the game, there would be something
unlike about it that would be worth understanding, but after
scanning a FAQ, it doesn't seem so.</p>

<p>I would really like a procedurally generated game like this where
I could play at incredibly small chunks overtime. Until then... I
think I'll abandon it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gargoyle's Quest (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Gargoyle-s-Quest--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/20/Game--Gargoyle-s-Quest--GB--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour and a half. It's a very
intriguing game.</p>

<p>It's like a normal platforming game, but after you beat the first
level, you are thrust into a weird RPG-like world. You wander
around talking to people and getting little side-quests.</p>

<p>When you are in the overworld, you can get into random battles
that are like Zelda 2---tiny side-scrolling segments---where you
have to defeat all the enemies to escape. There's no experience
or progress system, other than receiving items which power you
up.</p>

<p>I got about half-way through the game (according to a FAQ) and
got a lot of interesting power-ups: breaking blocks, jumping
higher, flying longer, etc.</p>

<p>It was interesting, but it is very hard to enjoy Gameboy games (my
eyes bleed), especially on the emulator I was using because it
would get laggy a bit too often. I think I will try the NES game
and definitely the SNES game in this series. I have high hopes for
the SNES game.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this game tonight. I found it to be less
ridiculously hard than the first one because I found the powerups
and ninja power recharges to be more available. The environmental
hazards (wind, darkness, etc) were really rough. The cinema
sequences are way too long. I found confirmation in this
play-through of something that James Rolfe said in AVGN: you
forget that there is a health bar in this game, because you only
normally die by being whacked off platforms when you get
hit. It's so true. Also, the powerup that shoots fire diagonally
upwards is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
