<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I had to restart because my
save was lost somehow. I got to Portoa and got the Sword of
Water. (This appears to be about half-way by glancing at the Table
of Contents of a guide.)</p>

<p>The mechanics in the game never really get much more
interesting. They definitely add a few things: like the Rabbit
Boots, and presumably you eventually are able to cross water, and
then the keys that the swords become after you get their balls,
etc. But all the things that are different in the game are on the
level of navigation annoyances (not really "puzzles").</p>

<p>I wouldn't say that I'm opposed to games that don't change their
mechanics---Super Mario, for instance, doesn't have different
mechanics through the game. But, Mario can do this because (a) the
game play is awesome and (b) the game play is rich enough that it
supports gaining mastery and then increasing the challenge.</p>

<p>In my time playing Crystalis, it was very true to the literal
definition of "Action RPG". The individual encounters were totally
trivial (like hitting "Fight" over and over), but did require
moderate action. The challenge came from requiring a deep grind to
get resources---power to attack with and money to pay for healing
and rests. The severely limited inventory and the large number of
enemies really encourages you to go incredibly slowly and defeat
every enemy. But, it's not fun enough to do. It feels pretty good
for about an hour, but after that it gets really aggravating, and
I feel like I want to just rush by.</p>

<p>Something I'm surprised I was annoyed by was the need to switch
weapons to fight different kinds of enemies. It just felt so
tedious to do, because you generally want to walk around with a
sword charge, only to go to the menu to change swords when you
see an enemy. It was particularly annoying that you can't turn
off the bracelet power once you get it, so you have to either use
MP (because it's so easy to accidentally charge to level 3 shots)
or only use level 1 (by turning off the power-up altogether.)</p>

<p>I'd say that the game is not bad, but it has been so out-done by
games like Secret of Mana that there's no reason to play this
older Action RPG (as if Mana is really much newer!) I was hoping a
little that this would be much more Action-y because it was
older. It is interesting for me to notice that as I get older I
like more action-based games, because they cut away all that fat
from RPGs that I used to love.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunt for Red October, staring Sean Connery (1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun movie. I'm on a <em>REDACTED</em> Ryan kick and I want to go read
all the novels. The story is really great and I love that the
engine really exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It's very
fun. There's a little too much grinding... I feel like I can't
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it's fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it's a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Adventures of Lolo 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played through this whole game... throughout the day... a
total of seven hours and eleven minutes! Woah! This is a great
game. I love these escape puzzle games.</p>

<p>There are fifty puzzles, so each took an average of eight minutes,
but I'd say most were either really short... like one or two
tries... or very long. I had to seek hints about five times. The
ones that were the hardest were ones where you need to push a
block half a tile, or cover a monster spawning location with a
block so it would appear somewhere else, or where you need really
precise timing. The biggest problem with the game is when Lolo
gets stuck on edges of the grid. Nevertheless, It's a lot of fun
to play.</p>

<p>The graphics are simple and to the point, but super adorable. I
love the way Lolo runs.</p>

<p>My son had fun helping me and giving me advice during the game.</p>

<p>There's not much more to say about it, but it's very enjoyable.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat three levels after about forty minutes of play. This game
is very similar to Super Mario Brothers 2. It's focused around
picking up blocks and throwing them, although you can throw them
in more directions in this game. The co-op play is a memorable
feature, although I played by myself.</p>

<p>The platforming is pretty good, but the hit detection against
projectiles and enemies is too imprecise... you can get hits
registered that look very far away from your character. This
annoyance combined with the extreme speed of a lot of the enemies
(particularly the flying ones) leads to a lot of frustration. The
boss of the third level is really vicious because it zooms across
the screen and drops two moving creatures that have big hit
boxes.</p>

<p>The first boss fight is super easy once you realize what you need
to do and is pretty bland. The third is more interesting, but
also flawed because you can't effective shot in mid-air because
you fall so quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say this is a C+ NES platformer. It's not
horrific... it's certainly playable (unlike TMNT, for instance)
but it by no means enters the canon, and I don't feel it's really
worth my time. If I could have used a Game Genie code to get
infinite lives, I would have done it though and taken one screen
at a time. As it stands, the three lives per continue and three
continues barrier is too high for me to go through imperfect
mechanics.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
