<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-05T00:29:52-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son and I played through Snake Man's level, then started
Hard Man. He thought Snake Man was very cool. He said, at the
beginning of the level, "Is this Snake Man's body?" because it
looked like a Snake. He's very cute when he watches me play Mega
Man.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake (PS2, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake over the last
three or four days. I played the MSX2 version that comes with
Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence.</p>

<p>This game is the true prequel to Metal Gear Solid. The story is
explicitly a sequel, whereas the original Metal Gear is obviously
ret-con'd to be about the same stuff. The themes definitely
originate here: the pacifism is so much more clear. The gameplay
gets a whole lot deeper in this game with the radar, the guards
hearing you, etc. There are very direct callbacks to this game in
later entries in the series---such as climatic fist fights.</p>

<p>This was an amazing game. I initially found it much harder than
the first one because the guards are so much more perceptive and
the first area is a tightly confined space, but as I played I got
a lot better. Also, it is harder to be glutted with ammo and
rations, but you definitely get to that point by the end of the
game. I was initially confused and annoyed about when you were
allowed to save, but then I realized it was on area transitions
(when there was a loading screen) and so I was able to use that to
my advantage when I was going to a place I was scared of.</p>

<p>Here are my play-through stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 4:59:44
Save: 27
Continue: 17
Alert Mode: 117
Humans Killed: 246
Ration Used: 7
Special Item: Not Used
Code Name: Zebra</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario World (SNES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/02/Game--Super-Mario-World--SNES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/02/Game--Super-Mario-World--SNES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've recently played through Super Mario World for the first
time. When I got a Super Nintendo it didn't come with this game,
so I didn't play it a lot or beat, but I had played it before. I
used to not really be into platformers, but as I've gotten older I
like them much more. This game was really fun. I love all the
different kinds of enemies and the differently colored Yoshis were
very fun. I played through every level, except the Special
World. After doing the first special level, the second was
mind-bogglingly hard for me. Perhaps I will go back later.</p>

<p>I beat this game. I didn't get every goal, because sometimes I
only got the secret one. And I didn't do the special world. There
is a save state (#1) that has me before going in the Back Door of
Bowser's Castle.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Bonk's Adventure (PCE, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/23/Game--Bonk-s-Adventure--PCE--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/23/Game--Bonk-s-Adventure--PCE--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played Bonk's Adventure for the PC Engine (or
TurboGrafx-16.) The beginning of the game was very fun and
straight-forward, but once you get to the final level the
difficulty ramps up to an insane degree. It starts with a tunnel
in the water where there are spikes on the top and the bottom and
I have no idea how to get through without just spending multiple
lives to get through it. After that, there is a huge level full of
Mega Man-style disappearing blocks. Then there's basically a boss
rush where you face all the previous bosses then two final bosses,
which are both insane. Nevertheless, the game was fun, but crazy
at the end. I got 66,080 points. Word.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
