<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-08T21:04:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunt for Red October, staring Sean Connery (1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun movie. I'm on a <em>REDACTED</em> Ryan kick and I want to go read
all the novels. The story is really great and I love that the
engine really exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It's very
fun. There's a little too much grinding... I feel like I can't
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it's fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it's a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Adventures of Lolo 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played through this whole game... throughout the day... a
total of seven hours and eleven minutes! Woah! This is a great
game. I love these escape puzzle games.</p>

<p>There are fifty puzzles, so each took an average of eight minutes,
but I'd say most were either really short... like one or two
tries... or very long. I had to seek hints about five times. The
ones that were the hardest were ones where you need to push a
block half a tile, or cover a monster spawning location with a
block so it would appear somewhere else, or where you need really
precise timing. The biggest problem with the game is when Lolo
gets stuck on edges of the grid. Nevertheless, It's a lot of fun
to play.</p>

<p>The graphics are simple and to the point, but super adorable. I
love the way Lolo runs.</p>

<p>My son had fun helping me and giving me advice during the game.</p>

<p>There's not much more to say about it, but it's very enjoyable.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat three levels after about forty minutes of play. This game
is very similar to Super Mario Brothers 2. It's focused around
picking up blocks and throwing them, although you can throw them
in more directions in this game. The co-op play is a memorable
feature, although I played by myself.</p>

<p>The platforming is pretty good, but the hit detection against
projectiles and enemies is too imprecise... you can get hits
registered that look very far away from your character. This
annoyance combined with the extreme speed of a lot of the enemies
(particularly the flying ones) leads to a lot of frustration. The
boss of the third level is really vicious because it zooms across
the screen and drops two moving creatures that have big hit
boxes.</p>

<p>The first boss fight is super easy once you realize what you need
to do and is pretty bland. The third is more interesting, but
also flawed because you can't effective shot in mid-air because
you fall so quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say this is a C+ NES platformer. It's not
horrific... it's certainly playable (unlike TMNT, for instance)
but it by no means enters the canon, and I don't feel it's really
worth my time. If I could have used a Game Genie code to get
infinite lives, I would have done it though and taken one screen
at a time. As it stands, the three lives per continue and three
continues barrier is too high for me to go through imperfect
mechanics.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy Legend (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half-hour. I was a Human Female,
Human Male, Mutant Female, and Human Male. I sold my Saber, bought
some armor and went out to fight. It took the whole thirty minutes
to be able to afford one more piece of armor. I went out to fight
again and got into a fight with a Red Bull, during the course of
the fight, all my weapons broke and two of my characters died,
then the monster fled, so I didn't get to kill and didn't get any
gold. Now I don't have the money to replace the weapons or revive
the fallen characters. This game seems like it will be nothing
but Kawazu brutalization and grinding. No thank you.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
