<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T23:15:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this game tonight. I found it to be less
ridiculously hard than the first one because I found the powerups
and ninja power recharges to be more available. The environmental
hazards (wind, darkness, etc) were really rough. The cinema
sequences are way too long. I found confirmation in this
play-through of something that James Rolfe said in AVGN: you
forget that there is a health bar in this game, because you only
normally die by being whacked off platforms when you get
hit. It's so true. Also, the powerup that shoots fire diagonally
upwards is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 4 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Dragon-Warrior-4--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Dragon-Warrior-4--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played the DS remake of this and it was amazing, but I
can't play this older version. I have some memories of it because
my good friend from elementary school had it and I borrowed it. I
think I only made it to Taloon's part when I played it then. In
situations like this, I'm worried that someone will come to my
site's rankings and think I dislike this game, but I do
like... just not this release. Perhaps I should change my
tracking program to keep track of releases and games distinctly
so I can rank the games, not just the releases?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I had to restart because my
save was lost somehow. I got to Portoa and got the Sword of
Water. (This appears to be about half-way by glancing at the Table
of Contents of a guide.)</p>

<p>The mechanics in the game never really get much more
interesting. They definitely add a few things: like the Rabbit
Boots, and presumably you eventually are able to cross water, and
then the keys that the swords become after you get their balls,
etc. But all the things that are different in the game are on the
level of navigation annoyances (not really "puzzles").</p>

<p>I wouldn't say that I'm opposed to games that don't change their
mechanics---Super Mario, for instance, doesn't have different
mechanics through the game. But, Mario can do this because (a) the
game play is awesome and (b) the game play is rich enough that it
supports gaining mastery and then increasing the challenge.</p>

<p>In my time playing Crystalis, it was very true to the literal
definition of "Action RPG". The individual encounters were totally
trivial (like hitting "Fight" over and over), but did require
moderate action. The challenge came from requiring a deep grind to
get resources---power to attack with and money to pay for healing
and rests. The severely limited inventory and the large number of
enemies really encourages you to go incredibly slowly and defeat
every enemy. But, it's not fun enough to do. It feels pretty good
for about an hour, but after that it gets really aggravating, and
I feel like I want to just rush by.</p>

<p>Something I'm surprised I was annoyed by was the need to switch
weapons to fight different kinds of enemies. It just felt so
tedious to do, because you generally want to walk around with a
sword charge, only to go to the menu to change swords when you
see an enemy. It was particularly annoying that you can't turn
off the bracelet power once you get it, so you have to either use
MP (because it's so easy to accidentally charge to level 3 shots)
or only use level 1 (by turning off the power-up altogether.)</p>

<p>I'd say that the game is not bad, but it has been so out-done by
games like Secret of Mana that there's no reason to play this
older Action RPG (as if Mana is really much newer!) I was hoping a
little that this would be much more Action-y because it was
older. It is interesting for me to notice that as I get older I
like more action-based games, because they cut away all that fat
from RPGs that I used to love.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunt for Red October, staring Sean Connery (1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Movie--The-Hunt-for-Red-October--staring-Sean-Connery--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a fun movie. I'm on a <em>REDACTED</em> Ryan kick and I want to go read
all the novels. The story is really great and I love that the
engine really exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It's very
fun. There's a little too much grinding... I feel like I can't
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it's fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it's a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
