<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-25T23:32:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Adventures of Lolo 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played through this whole game... throughout the day... a
total of seven hours and eleven minutes! Woah! This is a great
game. I love these escape puzzle games.</p>

<p>There are fifty puzzles, so each took an average of eight minutes,
but I'd say most were either really short... like one or two
tries... or very long. I had to seek hints about five times. The
ones that were the hardest were ones where you need to push a
block half a tile, or cover a monster spawning location with a
block so it would appear somewhere else, or where you need really
precise timing. The biggest problem with the game is when Lolo
gets stuck on edges of the grid. Nevertheless, It's a lot of fun
to play.</p>

<p>The graphics are simple and to the point, but super adorable. I
love the way Lolo runs.</p>

<p>My son had fun helping me and giving me advice during the game.</p>

<p>There's not much more to say about it, but it's very enjoyable.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat three levels after about forty minutes of play. This game
is very similar to Super Mario Brothers 2. It's focused around
picking up blocks and throwing them, although you can throw them
in more directions in this game. The co-op play is a memorable
feature, although I played by myself.</p>

<p>The platforming is pretty good, but the hit detection against
projectiles and enemies is too imprecise... you can get hits
registered that look very far away from your character. This
annoyance combined with the extreme speed of a lot of the enemies
(particularly the flying ones) leads to a lot of frustration. The
boss of the third level is really vicious because it zooms across
the screen and drops two moving creatures that have big hit
boxes.</p>

<p>The first boss fight is super easy once you realize what you need
to do and is pretty bland. The third is more interesting, but
also flawed because you can't effective shot in mid-air because
you fall so quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say this is a C+ NES platformer. It's not
horrific... it's certainly playable (unlike TMNT, for instance)
but it by no means enters the canon, and I don't feel it's really
worth my time. If I could have used a Game Genie code to get
infinite lives, I would have done it though and taken one screen
at a time. As it stands, the three lives per continue and three
continues barrier is too high for me to go through imperfect
mechanics.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Bugs Bunny in The Crazy Castle (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle--GB--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for almost an hour tonight. It is brilliant in
its simple setup, but complex puzzles. The controls are
horrible---you can't turn in mid-step, you can't stop on stairs,
and you don't always use a special attack when you think you
will. The graphics are horrific. The music is about 4 notes
repeated. But nevertheless, it's a really addicting and satisfying
game. It's neat that you can watch replays of your last
attempt. This game is very similar to Lolo-style games, but
different enough that it feels unique. I was very impressed.</p>

<p>On the Game Boy, apparently it has 80 levels, and I did 31. I
think I burnt myself out on it in the one sitting I did. I will
definitely play this again, and probably pick up where I was
before, but I'll mark it as done because I think I understand the
game pretty thoroughly and (like the Crush games) I can't really
binge on it.</p>

<p>Stage 31: XPAZ</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Devil's Crush (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like Alien Crush, this game is a very exciting and interesting
pinball table. I feel like this game is a lot crazier because
after the initial ideas in Alien Crush, they were able to go all
out. There's lots moving around on the course, there's three
layers, and many complicated dependencies between
pieces. In that sense, it's much better. Plus, they added a
pass-the-controller 2-player option, which is pretty neat.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the ball physics feel much worse and the ball seems
totally outside of your control. I think part of it is that the
board is broken into three screens and each one is squatter (and
thus more detailed) than any screen was in Alien Crush. At the end
of the day, the game feels worse, despite looking much cooler.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I could imagine playing this game a lot... if not
for the interface friction.</p>

<p>When I played, my dad and I did the pass-the-controller for a
bit. My best score was 3.7 mil. I got this by getting the castle
on the bottom and then just being super cautious whenever I was
on the bottom screen. It worked like a charm!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we played for a bit more than an hour and beat the
game. I played through all of Wily's Fortress three times. The
first time I got stuck on the level before the triplicator
because I ran out of energy for the Rush Jet. The second time I
got to Wily but after continuing I didn't have any E-tanks or any
of the weapons I needed to kill him. The third time I won. It was
a brutal fight and I got really good at getting through the
fortress. I think this is a great game. Mega Man 2 is awesome,
but this is great too.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
