<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T07:26:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Devil's Crush (TG16, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Devil-s-Crush--TG16--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Like Alien Crush, this game is a very exciting and interesting
pinball table. I feel like this game is a lot crazier because
after the initial ideas in Alien Crush, they were able to go all
out. There's lots moving around on the course, there's three
layers, and many complicated dependencies between
pieces. In that sense, it's much better. Plus, they added a
pass-the-controller 2-player option, which is pretty neat.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, the ball physics feel much worse and the ball seems
totally outside of your control. I think part of it is that the
board is broken into three screens and each one is squatter (and
thus more detailed) than any screen was in Alien Crush. At the end
of the day, the game feels worse, despite looking much cooler.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I could imagine playing this game a lot... if not
for the interface friction.</p>

<p>When I played, my dad and I did the pass-the-controller for a
bit. My best score was 3.7 mil. I got this by getting the castle
on the bottom and then just being super cautious whenever I was
on the bottom screen. It worked like a charm!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we played for a bit more than an hour and beat the
game. I played through all of Wily's Fortress three times. The
first time I got stuck on the level before the triplicator
because I ran out of energy for the Rush Jet. The second time I
got to Wily but after continuing I didn't have any E-tanks or any
of the weapons I needed to kill him. The third time I won. It was
a brutal fight and I got really good at getting through the
fortress. I think this is a great game. Mega Man 2 is awesome,
but this is great too.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little more than thirty minutes. We got to
the final boss rush, but I didn't have enough skill to beat them,
and then when I got to the continue screen I accidentally
selected "Stage Select" rather than "Continue" so was put back at
the beginning of Wily's Castle. In frustration, I quit. I
understand why this option is there---so you can gave E
tanks. But I was very annoyed that it was default and it took so
long to restart the game back to where I was.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for about an hour and a half. I beat three of the
Doc Robot stages but the Quick Man duplicate kept getting me. I
can't dodge him very well and even though I have a lot of E-Tanks,
when I use the Gemini Laser or the Search Snake, I can use them
while a "bullet" is out. Very painful. The last time I died on the
spike vertical corridor and had to fight the boss again. Pain.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:04</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about thirty minutes today and beat Gemini Man and
Needle Man. My daughter (2) played the beginning of Gemini Man's
stage. She killed a penguin! She's getting pretty good at moving
and jumping at the same time... something my son has a bit of
trouble with. We were very proud of her.</p>

<p>I need the extra Needle Man stage after, but the pole-vaulters
after the flying sequence knocked me off the ladder and down to
the bottomless pit two screens down. It was very sad, especially
because I didn't have the energy to use the Rush Jet again
(because the energy ups were now gone!) It was very very sad.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
