<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1990 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1990/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-04T23:17:08-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we played for a bit more than an hour and beat the
game. I played through all of Wily's Fortress three times. The
first time I got stuck on the level before the triplicator
because I ran out of energy for the Rush Jet. The second time I
got to Wily but after continuing I didn't have any E-tanks or any
of the weapons I needed to kill him. The third time I won. It was
a brutal fight and I got really good at getting through the
fortress. I think this is a great game. Mega Man 2 is awesome,
but this is great too.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little more than thirty minutes. We got to
the final boss rush, but I didn't have enough skill to beat them,
and then when I got to the continue screen I accidentally
selected "Stage Select" rather than "Continue" so was put back at
the beginning of Wily's Castle. In frustration, I quit. I
understand why this option is there---so you can gave E
tanks. But I was very annoyed that it was default and it took so
long to restart the game back to where I was.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/14/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for about an hour and a half. I beat three of the
Doc Robot stages but the Quick Man duplicate kept getting me. I
can't dodge him very well and even though I have a lot of E-Tanks,
when I use the Gemini Laser or the Search Snake, I can use them
while a "bullet" is out. Very painful. The last time I died on the
spike vertical corridor and had to fight the boss again. Pain.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:04</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about thirty minutes today and beat Gemini Man and
Needle Man. My daughter (2) played the beginning of Gemini Man's
stage. She killed a penguin! She's getting pretty good at moving
and jumping at the same time... something my son has a bit of
trouble with. We were very proud of her.</p>

<p>I need the extra Needle Man stage after, but the pole-vaulters
after the flying sequence knocked me off the ladder and down to
the bottomless pit two screens down. It was very sad, especially
because I didn't have the energy to use the Rush Jet again
(because the energy ups were now gone!) It was very very sad.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I beat Top Man, Shadow Man, Spark Man, and Magnet
Man. I think it took three continues. The kids instigated it and I
think this time we'll actually play through the whole
game... gradually.</p>

<p>In the afternoon I beat Hard Man and Snake Man. Snake Man, and
his level, were excruciatingly hard. I found it very hard to
avoid Snake Man or do enough damage, but I lucked out with a good
pattern when I finally got him. I found the smoke stacks to be
the worst part of his level. A few times when the platform
appeared it launched me off into the abyss. Other times, the
bullets would hit me in mid-air, even if I killed them first
(because they'd respawn when I realigned so I wouldn't be pushed
off. It was very painful.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:12</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
