<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Acid 2 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-acid-2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-22T23:06:35-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid 2 (PSP, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/16/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid-2--PSP--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/16/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid-2--PSP--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After loving Metal Gear Acid so much, I played Metal Gear
Acid 2.</p>

<p>The opening movie of this was amazing.</p>

<p>The gameplay makes the last game feel like the first Dragon Quest:
there are so many ways the new interface is cleaner, easier, more
fluid, etc. I really like the improvements. The new gameplay
mechanics (like linkages and cover fire) where interesting, but
didn't really make it different. But I'm fine with that, because I
just wanted more game. (The blinding mechanic was definitely new,
but very annoying.)</p>

<p>The game gives you cards in a different order from the last game
and I generally felt the weapon power-level was higher initially,
although the support cards had the same path.</p>

<p>I really liked the cell-shaded style of the 3D graphics.</p>

<p>The game does an absurd jiggling animation with the female
characters. It is ridiculous.</p>

<p>This game seems even more combat focused than the last
game. Whereas in the last game, there were many traversal levels
where combat was the best approach, in this game there are many
straight-out combat missions. This game also feels like it has a
lot less time in between boss encounters. I also noticed that
there weren't really any "puzzle" levels, like before.</p>

<p>One thing that was close to a puzzle was the train level. It was
really cool to coax enemies into the path of the train and get
them squashed. Woo!</p>

<p>I did a little bit of grinding to get good cards, but I also made
some really stupid decks to get through some levels with a
challenge; both were fun.</p>

<p>The ending was very neat in its cinematic-ness, but the game in
general (and the bosses in particular) was a lot easier.</p>

<p>This game probably has more replay value because of the special
missions, but I didn't do any.</p>

<p>Here are my final stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Normal
Play Time: 14:24:20
Cost: 4395
Found: 45
Kills: 73
Total Damage: 15035
Clear Count: 1
Cards Collected: 41 (I don't know what this means... maybe in the stages?)</p>

<p>I hope there will be an Acid 3.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
