<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: N+ | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/n-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-20T23:06:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--N---X360--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--N---X360--2008--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Based on my last experience with the game, I think I'm basically
done with the game. I'm pretty conflicted about it, because it is
good on many levels, but a lot of it is so broken. The structure
of the game play---5 levels at a time, no saving, is probably the
worst thing about it for me, because I like to play in such small
chunks. But also, the mechanics just aren't tight enough for me. I
know that the physics/momentum is a conscious design decision, but
I don't think it works. Whereas in Super Meat Boy, I can do many
sequences exactly the same every time, I find N+ to be very
variable in how I perform, even though I feel like I'm doing the
same thing, because the momentum isn't quite right. This leads to
great frustration and lack of fun. I can't remember if the DS game
was like this and I just hadn't noticed because I hadn't play SMB
yet.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/Game--N---X360--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/Game--N---X360--2008--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played Episode 41 Level 4 for almost an hour. Sometimes when I
play this game, I think to myself, "Wow, I hate this game's
controls so much." It is so frustrating that they never seem to
work right. Super Meat Boy has almost ruined every other
platformer for me. In fact, I'm so mad at the game right now, I am
demoting it from every two days to once a week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--N---X360--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--N---X360--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Episode 40 Level 1 was pretty painful, but only 30 minutes
painful, not an hour painful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/20/Game--N---X360--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/20/Game--N---X360--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing Episode 39 for over an hour. The majority of
that time was spent on level 1. My eyes hurt and I can't play
anymore. I'm going to take a break. Currently I am at
level 4. Phew!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Game--N---X360--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Game--N---X360--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Some of the levels in the game are just too absurd. For example,
Episode 39, level 1 has you do the same challenge over and over
again. The game just isn't very streamlined in the teaching
you. You feel like you know how to do something but are forced to
do it again, even though you aren't really dying and
restarting. Obviously I'll still be it, but it's very
annoying. The worst thing about the game is having to do 5 at a
time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
