<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2003 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2003/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-22T16:16:39-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Le Divorce, starring Naomi Watts and Kate Hudson (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/08/Movie--Le-Divorce--starring-Naomi-Watts-and-Kate-Hudson--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is an interesting movie. I feel like the main point is that
we have two groups of people with loose morals, but vastly
different ways of reacting to them coming into conflict. The
characters are pretty complex and interesting. The environments,
food, clothes, and women all look very beautiful and elegant. It's
a fun non-stereotyped picture of France. I particularly like the
scene where the two police flirt. It serves no purpose other than
to say, "This can't happen in America."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld, starring Kate Beckinsale (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget why, but the other day I was reminded of this series. I
decided to start watching it, similar to how I went through the
Resident Evil movies. Like that series, I saw the first one when it
came out, but never saw the others. I remember thinking the movie
was cool and that Kate Beckinsale was amazing attractive.</p>

<p>On a second viewing, significantly older, I still think some parts
of the movie are cool. The mythology is interesting and fairly
developed. The actor of Viktor is pretty awesome; while the actor
that played Kraven was unbelievably bad. The character of Erica is
really interesting and subtle. And, yes, Kate Beckinsale is
woah---except, I don't understand the appeal of the "cat suits",
they make all her natural curves indistinguishable, like a running
bra or something. I don't get it, but I guess that had to because
this movie was made to be so Matrix-y. The action sequences are
very derivative of the Matrix and pretty boring overall
actually. Lots of akimbo and chunks of buildings flying off. The
best fight is probably the very first one. Even the final fight
between Viktor and Michael is pretty meh, because Michael is so
"whatever" that it doesn't get too exciting.</p>

<p>Definitely not a classic, but I'm interested in watching the rest
of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow (GBA, 2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last little bit, I played and beat this for the
Nintendo GBA. This is definitely a good entry in the Castlevania
franchise. I really appreciated the variety that came from the
Soul system, but I felt like it had a problem that many RPGs with
these "collecting" systems: most of the things you collect are
totally useless. This game had two other problems in my mind:
first, the difficulty curve had a really sharp spike at one point
which required me to grind for almost two hours to get past a
boss; and second, the user interface was really poor and that
complicated switching souls quickly to navigate around the
map. Both of these were fixed in the next entry; in particular the
Doppelganger soul allowed you to have two equipment sets
readied.</p></p>

<p>I will definitely play this again as the secret character, so
maybe I'll report back then.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kal Ho Naa Ho (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/27/Movie--Kal-Ho-Naa-Ho--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/27/Movie--Kal-Ho-Naa-Ho--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kal No Naa Ho stars Sharhukh Khan, Saif Ali Khan, and Preity Zinta.</p>

<p>Accidentally, I rented a bootleg DVD. So, it was blurry, and I
think some parts were cut, and the subtitles were not on the
songs.</p>

<p>Even with this bumble, I can say that the story was cute and the
characters were interesting. Unfortunately, most of the songs were
pretty bad. There were two towards the end (the first when Preity
falls in love; and some other) that were actually good though.</p>

<p>Recommendation: Decent, but bear through the first few songs and
get a good copy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Khushi (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/25/Movie--Khushi--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/25/Movie--Khushi--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Khushi stars Kareena Kapoor and Fardeen Kapoor.</p>

<p>Story: The story was pretty cute and without some of the more
ridiculous things that happen in movies like this. The first five
minutes are particularly cheeseball though, so don't be turned off
right away.</p>

<p><em>REDACTED</em>acters: The two characters are very lovable. And their
relationship is ultra-cute. Basically, they fight all the time
about little things... Kareena always mistakes what Fardeen means
and this is humourous. Kareena is also very difficult and gives
Fardeen pain in an amusing way. (I was very proud of myself when I
got what a surprised/confused/hurt face was about--Kareena made
Fardeen call her by the formal second person pronoun, /aap/,
rather than the informal, /tum/, that they used before a
fight. But I don't think I should be proud, a billion Indians would
have gotten it when they were six.)</p>

<p>Costumes: Kareena's outfits throughout the movie are great; not
/Devdas/ great, but good in a different way.</p>

<p>Songs: The first few songs were kind of bad and there's
basically a Pepsi ad in the middle of the movie; but, the later
songs are really good -- particularly the one when they dress up as
different people and after the hospital scene.</p>

<p>Overall: I thought it was good overall and can imagine renting it
again to show to someone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
