<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2003 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2003/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-11T21:29:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld, starring Kate Beckinsale (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Movie--Underworld--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I forget why, but the other day I was reminded of this series. I
decided to start watching it, similar to how I went through the
Resident Evil movies. Like that series, I saw the first one when it
came out, but never saw the others. I remember thinking the movie
was cool and that Kate Beckinsale was amazing attractive.</p>

<p>On a second viewing, significantly older, I still think some parts
of the movie are cool. The mythology is interesting and fairly
developed. The actor of Viktor is pretty awesome; while the actor
that played Kraven was unbelievably bad. The character of Erica is
really interesting and subtle. And, yes, Kate Beckinsale is
woah---except, I don't understand the appeal of the "cat suits",
they make all her natural curves indistinguishable, like a running
bra or something. I don't get it, but I guess that had to because
this movie was made to be so Matrix-y. The action sequences are
very derivative of the Matrix and pretty boring overall
actually. Lots of akimbo and chunks of buildings flying off. The
best fight is probably the very first one. Even the final fight
between Viktor and Michael is pretty meh, because Michael is so
"whatever" that it doesn't get too exciting.</p>

<p>Definitely not a classic, but I'm interested in watching the rest
of them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance (PS2, 2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished playing through Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance early
this morning/late last night. I played for about 11 days, from the
17th to the 28th.</p>

<p>First, some stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Hard
Game Over if Spotted: On
Play Time: 17:56:01
Save: 14 times
Continue: 186 times
Alert Mode: 8 times
Persons: 174 killed
Rations: 83 used
Code Name: Mammoth</p>

<p>I remember playing this game when it came out. I don't remember
beating it. Up until I fought with Fatman, I was constantly having
deja vu about the things that were going on, but I couldn't tell
you anything that was going to happen. That totally stopped after
the Fatman fight. I guess I stopped playing at that point back in
the day?</p>

<p>I played on Hard just so that I could get the "Game Over if
Spotted" option. I wish I could turn that on at the other
difficulty levels. As I've said before, I really dislike the
combat in Metal Gear and when you play on Hard, the bosses are
significantly stronger and it is very tedious and boring, in my
opinion. But, I think the Game Over if Spotted is amazing, because
it forces you to figure out how to get by undetected. I love
that. Given that though, I don't know how it was possible that I
ever got any Alert Modes. Perhaps because I killed a guard,
another saw the body, they called reinforcements, and that counts
as Alert Mode.</p>

<p>Obviously I continued A LOT to be able to get through
undetected. I don't really care, because it doesn't make it any
easier, because you still have to go room-by-room undetected.</p>

<p>I didn't really remember anything about the story of this game, so
it was nice to be learn it. It connects really well with what I
remember from MGS4. I'm excited to continue the saga.</p>

<p>One of my favourite aspects of the game was the way it continually
called back to earlier games; sometimes in a self-acknowledging
way. There were many many scenes, angles, etc that were pulled
right from earlier games. I especially like how at the end of the
game, they integrate that into the story. I really like the way
the game is about video games and people who play them, in a
sense.</p>

<p>One of my favourite moments was when Snake tells Raiden he can get
more ammo from him, Raiden asks him how he has so much ammo, Snake
points at his bandanna and says "Infinite Ammo". Of course, in
MGS1 if you save Meryl, the next time you play you get a bandanna
that gives you infinite ammo. =)</p>

<p>Another great moment for me was when Snake and Otacon depart at an
elevator and the theme song slowly swells. Very touching.</p>

<p>I didn't mind Raiden at all. Of course, the cat has long been out
of the bag that the game isn't about him. I don't remember
thinking it was weird at all when I was younger either. I do
really like how they initially call him Snake---of course,
because, it's just a code name, but change it. I also like how at
the end of the game, when Snake finally appears in his sneaking
suit, he says, "Have you been waiting long?" or something to
Raiden, and, of course, to the player.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game were great. I especially like that
guards can follow footprints better now.</p>

<p>There were a few things about the gameplay that bugged me.</p>

<p>First, Raiden doesn't start with the means to tranquilize people,
so I felt compelled to kill pretty early, whereas I got through
Snake's part without killing anyone. I was planning on doing that,
but it quickly failed. Later in the game, there are many many
places that are very combat focused (the tag team with Snake, for
example) and that's not what the game is about for me, so it
bugged me.</p>

<p>Second, the end of the bomb disposal segment was annoying because
I got to the area of the final bomb with almost 200 seconds to
spare, but I couldn't figure out how to get close enough to the
bomb. (You had to crawl on a rail in the water, on Hard.) And so I
had to run all the way back two or three times, even though I got
there perfectly. Relatedly annoying was the distance you needed to
be before you jumped into water---to far. I did it accidentally a
lot.</p>

<p>Third, the swimming controls are awful. Ugh.</p>

<p>Fourth, escort missions suck. Ugh.</p>

<p>At the very end of the game, there is a huge spike in combat
difficulty, especially with the last two bosses. I probably tried
30 times on each. I almost gave up and just watched the ending of
YouTube, but decided to man up and do it. It worked out well too,
because in the end I beat the final boss without using any
rations. I had enough practice with his attacks. =)</p>

<p>Great game!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow (GBA, 2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last little bit, I played and beat this for the
Nintendo GBA. This is definitely a good entry in the Castlevania
franchise. I really appreciated the variety that came from the
Soul system, but I felt like it had a problem that many RPGs with
these "collecting" systems: most of the things you collect are
totally useless. This game had two other problems in my mind:
first, the difficulty curve had a really sharp spike at one point
which required me to grind for almost two hours to get past a
boss; and second, the user interface was really poor and that
complicated switching souls quickly to navigate around the
map. Both of these were fixed in the next entry; in particular the
Doppelganger soul allowed you to have two equipment sets
readied.</p></p>

<p>I will definitely play this again as the secret character, so
maybe I'll report back then.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Kal Ho Naa Ho (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/27/Movie--Kal-Ho-Naa-Ho--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/27/Movie--Kal-Ho-Naa-Ho--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Kal No Naa Ho stars Sharhukh Khan, Saif Ali Khan, and Preity Zinta.</p>

<p>Accidentally, I rented a bootleg DVD. So, it was blurry, and I
think some parts were cut, and the subtitles were not on the
songs.</p>

<p>Even with this bumble, I can say that the story was cute and the
characters were interesting. Unfortunately, most of the songs were
pretty bad. There were two towards the end (the first when Preity
falls in love; and some other) that were actually good though.</p>

<p>Recommendation: Decent, but bear through the first few songs and
get a good copy.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Khushi (2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/25/Movie--Khushi--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/25/Movie--Khushi--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Khushi stars Kareena Kapoor and Fardeen Kapoor.</p>

<p>Story: The story was pretty cute and without some of the more
ridiculous things that happen in movies like this. The first five
minutes are particularly cheeseball though, so don't be turned off
right away.</p>

<p><em>REDACTED</em>acters: The two characters are very lovable. And their
relationship is ultra-cute. Basically, they fight all the time
about little things... Kareena always mistakes what Fardeen means
and this is humourous. Kareena is also very difficult and gives
Fardeen pain in an amusing way. (I was very proud of myself when I
got what a surprised/confused/hurt face was about--Kareena made
Fardeen call her by the formal second person pronoun, /aap/,
rather than the informal, /tum/, that they used before a
fight. But I don't think I should be proud, a billion Indians would
have gotten it when they were six.)</p>

<p>Costumes: Kareena's outfits throughout the movie are great; not
/Devdas/ great, but good in a different way.</p>

<p>Songs: The first few songs were kind of bad and there's
basically a Pepsi ad in the middle of the movie; but, the later
songs are really good -- particularly the one when they dress up as
different people and after the hospital scene.</p>

<p>Overall: I thought it was good overall and can imagine renting it
again to show to someone.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
