<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Battlefield 3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/battlefield-3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-10T23:02:19-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Battlefield 3 (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/26/Game--Battlefield-3--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/26/Game--Battlefield-3--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played through the Battlefield 3 campaign.</p>

<p>A friend of mine lent me the game because he had played through it
and enjoyed it.</p>

<p>A little background before I discussed the game. I played through
all the original id FPS games: Wolf, Doom, Doom 2, Quake, Quake 2,
and then Quake 3. I got really into deathmatch around Quake 2 time
and played very competitively. The only console FPS games I have
ever played were Modern Warfare 1 and this. I basically had a 10
year gap of playing FPS games and have never played one on the
computer since then.</p>

<p>The first thing I noticed about this game was that the language
was very poor in attempt to be realistic, although they seem to
almost exclusively use the F swear word. This is most prominent in
the very beginning of the game when you are with a group of
people.</p>

<p>The graphics are quite good, although nothing really
spectacular. In some places, there are really bad glitches. For
example when you a driving a tank quickly there are fields of
shrubs popping into existence in front of you as you drive. The
degree to which they go to duplicate film is almost
embarrassing. There are many fake film grains and "dust in the
air" effects. One character model looks exactly like the voice
actor (who is a relatively famous actor). Why not just be a movie
if you really want to be a movie? While playing the game, the most
impressive thing is the lighting.</p>

<p>Another thing I noticed quickly about the game is how slow it
is. You feel like you are crawling all the time or that there is a
run button that you can't find and thus are in stealth mode or
something. This sluggishness extends to the aiming controls as
well. I found that the sensitively just increased the size of the
"jumps" rather than their frequency. This is definitely a place
where old games were vastly superior. I assume the change is to
support the inferior console controls and/or inferior mass player
population.</p>

<p>I assumed that it would be fun to be part of a squad and run
around with other dudes. But most of the time you are just
following one guy (with a giant "Follow" marker on his head) and
then you get somewhere and they give you something important to
do. (Inexplicably you are the best at everything, yet need to
always be told exactly what to do.) An annoying necessity to give
the player something exciting to do.</p>

<p>The squad mechanics are related to my least favourite thing about
the game: you feel like you never accomplished anything. There
were many times where I was with my squad trying to advance or
defend some position and there seem to be an infinite number of
attackers (both at that instant and because more would come) but
then I kill one guy and suddenly all the opponents are suddenly
dead and it is time to move forward. I feel like the abstraction
inside the game is that X enemies must be killed before you can
advance or one from each of the 12 positions, which otherwise
refill shortly. It's very strange and gives you the impression
that you are randomly shooting until the roller coaster moves on.</p>

<p>The shooting itself is very infantile. The aim assist system is so
strong that it seems like you can just alternately tap the left
and right shoulder buttons to bring up the sights... auto
aim... shoot... do it again. It is easily the most effective way
to play and it has basically no skill, yet it is also visually
jarring and makes me a little dizzy.</p>

<p>Dodging is just as easy because you don't need to. It's like an
action movie where every enemy always misses and the hero never
misses. You feel like there are always bullets flying but they
never hit you unless you are totally out in the open (i.e. not in
the right place... behind the guy you are following.) If you ever
do get hit, just duck for a few seconds and go back.</p>

<p>Since you don't have to really plan where to go (follow the guy),
or what to shoot (everything), or try very hard to shoot (auto
aim), or dodge, you rarely feel like you have any impact on
the game or any real challenge. It's just like a ride.</p>

<p>Roller coaster ride is normally a good thing to describe something
as, but in this case it has one of the bad aspects of a roller
coaster. You have no idea where you are going and don't feel like
you have control over it. There is literally never any reason to
go backwards or on a different path.</p>

<p>The only times I ever died was before I learned to always follow
the guy, during cutscenes (more below), and when I didn't realize
it wasn't time to advance (related to not following the guy.) I
never felt like any death was due to lack of skill, but was due to
the game's weird rules. (For example, you kill all the guys you
can see in front of you, but you haven't killed enough on the
other side, so when you get beyond them you instantly die from
advancing to far or everyone inexplicably turns to you because now
they can see you.... and you're the player.)</p>

<p>The ride has little breaks where you pilot vehicles. These seemed
like a preview for the multiplayer, because they weren't very fun
or challenging, but they were just a little break. The best part
was actually the pre-flight checks on the jet mission. Not because
it was particularly fun, but because it felt really realistic and
cute. I was kind of surprised at how boring the flying was. The
tank drive was just frustrating because it controlled so poorly. I
guess that's realistic. =)</p>

<p>Easily the worst thing about the game were the quick-time events
and the pseudo-cutscene where you need to do something. The QTEs
are so dumb because you have a split second to make a button
press, but there's no reason why that should be the button you
have to press and it is up so far. Basically this means that you
have to die three or four times and memorize the button sequence
at do it. This would not be so horrific it didn't take so long to
get back to where you were before. At the last QTE, the whole
sequence maybe took 40 seconds, but every time you died, it would
take about 160 seconds to reload. It was excruciating. Another
occasion was like that because you weren't really in a normal
cutscene, but control was taken away from you, but then suddenly
you need to shoot... but the rules of shooting were broken because
you can't aim. The first time I did I died because I tried to aim
and then shoot rather than just shoot. Argh.</p>

<p>The way they deal with failure in the game is really weird. If you
get shot at and died, you fall down dead. That's great. If you do
something incorrectly, like you don't get to the vehicle fast
enough, the game screen just turns black and you do it again. They
don't depict the consequence in any way. It's very weird and
jarring.</p>

<p>The height of the game for me was the sniper mission, because it
felt very cool and had great graphics.</p>

<p>The story of the game was fine. It was like a Tom Clancy book, but
with this strange interrogation/flash-back/flash-forward motif. I
thought it was really neat that you played the end first and then
went back, and the second time you did it, it seemed to be
harder... i.e. not actually harder, but with more enemies. Some
story segments were very meh. For instance, the HALO jump that the
soliders do is so lame compared to Metal Gear Solid 3.</p>

<p>A few tiny annoyances: You can't pause cutscenes and when I tried
I accidentally skipped on. They give you hints to do things even
if you are already doing them... like crouching, so you think you
must not really be crouching, so you stand up, and then you
die. Thanks game.</p>

<p>The game didn't give me any play statistics, but I started at
7:15pm (that was the earliest achievement at least, so it must
have been a bit before that) and the last achievement was at
1:38am, but I took a break to have a big snack, talk to the wife,
get ready for bed, etc. I'd reckon the game took about 5 hours.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
