<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS2 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-20T22:46:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence (PS2, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/31/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-3--Subsistence--PS2--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/31/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-3--Subsistence--PS2--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence over three days
from the 28th to the 30th. My stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Normal
Play time: 19:14:20
Save: 12 times
Continue: 18 times
Alert Phase: 51 times
Humans Killed: 97 people
Seriously Injured: 129 times
Total Damage: 29 life bars.
Life Medicine Used: 0 times.
Plants &amp; Animals Captured: 11 kinds
Meals Eaten: 28 meals
Special Item: Not used
Title: Iguana</p>

<p>I have a lot of good things to say about this game, but I have a
few bad things and comments on the above stats.</p>

<p>First, I didn't use any life medicine, because I never realized
what it did. I guess it was like a traditional ration from the
earlier games. I'm not sure how I missed the instructions that
they did that, but I totally ignored them the whole game. It
probably would've made a few things easier if I hadn't. D'oh!</p>

<p>Next, I played on Normal, because there was no "Game Over if
Spotted" on any mode except European Extreme, which I don't have
the fortitude for. This made me really mad, because I find the
game mechanically weak unless you have to sneak, but implementing
that mode yourself with saves, reloads, etc is waaay to tedious to
actually do. As such, I think my enjoyment of the game suffered a
lot. I don't think I can think of any areas of the game that I got
through without alerting the guards. That means that I tried to
sneak, failed, and just ran past them frantically until I got to
the next cut-scene (which stopped the alert) or found somewhere to
hide, but then I'd just do it again. Thus, the game was basically
totally broken for me. The only mechanics I really did were the
combat mechanics during boss fights, which I've mentioned many
times before, I really don't like. The biggest problem though is
that by not having to do areas many times until I got them right,
I really only saw most areas for a few minutes (and in a rush at
that.) Therefore, the scenery of the game didn't have time to sink
in and create a lasting memory for me. I think that's really
annoying. I almost want to play it again on EE, but then my sanity
checks and I have no desire to go through the horrible combat. I
wish Kojima Productions would realize that the sneaking and the
combat difficulty can be separated. Bummer.</p>

<p>Finally, the game very inelegantly gave me the RPG-7 after a
cut-scene where Snake used it, even though I had never found it up
to that point in the game. Snake just talks about having it, then
uses it, and then I have access to it. Generally these games are
good at forcing you to get things like that, I'm surprised they
missed this one.</p>

<p>On to the praise... Most of my praise for the game focuses on
its unique story and setting.</p>

<p>A few gameplay things... Since the setting is low-tech, I really
enjoy the need to heal yourself, eat food, etc. It makes
everything feel so much more real and impacting. It's hard to
express just how that is. This game is a lot more linear than the
previous two MGS games, although very similar in linearity to the
Game Boy Color game I really liked. Basically, there are one-way
doors that lock you from going back in the world. This makes
things constantly feel fresh and new. It works really well in the
story as well, because you are not exploring one area like the
previous games, but you are pushing forward through a jungle to a
base and then to the escape. In a similar way, some of the
fundamental formulas of Metal Gear are really broken off in this
game. The biggest, I think, is that the game does not feel
"puzzley", but rather the challenges come about very
organically. For example, there's always been a token mine-field
that you must pass through that you are notified about, but in
this game mines appear very organically where they sensibly
should, and no one warns you about it. Another example is the lack
of remote controlled missile puzzles, etc. A lot of the same
elements are in this game, but they feel much more real and less
abstract, which is great. Overall, I'd say that I would prefer
more Metal Gear games like this, in particular, with the low-tech,
organic worlds.</p>

<p>On a technical level, there are some great aspects. First, the
music and ambient sound is out of the park amazing. The jungle
sounds like a jungle. Second, the areas are huge and impressive,
not the tiny corridors and rooms from previous games. The models
are nice and the art direction controls the exposure of their
flaws. Third, the first-person view jokes are great.</p>

<p>The best part of the game though, as I said before, is the setting
and story.</p>

<p>I love the opening James-Bond-style movie.</p>

<p>There are many times when characters will quote people from
earlier games that fill the same role as them. For example, Naked
Snake quotes Big Boss (himself) from MG2:SS and Solid Snake from
MGS1 (although I guess in the second case that would imply that
Big Boss had a big influence on Solid and gave him that idea.)</p>

<p>The whole development of Revolver Ocelot is amazing. The subtle
reveals when he is first introduced that he is one and the same;
the relationship between him and Naked; the "origin" story they
setup; and the best part---the post-credits reveal that harkens
back to MGS1 and lays a huge foundational mystery for the whole
series. If there weren't so many other amazing characters, Ocelot
would've been the star.</p>

<p>In general, all the characters have really great moments that
reveal who their characters are. The characters serve really well
to reinforce the setting's believably and put you in the time
period. I especially like the constant chatter about old movies on
the radio.</p>

<p>But in the end, the game totally sold me on the amazing heroism of
Naked Snake and The Boss. They are so honorable and amazing,
self-sacrificing heroes. I know it sounds cheesy, but it makes me
so proud of people and touches my heart that such pure virtues are
conceivable. When Big Boss was honoring The Boss at the end, it
gave me chills and brought some tears to my eyes. I'm especially a
sucker for tragedy and it hit the spot there too. Another part I
loved the heroism of was when EVA and Snake are about to go off
towards the end of the game and the Metal Gear theme slowly starts
to play... amazing.</p>

<p>I found the philosophy of the game great too. Especially The
Boss's speech about how enemies don't really exist, because we're
all human beings and can connect on that level.</p>

<p>This has hands down the best "ending sequence" of any Metal
Gear. Not just the scenes after you can play, but the whole final
sequence of getting to the end---basically from planting the bombs
to the end. It is so epic and awesome.</p>

<p>What a game. I will play it again some day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance (PS2, 2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished playing through Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance early
this morning/late last night. I played for about 11 days, from the
17th to the 28th.</p>

<p>First, some stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Hard
Game Over if Spotted: On
Play Time: 17:56:01
Save: 14 times
Continue: 186 times
Alert Mode: 8 times
Persons: 174 killed
Rations: 83 used
Code Name: Mammoth</p>

<p>I remember playing this game when it came out. I don't remember
beating it. Up until I fought with Fatman, I was constantly having
deja vu about the things that were going on, but I couldn't tell
you anything that was going to happen. That totally stopped after
the Fatman fight. I guess I stopped playing at that point back in
the day?</p>

<p>I played on Hard just so that I could get the "Game Over if
Spotted" option. I wish I could turn that on at the other
difficulty levels. As I've said before, I really dislike the
combat in Metal Gear and when you play on Hard, the bosses are
significantly stronger and it is very tedious and boring, in my
opinion. But, I think the Game Over if Spotted is amazing, because
it forces you to figure out how to get by undetected. I love
that. Given that though, I don't know how it was possible that I
ever got any Alert Modes. Perhaps because I killed a guard,
another saw the body, they called reinforcements, and that counts
as Alert Mode.</p>

<p>Obviously I continued A LOT to be able to get through
undetected. I don't really care, because it doesn't make it any
easier, because you still have to go room-by-room undetected.</p>

<p>I didn't really remember anything about the story of this game, so
it was nice to be learn it. It connects really well with what I
remember from MGS4. I'm excited to continue the saga.</p>

<p>One of my favourite aspects of the game was the way it continually
called back to earlier games; sometimes in a self-acknowledging
way. There were many many scenes, angles, etc that were pulled
right from earlier games. I especially like how at the end of the
game, they integrate that into the story. I really like the way
the game is about video games and people who play them, in a
sense.</p>

<p>One of my favourite moments was when Snake tells Raiden he can get
more ammo from him, Raiden asks him how he has so much ammo, Snake
points at his bandanna and says "Infinite Ammo". Of course, in
MGS1 if you save Meryl, the next time you play you get a bandanna
that gives you infinite ammo. =)</p>

<p>Another great moment for me was when Snake and Otacon depart at an
elevator and the theme song slowly swells. Very touching.</p>

<p>I didn't mind Raiden at all. Of course, the cat has long been out
of the bag that the game isn't about him. I don't remember
thinking it was weird at all when I was younger either. I do
really like how they initially call him Snake---of course,
because, it's just a code name, but change it. I also like how at
the end of the game, when Snake finally appears in his sneaking
suit, he says, "Have you been waiting long?" or something to
Raiden, and, of course, to the player.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game were great. I especially like that
guards can follow footprints better now.</p>

<p>There were a few things about the gameplay that bugged me.</p>

<p>First, Raiden doesn't start with the means to tranquilize people,
so I felt compelled to kill pretty early, whereas I got through
Snake's part without killing anyone. I was planning on doing that,
but it quickly failed. Later in the game, there are many many
places that are very combat focused (the tag team with Snake, for
example) and that's not what the game is about for me, so it
bugged me.</p>

<p>Second, the end of the bomb disposal segment was annoying because
I got to the area of the final bomb with almost 200 seconds to
spare, but I couldn't figure out how to get close enough to the
bomb. (You had to crawl on a rail in the water, on Hard.) And so I
had to run all the way back two or three times, even though I got
there perfectly. Relatedly annoying was the distance you needed to
be before you jumped into water---to far. I did it accidentally a
lot.</p>

<p>Third, the swimming controls are awful. Ugh.</p>

<p>Fourth, escort missions suck. Ugh.</p>

<p>At the very end of the game, there is a huge spike in combat
difficulty, especially with the last two bosses. I probably tried
30 times on each. I almost gave up and just watched the ending of
YouTube, but decided to man up and do it. It worked out well too,
because in the end I beat the final boss without using any
rations. I had enough practice with his attacks. =)</p>

<p>Great game!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake (PS2, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake over the last
three or four days. I played the MSX2 version that comes with
Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence.</p>

<p>This game is the true prequel to Metal Gear Solid. The story is
explicitly a sequel, whereas the original Metal Gear is obviously
ret-con'd to be about the same stuff. The themes definitely
originate here: the pacifism is so much more clear. The gameplay
gets a whole lot deeper in this game with the radar, the guards
hearing you, etc. There are very direct callbacks to this game in
later entries in the series---such as climatic fist fights.</p>

<p>This was an amazing game. I initially found it much harder than
the first one because the guards are so much more perceptive and
the first area is a tightly confined space, but as I played I got
a lot better. Also, it is harder to be glutted with ammo and
rations, but you definitely get to that point by the end of the
game. I was initially confused and annoyed about when you were
allowed to save, but then I realized it was on area transitions
(when there was a loading screen) and so I was able to use that to
my advantage when I was going to a place I was scared of.</p>

<p>Here are my play-through stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 4:59:44
Save: 27
Continue: 17
Alert Mode: 117
Humans Killed: 246
Ration Used: 7
Special Item: Not Used
Code Name: Zebra</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Katamari Damacy (PS2, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/15/Game--Katamari-Damacy--PS2--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/15/Game--Katamari-Damacy--PS2--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After Final Fantasy 13, I wanted to play something really
light. Katamari Damacy was a good choice. It's crazy, bizarre, and
really fun. I've heard a lot about it over the past few years and
I was glad to be able to try it out.</p>

<p>I really like the way you collect countries in the ending
sequence. It's funny.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kingdom Hearts 2 (PS2, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2007/12/31/Game--Kingdom-Hearts-2--PS2--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2007-12-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2007/12/31/Game--Kingdom-Hearts-2--PS2--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat this game after playing FF12 while I lived with my wife's
parents before we moved, but I'm not sure exactly when it was.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
