<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Castlevania: Harmony of Despair | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/castlevania-harmony-of-despair/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-11T00:18:36-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Harmony of Despair (X360, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Despair--X360--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Despair--X360--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing through as Soma and I've played through
everything up to Dracula without getting a better weapon than the
Claymore! I just got the Bhuj though! Nice. Still too slow though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Harmony of Despair (X360, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/29/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Despair--X360--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/29/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Despair--X360--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just beat Castlevania: Harmony of Despair.</p>

<p>I was really excited when the game was announced, because
Castlevania games are basically perfect in my eyes. I was also
excited that it would be multiplayer, because I wanted to have
my wife play with me.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, as more information about the game came out, I was
pretty disappointed. You can't play multiplayer in the same room
and it's just the combat sub-system of the game, with a lot of the
progression stripped out.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I decided to get it and play it.</p>

<p>I played through the whole game with Alucard. I was originally
planning on playing through with all the characters, going through
the DLC characters and levels, etc... but after playing through
once I'm kind of non-plussed about doing that. I expect that it
will be more and more of the same with very little excitement.</p>

<p>While I won't play more of it, I did enjoy what I played. It is
very difficult to play by yourself, because there are very few
benefits to grinding and it isn't balanced for single player, but
it is very rewarding to conquer and master the boss patterns. In
particular, Death and Dracula each took me a few weeks to
beat. When I finally beat Dracula, I could only take one more hit
and I was in that state for a few minutes... miraculously dodging
everything. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>I started the game in April and played about twice a week, then I
switched to playing every two days about two months ago.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
