<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Muramasa: The Demon Blade | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/muramasa-the-demon-blade/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-09T22:55:18-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Muramasa: The Demon Blade (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/22/Game--Muramasa--The-Demon-Blade--Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/22/Game--Muramasa--The-Demon-Blade--Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing Muramasa: The Demon Blade for the Wii.</p>

<p>I can't believe how good this game is. It is stunningly
beautiful. The gameplay is really fun and never gets old. The
story is unique. Wow, just wow.</p>

<p>A few things I really loved:
- The backgrounds are DEEP and many layered. I loved walking
through a forest and seeing the shaded groves in the back. I
loved walking through the countryside and seeing houses in the
background. The detail is just exceptional.
- I love the interaction with the environment during battle. For
example, you'll be fighting in a bamboo forest, and when you
attack you will cut bamboo shoots and they'll fall down. It is a
really subtle effect, but it feels and looks great when it
happens.
- I love the art on the food that the characters eat and the
animation of bites being taken out of it. Again, it is a very
subtle and funny thing to see, but I liked it so much I went out
of my way to eat everything so I could see what it looked
like. It made me hungry for Japanese food.
- I enjoy that the characters can hang out a hot spring to get
rejuvenated. It is especially funny when they run into a spirit,
a monkey, or the other character while they're there, because
there's always funny dialogue.
- I like that both stories revolve around a woman: Momohime is the
central character of her story, although the possessing spirit
is also important; Kisuke is not really the central character in
his, instead Torahime is.
- I /really/ like how the characters talk trash against enemies in
the dialogue sequences before they fight them. It is really
funny and the style of their trash talk is really unique too.</p>

<p>A few things I thought could be better:
- It was a pain to see how many souls you'd collected, because it
was on the Start menu or the main screen. It was a few clicks
away.
- The animation getting out of battle was a little slow and didn't
kick in until all the souls had floated to you. So there were
quite a few times when I was traveling a far distance and was
annoyed that I had to wait so long to move again.
- It was annoying to keep track of which Enemy Lairs you'd
defeated, because there was not "Todo list" and they looked the
same on the map before and after you'd completed them (although
not before and after you'd unlocked them, but you don't find out
the level recommendation until you'd unlocked them.)</p>

<p>One way you can tell how much I liked the game was my desire to
complete /everything/. The game has two characters and
three endings per character. Here are my stats for my
playthroughs:
- Momohime: 1st ending: 7 hours, 32 minutes; Level 47
- Kisuke: 1st ending: 5 hours, 40 minutes; Level 41
- Momohime: 2nd ending: 11 hours, 51 minutes; Level 92
- Kisuke: 2nd ending: 6 hours, 27 minutes; Level 49
- Momohime: 3rd ending: 13 hours, 20 minutes; Level 99
- Kisuke: 3rd ending: 9 hours, 5 minutes; Level 86</p>

<p>I really liked the game and highly recommend it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
