<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mega Man 1 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/mega-man-1/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-23T22:21:57-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 1 (NES, 1987) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The kiddo wanted to have me play this today because he likes Cut
Man so much. I creamed Cut Man: one death on the way, one death at
the fight. Next we did Ice Man I got through the disappearing
blocks really easily, but fell off on the floating platforms and
got a Game Over. Then it was time to give the monkeys lunch.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 1 (NES, 1987) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/17/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first Mega Man game I think I owned and played a lot was Mega
Man 2. But I remember trying to play Mega Man 1 quite a few times,
I don't know if I bought it or if I rented it from
Blockbuster. Regardless, I wasn't very good at it and can't really
ever remember getting to Wily's Castle at all. I think the biggest
problem was the lack of continues or passwords.</p>

<p>Today that 20 year battle was finished and I played through all of
Mega Man.</p>

<p>I'm amazed at how good this game is. I had always kind of thought
that the sequel was drastically better. It definitely has lots of
improvements, but this game is definitely amazing too.</p>

<p>I used an Infinite Lives Game Genie code so I didn't have to
Continue, etc. The spacing of checkpoints is pretty wide in this
game though, so it was nowhere near a walk in the park.</p>

<p>I'm very proud of myself for defeating some of the really
difficult segments. For example, the [[https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1NDK1tIaNwU&amp;feature=related][beginning of Guts Man's
stage]]; the <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zJ8cTlCMiE4&amp;amp;feature=player_detailpage#t=71s">disappearing blocks section of Ice Man's stage</a>; and
<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ahAKcUX5PW0">Yellow Devil</a>.</p>

<p>This game makes you feel like a super hero. It's awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 1 (NES, 1987) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/16/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/16/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played through Cut Man, Guts Man, and Ice Man. Guts Man's dropping
platform section was really rough, but nothing compared to Ice
Man's two screens of disappearing blocks followed by awful
circling death platforms.</p>

<p>After dinner, I played through the rest of the game. Wily's Castle
was insane. The hardest parts were the Wily Fortress 4 and Yellow
Devil. I did Yellow Devil sooo many times and I didn't use the
Thunder Beam or the pause trick. I have to admit that used the pause
trick on the final four robot masters and Wily.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 1 (NES, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/01/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/01/Game--Mega-Man-1--NES--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played for a bit and got destroyed by Guts Man's stage. The later
ones (with passwords and continues) are more my taste</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
