<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: GBA | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/gba/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-01T19:15:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario Advance (GBA, 2001)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/16/Game--Super-Mario-Advance--GBA--2001--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/16/Game--Super-Mario-Advance--GBA--2001--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the plane ride, I played this for a bit after my son fell
asleep. I was hoping he'd play it but he is having a hard time
learning to run in a direction and doesn't have the patience yet.</p>

<p>When I played, I got to the Birdo in 7-1 but didn't beat it. I
took the warps in 1-2 and 4-1 and then played through. I got 23%
of the game done. I think this version is quite a bit easier
because of the abundance of extra lives and hearts. But I like the
percentage indicator to show how much you've conquered.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap (GBA, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through The Legend of Zelda: The
Minish Cap. I knew I was almost done, so I stayed up a little too
late finish it tonight.</p>

<p>The graphics in this game are beautiful and vibrant. Many games
these days are dark and muddy, so it is refreshing to have such a
bright game. The game has the same style as /Link to the Past/,
but with a bit more cudly-ness.</p>

<p>The sound is good. I caught my wife humming a few of the
tunes.</p>

<p>The story is a respectable Zelda story. I like that the title
is a double entendre.</p>

<p>The gameplay is very good. It has the same core mechanics as
the first Zelda and /Link to the Past/ (my two
favourite), but almost all the items are brand new. The Kinstone
system (wherein you collect trinkets and give them to particular
NPCs) is a nice abstraction of a quest mechanic, although I
would've liked to have been able to get to the bonuses without
using a Kinstone, somehow. The boss fights are very fun and
difficult enough---I had to repeat two of them and the final
boss's first form got me the first time. The dungeon designs are
good. The puzzles are interesting without being infuriating. I
only had a few times where I wanted to throw the control (all in
the Wind Palace, btw.) The world is big enough to make it
interesting and the teleport system is convenient.</p>

<p>I finished the game with 14 heart containers, two bottles,
without the boomerang, with the original shield, without any bomb
bag/quiver upgrades (actually I'm not sure if there are any) and
with all the sword techniques. It was a little hard to complete
with such a small amount of life and only two bottles, but it was
obviously do-able and fun.</p>

<p>I definitely still prefer /Link to the Past/, but
this is worth playing again and thus worth playing for the first
time too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Aria of Sorrow (GBA, 2003)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Castlevania--Aria-of-Sorrow--GBA--2003--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>During the last little bit, I played and beat this for the
Nintendo GBA. This is definitely a good entry in the Castlevania
franchise. I really appreciated the variety that came from the
Soul system, but I felt like it had a problem that many RPGs with
these "collecting" systems: most of the things you collect are
totally useless. This game had two other problems in my mind:
first, the difficulty curve had a really sharp spike at one point
which required me to grind for almost two hours to get past a
boss; and second, the user interface was really poor and that
complicated switching souls quickly to navigate around the
map. Both of these were fixed in the next entry; in particular the
Doppelganger soul allowed you to have two equipment sets
readied.</p></p>

<p>I will definitely play this again as the secret character, so
maybe I'll report back then.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Harmony of Dissonance (GBA, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second GBA Metroid style Castlevania game. I played it
on the plane to and from a conference. It was very fun. There are
few points where the game is really confusing because there is
basically no direction about what you're supposed to do and how an
item you got is actually a key. It was frustrating to spend hours
wandering around looking for something that I could do that I
hadn't done, but I learned the map really well as a result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metroid - Zero Mission (GBA, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/04/01/Game--Metroid---Zero-Mission--GBA--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/04/01/Game--Metroid---Zero-Mission--GBA--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't beat this; I got stuck at Mother Brain.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
