<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/the-legend-of-zelda-the-minish-cap/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-30T00:46:00-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: The Minish Cap (GBA, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/15/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--The-Minish-Cap--GBA--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through The Legend of Zelda: The
Minish Cap. I knew I was almost done, so I stayed up a little too
late finish it tonight.</p>

<p>The graphics in this game are beautiful and vibrant. Many games
these days are dark and muddy, so it is refreshing to have such a
bright game. The game has the same style as /Link to the Past/,
but with a bit more cudly-ness.</p>

<p>The sound is good. I caught my wife humming a few of the
tunes.</p>

<p>The story is a respectable Zelda story. I like that the title
is a double entendre.</p>

<p>The gameplay is very good. It has the same core mechanics as
the first Zelda and /Link to the Past/ (my two
favourite), but almost all the items are brand new. The Kinstone
system (wherein you collect trinkets and give them to particular
NPCs) is a nice abstraction of a quest mechanic, although I
would've liked to have been able to get to the bonuses without
using a Kinstone, somehow. The boss fights are very fun and
difficult enough---I had to repeat two of them and the final
boss's first form got me the first time. The dungeon designs are
good. The puzzles are interesting without being infuriating. I
only had a few times where I wanted to throw the control (all in
the Wind Palace, btw.) The world is big enough to make it
interesting and the teleport system is convenient.</p>

<p>I finished the game with 14 heart containers, two bottles,
without the boomerang, with the original shield, without any bomb
bag/quiver upgrades (actually I'm not sure if there are any) and
with all the sword techniques. It was a little hard to complete
with such a small amount of life and only two bottles, but it was
obviously do-able and fun.</p>

<p>I definitely still prefer /Link to the Past/, but
this is worth playing again and thus worth playing for the first
time too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
