<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Street Fighter 4 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/street-fighter-4/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-21T17:14:15-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Street Fighter 4 (X360, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/30/Game--Street-Fighter-4--X360--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/30/Game--Street-Fighter-4--X360--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing Street Fighter IV almost every day since I
bought it last August. I've managed to beat the game on some
difficulty with every fighter. I've beat the game on every
difficulty with C. Viper (my main.) I played through 10 of the
Time Attack challenges and 11 of the Survival challenges. I had
originally planned on beating every challenge before calling it a
day with this game, but I've begun to appreciate them less. I
don't find it very fun to have arbitrary moves, etc taken away and
I'd rather just play the game itself. Since I don't plan on buying
/Super/ any time soon, I think I will move on to
another fighter.</p>

<p>It was fun C. Viper. I'll probably play every few weeks to
remember our times together :P</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Street Fighter 4 (X360, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Street-Fighter-4--X360--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/10/02/Game--Street-Fighter-4--X360--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>When I was growing up, I really liked fighting games like /Street
Fighter/, but I was horrible at them, whether I played the
computer or another person. I decided earlier this year that I
would learn how to be good, so I bought Street Fighter IV and I
practice every day. It is so much fun. I also bought a Mad Catz
Street Fighter 4 FightStick Tournament Edition Arcade
stick. Heaven! It is so sweet to use for this game and some many
others. Come to my house and I will show you its beauty!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
