<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: New Super Mario Brothers Wii | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/new-super-mario-brothers-wii/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-15T02:01:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: New Super Mario Brothers Wii (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/07/31/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers-Wii--Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/07/31/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers-Wii--Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>my wife bought me New Super Mario Brothers Wii for Christmas and
part of my gift was her willingness to play it with me.</p>

<p>We played it regularly for a few months, getting to World 4
with every star coin and secret exit, etc. We stopped for a few
months and then started up again. We completed the game in May;
actually technically my wife did because I died right before we
saved Princess Peach. During the second round of playing, we
didn't stress about getting every single star coin, because it was
a little too frustrating, especially for my wife, to play the same
course repeatedly. Now that we've completed the game, we started
trying to go back for the star coins and complete World 9, but it
is losing its appeal, so I thought it was the right time to review
it.</p>

<p>I really enjoy the game. It is a true Mario game. The joy of
running through a course bouncing around is great. The power-ups
are really fun, although we were probably too careful about using
them on the world map. The star coins are a good fun challenge,
although I think they are a little annoying because there is often
only a single way to get them, and when that entails bringing a
power-up into a course, it is particularly annoying.</p>

<p>The graphics are just right. The music is incredibly cute. One
of my favourite touches in the game is how the monsters do a
little dance with the music every so often. The super play videos
are out of control awesome. (The biggest sadness of not having all
the star coins is not being able to watch all these great videos.)
The platforming is definitely innovative. The rotating surfaces,
the way light is used, the way you can interact with the
environment (World 5-4 really stands out), etc. I'm a major
opponent of innovation for innovation's sake, but this innovation
really added to the fun of the game.</p>

<p>This game is FUN. I can't wait to play with the <em>REDACTED</em> and his
sister (We haven't decided on her pseudonym yet.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: New Super Mario Brothers Wii (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/01/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers-Wii--Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/01/01/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers-Wii--Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Started with the wifey</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
