<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Blue Dragon | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/blue-dragon/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-29T22:56:30-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through the rest of the game... meaning the final
optional dungeon and final dungeon tonight. I started to notice a
lot of chunky frame rate moments, strangely.</p>

<p>The end of the game was satisfying in a lot of ways. I got to the
power level where there was a lot of flexibility and fun in
planning the skill combinations, so I could create brutal
combos. The story wrapped up in a fun way too, with a few good
twists there at the end. The final bosses were not very hard
though.</p>

<p>Overall, I found the game on par. It wasn't particularly special:
the combat system was simple, the story was okay, and the skill
system didn't really flourish until the end. But, there also
wasn't anything really bad about it. The worst thing was probably
the plainness and the fact that a lot of the dungeons were very
samey because of small prop counts.</p>

<p>I don't think I would recommend the game to anymore, because there
are much better options. But obviously I didn't dislike it enough
to quit.</p>

<p>038:36:12 --- Clear --- 63/61/62/61</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/10/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/10/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I did a few more sidequests, including the Sea
Cube. During that I got a lot of class upgrades and had fun
picking out skill configurations. These side bosses are pretty
tough. There's one (the Ghost Yeet) that I can't survive more than
a round against.</p>

<p>The Devee Dance of Love was pretty funny. Stonesaurus is very
hard, but eventually I just used a strong Guard shadow and got
him. The boss music vocal track gets really old.</p>

<p>Before bed I wanted to finish a podcast, so I did a tiny bit of SP
grinding in the Underground River against the Kelolons.</p>

<p>I hope to do the last sidequest tomorrow night and finish that
night or the next.</p>

<p>030:47:16 --- Disc 3: Mechat Airship --- 50/50/49/49/50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/09/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/09/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I did two side quests and I tried to do a third but was
totally destroyed. I hope it isn't too much longer, because it is
getting a little tired. Nothing really to say else about the
game play today.</p>

<p>026:47:50 --- Disc 3: Mechat Airship --- 42/42/41/41/41</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The story took a bit of a depressing turn today. But it was a good
moment for the characters to come back from. Nothing particularly
exciting in the game happened though. I'm now at the part of the
game where it is possible to go to the final dungeon, but probably
not a good idea because I would be too weak. There are clearly a
lot of potential side-quests (the yellow stars on the map) that I
can go check out. I'll do a few.</p>

<p>The battling of the shadows, plus their ability to materialize for
super attacks that you ride on them during is very reminiscent of
the Eidolons in FF13. Weird.</p>

<p>023:15:05 --- Disc 3: Mechat Airship --- 33/33/31/32/31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/05/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/05/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight, although on the clock it
was only three. Since I was in Nene's fortress, I had a time limit
on myself and I pushed myself forward pretty fast. When I got to
the four robot boss fight... wow it was really hard. I probably
died 4 times. I was worried that I would have to quit the game
because when I fought around the area I was in, there were only a
few enemies and then there was no more AND I had a time limit. I
gave one more try and beat them just before I planned on giving
up. It was a frightening and annoying thought to have to quit,
although I don't think I would have really minded too
much... unfortunately. I looked at a FAQ for fight advice and it
suggested that I be at level 42... which I definitely am not.</p>

<p>As I play this game more, I'm liking Maru more and more. He's so
wacky and funny. Zola looks more and more like a tramp with every
day and her ridiculous headband is soooo <em>Snow</em>. Ugh.</p>

<p>In the final cut-scenes of the disc, Nene's mouth animations look
really weird and Nene is more and more of a jerk. Wow. What a
punk. He's not as pure evil on screen as Kefka was in FF6, but he
has the same quality where you just hate him. Shu is, of course,
super tough. I wonder where the game will go now the characters
have lost their magic (except for Shu)? Obviously they'll get them
back and save the day... but how?</p>

<p>Disc 2 was significantly short than Disc 1. 13.5 vs
about 7. Almost half as short.</p>

<p>020:55:56 --- Disc 3: Old Lady's House - 2F --- 31/31/30/29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
