<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1995 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1995/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 7 (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mega-Man-7--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mega-Man-7--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son asked for this game today (rather than the next game in our
sequence, Mega Man 4.) So I played it for about an hour. I
couldn't beat any levels, but I fought Freeze Man and Cloud Man a
few times and got all the secret items on their stages. I think I
need to invest in Energy Tanks prior to a boss battle.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Secret of Evermore (SNES, 1995) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/13/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/13/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went to play this game today and had a really weird
experience. Every time I tried to load the game we saved from
before, the screen went blank. I think it is an incompatibility
with the PowerPak. But there weirdest thing was that when I put
in the actual cart (which I own, of course), it couldn't get
passed the title screen... it also went black. I was able to
start a new game and get passed the first boss. But, on the way
back to the village with the axe, my daughter knocked the SNES
and the game froze. So frustrating.</p>

<p>Round time: 1:06
Total time: 2:00</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Secret of Evermore (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been telling my son the story of this game for a long time,
because he likes stories about dogs and exciting adventures by
boys. Today I suggested that he might like to see it. We played
for a bit. I forgot about how in the beginning you see the end of
the game and the various forms of the dog. Cool. We played
through to the bug boss of the pre-historic area, but I died. I
wasn't quick enough using items. I forgot that I wouldn't have a
checkpoint of some kind and we didn't save, but once. So, we
moved on to a different game.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:54</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Panzer Dragoon (SAT, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/28/Game--Panzer-Dragoon--SAT--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/28/Game--Panzer-Dragoon--SAT--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first game I decided to play with my new Sega Saturn was
Panzer Dragoon. When I first owned a Saturn, I bought Panzer
Dragoon Saga, but I didn't appreciate its uniqueness. I assumed it
would just be a normal JRPG and I don't really remember getting
that into it.</p>

<p>I decided to play this game because I enjoyed Sin and Punishment
so much. I assumed that /Panzer/ would be an Ur-Sin and
Punishment. It's strange because I didn't appreciate this game for
the same reason I didn't appreciate /Saga/ when I was younger:
different expectations.</p>

<p>The core gameplay of /Panzer/ is definitely fun and
a forebear of a kind of game that I really like, however, a lot of
things didn't work for me. The controls left a lot to be desired,
it was very easy to accidentally swing the camera more than the
number of arcs you intended and I never felt in control of the
dragon's position on the screen, so it was hard to avoid
obstacles, etc. There is a severe lack of contrast between the
enemies (and their bullets) and the background, so it is hard to
tell what you need to shoot at or avoid. These two mechanical
problems were pretty big deal breakers for me. The main difficulty
I felt playing it was dealing with the systems, rather than an
actual hurdle I needed to bring myself over. (This is, of course,
a classic critique of many old games, but I think it fits this one
appropriately because the exact gameplay has been done well in
other places.)</p>

<p>Nevertheless, there was a lot to enjoy about the game. First,
the story is pretty epic. One of my favourite things, however, is
that the story explains why you don't control the path of the
Dragon (i.e., why it is on rails): you're not the true rider, he
died and you happened to be there, his last words: "don't...let
him [his killer] go back to The Tower...my dragon...knows the
way..." Brilliant. Second, many of the level setups are really
inspired and spectacular. The first was the giant sandworms in the
second level. Gorgeous. The next was the boss in the third level:
you have to dodge vertically these rotating fans. It worked really
well and was different from the earlier segments. (BTW, I
mentioned it was hard to dodge in general, but it was definitely
easier vertically.) The next was the fourth level. Flying through
the tiny tunnels makes you feel like Luke Skywalker taking out the
Death Star. Also brilliant.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that I would have loved this game when it first
came out, but it is not worth it (for me) to spend my time
perfecting my performance in it. I will definitely play the
sequels, however.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blackthorne (32X, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Blackthorne--32X--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Blackthorne--32X--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very boring, bad music, bad controls. MEH.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
