<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1995 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1995/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-31T00:16:04-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Panzer Dragoon (SAT, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/28/Game--Panzer-Dragoon--SAT--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/28/Game--Panzer-Dragoon--SAT--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first game I decided to play with my new Sega Saturn was
Panzer Dragoon. When I first owned a Saturn, I bought Panzer
Dragoon Saga, but I didn't appreciate its uniqueness. I assumed it
would just be a normal JRPG and I don't really remember getting
that into it.</p>

<p>I decided to play this game because I enjoyed Sin and Punishment
so much. I assumed that /Panzer/ would be an Ur-Sin and
Punishment. It's strange because I didn't appreciate this game for
the same reason I didn't appreciate /Saga/ when I was younger:
different expectations.</p>

<p>The core gameplay of /Panzer/ is definitely fun and
a forebear of a kind of game that I really like, however, a lot of
things didn't work for me. The controls left a lot to be desired,
it was very easy to accidentally swing the camera more than the
number of arcs you intended and I never felt in control of the
dragon's position on the screen, so it was hard to avoid
obstacles, etc. There is a severe lack of contrast between the
enemies (and their bullets) and the background, so it is hard to
tell what you need to shoot at or avoid. These two mechanical
problems were pretty big deal breakers for me. The main difficulty
I felt playing it was dealing with the systems, rather than an
actual hurdle I needed to bring myself over. (This is, of course,
a classic critique of many old games, but I think it fits this one
appropriately because the exact gameplay has been done well in
other places.)</p>

<p>Nevertheless, there was a lot to enjoy about the game. First,
the story is pretty epic. One of my favourite things, however, is
that the story explains why you don't control the path of the
Dragon (i.e., why it is on rails): you're not the true rider, he
died and you happened to be there, his last words: "don't...let
him [his killer] go back to The Tower...my dragon...knows the
way..." Brilliant. Second, many of the level setups are really
inspired and spectacular. The first was the giant sandworms in the
second level. Gorgeous. The next was the boss in the third level:
you have to dodge vertically these rotating fans. It worked really
well and was different from the earlier segments. (BTW, I
mentioned it was hard to dodge in general, but it was definitely
easier vertically.) The next was the fourth level. Flying through
the tiny tunnels makes you feel like Luke Skywalker taking out the
Death Star. Also brilliant.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that I would have loved this game when it first
came out, but it is not worth it (for me) to spend my time
perfecting my performance in it. I will definitely play the
sequels, however.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blackthorne (32X, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Blackthorne--32X--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Blackthorne--32X--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Very boring, bad music, bad controls. MEH.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chrono Trigger (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/06/01/Game--Chrono-Trigger--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/06/01/Game--Chrono-Trigger--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat this again on the DS version. The extra content was pretty
lame.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Seiken Densetsu 3 (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/01/01/Game--Seiken-Densetsu-3--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-01-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/01/01/Game--Seiken-Densetsu-3--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started to play this on an emulator, but didn't get very far. I
dislike playing games on emulators, so it couldn't capture me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Tales of Phantasia (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Tales-of-Phantasia--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Tales-of-Phantasia--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this whole game on an emulator. It was pretty
cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
