<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Retro Game Challenge | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/retro-game-challenge/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-11T10:31:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Retro Game Challenge (DS, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Retro-Game-Challenge--DS--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Retro-Game-Challenge--DS--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>While I was on my tour, I played through most of Retro Game
Challenge and just completed the last challenge (beat all the
games) tonight. This game is incredibly brilliant.</p>

<p>The premise is that a demon version of a Japanese video game
playing TV star has sent you back into the 80s to challenge you
with old Famicom-style video games. You are presented with a game
and four challenges, when you complete most challenges you get a
new issue of a game magazine and when you complete all of them you
get another game and more challenges. Each game has an illustrated
manual. The game magazines are hilarious, because they will
preview games that you'll be unlocking soon, they'll report that a
game has been delayed, and they have a top 5 chart with hilarious
parody titles. When you play a game, it runs in to the top screen
of the DS, while on the bottom you see two kids sitting in front
of a TV playing. I love that the friend makes comments about how
you're playing as you do. It is hilarious.</p>

<p>The games are great too:
- <em>Cosmic Gate</em> - This is a Galaga-like fixed-screen shooter. It
is simple, but fun.
- <em>Robot Ninja Haggle Man</em> - This is a single screen platformer,
like Bubble Bobble, although you throw ninja stars to stun
things. The main mechanic is going in "doors" that hurt the
enemies and protect you from damage. This isn't my favourite
game, but it is enjoyable.
- <em>Rally King</em> - A racing game like RC Pro Am. The cool part is
the drift mechanic. I'm not a huge fan of racers, so when I beat
this game for the final challenge I used invincibility.
- <em>Star Prince</em> - A straight-forward vertically scrolling
shooter. The weapon selection is great and the hidden bonus
items are fun to find. You get a special controller to play this
game which turns your Y button into a rapid-fire. One of my
favourite subtleties is that you fire faster the closer you are
to the top of the screen (which is dangerous.)
- <em>Robot Ninja Haggle Man 2</em> - This game plays just like its
predecessor, although it is considerably more difficult and the
final boss is very interesting.
- <em>Rally King SP</em> - The same game as its predecessor but with new
graphics. The levels are the same, etc. This is a promotional
game for the game magazine and a soup company. Very funny.
- <em>Guadia Quest</em> - A Dragon Quest-style JRPG. A fun mechanic is
that you can capture strong enemies and they will fight for
you. It was very fun to play this old school RPG.
- <em>Robot Ninja Haggle Man 3</em> - This is a reboot of the Robot Ninja
Haggle Man series with new graphics and gameplay. The gameplay
and graphics are incredibly reminiscent of Ninja Gaiden,
although the colors pop a lot more than the original NES Ninja
Gaidens. In addition to that core gameplay, there is a
customization system reminiscent of Super Metroid. This is a
little bit of exploration as well, but the levels are mostly
linear.</p>

<p>My favourite games were Star Prince, Robot Ninja Haggle Man 3, and
Guadia Quest.</p>

<p>I /highly/ recommend this one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
