<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Resonance of Fate | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/resonance-of-fate/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-12T21:42:04-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Resonance of Fate (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/10/16/Game--Resonance-of-Fate--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/10/16/Game--Resonance-of-Fate--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>my wife got me Resonance of Fate for the PS3 for my birthday, but I
didn't start playing it until the beginning of August.</p>

<h1>Play details</h1>

<p>I played it pretty much every day in August, when it was my main
game, but by the end of August, I was getting a bit tired of it. I
did every thing that was possible to do in the game as I played:
all the extra missions, challenge fights, and going to the Arena
occasionally. Eventually, the grind wore down on me quite a bit. I
stopped doing the challenge fights in chapter 10 and then in
chapter 12 I decided to stop doing the extra missions. This was
after 38.5 hours of playing the game. At that point, I rushed to
the end, but when I got to chapter 14, I couldn't get past the
first room of the story mission dungeon. I realized I wouldn't be
able to do, so I went back to my chapter 12 save and just played
for a very short time (about 1 battle or 1 mission) every day. It
took me until yesterday to get to the last dungeon and I decided
to push on through to the end of the game.</p>

<p>In the end, I played for 54 hours. Vashyron was level 76
(30+28+18), Zephyr was level 86 (27+35+24), and Leanne was level 3
(32+27+24). I definitely will not do all the Arena ranks or play
through the secret Neverland dungeon.</p>

<h1>Story</h1>

<p>I found the story of the game to be really intriguing. The world
is very different than most games and I like the way that there
isn't a lot of exposition in the game. Instead, you are just
normal-ish people in the world and things gradually unfold. Most
cut-scenes are less than two minutes long it seems. Some cut
scenes are hilarious and some are really fascinating and
cool. However, after you get to level 10 or so and you realize
that the game must almost be over, it is really weird that it
seems like nothing really happened. It's just mild character
development. Even when the game was over, I said to myself, "What
even happened in this game?" I read the Wikipedia page about the
game and then all the dots connected. The story in the game is
intriguing and vague; the story in the Wikipedia page is
fascinating... I just wish it were in the game.</p>

<h1>Style</h1>

<p>The characters and world exude "style". I love the dress-up
mini-game and I bought lots of different clothes until I found an
outfit for each character I really liked. I dressed Leanne with
black glasses, a black tight sweater, a pink knee-length skirt,
and tall white boots with a big bow on the laces so they looked
like  knee-ish high socks. I dressed Vash in jeans and a cool
white Resonance of Fate jacket. I dressed Zephyr in a dark
green-ish suit with a red undershirt.</p>

<p>The style really comes to a head in the battle system. It feels
exactly like a John Woo movie.</p>

<p>The Christmas segment... including the costumes... is insane.</p>

<p>I can't believe tri-Ace... which I think of as a very small
company... could make such a beautiful game.</p>

<h1>Mechanics</h1>

<p>The most important part of a game to me is its mechanics. In RoF,
there are a few systems.</p>

<p>First, there's the world map. It is basically a board game where
you are unlocking pieces of the world with Tetris-like jigsaw
pieces you get from battles. You can only go places you unlock and
by unlocking places you gain other rewards such as items or
effects in battle. It is neat and totally unnecessary (for the
rest of the game to work), but I enjoy it, so it is a welcome
addition.</p>

<p>Second, there's the gun customization and item synthesize
systems. The game's combat is gun-based and you can customize your
guns with additional parts like barrels, scopes, magazines,
etc. There are like 5 attributes that you can enhance. I have no
idea what these attributes actually do, despite having played
through the whole game and spent a lot of time customizing. The
system works by laying out the extra parts in a 2D grid where they
must connect in appropriate ways (empty circle attaches to full
circle, empty square to full square, etc) to each other and
ultimately to the gun. It is fun to make ridiculous looking guns,
but I don't feel I really understood it enough to do it well. The
item synthesis is a corollary to this system because you can build
parts (and accessories, grenades, and bullets) with it. I don't
think I mastered (or needed to master) either system, but I did
use and have fun with them.</p>

<p>Third, there's the progression system. Each character has three
levels that are summed to get their total level. There's one level
per type of weapon---hand gun, machine gun, and thrown
weapon. Gaining levels gives you abilities when using that weapon,
like 10% damage increase, etc. I didn't focus each
character. Instead, I constantly rotated weapons around (you gain
levels in the weapons you use) to the weak character with that
weapon to boost their total level. Gaining total levels gives you
health and weight capacity (did I mention guns, accessories, and
their parts have weights?) I wonder if it would have been better
to focus each character.</p>

<p>Fourth, and biggest, there's the combat system. It is incredibly
complicated to explain, but very simple once you understand
it. The fundamental principle is that you can do a lot of blue
damage and very little red damage and only red damage kills
guys. However, if someone has 100 points of blue damage and you do
1 point of red damage, then the blue converts to red and you just
did 101 points of red damage. Everything in combat is about
filling up blue damage and then doing a little red
damage. However, there are many subtleties.</p>

<p>The most basic is that the angle you are firing at the enemy
matters and many enemies have shields that absorb fire from one
direction. The next is that blue damage recovers over time, so you
want to focus. The next is that you charge shots faster the closer
you are to the enemy. The next is that blue damage on you does not
turn into red damage, but instead when it fills up your whole life
gauge takes away 1 Hero point for every 1000 hit points. But
what's a hero point?</p>

<p>In this game, you can either stand still, charge and fire once, or
you can run past an enemy (jumping through the air and sliding on
the ground) and fire many times. When you make a run, you use a
Hero Point. You need to do this to make enough attacks. If you
ever run out of Hero Points, the next time your HP fills up blue,
you'll die, but you'll die anyways because you can't do these
runs. There's another subtlety though. If you run across the line
made by the other two characters, it gives you a Resonance Point,
which you can convert to one cycle of a tri-Attack where each
character makes a Hero Run to the point where the next character
is standing. During a tri-Attack, any enemy inside the triangle
cannot move or have their blue damage healed.</p>

<p>The trick to this system is that there is only one strategy: Have
each character make a hero run across the line of the other
characters such that they go really close to the enemy and end up
on the other side. Do this twice to set up a tri-Attack with a big
triangle. Then do it again. This technique wins every single
battle. The only thing you ever need to do in addition is
sometimes use grenades to cause area damage or wear the right
status-effect protection accessory.</p>

<p>In the beginning of the game (probably the first 20 hours), this
system feels really cool and neat every time. It is definitely fun
and original. However, after a while, you realize that it is just
like Sudoku. Every Sudoku board is the same because your strategy
is always the same. What you are doing is always the same. In
contrast, even though you can describe FF13 or Bayonetta in a
reductionist way---increase stress and then do damage OR do combos
and then do torture attacks----how you do that is different in
every situation. In RoF, it's the same. It doesn't exactly get
boring, but it loses its challenge.</p>

<p>The worst part, however, about the combat system is that it feels
a little too random sometimes. As mentioned before, there's just
one strategy I used. But I still often needed to make the attempt
to beat a boss three or four times in sequence before winning. The
only thing that separated one attempt from another were random
factors like causing a break, getting pushed a little bit by fire,
or getting a full scratch, or something. It doesn't seem right
that a random flip will make me go from utter defeat to utter
dominance. It seems like a random factor should make a small
difference, not a big one. This suggests to me that the game
really doesn't require much skill if I could never recover from
little flips like that.</p>

<p>A related problem is that it never feels like there is anything
you can do to make your characters better or more
powerful. Gaining levels, getting gun upgrades, etc don't seem to
make any difference on your play. I'm sure they do something but
it is so gradual they you never feel like you've reached a
new plateau where you can look down at where you were
and say you rock. There's nothing technically wrong with this, but
it doesn't give me the feeling I want.</p>

<h1>Summary</h1>

<p>I was looking forward to this game because I've enjoyed every game
that tri-Ace has released that I've played. (I think I have missed
two games.) And when it was first coming out, I heard lots of fun
conversations about its crazy battle system. I wasn't let down by
the game, but I don't think this game will be as lasting to me as
Valkyrie Profile or Star Ocean 3 are. Overall, I recommend the
game. If you aren't super hardcore like me, maybe it would better
to have an easy mode, but I don't think one exists.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
