<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-12T08:39:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour tonight and mainly did story and
exploration stuff. I got the ability to go to other planets and
got to the medieval world. The game is okay so far. I haven't
really been captured by it. I'm not sure why. The combat system
doesn't seem as advanced as I'd like and a lot of the world is
pretty empty and samey. I'll keep playing, but I'm a bit sad I
haven't been totally won over by it.</p>

<p>Total: 3:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
"Inn" to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I've been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There's just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one "episode" per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I'm looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don't really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It's the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful, although a little bit of the time
I felt like I was losing because I couldn't target the thing I
wanted. The graphics are pretty good, although the characters are
verrry anime-y and from some angles their clothes really clash
with their faces. (For example, the guy on the computer screen
that Edge talks to.) The controls are responsive.  Although the
camera controls are a little too "tight" for my taste so far. I
got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I think the
problem is that the world is so "bright" that it's hard to notice
something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of the time was
spent in videos, so I don't really have a good feel for the game
yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today and finished the game. I got
As on the last few missions, which was pretty cool. I think I got
As on almost all of them, but I didn't load my Clear data, so I'm
not sure if it would say what my overall statistics were, etc.</p>

<p>It was a really cool game. The ending was sweet. There were so
pretty crazy revelations about the characters, the events were
suitably epic, and the final boss was intense. I particularly
liked the sequence at the end where they showed what each
character did after the war... especially the little vignette
about Welkin and Alicia and their baby girl :) So cute!</p>

<p>The combat in the game is really interesting too. I enjoyed both
the "stealth" missions and the other ones. It makes me think a lot
about how you'd make a game like this. (And in particular,
randomly generate levels for it.)</p>

<p>I saw that there were some DLC missions, but I don't think it is
worth it for me right now given my queue. I do like the game a
lot, but I feel like I've got the missions down to be a bit rote,
so it's mainly the story pushing me to do more.</p>

<p>It was interesting to compare my final in-game timer (25:08) to my
count (33:39), because it shows how much time was taken up by
mission attempts that ultimately failed and thus weren't counted
in the real total. Wow!</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>

<p>Total: 33:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (13)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--12/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today, split across watching a
movie. The battles were pretty tough. The once against Selvaria
was insane, because she dodges practically everything. I
eventually realized I should use a unit with the "Undodgeable
Shot" ability, then it was all over. The one where you have to
blow up the canyon walls, I kept doing it wrong because I didn't
realize there were two things to blow up to force it to
turn. D'oh. I wasted like 30 minutes because of that.</p>

<p>I can't believe that Welkin proposed to Alicia---he even had a
ring! This game is so grown up compared to other RPGs, especially
Japanese ones. The story is really cool, still.</p>

<p>Total: 30:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
