<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-22T21:48:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/07/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided that life is too short to play games like Rayman Origins
when there are amazing games I haven't played enough. So I'm
stopping. I did everything possible in the first world and
everything possible in the first half of the second world. The
horrible controls are not worth the adorable setting of the
game... unfortunately.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/02/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half today. I did two chase
levels and a shmup level. There's so much about this game that is
admirable: the music is cool, the level design is pretty neat,
the graphics are great. But man! The controls are SOOOOOOOOOO
bad. It's like every level is the worst under-water level ever
from Mario. Rayman is just so slippery and hard to
control. Ugh. It makes me want to not play the game at all, but
I'm a masochist and can't resist. I'll definitely remove every of
Rayman game from my list though.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gal*Gun (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--Gal-Gun--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--Gal-Gun--PS3--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I heard of this game online as a weird Japanese rail-shooter. I
like rail-shooters, but I find the zombie aesthetic to be pretty
boring. I thought it would be cute to have the girls/Cupid/love
thing going on in the game. I wasn't let down in that regard, but
I found the gameplay to be very easy. I was able to clear one of
the girls in a very short period of time. I only had a hard time
with the "boss fights" because they all had different mechanics. I
really didn't get what was going on with the book shelf
situation. I got a pretty good score on my first run, it said I
got 82% of the maximum or something and I got the "Good End". But
it wasn't really the sort of thing with a lot of interesting depth
to it... like Sin &amp; Punishment. This is kind of disappointing, but
I didn't pay too much for the game.</p>

<p>I was slightly nervous that the game would be too scandalous but
it's not bad at all. The girls are all normal anime girls and
there's no cleavage or anything like that at all. The most racy it
gets is that the girl's skirts rustle and sometimes it flash their
underwear for a moment. I was pleased that the girls in swimsuits
were wearing sports one-pieces, like they were properly on a swim
team.</p>

<p>I think my favourite part of the game were the animations and
sounds... particularly how when the girls get close, they give
the character an invitation or if they "attack" from far away
they shout something like "Love" or "Really Like You" and the
words are coming at you.</p>

<p>It's a totally bizarre game, but not very deep. I'm not sure how
its depth compares to something like Resident Evil: Umbrella
Chronicles, which is structurally identical but with a zombie
skin. But, Gal*Gun isn't interesting enough for me to want to
play more than a few times.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/22/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another level and got all the stuff in it, although I
was one second from getting the time flag. It was just because I
thought I would land on the flag, but actually had to move to the
right. Urgh.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son requested this again and I got all the awards on the second
level then got all the things on the third, except the medal and
the speed trophy. I found it un-intuitive to figure out how to do
the time course. I also find this game to control incredibly
sloppily. The character just swishes around all the time, it is
incredibly obnoxious and hard to deal with.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
