<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-05T23:13:05-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/05/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a little less than an hour tonight. I gained a level
by killing the gargoyle and then all the sentinels again---I
wanted to get all the chests... I forgot one. Then it took me a
while to figure out how to get to the chapel. I fought my way to
the fog gate, but then ran out of time for the night, so I walked
back. I wanted to do an epic jump, but misjudged the distance and
plummeted to my death. Nice.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Upgrade Iaito to Fire element
- Explore the rest of Sen's Fortress (Pit)</p>

<p>SL: 50</p>

<p>Vit: 29
Att:  8!
End: 30
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 21:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/03/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/03/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours tonight. I explored the rest of
Sen's Fortress (or at least, I got to the boss) and then I
unlocked a shortcut to the boss, and then I tried to fight the
boss many many times. I could generally avoid almost every single
attack... occasionally I would get grabbed, but I could generally
heal myself. The main problem was that I kept getting knocked off
the tower by him. I probably fought him about 20 times. I explored
a number of different weapon options. Probably the best was
putting a Lightning enhancement on my Iaito, but I didn't have
enough to keep using it. Eventually I used the Drake Sword
(because Iaito's bleed didn't effect the Golem.) I won and it felt
real good. I explored the next area a tiny bit. I killed all the
Sentinels and got a level from that. I'm excited to be making
steady progress.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Upgrade Iaito to Fire element
- Explore the rest of Sen's Fortress (Pit)</p>

<p>SL: 49</p>

<p>Vit: 28
Att:  8!
End: 30
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 20:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/02/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like two hours today. I fought and won against
Quelaag on my third or so time today. It was pretty epic to dodge
her attacks and take her down. (But I used all five of my healing
charges.) After taking care of business down there, I went back to
near Sen's Fortress and fought the demon underneath the
blacksmith, upgraded my weapon a bit, and then started into the
fortress. I died many times learning how to get through the first
area and exploring it a bit. I feel like I have a good sense of
the layout but not what I'm supposed to do in there. Maybe I need
to drop down to the pit and do something there? More tomorrow, I
guess.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)
- Upgrade Iaito to Fire element</p>

<p>SL: 43</p>

<p>Vit: 22
Att:  8!
End: 30
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 17:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/01/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/01/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for almost five hours tonight because the wife went to
bed early. I had a rough time.</p>

<p>I started in Blightown, near the boss, so I tried to fight her a
few times. She's a demon spider thing with a nude top (her hair
covers her tas.) That's important because there was an amazing
message outside her arena. It said "Amazing chest ahead". It's so
funny because you normally see that same message when there is a
good /treasure/ chest near by.</p>

<p>After failing utterly fighting her <em>and</em> realizing I hadn't
repaired my equipment in a while (I didn't buy the thing to do it
at any bonfire), I decided to leave and go do that.</p>

<p>I tried to escape from the area the way that I can, but I wasn't
strong enough with my alternative weapon to get through. I
probably tried maybe five times. It was rough.</p>

<p>So, I decided to go via the water wheel and the new areas. The
first time, I fell off the wheel. Nice. Then there were some
really rough dudes at the top of the water wheel that would knock
me off cause I'd get caught on the geometry. (This whole area, by
the way, has a really choppy frame rate.)</p>

<p>After I finally got back up to the top of the tower, I decided to
just run past the guys rather than fighting them. That worked
well.</p>

<p>I went back to the Undead Asylum after buying the repair kit and
got the ring that lets you walk through the swamp easily, and I
went and got the Spider Shield to protect myself from poison
attacks.</p>

<p>With that stuff in hand, I worked on getting to the Fire Keeper
Soul in Blighttown. I did a few rounds---first I killed all the
poison snipers and then I went back and sniped at all the dogs
from above (they gang up on you and hit <em>real</em> hard.) Eventually
it worked out and I got it.</p>

<p>Unfortunately, I couldn't actually use it and, in fact, getting it
seemed to kill the Fire Keeper in the Firelink Shrine. Ooops.</p>

<p>So, I went back to Blighttown and tried to fight the spider boss a
few more times. I got a pretty good rhythm going, but I'll have to
perfect it later.</p>

<p>TODO list:
- Explore the Blighttown - Swamp more
- Kill Stray Demon (in Aslyum)</p>

<p>SL: 40</p>

<p>Vit: 21
Att:  8!
End: 28
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 14:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/30/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I spent the time
working my way through Blighttown. It was very scary and tough. I
would get repeatedly pummeled by the huge ghouls and then I kept
falling off and getting swarmed closer to the swamp. It was pretty
rough. Quite a few times, the dogs at the very beginning caught me
off guard and decimated me.</p>

<p>Probably the worst time was when I was working my way back to the
swamp the first time, I attacked and the animation pushed me over
the edge of the cliff and I lost 7.7k souls... about a level where
I am in the game. After that, it was really hard to get back to
the swamp.</p>

<p>It's very fun in this game to slowly push through to the next area
and then the next, etc. One thing that I dislike compared to
Demon's Souls is that, because there is no hub, you can't get back
to a place to buy things, like arrows, if you need them
easily. It's kind of frustrating.</p>

<p>SL: 35</p>

<p>Vit: 18
Att:  8!
End: 26
Str: 16!
Dex: 20!
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 10:07</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
