<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-06T22:58:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for two hours tonight and got to 11.5. There were so
many absurd moments. I loved how Asura flew by punching the
ground and riding the shock wave. I loved the onsen sequence and
how Asura was denied. I loved how Augus and Asura are
inexplicably on the moon and how ridiculously huge Augus' sword
is (and how he's never drawn it but once). I loved the gigantic
crater from the sword and how Asura always ends up with no
arms. It's also very intriguing that Augus was robot-y too. What
could that mean?</p>

<p>Total time: 4:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed my wife the awesome Wyzen fight and then did the next
two episodes. The "ending" was cool and the awesome arm-less
fight. This game is just sooo ridiculous. I can tell my wife is
kind of appalled at how insane it is. I love that about it.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game on the recommendation of the Giant Bomb
podcast. Tonight I played for a little less than two hours and
played through the first five episodes. This game is insane. I
love the over-the-top-ness. I love the TV show stylings. The
combat and shooting feel interesting and like I'm doing something,
although I get the impression that I can't lose and it's just a
matter of smashing enough until I can Burst, although I suppose I
could simply pay attention to my score at the end. So far, I think
it's a really unique and amazing experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 2 (PS3, 2012) - DLC]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--26/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--26</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote in my calendar to check on the DLC about six months after
I beat the game, when presumably it would all have been
released. It has. I looked for information about it and almost
none of it seems interesting, except Lightning's episode. But, I
found that it only takes about 25 minutes (including cut-scenes)
and that's not worth 5 bucks, so I just watched it. The new ending
is neat. I'm excited for 13-3. I love this battle system so much
and I find the world to be really cool too. I hope it can be
efficient for them to produce, make them lots of money, and make
FF15 amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to retire this game for a while. I haven't really
been playing that much even though I have it scheduled and kind of
want to. I think I need to start again from the beginning with no
assists. I only have the Endurance Races, the Formula GT races,
and the Special Events to get Golds on, but I don't want to spend
the time on the Endurance ones and the Formula/Special events are
so technical, I think my skills just aren't up to the task. I
think I need to re-learn to play. I'm going to put it on my
schedule to play it again in January and give it another try. I
can't believe how much and how long I've played this game. It's
sooo good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
