<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-01T08:00:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight... the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn't understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it... but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I'm curious about what Zaka will be
like... do I really get another vehicle? I'm running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the "reports" I'd seen showing up were... how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service... I mean, the beach vacation... one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. The story battles are
getting pretty rough and un-cheese-able, which is really fun
because it forces me to try different things. I got a really bad
score in the second woodland battle, which was kinda sad, so I did
another skirmish so I could get the XP I missed. I really enjoyed
using the tank a lot in the woodland battle though.</p>

<p>Total: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three and half hours tonight. I spent a very
long time on the Desert Duel against the giant tank. There was a
lot of saving and reloading as I tried different techniques and
slowly got closer to victory. It was a really tough, complicated
fight. The stealth mission was pretty tough too; I kept making
stupid mistakes and trying to kill the soldier named "Ty the
Immortal"---I couldn't seem to land a killing hit on him... maybe
his name was a clue from the developers? I'm sad I didn't get an A
on that fight.</p>

<p>I think it is cool how the came is slowly becoming more
"fantastical" in its setting with the discovery at the ruins,
etc. It's neat because the earlier parts of the game are so
realistic-ish.</p>

<p>The battles tonight were especially fun because I couldn't cheese
them, so I had to really use all the options that were
available. Nevertheless, I had some pretty brutal strategies. For
example, in the desert fight, I was able to kill all the enemy
foot soldiers on the first round with my two snipers and
Rosie. Then I was able to take out all the gun turrets on the tank
in two rounds. Then it was just a matter of waiting around while
the radiators showed up. When Selvaria surprise attacked, Rosie
was right next to where her units appeared, so she was able to
kill every single one on the first round. Then Selvaria ignored
her and just ran past. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>Total: 10:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I did a whole bunch
of battles. The hardest was the Normal Skirmish that's like the
Woodland battle. It took me quite a few tries to get an A with
Alicia. Playing the game like this makes it like Metal Gear Solid
when you are trying to get a No Alert win. It's a very strange
optimization problem.</p>

<p>Total: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
