<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PS3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ps3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-26T22:16:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little over an hour. I got through the next
part of the Undead Parish. The Rhino was pretty tough and got me
once. Then I weaved my way around and accidentally stumbled into
the Bell Gargoyle fight. I died the first three times and then
accidentally died on the way. So I lost about 6k souls. Ouch. This
game is definitely great.</p>

<p>SL: 21</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 18
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 4:56</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dark Souls (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Dark-Souls--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today and got used to the game. I
spent a long time planning my character based on remembering what
was a good strategy in Demon's Souls. I'll be taking the same
approach: really fast, huge shield, melee focus, but with a good
bow.</p>

<p>The tutorial phase of the game was much shorter and so far the
game seems incredibly linear, which I thought wasn't the case, but
maybe I'm just still in the beginning. Last time I took a very
linear approach through the game, but this time I intend to
explore a bit more.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game are basically identical. The graphics
seem a little bit better... primarily in the lightning department,
but I don't know if I can really tell or I just have a bad
memory. It seems like this simply <em>is</em> Demon's Souls with a little
bit of a different structure---no hub, Humanity, etc.</p>

<p>That makes it sound like I don't like the idea of that, but I'm
actually very excited about playing it.</p>

<p>During my time tonight, I died twice. Each time against a boss on
my first fight with them. The game seems just as hard as before,
but I'm getting used to the controls again and learning how the
bosses behave. Overall, it's a pretty awesome game.</p>

<p>Here are my current stats (where ! indicates that the stat is at
the level I intend to leave it at for the foreseeable future):</p>

<p>SL: 19</p>

<p>Vit: 16
Att:  8!
End: 16
Str: 16!
Dex: 16
Res: 11!
Int:  9!
Fai:  9!</p>

<p>Total Time: 3:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I'm
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I'm on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I'll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but...</p>

<p>I can't remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I'm not compelled by this one at all. It's a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There's a
"blindside" system, but it's basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren't ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It's frustrating that
you can't really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there's no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you'll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You'll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it's
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don't think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I'm glad I've played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour tonight and mainly did story and
exploration stuff. I got the ability to go to other planets and
got to the medieval world. The game is okay so far. I haven't
really been captured by it. I'm not sure why. The combat system
doesn't seem as advanced as I'd like and a lot of the world is
pretty empty and samey. I'll keep playing, but I'm a bit sad I
haven't been totally won over by it.</p>

<p>Total: 3:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
"Inn" to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I've been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There's just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one "episode" per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
