<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Super Meat Boy | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/super-meat-boy/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-21T00:07:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I beat the level---The Coil. It was horrible. The first time
I beat it---after almost an hour---I was 1.02 seconds too late to
get an A+. I gave it another 15 minutes and got about 7 seconds
under the required time. Go!</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for another hour and a half later in the day beat a few
more levels. 5-19X was destroying me though. I have 5-19X, 5-20X,
Four Letter Word in Cotton Alley, and all the Dark World of
Dr. Fetus' castle and Cotton Alley left before I do everything in
the game. Exhausting. This game makes my hands hurt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/01/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For about a month I've been working on 5-14X (Necrosis). It was
very, very hard. You had to go down a shaft, across a wide area
with tiny platforms, then up a shaft, back down, back across, back
up, and then across the same area but now with disappearing
platforms. All while being pursued by floating monsters and all
the shafts had maggot piles getting you.</p>

<p>Today I was playing with my son and after about 15 minutes of
doing okay, I say, "Well, I think this should be the last try
before we go to church." He says, "Okay! Let's DO it!" Then, of
course, I do it. I just needed a cheerleader.</p>

<p>I got 38.00 seconds when the par time was 60.00 seconds.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/27/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/27/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Dark World version of 4-20 was craaaazy hard. But I did it! 45
minutes!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/18/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just beat a Dark World level (4-15X) on my third try with
8.67/11.00 time. Wow, that's weak sauce.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/27/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/27/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought Super Meat Boy when it first came out (November 2010) and
I played the majority of the first world right when it came out,
but it took until about January 2011 until I started playing it
regularly---every two days---and I haven't stopped.&nbsp;I
finished the main game... i.e. got to the ending sequence... on
September 30th, but I've been going through the bonus levels and
the Dark World since then. <a href="http://supermeatboy.com/114/SMB_COMMENTARY_VIDEO_/#b">Here's a video commentary</a> of the whole
normal game.</p>

<p>This is a brilliant game. It's amazing how perfect the controls
are and how perfect the game just feels in general. There are very
very few ugly things about the game. The biggest annoyance for me
is that the replays are weird when you interact with things like
buttons on the level, because the effects you have on the world
aren't reflected in the replay. If that's the biggest problem with
the game, then it has no problems really.</p>

<p>Every level is a little exercise in gaining really tight muscle
memory and solving a little bit of a "puzzle". It's not really a
puzzle like a puzzle platformer, but a puzzle in the sense that
there is a specific way you have to traverse a level. For example,
using barriers to block the laser eye in a certain sequence,
etc. In essence, you aren't logically solving a puzzle as much as
you are gaining an intuitive understanding of some challenge and
then integrating it into your dexterous control of the Meat Boy. A
particularly memorable level is a boss fight where you race
another character. It's very neat and you don't need to have it
explained that you are racing, it's so obvious when you start.</p>

<p>The game is very hard and demanding, but it also very fair and
very very satisfying when you conquer a level. I thought it was
not as hard as N+... a game I really loved... on average, but
definitely on par and with some levels that are N+ hard or
harder. In particular, the ending levels are really really hard.</p>

<p>Something strange about the difficulty is that I would often have
more trouble at the beginning of a level than at the end. It
almost felt like the first part of a level was a new challenge,
whereas the last part of the level was just putting you through
some motions you'd done before.</p>

<p>I intend to 100% complete this game and do everything that is
possible on the XBLA release. It's an amazing game and definitely
goes in my canon.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
