<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Contra | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/contra/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-26T17:56:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Contra (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/25/Game--Contra--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/25/Game--Contra--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I played Contra on the Famicom.</p>

<p>I played for about an hour and got to the end of the third stage
reliably, but couldn't take care of the boss fast enough. I played
the Japanese version so I could use stage select and start from
the beginning of the level rather than the beginning of the
game. This effectively gives you infinite continues if you are
honest about not going past the point that you've gotten before. I
like infinite continue systems, provided the time in between
continue points is sufficient large. I feel like a lot of newer
games have such tiny checkpoint stretches that you can just plow
through. I realized that the reason I want to 1CC shmups is
because when you continue you start from exactly where you were
rather than the beginning of the level, so it feels really cheap
to do so.</p>

<p>After deciding to put it down for the day, I decided to play the
US version and use an infinite lives Game Genie code so I could
quickly play through the whole game and remember what all the
stages were like. (Since you begin a new life exactly where you
were, this allows you to plow through any problem.) It was nice to
remember what everything was like. The noises during the snow
stage were very memorable, as were the sounds of blowing up the
spiked walls in the factory.</p>

<p>This game is very tight and has a lot of friction, which is really
good, especially compared to some of the games that haven't stood
up very well. It's a solid game, but I think it has a few
problems. The major one is that it so wedded to the wrong arcade
sensibilities... namely cheap kills to get more
quarters. Nevertheless, this is definitely an optimal path through
most levels. For example, after a dozen or so tries, I could get
through the third stage without getting hit once. (Of course, the
boss trounced me.) I remember this game being great to play with a
friend, although in retrospect it has some bad co-op attributes:
you can kill your friend by scrolling the screen and you can too
easily steal their upgrade. Given these, I'm not sure I really
would want to play it with someone, because I wouldn't want to
make them mad.</p>

<p>Overall, I'm not sure I would play the game again or invest the
time to get past stage 3 honestly. The main reason is that it just
isn't a joy to play. It's fun, but it's not the giddy kind of fun
that a Mega Man 2 or Bayonetta is. It just isn't the
Ur-Run-n-Gun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
