<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wii | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/wii/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-10T23:35:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game tonight. The opening sequence is really cool,
especially after the battle when it pulls out and shows you how
people live on the two giant titans. It's such a cool concept.</p>

<p>The battle system I experienced during the walk to the first
village was incredibly reminiscent of FF12, but with a bit more
action on the part of the player. When I got to the town, it was
incredibly tempting to go and find all the glowing blue things
and get all the quests, etc. I can tell that it will be hard to
not make this game a giant collect-a-thon for myself.</p>

<p>I'm finding the mechanics a bit overwhelming. There are a lot of
different options about how to equip characters, so many quests,
so many different ways to buy things. It's very intimidating. I
think I will do the obvious thing until it hurts me rather than
trying to compute what the best solution will be.</p>

<p>I was amazed at how many different quests I unlocked so early,
though.</p>

<p>The voice acting in this game is actually really good. I almost
never like non-Japanese voice acting, because it is normally just
so horrendous. (Actually, now that I think about, Asura's Wrath
was pretty good.) Since the actors in this game are British,
there's something really fun and exotic about them. I like it.</p>

<p>I'm pretty excited to be playing this game. (One annoyance: I'm
using the Wii Pro controller. I hate having to have it plugged in
to the Wiimote that sits stupidly next to me on the couch.)</p>

<p>Total time: 1:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time... I considered restarting, but didn't and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He's really really hard. I've decided to put this as
"Scheduled" game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I'm kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for an hour and a half-ish. We beat the game! The
final boss and the last rocket sequence was pretty tough and my
wife was getting very frustrated, but we eventually did it.</p>

<p>The Nintendo Channel clocks our total time at 20 hours and 52
minutes (I haven't been keeping track of our game play that long.)</p>

<p>We decided that the game is a lot more sloppy in many ways
compared to NSMBW, but that we had a lot of fun, especially once
we got infinite lives. We don't love the game enough to try to get
all the bonuses to unlock the hidden temple, so that's that.</p>

<p>I like platformers, but I like playing games with my wife more.</p>

<p>Time: 7:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this in the morning and got to Great Tiger. I had a
tough time with Bear Hugger before I realized that I could duck
the Bear Hug. I only fought one round against Great Tiger, so I'm
just learning his patterns. It is interesting how this game is
almost, but not quite, identical to the NES version. There are
some things that are better and more convenient (like Saves and
Retry in the middle of a match) but other than that it's just
tweaked on the edges. It's cool.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for an hour and beat the first three levels of
World 8. There was a normal platforming level (although it had
lots of breaking platforms), then a rocket level, then a mine-cart
level. The rocket levels are so terrible because they are just
memorization mazes with an awful control scheme. It was
annoying. But eventually I got in the zone and did it. I think my
wife was a bit mad because she kept trying and dying every other
time.</p>

<p>Time: 6:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
