<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2008 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2008/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-12T19:30:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/12/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I plan on starting this game today. I thought I'd write about my
expectations before I played it.</p>

<p>Like Blue Dragon, I'd heard of and vaguely followed this game
before it came out. It's one of the first "next gen" games that
Square produced, so I thought that it might be cool. I've heard
that it has a very strange combat system. Most people who say this
mean it as a bad thing, but that sounds like a plus to me. I don't
really know anything about the story, but from what I do know it
sounds pretty different, which sounds like it could be good. I've
heard there are technical problems with laggyness and pop-in, but
that some of them go away if you install to the HDD. The laggyness
could be killer for me, but I don't really care about stuff like
pop-in, especially in slow paced games like RPGs.</p>

<p>I looked on HowLongToBeat and there are 6 playthroughs, all over
100 hours. That makes me nervous, because I'm skeptical of loving
the game that much and it suggests to me that it could be really
grind heavy, which would be terrible.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, I'm pretty excited about seeing what it is like.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/Game--N---X360--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/26/Game--N---X360--2008--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played Episode 41 Level 4 for almost an hour. Sometimes when I
play this game, I think to myself, "Wow, I hate this game's
controls so much." It is so frustrating that they never seem to
work right. Super Meat Boy has almost ruined every other
platformer for me. In fact, I'm so mad at the game right now, I am
demoting it from every two days to once a week.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Ponyo, directed by Hayao Miyazaki (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/25/Movie--Ponyo--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/25/Movie--Ponyo--directed-by-Hayao-Miyazaki--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My three year old loved this movie when he was two and it was on
Netflix. I think it is very cute and does a great job with the
visuals and in particular the expressiveness of the characters. I
think the kids act <em>just</em> like little kids. I don't like the plot
as much as other Miyazaki movies because almost nothing
happens. It's very meh. But it is still good because of how cool
the characters are.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--N---X360--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--N---X360--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Episode 40 Level 1 was pretty painful, but only 30 minutes
painful, not an hour painful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: N+ (X360, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/20/Game--N---X360--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/20/Game--N---X360--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing Episode 39 for over an hour. The majority of
that time was spent on level 1. My eyes hurt and I can't play
anymore. I'm going to take a break. Currently I am at
level 4. Phew!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
