<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2008 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2008/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-11T13:12:56-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: My Mom's New Boyfriend, starring Colin Hanks (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--My-Mom-s-New-Boyfriend--starring-Colin-Hanks--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--My-Mom-s-New-Boyfriend--starring-Colin-Hanks--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched about half of this movie with my parents. I missed the
beginning. It was pretty stupid with lots of very phoned-in
dialog and plot. In some ways it is like "This Means War", in terms
of what the basis of the jokes are. I don't think Meg Ryan can play
an insanely "hot" lady, although she's definitely good
looking. Selma Blair is great, but her "sexy" scene is really
forced. The finale at the museum is pretty clever, but overall I
can understand why it was direct-to-DVD.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea that the Muttations are really the tributes is
fascinating. The magic technology of the capital is pretty
interesting overall.</p>

<p>I finished the book today. As I said the other day, I find it to be
almost perfectly captured in the movie. That disappoints me a
little because I was hoping to learn more about the world from the
book.</p>

<p>I can't imagine how the other books could continue the style of
this one. The story can definitely move, there's no doubt about
that, but I'm not convinced that Collins could write a political
thriller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/26/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm disappointed the movie didn't use the plot-point about the
"traitor" that Katniss saw in the woods that time. It's a cool
idea.</p>

<p>I find there to be a lot more making out and conflict in Katniss
about Peeta in the book than the movie. But both are incredibly
sterile... I can't imagine the audience really being excited about
it.</p>

<p>Another point where the movie exceeds the book is that it shows
people outside the Arena reacting. It's very interesting. Collins
tries to do that by having Katniss imagine things, but it
definitely isn't as touching.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/25/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the first five chapters of this. The writing is quite better
than the Twilight series. Katniss has a strong voice that can pull
the story along well and keep your attention. The world is very
interesting, with not enough detail, but perhaps just enough.</p>

<p>I find it very strange that if the Capitol is "surrounded" by the
12 districts, and it is in the Rockies, but District 12 is in
Appalachia... i.e. very far away... how is it that only eight
thousand people live there and can all gather together in a single
public square? District 12 is the size of a small town in modern
America. It strains credulity to think that the world is so
sparsely populated and this place with so few people can really
have major starvation problems, but not be totally decimated by
them.</p>

<p>Katniss did say that there were some severe natural disasters at
some point in the past (at least 74 years) that led to the world
being like this, and at this point no information has been given
about the size of other districts, but I find it very difficult to
believe at this point.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin (DS, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my flight back I beat the rest of the missions. They were
really, really hard. Brutally hard. Especially the one where you
couldn't build any new units. It was rough. This game has a really
good difficulty management system... in the beginning it is pretty
tough, but do-able and then near the middle to end it is insane,
but it's all the same rules. It's cool.</p>

<p>The story is totally absurd. But whatever. =)</p>

<p>Total Time: 18:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
