<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-2-solid-snake/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-18T22:54:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake (PS2, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/05/Game--Metal-Gear-2--Solid-Snake--PS2--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Metal Gear 2: Solid Snake over the last
three or four days. I played the MSX2 version that comes with
Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence.</p>

<p>This game is the true prequel to Metal Gear Solid. The story is
explicitly a sequel, whereas the original Metal Gear is obviously
ret-con'd to be about the same stuff. The themes definitely
originate here: the pacifism is so much more clear. The gameplay
gets a whole lot deeper in this game with the radar, the guards
hearing you, etc. There are very direct callbacks to this game in
later entries in the series---such as climatic fist fights.</p>

<p>This was an amazing game. I initially found it much harder than
the first one because the guards are so much more perceptive and
the first area is a tightly confined space, but as I played I got
a lot better. Also, it is harder to be glutted with ammo and
rations, but you definitely get to that point by the end of the
game. I was initially confused and annoyed about when you were
allowed to save, but then I realized it was on area transitions
(when there was a loading screen) and so I was able to use that to
my advantage when I was going to a place I was scared of.</p>

<p>Here are my play-through stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 4:59:44
Save: 27
Continue: 17
Alert Mode: 117
Humans Killed: 246
Ration Used: 7
Special Item: Not Used
Code Name: Zebra</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
