<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear Solid 4 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-solid-4/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-07T22:16:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 4 (PS3, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-4--PS3--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/08/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-4--PS3--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid 4 from the 25th to late last
night (although, I had a break from the 30th to the 6th.)</p>

<p>First, some stats about my play through. I played on Big Boss
Hard---the hardest difficulty available when you first turn it on,
but not the hardest overall. I chose this difficulty because there
was no "Game Over if Spotted" mode, so I thought by making combat
more lethal it would force more stealth. I think that worked
out.</p>

<p>After each of the five Acts, the game gives you stats, which I
wrote down:</p>

<p>Act 1:
Total Play Time: 03:48:51
Continues: 9
Alert Phases: 29
Kills: 0
Recovery Items Used: 14
Current Drebin Points: 76,710DP</p>

<p>You'll notice that I didn't make any kills in this act (or, in
fact, in the entire game.) I'm proud of that. I had more alerts in
this act than any other. I think that's attributed to getting used
to the game, rather than its difficulty.</p>

<p>Act 2:
Total Play Time: 07:52:10 (4 hours more)
Continues: 12 (3 more)
Alert Phases: 53 (24 more)
Kills: 0
Recovery Items Used: 28 (14 more)
Current Drebin Points: 66,811DP</p>

<p>I ended with fewer Drebin points because I bought the tranquilizer
sniper rifle. I used less continues on this act. It also took
about the same amount of time time.</p>

<p>Act 3:
Total Play Time: 11:43:25 (~4 hours more)
Continues: 17 (5 more)
Alert Phases: 63 (10 more)
Kills: 0
Recovery Items Used: 34 (6 more)
Current Drebin Points: 66,741DP</p>

<p>I think I bought a shotgun or something.</p>

<p>Act 4:
Total Play Time: 16:10:38 (~4.5 hours more)
Continues: 31 (14 more)
Alert Phases: 81 (18 more)
Kills: 0
Recovery Items Used: 64 (30 more)
Current Drebin Points: 153,021DP</p>

<p>At this point, I stopped needing money that much. I used more
healing items in this act than any other. I think the main
offender was the unmanned vehicles that take out a whole life bar
on a melee attack.</p>

<p>Act 5:
Total Play Time: 20:53:19 (~4.5 hours more)
Continues: 46 (15 more)
Alert Phases: 89 (8 more)
Kills: 0
Recovery Items Used: 81 (17 more)
Weapon Types Procured: 37
Flashbacks Watched: 214
Special Items Used: Not Used
Current Drebin Points: 332,947DP
Code Name: "Pigeon"
Other titles: Inchworm, Hyena, Pig, Leopard</p>

<p>I used more continues in the final stage than any other.</p>

<p>One of my general comments about the game is that it is very
similar, structurally, to MGS3 where there is a tight, linear act
structure. However, MGS3 was better in a sense by making
everything feel much more connected. In exchange, however, MGS4
makes the globe-trotting incredibly epic, which is nice.</p>

<p>In the department of gameplay, I found the two trailing sequences
to be REALLY fun. There are many things in Metal Gear that make me
think you could build a whole game around one of the parts. I
thought that the fight with Vamp was very frustrating because I
couldn't grab him well. However, after getting to that point so
many times, on my final fight, he didn't hit me a single time. The
final battle was similar: the gameplay was so drastically
different it was very annoying to have it so difficult and
different at a crucial time, but on my last try, I didn't get hit
at all. (Pro Tip: Trap him against a wall.)</p>

<p>In the story department, this game is a winner.</p>

<p>All the scenes with Raiden are really cool.</p>

<p>The many reveals (especially in Europe) are really cool,
especially after having played the other games so recently.</p>

<p>The scene where Liquid triumphs is hilariously well acted.</p>

<p>There are many funny throw-back jokes. For example, Otacon tells
Snake to switch discs when going into the building he had to do
that in on the PS1. Also, during the Mantis fight, there are many
funny references (especially on the codec) to past
games. Brilliant.</p>

<p>I found the story behind the beauties to be very sad, and
tragic.</p>

<p>The scene between Johnny and Meryl is great.</p>

<p>my wife's comment: People's butts in this game look weird.</p>

<p>In a conversation at the end, someone says that Snake will no
longer be anyone's toy. I feel like this was a reference to him
not being in any more games.</p>

<p>The credits music is beautiful.</p>

<p>It took about 90 minutes after beating the last boss for the game
to be done. I stayed up toooo late.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 4 (PS3, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-4--PS3--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2008/09/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-4--PS3--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played it the first time with my shiny new PS3</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
