<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Fallout 3 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/fallout-3/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-02T00:07:45-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Fallout 3 (X360, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/09/Game--Fallout-3--X360--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-02-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/02/09/Game--Fallout-3--X360--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past month I've been playing /Fallout 3: Game of the
Year Edition/ (it comes with all the DLC.) This is the first
Western-style RPG I've ever played.</p>

<p>I started out on my own and played about 7 hours. I noticed
pretty quickly that there were many things that I was missing,
both from the perspective of loot and from the perspective of
quests and story events. So, I stopped and restarted and used a
spoiler-free walkthrough. I felt really dirty doing this. In
retrospect, I would have really disliked playing it again and
would have felt like I was cheated out of getting the full
experience if not for the walkthrough.</p>

<p>I thought that the VATS combat system was really fun, but after
about 20 hours of trying to figure out how to target the head, it
got really frustrating or boring, depending on if it was working
or not. I thought the story was interesting, but there were
interface problems that really hurt experiencing it. First, much
of the story and background is told through text, but the text
display is not designed to be read from a couch: it is green text
on black background that is deliberately fuzzy to simulate the
terminal it is being read on /plus/ it doesn't use the
whole screen because of the simulation. /Very annoying./ In
fact, so annoying, that I simply stopped reading text after a
about 20 hours. The background was interesting, but not
interesting enough to suffer through the bad interface.</p>

<p>That's a good description of the game for me: good ideas that
take too long or are presented to poorly to sustain the fun. I
completed every single quest and got to level 29 and about 50% of
the way to level 30. Yet, I don't want to finish all the
achievements, get all the Bobbleheads, or explore every area
because I know that it will be frustrating and boring. I spent
59.75 hours on the game but don't want to spend a minute
more. That says a lot about the game to me. Yet, I don't regret it
and would recommend it, although perhaps on the PC where your face
would be closer to the screen.</p>

<p>There were numerous technical problems as well. It crashed
about a half-dozen times. After about 30 hours it would regularly
get very slow. I got stuck in walls, in debris, on train tracks,
etc and had to restart and lose progress. I had quests get into
stuck states and had to restart.</p>

<p>Most of the DLC was quite good. The Pitt was dumb. Operation
Anchorage was boring. But Broken Steel and Point Lookout were
great. Mothership Zeta was borderline, but the loot was pretty
awesome.</p>

<p>I don't think I will play older Bethesda games because there
were so many technical and UI problems, but I will keep an eye out
for future releases.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
