<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Wonder Boy in Monster Land | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/wonder-boy-in-monster-land/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T15:43:44-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy in Monster Land (SMS, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour today. I used an emulator and
couldn't resist save states. In the beginning, I worked my way
through on my own, using saves at each screen. I had no sense of
what the items would do, so I didn't really buy any. After a
while, I looked at a walkthrough (which basically just recommended
which items to buy) and learned that I missed a few essential
hidden items. I restarted and made it to stage 4 following the
guide. I went away to eat, paused, and when I came back, the game
had reset itself.</p>

<p>This game looks and sounds really good, especially for its
age. It's cute and has some interesting mechanics. I think of it
as a lot like Zelda 2, but with a less interesting combat system,
sloppier mechanics, and a more advanced inventory system. I found
the jumps to feel really wrong and the combat delays to be pretty
painful. The inventory system, once you realize what things are,
is neat.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that this is a pretty amazing game for its age,
but that a lot about it works against it. The biggest problem is
the lack of continues. The game is too deep on a customization
level to make sense as an arcade game. I presume that later
version of the game change this, because they were designed for
consoles. Secondly, the sprites are a bit too big and they make
it hard to see what's going on. Third, the jumps and fighting
don't feel quite right.</p>

<p>I won't play this, but I'm excited to investigate other games in
this series.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
