<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Legend of Zelda (First Quest) | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/the-legend-of-zelda-first-quest-/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-29T22:03:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda (First Quest) (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/07/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--First-Quest---NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/07/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--First-Quest---NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played The Legend of Zelda on my AV Famicom with a RetroZone
PowerPak. It was awesome.</p>

<p>I started on Monday and played for about an hour while the <em>REDACTED</em>
was asleep. I got to the 2nd Dungeon, but got my butt kicked
pretty bad. I played yesterday and spent a lot of time in the
beginning crawling the map buying everything and finding all the
heart containers I could, then I got up to the 6th Dungeon in a
few hours. Today, I took it the rest of the way. I found the 6th
Dungeon to be very hard. I was able to complete the last dungeon
with two visits: the first one got me all the items and got me
familiar with the layout, but when I got to Ganon, I died, because
I only had 3 lives and no potions. I refilled hearts, potions, etc
and then went back and beat Ganon on my first (real) try---I only
used one potion too.</p>

<p>I tried to limit myself to the information in the Nintendo Power
archive I had, although I used Google at least once to find out
why I couldn't shoot arrows (they consume money.)</p>

<p>It was very nostalgic to play, because I remember playing this a
lot when I was a kid (although I don't remember ever beating it, I
do remember getting to Ganon.) My strongest memories of playing
the game are the first three dungeons. But stronger than memories
of playing it are memories of reading the manual and looking at
the map my dad made while he or my brother played. My mom says
that before I could read or play well, I would tell Joe what to do
by looking at my dad's map.</p>

<p>I remember thinking it was really hard when I was a kid. It is
definitely difficult---much more so than modern Zelda games---but
I found it pretty straightforward to get good at. It wasn't
crushingly hard like most people say NES games were.</p>

<p>I'm very glad I played this again. I intend to do the Second Quest
in a few months or something.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
