<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Final Fantasy 13 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/final-fantasy-13/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T22:08:25-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 (PS3, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/10/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/10/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to play through Final Fantasy 13 again in preparation
for Final Fantasy 13-2's release.</p>

<p>I started on 2011/11/26 and finished on 2012/01/09 and played it
basically every day. I intended to just critical path the story
and not do any side quests or grinding of any kind. I kept that up
until the final boss area. It took 23 hours (23:15) to get to Gran
Pulse, about 12 hours (34:40) to get through Pulse and then 3
hours (38:45) to get to the final area. At that point I decided
that I would get all the achievements, so I grinded for 30 hours
(64:30), then did side quests for about 9 hours (73:45), then
grinded a bit more (77:57), then beat the game (79:56), and then
finished the remaining side quests and trophies (88:54). It was
interesting that this was the same amount of time as the last time
I played through and didn't get everything.</p>

<p>Playing through the second time really solidified for me how
awesome this game is. It does an amazing job at making the combat
section action-packed and skill based. I remember being totally
destroyed by a few bosses the first time through the game; and
this time even though I was less powerful after I was beat once, I
could re-orient my strategy based on a better understanding of the
mechanics and conquer it.</p>

<p>I still think there are some improvements that could be made. I
noticed that the voice acting throughout Pulse is much worse than
the rest of the voice acting. I was bugged by how important
position was in combat, even though you can't really influence
it. I was also re-convinced that the game is way too stingy on
money and experience.</p>

<p>But nevertheless, it was amazing and it definitely enters the FF
canon for me. I look forward to the next one with great
anticipation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 (PS3, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/26/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-26T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/26/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Started for the second time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 (PS3, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/01/09/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/01/09/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finished for the second time</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/14/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/14/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played Final Fantasy 13 for another 26 hours (making 88
total.) I got all the trophies except the incredibly tedious ones
(getting all other trophies, getting all items, getting 5 stars on
every mission, and beating a Long Gui.) This made me almost hate
this game.</p>

<p>The post-game is much more tedious than previous games. Completing
all the missions was very fun, but the grinding for money was
horrible. I did enough to get 4 Ultimate Weapons and max out 2 of
them. I see no justification for how stingy the game is.</p>

<p>I would've much /much/ rather played the main game in a New Game
Plus mode with higher money drop rates so I could re-view the
story and work through getting all the items.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/03/28/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/03/28/Game--Final-Fantasy-13--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this post, I will "respond" to articles on the Internet about
FF13. I've been delaying reading any until after I beat, so I
think now is the appropriate time. I will do my best to not be a
rabid fan boy about it. My goal is to capture my reactions to new
ideas I read elsewhere, rather than to argue anyone who disagrees
with my preferences.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p=630">Tim Rogers</a>. This review is hilarious, as all his are. (He curses a
lot by the way.) Here's a great quote: "The idea of the game is
that the characters all look like people who someone would want to
cosplay; they all act like characters who would be someone’s
favorite character." His discussion of the battle system is spot
on. I suppose the big difference is that I love it and he
doesn't. Same with launching enemies into the air. Here's
something that is quite true:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>The battles will sometimes envelop you in<br/>sometimes ten entire minutes of grueling uphill climbing, forcing<br/>you to know that you’re doing something wrong. You pray for a<br/>zero-star ranking, for there to be some obvious “right way” to do<br/>this. Then the game gives you a five-star ranking, and your heart<br/>sinks: oh god, you are doing it the right way.</p></blockquote></p>

<p>Just read his comment about the monsters not looking like
anything. That's true and its always been that way. I'm totally in
his "that's the way things are" camp.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.destructoid.com/review-final-fantasy-xiii-167136.phtml">Jim Sterling</a>. "If you're a hardcore Final Fantasy XIII fan, prone
to emotional outburts and so defensive of Square Enix's latest
effort that you'll get upset by harsh criticism, then you're
advised to not read this review. If you don't want to see somebody
tear this game limb from limb, or are upset by videogame review in
general, then you should definitely not read it." I can see why
someone would be upset at his review, but I'm not in the
least. <a href="http://www.destructoid.com/the-joys-of-being-a-videogame-reviewer-167383.phtml">I'm amazed at how people react to him</a>.</p>

<p>I read a bunch of other reviews but didn't really feel like
commenting on any of them.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/4304/the_mind_and_heart_of_final_.php">Here's an interesting interview with Motomu Toriyama.</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
