<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: MAME | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/mame/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-01T19:15:01-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Top Hunter - Roddy & Cathy (MAME, 1994)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/14/Game--Top-Hunter---Roddy---Cathy--MAME--1994--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/14/Game--Top-Hunter---Roddy---Cathy--MAME--1994--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Top Hunter: Roddy &amp; Cathy. I found out about
the game through <a href="http://www.racketboy.com/retro/2007/02/best-undiscovered-neo-geo-games.html">Racketboy's Undiscovered Neo-Geo Games</a> list.</p>

<p>The game is a side-scrolling action game with two planes of
movement. You can jump from one plane to the other and most of the
action in the game revolves around quickly and accurately getting
on the correct plane. Even though there is jumping, this isn't
really a platforming game, because it stays on one path mostly and
there are rarely obstacles to jump over. There are four
worlds---each with two levels, one mid-boss, and one main boss;
followed by a final level with only a boss---which is actually a
six boss rush.</p>

<p>There are some interesting mechanics in the game. You can grab
things from a distance by stretching your arm. This allows you to
grab things from far away, as well as punch from a distance. Most
of the "puzzles" are about doing this effectively. There is a very
low time limit on the game and there are items that allow increase
it by 5, 10, or 20 seconds. I thought this would be stressful, but
I didn't notice it at all. (That might have been because I
credit-fed.)</p>

<p>The animation is not nearly as good as Metal Slug, but it is
decent. There is a little bit of quirkiness. For example, there is
a funny animal in the final stage... the enemies will often wave
white flags at you... etc. There are some good details too: for
example, most vehicles are destructible and you can throw their
parts at the enemies once they are destroyed.</p>

<p>Overall, the game had a very basic and repetitive design. Most of
the enemies and bosses were dealt with in the same way. I didn't
feel it was very deep. I could imagine feeling it was a bit deeper
if I restricted my credit usage. I would typically use 2 on a boss
and .5 on a level. I assume that most of the challenge of getting
credit usage down would be very much luck: enemies hit for a
lot.</p>

<p>I played through it in under an hour. I'd say it was worth
it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Slug 1 (MAME, 1996)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/22/Game--Metal-Slug-1--MAME--1996--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/22/Game--Metal-Slug-1--MAME--1996--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last night I played through Metal Slug for the Neo-Geo. I didn't
do very well: I got 508k points and used 28 continues. Ouch. It
was really fun though. The graphics in this game are /amazing/! I
have a hard time thinking of a modern game that is as
beautiful. The only real problem with the game is that shooting
diagonally is a big pain, but I probably just need practice. I
can't wait to play it again or play sequels!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
