<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/hot-shots-golf-world-invitational/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-13T22:21:22-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about half an hour and did 3-5. I ended in 4th place
on Easy. The game is getting hard. I wonder if Pancho is just not
a good character because of his bad control?</p>

<p>Total time: 10:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/29/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today. I'm trying to beat the Pro VS
match. I tried first and the match lasted 15 minutes and I
ultimately lost after a good run of wins. I decided to try "Easy
Mode" to see how easy it was... and I lost twice and then won,
but failed on 3-5 twice. Easy doesn't really seem that much
easier and it's not worth having the green medal on the score
icon. I feel like I'm at a bit of a wall in this game and should
play it a lot less.</p>

<p>I'm going to schedule it for a weekly session on Sunday morning.</p>

<p>Total time: 9:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/28/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for an hour and half this morning. I got stars in every
beginner event. I did 1-5 as Chang and I beat Isabella in Sudden
Death on the third hole. It was very intense. Also, in 1-5 I got
a crown. I haven't figured out how to find out what will give you
a crown though. Everything seemed a lot easier with Change
because he had so much power, but it also seems like the
characters aren't really supposed to be better than one-another,
but just represent different play styles. I'm not sure.</p>

<p>In the evening, I played all night while chatting and burping my
new baby. I got stars up to 3-4 and did the Pro VS match twice. In
the first one, I lost after just a few holes and in the second I
had her tied until the second to last hole, then lost by one
stroke in the last. Ouch. It's a very fun game. But I might be
playing too much :/</p>

<p>Total time: 9:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for two and three quarter hours. I got stars in
1-1, 1-2, and 1-3. The game is very fun and I like the abstract
way it presents golf. I feel like I know nothing about golf, but
that I can do the game pretty well and have fun. One thing I
don't like though is that golf punishes mistakes soooo
heavily. Basically one mistake can cause you to get two or three
strokes behind and then you'll never get back. I went from being
1st in 1-4 to 13th in one hole and then ended in 19th because I
made another single mistake. It is brutal.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for like 20 minutes. I've never played at Hot Shots
Golf game before, but I've been curious. The PS Vita bundle I
bought came with it, so I figured, what the heck. I played two
holes as Yuna. It was kind of fun.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
