<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Asura's Wrath | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/asura-s-wrath/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-08T09:45:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/07/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I think I'm basically at
the end of the game. It was cool to play as Yasha at first,
although I was kind of disappointed I didn't get to play as
Berserker Asura. This game is totally nuts. Today I decided that
Deus looks like Ganon from Twilight Princess. Also, I think that
something I enjoy about this is how it is a lot like Bayonetta in
terms of its style and craziness. If only the action were as good
as Bayonetta, that would be awesome. But as it stands, the style
of the game is a really great substitute.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/06/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for two hours tonight and got to 11.5. There were so
many absurd moments. I loved how Asura flew by punching the
ground and riding the shock wave. I loved the onsen sequence and
how Asura was denied. I loved how Augus and Asura are
inexplicably on the moon and how ridiculously huge Augus' sword
is (and how he's never drawn it but once). I loved the gigantic
crater from the sword and how Asura always ends up with no
arms. It's also very intriguing that Augus was robot-y too. What
could that mean?</p>

<p>Total time: 4:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed my wife the awesome Wyzen fight and then did the next
two episodes. The "ending" was cool and the awesome arm-less
fight. This game is just sooo ridiculous. I can tell my wife is
kind of appalled at how insane it is. I love that about it.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game on the recommendation of the Giant Bomb
podcast. Tonight I played for a little less than two hours and
played through the first five episodes. This game is insane. I
love the over-the-top-ness. I love the TV show stylings. The
combat and shooting feel interesting and like I'm doing something,
although I get the impression that I can't lose and it's just a
matter of smashing enough until I can Burst, although I suppose I
could simply pay attention to my score at the end. So far, I think
it's a really unique and amazing experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
