<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Xenoblade Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/xenoblade-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T22:08:25-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I ended just before the final cut-off point to the final
bosses and end of the game. I finished the game today in about an
hour. Today as I started to play, I left the title screen on for a
while... it was very beautiful as the time of day changed.</p>

<p>I thought the end of the game was fun and crazy. It was so
incredibly Evangelion and so classically Japanese, like I said
before, but even more so given the ending---everyone you thought
was good is actually bad and everyone that was bad is really good,
and all that. I especially liked walking around in space and the
origin story given to Zanza. It was also neat how Dickson ended
up.</p>

<p>Total time: 26:36</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>In the end, I feel like this was a really interesting story and
world, but a pretty terrible game. The mechanics were just very
shallow and boring, lacking in meaningful choices. I think you
could do something with the concepts in the combat system, but
they didn't really do it. One thing that I reckon WoW does that
this game lacks is that because you need to assemble large groups
with varied skills, there is an interesting meta-process of doing
that, but it is still ultimately boring for the individual
players.</p>

<p>I heard so much about how amazing this game was and how it was so
great that Japanese developers were learning from the West, but I
feel like all the Western ideas here are bad ideas that I don't
want to see more of.</p>

<p>I really disliked that every item changed your appearance because
it was hard to look consistent while having the best
stats. Everyone just looked so stupid generally.</p>

<p>The interface was pretty terrible because it took so many clicks
to do everything and the buttons were reversed from what they
should be on the controller. Ugh.</p>

<p>I don't think I can really recommend this game... maybe I would
just recommend watching some videos and reading about the story,
but I found the mechanics to be unbearably weak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like four hours tonight. The ending of this game is
classic Japanese insanity where you fight God and conquer your
fate. The changing alliances and what not at the end of the game
are pretty crazy too. I like a lot of what went on and it is very
intriguing in its Evangelion-ness. Some of the boss battles are
getting to be very tedious slog fests.</p>

<p>Total time: 25:32</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play for like two hours this morning to entertain my kids so my
wife could sleep in. It was very interesting to be down on the
Mechonis foot and get to know what happened to Fiora. Her outfits
look very cool... very similar to KOS-MOS. Dickson is ridiculous
in his ability to be everyone instantly, despite being a level 25
NPC.</p>

<p>Later in the day, we played for another hour and had an epic fight
then went on a dumb fetch quest to get bomb parts. We played again
for just thirty minutes and did a little exploring, before
watching the first war scene and calling it quits for the night.</p>

<p>Total time: 21:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like three hours tonight. There's been lots of crazy
reveals in the game, some that have been obvious for a long time
and others that were just cool. Getting on to Mechonis was
awesome. It was crazy to see the new map screen. Rad.</p>

<p>Some of the main-line fetch quests in this game are absurd. You
walk through an area and then get to the end are given a fetch
quest where you walk all the way back across the area. It's
totally insane.</p>

<p>Total time: 18:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours tonight. I got to the gate of Prison
Island. The whole High Entia concept is pretty cool... especially
that there is this giant civilization that's totally disconnected
from others beneath it on the monster. The message at the Tomb was
very interesting too... I wonder what the ancestor's plans were
regarding the genetic destiny of their people?</p>

<p>I really enjoyed seeing the waterfall in the forest. It was very
magnificent. My son was very impressed too.</p>

<p>Exploring the Entia capital was very confusing because the arrow
points in the direction of the destination, not the teleporter
that you have to use to get to it. It was very confusing. When I
was exploring these big empty places with very same-y textures and
models, it made me think how much this game is like mid to late
PS2 games in terms of what it tries to do technically. Rather than
having detailed environments, it often has very large environments
with big draw distances as a way to show, for example.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
