<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Xenoblade Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/xenoblade-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-10T23:35:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game tonight. The opening sequence is really cool,
especially after the battle when it pulls out and shows you how
people live on the two giant titans. It's such a cool concept.</p>

<p>The battle system I experienced during the walk to the first
village was incredibly reminiscent of FF12, but with a bit more
action on the part of the player. When I got to the town, it was
incredibly tempting to go and find all the glowing blue things
and get all the quests, etc. I can tell that it will be hard to
not make this game a giant collect-a-thon for myself.</p>

<p>I'm finding the mechanics a bit overwhelming. There are a lot of
different options about how to equip characters, so many quests,
so many different ways to buy things. It's very intimidating. I
think I will do the obvious thing until it hurts me rather than
trying to compute what the best solution will be.</p>

<p>I was amazed at how many different quests I unlocked so early,
though.</p>

<p>The voice acting in this game is actually really good. I almost
never like non-Japanese voice acting, because it is normally just
so horrendous. (Actually, now that I think about, Asura's Wrath
was pretty good.) Since the actors in this game are British,
there's something really fun and exotic about them. I like it.</p>

<p>I'm pretty excited to be playing this game. (One annoyance: I'm
using the Wii Pro controller. I hate having to have it plugged in
to the Wiimote that sits stupidly next to me on the couch.)</p>

<p>Total time: 1:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
