<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Xenoblade Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/xenoblade-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-13T23:20:21-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/13/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I did a lot of exploring and
got into the mines. I've decided that the game play in this really
sucks:</p>

<p>Basically the only task that you do in combat as a player is
click on the 8 buttons for the different skills. There's no real
reason to do any skill at any particular time, because status
effects will either stack or not and by the time one runs out,
you can just cast it again. So basically, everyone combat starts
by clicking everything and then waiting until you can click them
all again in sequence. Occasionally you have to remember to use
Enchant when you're fighting Mechon and to move around a little
after killing each enemy so you're in range, but you really don't
need to give any of it much more thought than that. I can tell
that no more strategy is required because I can basically walk
through the game up to this point, doing this strategy, and
winning basically every fight. I've only lost if I got into a
fight that was way over level or I was too close to two groups of
enemies and they joined together. It's very uninteresting.</p>

<p>Outside of combat, there also isn't that much to do because each
character basically only has 10 or so abilities and they are all
so meh and I can't imagine really caring one way or another about
why you'd pick one versus the other.</p>

<p>I can't really understand why a lot of people gave this game such
high reviews. It pales in comparison to other RPGs like FF13 or
Lost Odyssey, where there are actually interesting choices to
make in combat. I've read so much that the game is so good
because it takes (presumably "good") Western ideas and mixes them
with Japanese design. Man, this Western design, if it means the
combat system, is total junk. I've read that it's very similar to
WoW... now I'm sure I wouldn't like WoW.</p>

<p>I've tried to think of why I feel like it's different than FF12,
which was very MMO-ish. I think the reason why it is different is
the Gambits. Basically in FF12, Gambits automated what the player
is "doing" in Xenoblade. Since that was necessarily going on, the
game was free to through bigger challenges on top of those and
have lots of split second usage of the special moves, which
constituted a really large set. In Xenoblade, you never feel like
you died because of lack of strategy, you feel like you died
because of stupid AI or not enough grinding. Whereas in FF12, I
could die, gain some knowledge from the experience, restart and
immediately win the battle, because I knew something I didn't
know before. With Xenoblade (so far), the only reason you didn't
grind enough or you fell asleep with an active fight.</p>

<p>Xenoblade has caused me to think about RPG combat systems at the
meta-level a bit. In Xeno, you have 8 skills, each with separate
cool-downs, so basically every 30 seconds you are using skill A
and since you can spawn so many at once, basically, there are
little bursts of doing a lot of skills followed by waiting around
for the skills to be reusable. In contrast, in a traditional
JRPG, there are about 30 or 40 skills (i.e. magic spells,
summons, attack techniques, etc) plus items. Each skill has a
cost of some kind so you can't always choose it (summons are once
per battle, items are limited, spells use MP, etc.) But you can
only do one action every 5 seconds when your turn comes up. Since
every character is on their own timer and the enemies are acting
to. There is always one thing happening and you can always pay
attention to it (if it is a player, you're picking it, and if it
is an enemy, you're thinking about how to respond.) In contrast,
with Xeno, there's a lot going at once so you can't pay attention
and the decisions that you make are basically non-existent. Once
you choose the initial skill order, there's no reason to do
anything except use the skills again once they cool down. All
strategy takes place in the first few seconds and then you're
just doing a rote execution. In addition, the number of skills in
the traditional JRPG makes it so the solution space is much large
so it can more difficult to plan. (For example, you have the
elemental affinities, healing spells, buffs, etc.)</p>

<p>Xenoblade is just a really boring game combat-wise and the
meta-game is very tedious and/or confusing. I'm really let down
by this because the game was so hyped.</p>

<p>However, I'm incredibly compelled by the world and the story. It's
so strange and interesting. I want to play the game just to
experience that, provided it won't cost 50 hours. I wonder if I
can easily speed my way through the game without any grinding or
BS and if I'll be able to bear it long enough.</p>

<p>This conclusion makes most nervous about Last Story which I have
been equally (actually /more/ hyped about.) We'll see.</p>

<p>Total time: 9:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/12/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/12/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p%3D2597">This action button review</a> of the game captures my feelings about a
lot of the system-overload this game throws at you so early and
the sheer weight of the quests. The comment about the difference
between abilities and skills is very apt---I have no clue what's
going on in that system. Something related is that for a lot of
the game so far I've been killing every enemy in my path, but then
I noticed that a lot of the enemies are just giving me 1 or 2
EXP... what's the point of that? But there doesn't seem to be a
good way to tell what is going to be a good amount of EXP before
hand. It's a bit confusing.</p>

<p>Today, I played for a little over three hours. I advanced the
story quite a bit. I was really annoyed by the lack of a feeling
of progress behind all the numbers. I repeatedly tried to get
past a little path that was blocked by enemies and I seemed to be
dying with no explanation.</p>

<p>I went back to the gem guy to create a whole bunch of gems, but I
don't really know if they are really all that good or if I
shouldn't have spent them all, because I have a lot of gems now
and not enough places to put them.</p>

<p>I'm really conflicted about the battle system. In some ways, it's
no different than a traditional FF or DQ game, because you
generally attack and then use special attacks when you have
enough energy to. But on the other hand, it feels like a lot of
meaningful decision is taken from you. For example, there's an
air of strategy in your positioning, but with huge crowds of
enemies it is so hard to see where you are, where their face is,
etc that being in the front/back/side is almost irrelevant
because you can't reliably tell. The whole
Monado-tells-the-future system being integrated into the combat
is really remarkable and unique. I'm not yet to the point though
where the vision really does me any good because I don't
understand how it is supposed to be canceled.</p>

<p>Basically, at this point, I find the whole game to be really
confusing in the mechanic department. There's a lot that I can do
and I'm treating it like a traditional JRPG, but I feel like I'm
missing something when I do, but I'm not really being punished
for ignoring it, but I'm constantly being flirted with by all
these other weird numbers and concepts. It's just a really
strange game.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. I have a few thoughts
about my experiences tonight...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The controls are really annoying. It is very weird that A is
the confirm button on the Wii Pro controller, because it is in
the cancel spot. There should have been a way to change.</p></li>
<li><p>The user interface is really painful. There's a big loading
time to do everything. The equipment management system is
really annoying---you can't equip from a shop and when you
change equipment, the gems don't automatically get unequipped
and I haven't found a way to remove them other than putting the
thing back on and removing it from there. It's really
painful. The quick travel system is really slow too because you
have to go so deep in the menus.</p></li>
<li><p>I'm amazed that the killed off what seemed like a main
character after giving you the opportunity to spend /a lot/ of
money on her to give a special bikini outfit. I didn't realize
it would be a wasted expense.</p></li>
<li><p>The graphics are quite good for some Wii games, but feel really
bad in other ways. I think this is most noticeable when they
show faces, because they are totally flat. The environments are
really beautifully constructed and I love how open they are.</p></li>
<li><p>The combat system is pretty interesting. I still don't feel
like I totally understand all my choices, but I have a bit of a
technique worked out that is being useful so far.</p></li>
<li><p>The story is pretty compelling and the world is very bizarre
and fascinating for it.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Total time: 4:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game tonight. The opening sequence is really cool,
especially after the battle when it pulls out and shows you how
people live on the two giant titans. It's such a cool concept.</p>

<p>The battle system I experienced during the walk to the first
village was incredibly reminiscent of FF12, but with a bit more
action on the part of the player. When I got to the town, it was
incredibly tempting to go and find all the glowing blue things
and get all the quests, etc. I can tell that it will be hard to
not make this game a giant collect-a-thon for myself.</p>

<p>I'm finding the mechanics a bit overwhelming. There are a lot of
different options about how to equip characters, so many quests,
so many different ways to buy things. It's very intimidating. I
think I will do the obvious thing until it hurts me rather than
trying to compute what the best solution will be.</p>

<p>I was amazed at how many different quests I unlocked so early,
though.</p>

<p>The voice acting in this game is actually really good. I almost
never like non-Japanese voice acting, because it is normally just
so horrendous. (Actually, now that I think about, Asura's Wrath
was pretty good.) Since the actors in this game are British,
there's something really fun and exotic about them. I like it.</p>

<p>I'm pretty excited to be playing this game. (One annoyance: I'm
using the Wii Pro controller. I hate having to have it plugged in
to the Wiimote that sits stupidly next to me on the couch.)</p>

<p>Total time: 1:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
