<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mario and Luigi: Partners in Time | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/mario-and-luigi-partners-in-time/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-28T22:44:39-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mario and Luigi: Partners in Time (DS, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/16/Game--Mario-and-Luigi--Partners-in-Time--DS--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/16/Game--Mario-and-Luigi--Partners-in-Time--DS--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played Mario &amp; Luigi: Partners in Time for the DS.</p>

<p>Ever since Super Mario RPG, I've liked the idea of a Mario-based
RPG, especially because of the action-based combat. I played Super
Paper Mario when I first got a Wii and enjoyed it a lot, but I
hadn't played any of the portable Mario and Luigi games. I heard a
lot of good things about Bowser's Inside Story, so I decided to
play this game in preparation.</p>

<p>Overall, I found the game to be very enjoyable, but with a few
big flaws.</p>

<p>First, the dialogue is hilarious and ridiculous. There were many
times when I stopped, found my wife, and told her some of the great
lines. Second, the battle system was initially extremely
fun. Fighting each different enemy actually /feels/ different, as
opposed to a traditional turn-based RPG where you may use
different strategies, but what you're doing feels the same. I'm
very impressed that they were able to do that.</p>

<p>I was not excellent at avoiding the enemies' attacks (you can
counter or dodge basically every attack against you), so I got
hammered a lot. This made me notice that average monsters would do
damage equal to about a third of your total health on every
attack. Since the players are normally out-numbered, this meant
that you could be KO'd in a single round on almost every battle if
you didn't dodge. I don't think I was under-leveled, because I was
able to get so far in the game. This was really obnoxious to me,
because I didn't feel it fit the light-hearted tone of the game
and there were not very good ways to practice. (For example, it
takes about 2 minutes to get back into a fight after dying,
quitting, loading, etc; and I never found any "Heart Blocks" next
to a field where monsters were.)</p>

<p>A related problem was that it seemed like monsters had
extremely high health counters. For example, near when I quit, I
would regularly fight groups of 4 or 5 monsters, each with 170 HP
and I was able to do about 31 HP of damage each round with each
character. Each battle took almost 13 rounds---and that's only if
I was able to dodge every attack and not have to heal. I don't
think I'm that bad at games, so I find it easier to blame the
game.</p>

<p>The problem, however, is probably that after about 6 or 7
hours, I got really tired of the incredibly long and frustrating
battles, so I tried to avoid them as much as possible. I---as a
hardened RPG player---should have known better. If you avoid
combat, then you won't level as much, so you won't be able to
compete against bosses and other enemies, which spawns more
dodging, but now for necessity, etc. This was a bad strategy
because it really exacerbated my dislike of the game.</p>

<p>If I design a game with experience like this, I will have to
make a point of ensuring that the player cannot dig themselves
into a hole like this. One technique is to use a field-enemy
system like Chrono Trigger or Final Fantasy XIII where generally
enemies can only be avoided in "traversal" segments rather than
"dungeon" segments; and then control the pacing of combat through
that means.</p>

<p>On Tuesday, I had a particularly horrendous battle. I fought B&amp;BB
(no spoilers). I started playing at the beginning of my student's
final that started at 11am and got to the fight in about 15
minutes (not sure exactly.) The final was three hours and one
student made use of all the time. I beat the battle at 1:45pm. I
was in the battle for almost two hours! I couldn't believe it!
This is supposed to a /portable/ game, as well. (You also cannot
pause in battle, which I find very odd.)</p>

<p>Last night, I was 12 hours into the game, at level 18, at the
fifth to last boss (according to a walkthrough), and getting
unbelievably pummeled. I decided that life is too short to play
games I don't love. I walked away.</p>

<p>I'm still going to play Inside Story, but I probably will not
come back to this game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
