<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2002 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2002/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T19:11:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Resident Evil, starring Milla Jovovich (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/Movie--Resident-Evil--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/Movie--Resident-Evil--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched this because I listened to Retronauts and they talked
about it. I remember seeing it when it first came out and I enjoyed
it---as far as random action movies are enjoyable. The second time
around I continued enjoying it on that level. The CG effects are
pretty poorly integrated, but other than that it is really an on
par movie. I don't mind that the movie doesn't directly reference
anything in the game, because I think that it definitely feels like
it could be in the same universe. I enjoy that about it... it is
not stuck with decisions of the games and can do its own thing. On
the other hand, I read the original script by George Romero and
that it was pretty awesome and would have made a much better,
awesome movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rez (DC, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/Game--Rez--DC--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/04/25/Game--Rez--DC--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just played through Rez on the Dreamcast.</p>

<p>This is a very acclaimed game that I've heard a lot about. It's
well-known for its synergy between music, sound effects, visuals,
and actions. It is a Panzer Dragoon-style rail shooter with a
trance soundtrack and trippy theme. You start exploring a computer
system, but as you progress it implies that this computer system
has somehow consumed the real world and you are freeing it and
thus recreating Earth.</p>

<p>The game has really great style and fun gameplay. I had to play
each level (of 5) twice before beating them and I played the 1st
level a third time so I could get 100% to unlock level 5. I did
this over two days. I read online that there are unlockables for
getting more perfect scores, but the gameplay didn't compel me to
finish that part of the game.</p>

<p>This game solidifies more for me that I dislike the Dragoon-style
games, probably because I first played Sin &amp; Punishment and
like the ability to dodge too much. I find the gameplay
surprisingly shallow: the key is to chain and destroy things in
basically the order they appear on the screen.</p>

<p>Overall, I'm glad I played the game because I have more context
for thinking about games and a better understanding of the history
of this genre and a knowledge of this influential game, but I
won't be trying to complete it 100%.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shantae (GBC, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Shantae--GBC--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Shantae--GBC--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't execute the dances because of rhythm problems on either
my controller or the emulator. :(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Harmony of Dissonance (GBA, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second GBA Metroid style Castlevania game. I played it
on the plane to and from a conference. It was very fun. There are
few points where the game is really confusing because there is
basically no direction about what you're supposed to do and how an
item you got is actually a key. It was frustrating to spend hours
wandering around looking for something that I could do that I
hadn't done, but I learned the map really well as a result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Devdas (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/24/Movie--Devdas--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2005-03-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2005/03/24/Movie--Devdas--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Devdas stars Shahrukh Khan, Madhuri Dixit, and Aishwarya Rai.</p>

<p>I can't say much about the story, besides that it
/sounds/ very interesting from the DVD box blurb, but the
DVD I got did not have subtitles (and did not seem to be a bootleg
either.) However, the blurb was very detailed, so I was able to get
most of what was going on in the movie.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the dancing and music, particular the song /Dola
Re Dola/ (chapter 17 on the DVD.) I cannot stress how amazing it
is. It motivated me to go read about the different styles of Indian
dance, whereupon I found <a href="http://www.meissoun.ch/dlai/dlai-bw-artikel-e.htm">this article</a> that talks about the
different kinds in movies. It actually mentions that the dancing in
/Devdas/ is the Kathak style.</p>

<p>Recommendation: If you know Hindi, it's probably fabulous. If
you can find a DVD with subtitles, it's probably great. If not,
check out the songs. (And if I know you, I can show you the one
song I /really/ like.)</p>

<p>(More on the DVD: The DVD from Eros Entertainment is supposed to
be a special edition double-disc and is probably much better than
what I found, from the original producer.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
