<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2002 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2002/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T22:55:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Sum of All Fears, starring Ben Affleck (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie--The-Sum-of-All-Fears--starring-Ben-Affleck--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/29/Movie--The-Sum-of-All-Fears--starring-Ben-Affleck--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of my favourite movies. I love the early scenes of his
life as a boring analyst. Especially when his office mates are
talking about the intimate details of the lives of the people they
spy on. This is such a clever movie and it has so much great
acting. I greatly enjoy the disturbing way politics and personal
relationships get in the way of the right things happening. It's
deliciously cynical.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Resident Evil, starring Milla Jovovich (2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/Movie--Resident-Evil--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/16/Movie--Resident-Evil--starring-Milla-Jovovich--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched this because I listened to Retronauts and they talked
about it. I remember seeing it when it first came out and I enjoyed
it---as far as random action movies are enjoyable. The second time
around I continued enjoying it on that level. The CG effects are
pretty poorly integrated, but other than that it is really an on
par movie. I don't mind that the movie doesn't directly reference
anything in the game, because I think that it definitely feels like
it could be in the same universe. I enjoy that about it... it is
not stuck with decisions of the games and can do its own thing. On
the other hand, I read the original script by George Romero and
that it was pretty awesome and would have made a much better,
awesome movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance (PS2, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Substance--PS2--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished playing through Metal Gear Solid 2: Substance early
this morning/late last night. I played for about 11 days, from the
17th to the 28th.</p>

<p>First, some stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Hard
Game Over if Spotted: On
Play Time: 17:56:01
Save: 14 times
Continue: 186 times
Alert Mode: 8 times
Persons: 174 killed
Rations: 83 used
Code Name: Mammoth</p>

<p>I remember playing this game when it came out. I don't remember
beating it. Up until I fought with Fatman, I was constantly having
deja vu about the things that were going on, but I couldn't tell
you anything that was going to happen. That totally stopped after
the Fatman fight. I guess I stopped playing at that point back in
the day?</p>

<p>I played on Hard just so that I could get the "Game Over if
Spotted" option. I wish I could turn that on at the other
difficulty levels. As I've said before, I really dislike the
combat in Metal Gear and when you play on Hard, the bosses are
significantly stronger and it is very tedious and boring, in my
opinion. But, I think the Game Over if Spotted is amazing, because
it forces you to figure out how to get by undetected. I love
that. Given that though, I don't know how it was possible that I
ever got any Alert Modes. Perhaps because I killed a guard,
another saw the body, they called reinforcements, and that counts
as Alert Mode.</p>

<p>Obviously I continued A LOT to be able to get through
undetected. I don't really care, because it doesn't make it any
easier, because you still have to go room-by-room undetected.</p>

<p>I didn't really remember anything about the story of this game, so
it was nice to be learn it. It connects really well with what I
remember from MGS4. I'm excited to continue the saga.</p>

<p>One of my favourite aspects of the game was the way it continually
called back to earlier games; sometimes in a self-acknowledging
way. There were many many scenes, angles, etc that were pulled
right from earlier games. I especially like how at the end of the
game, they integrate that into the story. I really like the way
the game is about video games and people who play them, in a
sense.</p>

<p>One of my favourite moments was when Snake tells Raiden he can get
more ammo from him, Raiden asks him how he has so much ammo, Snake
points at his bandanna and says "Infinite Ammo". Of course, in
MGS1 if you save Meryl, the next time you play you get a bandanna
that gives you infinite ammo. =)</p>

<p>Another great moment for me was when Snake and Otacon depart at an
elevator and the theme song slowly swells. Very touching.</p>

<p>I didn't mind Raiden at all. Of course, the cat has long been out
of the bag that the game isn't about him. I don't remember
thinking it was weird at all when I was younger either. I do
really like how they initially call him Snake---of course,
because, it's just a code name, but change it. I also like how at
the end of the game, when Snake finally appears in his sneaking
suit, he says, "Have you been waiting long?" or something to
Raiden, and, of course, to the player.</p>

<p>The mechanics of the game were great. I especially like that
guards can follow footprints better now.</p>

<p>There were a few things about the gameplay that bugged me.</p>

<p>First, Raiden doesn't start with the means to tranquilize people,
so I felt compelled to kill pretty early, whereas I got through
Snake's part without killing anyone. I was planning on doing that,
but it quickly failed. Later in the game, there are many many
places that are very combat focused (the tag team with Snake, for
example) and that's not what the game is about for me, so it
bugged me.</p>

<p>Second, the end of the bomb disposal segment was annoying because
I got to the area of the final bomb with almost 200 seconds to
spare, but I couldn't figure out how to get close enough to the
bomb. (You had to crawl on a rail in the water, on Hard.) And so I
had to run all the way back two or three times, even though I got
there perfectly. Relatedly annoying was the distance you needed to
be before you jumped into water---to far. I did it accidentally a
lot.</p>

<p>Third, the swimming controls are awful. Ugh.</p>

<p>Fourth, escort missions suck. Ugh.</p>

<p>At the very end of the game, there is a huge spike in combat
difficulty, especially with the last two bosses. I probably tried
30 times on each. I almost gave up and just watched the ending of
YouTube, but decided to man up and do it. It worked out well too,
because in the end I beat the final boss without using any
rations. I had enough practice with his attacks. =)</p>

<p>Great game!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shantae (GBC, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Shantae--GBC--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/01/Game--Shantae--GBC--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I couldn't execute the dances because of rhythm problems on either
my controller or the emulator. :(</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Harmony of Dissonance (GBA, 2002)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/09/05/Game--Castlevania--Harmony-of-Dissonance--GBA--2002--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the second GBA Metroid style Castlevania game. I played it
on the plane to and from a conference. It was very fun. There are
few points where the game is really confusing because there is
basically no direction about what you're supposed to do and how an
item you got is actually a key. It was frustrating to spend hours
wandering around looking for something that I could do that I
hadn't done, but I learned the map really well as a result.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
