<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T23:19:57-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy III: The Dragon's Trap (SMS, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Wonder-Boy-III--The-Dragon-s-Trap--SMS--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for a bit. It's definitely better than the
last one. It seems a lot more deep and complex. It's got this
non-linear-ness to it which is interesting, but the controls are
still pretty sloppy. There were many times when I just couldn't
line up with an enemy and it was on top of me doing damage every
time it was possible. I'm still hopeful for the next sequel. But
this game doesn't do it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario Land (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Super-Mario-Land--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Super-Mario-Land--GB--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for one run of about ten minutes. I got to 1-3. I
could very easily tell that this game was a novelty of its day:
Mario in Portable form! Today, there's no reason to play
this. It's not like it's bad... but the limitations of the Game
Boy are way too awkward to really enjoy it. There are some cool
things though, such as the rolling boulders and the different
enemy types, but there's no reason to play this when you're at
home (or even with the hand-held options that are available
today.)</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy Legend (GB, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Final-Fantasy-Legend--GB--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half-hour. I was a Human Female,
Human Male, Mutant Female, and Human Male. I sold my Saber, bought
some armor and went out to fight. It took the whole thirty minutes
to be able to afford one more piece of armor. I went out to fight
again and got into a fight with a Red Bull, during the course of
the fight, all my weapons broke and two of my characters died,
then the monster fled, so I didn't get to kill and didn't get any
gold. Now I don't have the money to replace the weapons or revive
the fallen characters. This game seems like it will be nothing
but Kawazu brutalization and grinding. No thank you.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Bugs Bunny in The Crazy Castle (GB, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle--GB--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/23/Game--Bugs-Bunny-in-The-Crazy-Castle--GB--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for almost an hour tonight. It is brilliant in
its simple setup, but complex puzzles. The controls are
horrible---you can't turn in mid-step, you can't stop on stairs,
and you don't always use a special attack when you think you
will. The graphics are horrific. The music is about 4 notes
repeated. But nevertheless, it's a really addicting and satisfying
game. It's neat that you can watch replays of your last
attempt. This game is very similar to Lolo-style games, but
different enough that it feels unique. I was very impressed.</p>

<p>On the Game Boy, apparently it has 80 levels, and I did 31. I
think I burnt myself out on it in the one sitting I did. I will
definitely play this again, and probably pick up where I was
before, but I'll mark it as done because I think I understand the
game pretty thoroughly and (like the Crush games) I can't really
binge on it.</p>

<p>Stage 31: XPAZ</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy in Monster Land (SMS, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour today. I used an emulator and
couldn't resist save states. In the beginning, I worked my way
through on my own, using saves at each screen. I had no sense of
what the items would do, so I didn't really buy any. After a
while, I looked at a walkthrough (which basically just recommended
which items to buy) and learned that I missed a few essential
hidden items. I restarted and made it to stage 4 following the
guide. I went away to eat, paused, and when I came back, the game
had reset itself.</p>

<p>This game looks and sounds really good, especially for its
age. It's cute and has some interesting mechanics. I think of it
as a lot like Zelda 2, but with a less interesting combat system,
sloppier mechanics, and a more advanced inventory system. I found
the jumps to feel really wrong and the combat delays to be pretty
painful. The inventory system, once you realize what things are,
is neat.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that this is a pretty amazing game for its age,
but that a lot about it works against it. The biggest problem is
the lack of continues. The game is too deep on a customization
level to make sense as an arcade game. I presume that later
version of the game change this, because they were designed for
consoles. Secondly, the sprites are a bit too big and they make
it hard to see what's going on. Third, the jumps and fighting
don't feel quite right.</p>

<p>I won't play this, but I'm excited to investigate other games in
this series.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
