<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-18T22:54:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play for like two hours this morning to entertain my kids so my
wife could sleep in. It was very interesting to be down on the
Mechonis foot and get to know what happened to Fiora. Her outfits
look very cool... very similar to KOS-MOS. Dickson is ridiculous
in his ability to be everyone instantly, despite being a level 25
NPC.</p>

<p>Later in the day, we played for another hour and had an epic fight
then went on a dumb fetch quest to get bomb parts. We played again
for just thirty minutes and did a little exploring, before
watching the first war scene and calling it quits for the night.</p>

<p>Total time: 21:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this while my kids watched for like 40 minutes. We
played up to the Fork Lift one. I had a really hard time with it
and the See Saw. I really enjoyed the Double Date one, it was
super cute. The first Remix was fun too.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son requested this again and I got all the awards on the second
level then got all the things on the third, except the medal and
the speed trophy. I found it un-intuitive to figure out how to do
the time course. I also find this game to control incredibly
sloppily. The character just swishes around all the time, it is
incredibly obnoxious and hard to deal with.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deathsmiles (X360, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Deathsmiles--X360--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is one of the first games that my son would specifically
request. He hasn't in a long time, but wanted to today. I played
through it with three continues (one on Tyrannosatan). It was
fun. I didn't do too well, but I did get the extend during the
castle stage.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like three hours tonight. There's been lots of crazy
reveals in the game, some that have been obvious for a long time
and others that were just cool. Getting on to Mechonis was
awesome. It was crazy to see the new map screen. Rad.</p>

<p>Some of the main-line fetch quests in this game are absurd. You
walk through an area and then get to the end are given a fetch
quest where you walk all the way back across the area. It's
totally insane.</p>

<p>Total time: 18:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
