<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-11T10:31:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought my son might like this game, given how much he enjoyed
watching the beginning of Castlevania: SOTN. I also thought he
might be willing to play it because the controls are simpler. I
was right. He really enjoyed watching the beginning and then all
of sudden he said, "Dad, how do you move? How do you attack? Can I
try?" He explored the world a little and fought some enemies. He
started getting frustrated because he kept dying. His problem was
that he wouldn't move away from enemies when they came to attack
him. He would swing his sword while the enemies were on top of him
and this killed him eventually.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The kids and I played this for a bit today. We did Needle Man and
couldn't do enough damage to the boss. Then we did Top Man, and
won. Then we did Hard Man (couldn't get past the second monkey)
and Gemini Man and then they got bored so we switched to a different
game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a long drive today, so I played for almost four hours. I've
had lots of cute experiences in the game. I really like the towns
in this game... they feel much more fleshed out and real than
towns in most RPGs. I decided to marry Deborah because I think her
sprite is really cool and I thought she'd be funny. So far she has
been really hilarious with all her little comments. I like it a
lot. The wedding voes were really funny because they said "until
you stop getting resurrected at church when you die" instead of
"until death do you part"... thus acknowledging that the
characters really do die and get resurrected in the story. It was
really funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I made a lot of progress and saved the kingdom. It was
fun. I started exploring the new continent. I had a really hard
time with fighting the giant cat. I could tell there was some
trick but couldn't tell what it would be. It was annoying to have
no clue. I played for like two hours.</p>

<p>Total time: 8:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/22/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/22/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like three hours today at various times. I got
through the next few adventures and now I've escaped from the
slave camp and I'm trying to get Coburg back in order. I really
enjoy the story in this Dragon Quest. It does a really good job of
making you feel like your dad is really strong and cares about
you. It's neat. I feel like there's a lot of cute foreshadowing
going on too.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
