<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T22:13:59-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I advanced the story quite a bit. I feel like I'm in the closing
stages: I'm going to fight Zangurak, then send the Outsider back,
and live happily ever after with Calista. I thought her wedding
dress was very cute and I liked the resolution of the wedding
plot. In the game play, there's been a bit of a boss rush of sorts
where boss encounters similar to ones from earlier in the game
keep coming back. It's fun though. The fight next to the Outside
was pretty exciting and difficult. That whole sequence going down
the tunnel was very difficult---I think I died three times.</p>

<p>I accidentally used the Auto-Equip feature and all my outfits
changed. It was very painful to go back to dressing all the girls
how I like.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48
Total time: 23:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a few rounds today with the kids. I did pretty well
against Sandman... I'm getting better. But I still didn't beat
him.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we've been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a short amount of time yesterday before going to
bed. I mainly just advanced the story. It turns out that Lavos is
behind Zael's power and the destruction of the world. Bummer. I'm
excited about a cute wedding scene.</p>

<p>TODO Go back to the mysterious island and go behind the entrance
where the Lvl 40 Cave Cougars are.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played for a lot. A new arena season was opened, so I
had a lot of fun playing it over and over so I could max out all
my currently available items, etc. I did it like seven times. In
addition to that, I did some story missions, including the
haunted mansion. The best part of that was Horace's ridiculous
comment about his wife afterwards. The stealth section escaping
from the castle was kind of odd, but worked as much as it needed
to. It was much better with Callista than with Zael alone. I'm
weirded out by Dagran being a sketch ball. I wonder where the
story is going. I presume that the Count is really the big bad in
some way, but maybe also I'll fight "The Outsider".</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
