<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T22:50:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for a little more than an hour. We got to the Dark
World and got the first crystal. I beat the boss that was giving
me such a hard time before on the first try. It was cool. I
decided to keep track of my time from now on.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I beat the level---The Coil. It was horrible. The first time
I beat it---after almost an hour---I was 1.02 seconds too late to
get an A+. I gave it another 15 minutes and got about 7 seconds
under the required time. Go!</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for another hour and a half later in the day beat a few
more levels. 5-19X was destroying me though. I have 5-19X, 5-20X,
Four Letter Word in Cotton Alley, and all the Dark World of
Dr. Fetus' castle and Cotton Alley left before I do everything in
the game. Exhausting. This game makes my hands hurt.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 5 (NES, 1992)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Mega-Man-5--NES--1992--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Mega-Man-5--NES--1992--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play this while my son watched today. I spent twenty minutes
going through Stone Man's stage. I got to him and was doing pretty
well, but the Mega Buster wasn't powerful enough against him. The
spinning things are the worst... they crowd you and you can't
shoot them while they are touching you. It stinks, you have to
draw them away and then jump n shoot them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing this regularly for so long and I've never gotten
past Soda Popinski. I think I will retire it for a
while. Definitely an awesome game, but it has shattered me for a
while. A part of me suspects that I need to get a TV setup with
lower lag to be successful. But that's probably just being a sore
loser.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've decided to retire this game for a while. I haven't really
been playing that much even though I have it scheduled and kind of
want to. I think I need to start again from the beginning with no
assists. I only have the Endurance Races, the Formula GT races,
and the Special Events to get Golds on, but I don't want to spend
the time on the Endurance ones and the Formula/Special events are
so technical, I think my skills just aren't up to the task. I
think I need to re-learn to play. I'm going to put it on my
schedule to play it again in January and give it another try. I
can't believe how much and how long I've played this game. It's
sooo good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
