<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-12T23:47:28-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/12/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/12/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.actionbutton.net/?p%3D2597">This action button review</a> of the game captures my feelings about a
lot of the system-overload this game throws at you so early and
the sheer weight of the quests. The comment about the difference
between abilities and skills is very apt---I have no clue what's
going on in that system. Something related is that for a lot of
the game so far I've been killing every enemy in my path, but then
I noticed that a lot of the enemies are just giving me 1 or 2
EXP... what's the point of that? But there doesn't seem to be a
good way to tell what is going to be a good amount of EXP before
hand. It's a bit confusing.</p>

<p>Today, I played for a little over three hours. I advanced the
story quite a bit. I was really annoyed by the lack of a feeling
of progress behind all the numbers. I repeatedly tried to get
past a little path that was blocked by enemies and I seemed to be
dying with no explanation.</p>

<p>I went back to the gem guy to create a whole bunch of gems, but I
don't really know if they are really all that good or if I
shouldn't have spent them all, because I have a lot of gems now
and not enough places to put them.</p>

<p>I'm really conflicted about the battle system. In some ways, it's
no different than a traditional FF or DQ game, because you
generally attack and then use special attacks when you have
enough energy to. But on the other hand, it feels like a lot of
meaningful decision is taken from you. For example, there's an
air of strategy in your positioning, but with huge crowds of
enemies it is so hard to see where you are, where their face is,
etc that being in the front/back/side is almost irrelevant
because you can't reliably tell. The whole
Monado-tells-the-future system being integrated into the combat
is really remarkable and unique. I'm not yet to the point though
where the vision really does me any good because I don't
understand how it is supposed to be canceled.</p>

<p>Basically, at this point, I find the whole game to be really
confusing in the mechanic department. There's a lot that I can do
and I'm treating it like a traditional JRPG, but I feel like I'm
missing something when I do, but I'm not really being punished
for ignoring it, but I'm constantly being flirted with by all
these other weird numbers and concepts. It's just a really
strange game.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/11/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. I have a few thoughts
about my experiences tonight...</p>

<ul>
<li><p>The controls are really annoying. It is very weird that A is
the confirm button on the Wii Pro controller, because it is in
the cancel spot. There should have been a way to change.</p></li>
<li><p>The user interface is really painful. There's a big loading
time to do everything. The equipment management system is
really annoying---you can't equip from a shop and when you
change equipment, the gems don't automatically get unequipped
and I haven't found a way to remove them other than putting the
thing back on and removing it from there. It's really
painful. The quick travel system is really slow too because you
have to go so deep in the menus.</p></li>
<li><p>I'm amazed that the killed off what seemed like a main
character after giving you the opportunity to spend /a lot/ of
money on her to give a special bikini outfit. I didn't realize
it would be a wasted expense.</p></li>
<li><p>The graphics are quite good for some Wii games, but feel really
bad in other ways. I think this is most noticeable when they
show faces, because they are totally flat. The environments are
really beautifully constructed and I love how open they are.</p></li>
<li><p>The combat system is pretty interesting. I still don't feel
like I totally understand all my choices, but I have a bit of a
technique worked out that is being useful so far.</p></li>
<li><p>The story is pretty compelling and the world is very bizarre
and fascinating for it.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Total time: 4:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ziggurat (iOS, 2012) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Ziggurat--iOS--2012--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Ziggurat--iOS--2012--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've had this game on my "Queue" since I bought it, but I've had
to admit to myself that I just hate playing games on the iPhone
so much, I'm definitely not going to sit down and play
this. Sometimes I play it when I'm waiting for something, but I
have other things that feel more productive that I could be doing
on my phone.</p>

<p>I like the game and I think it is the best iPhone game I've
played, but I really dislike the iPhone interface and this game
in particular feels like it would work just as well with
buttons. I feel like the only way for me to appreciate this game
will be for me to re-implement it myself and give it buttons.</p>

<p>So, I'm retiring it from my queue, with a bit of a sad face.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/10/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game tonight. The opening sequence is really cool,
especially after the battle when it pulls out and shows you how
people live on the two giant titans. It's such a cool concept.</p>

<p>The battle system I experienced during the walk to the first
village was incredibly reminiscent of FF12, but with a bit more
action on the part of the player. When I got to the town, it was
incredibly tempting to go and find all the glowing blue things
and get all the quests, etc. I can tell that it will be hard to
not make this game a giant collect-a-thon for myself.</p>

<p>I'm finding the mechanics a bit overwhelming. There are a lot of
different options about how to equip characters, so many quests,
so many different ways to buy things. It's very intimidating. I
think I will do the obvious thing until it hurts me rather than
trying to compute what the best solution will be.</p>

<p>I was amazed at how many different quests I unlocked so early,
though.</p>

<p>The voice acting in this game is actually really good. I almost
never like non-Japanese voice acting, because it is normally just
so horrendous. (Actually, now that I think about, Asura's Wrath
was pretty good.) Since the actors in this game are British,
there's something really fun and exotic about them. I like it.</p>

<p>I'm pretty excited to be playing this game. (One annoyance: I'm
using the Wii Pro controller. I hate having to have it plugged in
to the Wiimote that sits stupidly next to me on the couch.)</p>

<p>Total time: 1:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time... I considered restarting, but didn't and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He's really really hard. I've decided to put this as
"Scheduled" game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I'm kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
