<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-01T08:00:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight... the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn't understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it... but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I'm curious about what Zaka will be
like... do I really get another vehicle? I'm running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat the game tonight after playing for about 5 hours. The final
battle was super tough. I liked all the build-up side battles
too. The best part of the final battle were the cool 2D animations
and "camera" changes. It was pretty unique, although something
similar happened a few times in earlier parts of the game.</p>

<p>Overall, I found this game to be pretty rad. The game play is
straight-forward, but quick enough to not be too tedious compared
to the first three. The lack of a job system is fine, because the
individual characters you are given are interesting enough. The
story is very quaint and cute; the way they broke up the story is
very cool, especially how people act around the Hero.</p>

<p>I can't tell how much of what I like (such as the Heal All option)
were added in the remake, but I don't feel like I need to play the
NES version to find out.</p>

<p>I don't think I'd play it again, because I'm willing to bet that
another Dragon Quest game (maybe a SNES one?) will be a more
refined experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 23:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the "reports" I'd seen showing up were... how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service... I mean, the beach vacation... one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 4: Chapters of the Chosen (DS, 2007) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Dragon-Quest-4--Chapters-of-the-Chosen--DS--2007--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours throughout the day today while the
kids were playing and/or sick. I explored the waterfall and used
my water soaking stone and got a rad sword. I also did a little
bit of grinding until I could be Estark... which I barely did;
Ragnar was the only one left and he would've only last one
hit... and he was killed in the first fight as I tried to
escape. But, alas, I did.</p>

<p>After I got the balloon, I decided to be done for the night. As I
was looking at the world map, I thought how geeky and funny it
would be to have an "accurate" polar projection map with scaling
deformation in certain regions (including on the characters &amp;
their speed.) That would be funny.</p>

<p>Shopping list:
- 35k per Liquid Metal Armor in Endor (secret shop, need 3)
- Female armor in Elf town (need 2?)</p>

<p>Total time: 19:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/28/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been plugging along in the game doing one a day. I got the
train mini-game today. It's a neat version of the car mini-game
from the last one. The idea of dealing with multiple trains at a
time sounds like it will be challenging.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
