<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-21T23:31:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/21/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started this game today. I pre-ordered it and have been excited
about it since I heard that it would come out. I don't think I've
ever really been an extremely "Sakaguchi" Final Fantasy fan... I
feel like I've responded more to Kitase's direction, but
nevertheless, I enjoyed Blue Dragon and LOOOVED Lost Odyssey, so
I had high expectations for this game. But, after being let down
so bad so recently by Xenoblade, I was a little skeptical.</p>

<p>When I first turned it on, the first thing I noticed was that the
language is surprisingly crass. I think the very first sentence
has a swear. It's not the worst curses, but it's there and it was
a little jarring.</p>

<p>After that, I really enjoyed how the game started "in media
res". You have a really immediate connection to the action and the
characters and they reveal themselves in a pretty nice and subdued
way. I think the voice acting is really good... especially
Syrene's voice actress. She sounds very, very cool. In general,
all the characters strike me as really interesting and cool. The
"sweet" girl seems very sweet too, which I like.</p>

<p>At this point in the story (after chapter 6), I really like how
"low-key" the story is. Coming from Xenoblade where you fight
God, it's nice to have a story that is much more low level and
intimate (at least at the beginning, who knows what will happen
in the end?)</p>

<p>When I first got to the tavern, I was kind of amazed by the unique
voice acting and animated interactions with the group. I was
worried that I had accidentally advanced the story when I was
trying to just wander around and talk to people.</p>

<p>I feel like the sub-quest system isn't very good, because there's
no list of who wants what from you. This is a place where
Xenoblade was clearly superior in the interface department, but
Last Story seems to be keeping you more connected with the
characters, at the expense of forgetting about them all together.</p>

<p>The equipment system is interesting. It seems like armor isn't
really that important because they were all equal for me, but
they seem to have different status effects after they've been
upgraded. There seems to be an assumption that you will be
upgrading every item, rather than reserving upgrading for the end
(as many games, in fact, assume.)</p>

<p>I bought all the weapons and armor that I could in the first town
and maxed them all out (up to getting some sort of rare item that
would be required to progress them.)</p>

<p>The concept of "local goods" seems strange. I get the inkling
that you can do arbitrage to make money... sounds tedious. I hope
it isn't necessary.</p>

<p>The clothing dying system is difficult for me to imagine how to
use effectively. I feel like I want to look online for a gallery
of cool colourings. The "invisible" option is very intriguing.</p>

<p>When I was exploring, I found the arena. Syrene's dialogue about
it was awesome... so funny. I had a really hard time the first
time in the arena, because I had yet grasped the combat system. I
originally felt like I needed to be up next to enemies all the
time, but now I feel like it is more important to manage the
battlefield and setup sneak attacks, etc. I think I may also want
to turn on the "Manual" attack mode, because I think it will feel
better.</p>

<p>After I died and retried in the arena, I then played through the
first Season of the arena six more times. The combat system
is <em>really</em> <em>really</em> fun. I like it a lot and it was cool to just
go at it and feel the excitement of the mechanics. What an
awesome change from Xenoblade.</p>

<p>I moved on with the story after that and met Lisa... accidentally
tried to walk in on them in the bath and got some really funny
text. Then moved on to the next area. The boss in that area was
difficult to do properly, because I didn't realize I could do a
Slash over the railing. I was trying to get the auto-attack to
happen and it never did before I got hosed. Once I realized that
I could Slash, it was cake and I learned more about the game.</p>

<p>From this experience, I can say that I really love this game play
so far and I've very excited to see where the story goes too.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 12
Total time: 4:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I ended just before the final cut-off point to the final
bosses and end of the game. I finished the game today in about an
hour. Today as I started to play, I left the title screen on for a
while... it was very beautiful as the time of day changed.</p>

<p>I thought the end of the game was fun and crazy. It was so
incredibly Evangelion and so classically Japanese, like I said
before, but even more so given the ending---everyone you thought
was good is actually bad and everyone that was bad is really good,
and all that. I especially liked walking around in space and the
origin story given to Zanza. It was also neat how Dickson ended
up.</p>

<p>Total time: 26:36</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>In the end, I feel like this was a really interesting story and
world, but a pretty terrible game. The mechanics were just very
shallow and boring, lacking in meaningful choices. I think you
could do something with the concepts in the combat system, but
they didn't really do it. One thing that I reckon WoW does that
this game lacks is that because you need to assemble large groups
with varied skills, there is an interesting meta-process of doing
that, but it is still ultimately boring for the individual
players.</p>

<p>I heard so much about how amazing this game was and how it was so
great that Japanese developers were learning from the West, but I
feel like all the Western ideas here are bad ideas that I don't
want to see more of.</p>

<p>I really disliked that every item changed your appearance because
it was hard to look consistent while having the best
stats. Everyone just looked so stupid generally.</p>

<p>The interface was pretty terrible because it took so many clicks
to do everything and the buttons were reversed from what they
should be on the controller. Ugh.</p>

<p>I don't think I can really recommend this game... maybe I would
just recommend watching some videos and reading about the story,
but I found the mechanics to be unbearably weak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like four hours tonight. The ending of this game is
classic Japanese insanity where you fight God and conquer your
fate. The changing alliances and what not at the end of the game
are pretty crazy too. I like a lot of what went on and it is very
intriguing in its Evangelion-ness. Some of the boss battles are
getting to be very tedious slog fests.</p>

<p>Total time: 25:32</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played before dinner for like 10 minutes. I brought down the
Sandman three times, once per round, but died each of the two
matches. I'm getting better though!</p>

<p>Total time: 3:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play for like two hours this morning to entertain my kids so my
wife could sleep in. It was very interesting to be down on the
Mechonis foot and get to know what happened to Fiora. Her outfits
look very cool... very similar to KOS-MOS. Dickson is ridiculous
in his ability to be everyone instantly, despite being a level 25
NPC.</p>

<p>Later in the day, we played for another hour and had an epic fight
then went on a dumb fetch quest to get bomb parts. We played again
for just thirty minutes and did a little exploring, before
watching the first war scene and calling it quits for the night.</p>

<p>Total time: 21:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
