<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-11T21:29:11-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/11/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In the morning, we played for about a half hour and beat level 4'
via the secret route---beating Camilla---but not getting to 5'. I
started on stage 5 a bit, but was pretty beat down.</p>

<p>Later, I played for about an hour and a half and beat
stage 5. Eventually I was able to use the watch to get through up
to Death without getting hit at all... by pausing the action just
before the large green monsters. Sometimes this game seems totally
impossible and brutalizing. The key seems to always be using the
sub-weapons effectively and breaking the challenges. Or, learning
pitch perfect timing and getting through unscathed... but mostly
doing the sub-weapons just right. It's a fascinating design.</p>

<p>After I mastered that, it took about 7 tries to kill Death. I
stuck with the Cross. I used an Item Crash early and pummeled
him. I dodged the huge skulls by staying to the left and
right. The melee fight was pure stick-and-move. It is so
satisfying to win at this game.</p>

<p>After Death was dead, I fought the Vampire Bat and was killed
Medusa in the Boss rush stage. I decided to go back and fight
Camilla again, because supposedly you need to beat Death to get
the secret exit... but no luck.</p>

<p>Total time: 4:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I played this game with my son for about an hour. We
beat level 2 the normal way after getting Maria. Now I have
unlocked up to 4 and 4'. We tried 4 but were totally brutalized by
the boss playing as Maria (she's really weak.) We also rescued two
of the non-playable girls. Still... amazing game.</p>

<p>Later in the day we played for about thirty minutes and beat level
4' via the normal route and got to stage 5. I wish the game a
better way of tracking which levels/exits you have done.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Akumajou Dracula X: Chi No Rondo (TG-16 CD, 1993) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Game--Akumajou-Dracula-X--Chi-No-Rondo--TG-16-CD--1993--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought a PC Engine and got this game. It is really fun to play
it again, especially without an emulator and save states, so I
have to do it better. Additionally, I've had a lot more
experience with the other early Castlevania games so I'm just
better at playing it. It's really fun and smooth feeling, despite
having classic Casltevania stickiness.</p>

<p>I played only as Richter today and I did all secret exits. I went
from 0 to 1 to 2' to 3' to 4'. I fought the Serpent, the Minotaur,
the Werewolf, and the floaty head thing. It's a lot of fun.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda (Second Quest) (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost a year ago, I beat the first quest of Legend of Zelda. I'd
never really played the second quest, but I knew it existed, so
after doing Castlevania II, I decided to knock it out.</p>

<p>I played for about 2 hours and 15 minutes and got up to level 4
and had about 9 hearts and other stuff from the overworld. It was
very painful to gather all the money. I decided that I wanted to
buy the arrows and wanted to try the Money Making Game trick, but
I needed to plug in the second controller. I was scared of
accidentally bumping the NES and causing it to glitch, so I
figured I'd save first. I stupidly didn't realize that when you
do "Continue" it doesn't also save, so I just held down RESET,
saved the SRAM on my PowerPak, and rebooted. And thus I deleted
all my progress. Ouch.</p>

<p>I decided to play again, but with a Game Genie code to give me
more access to money, so I wouldn't have to do the rupee grinding
like I did the first time. It took about one hour to get back to
where I was before. Then another 2 and a half to win. 3:34 total.</p>

<p>This version of the game is much more difficult. There are parts
where you almost have to play it like a stealth game because you
are so limited in your ability to take damage.</p>

<p>I like that the maps are rearranged, but since I used online maps,
it didn't really matter... I don't have the patience to make my
own tools to do mapping for myself. I would never look at a map in
game like Castlevania (one of the Metroid-style ones) because the
in-game map system is so good. A game like Legend of Zelda that
had a really good map like there, maybe with the ability to make
notes like in Etrian Odyssey. That would be cool and you could
probably randomly generate the maps to have infinite fun. I wonder
if it would be too much like Sudoku though (in the sense that you
would always start off by trying to find the Blue Ring and then
the Candle, etc, etc.)</p>

<p>I liked the final message: "You are great. You have an amazing
wisdom and power."</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:34
Total time: 5:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played 5-19X for 35 minutes today. It was brutal, but I got
further than ever before... I got to the top of the tower of
disappearing blocks.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
