<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-18T15:43:44-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Skull Man's stage tonight (my son is very
fascinated with his appearance.) It was a fun level and I managed
to get an E tank and lots of 1-UPs on it. I had 4 lives for the
boss fight but was totally destroyed. I feel like in these later
Mega Man games, it is impossible to beat bosses out of
order. It's a bit disappointing that it isn't as free, but it
doesn't detract that much from the experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xexyz (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Xexyz--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Xexyz--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about 15 minutes today. This is one of those
older NES games with really spotty controls but lots of
interesting ideas, that really doesn't work super well. On the
first level you have to wander around a whole bunch of screens
looking for which star block to shoot five times to open a secret
door. I didn't find the controls and mechanics very appealing, so
I think that's it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 4 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Dragon-Warrior-4--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Dragon-Warrior-4--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played the DS remake of this and it was amazing, but I
can't play this older version. I have some memories of it because
my good friend from elementary school had it and I borrowed it. I
think I only made it to Taloon's part when I played it then. In
situations like this, I'm worried that someone will come to my
site's rankings and think I dislike this game, but I do
like... just not this release. Perhaps I should change my
tracking program to keep track of releases and games distinctly
so I can rank the games, not just the releases?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I had to restart because my
save was lost somehow. I got to Portoa and got the Sword of
Water. (This appears to be about half-way by glancing at the Table
of Contents of a guide.)</p>

<p>The mechanics in the game never really get much more
interesting. They definitely add a few things: like the Rabbit
Boots, and presumably you eventually are able to cross water, and
then the keys that the swords become after you get their balls,
etc. But all the things that are different in the game are on the
level of navigation annoyances (not really "puzzles").</p>

<p>I wouldn't say that I'm opposed to games that don't change their
mechanics---Super Mario, for instance, doesn't have different
mechanics through the game. But, Mario can do this because (a) the
game play is awesome and (b) the game play is rich enough that it
supports gaining mastery and then increasing the challenge.</p>

<p>In my time playing Crystalis, it was very true to the literal
definition of "Action RPG". The individual encounters were totally
trivial (like hitting "Fight" over and over), but did require
moderate action. The challenge came from requiring a deep grind to
get resources---power to attack with and money to pay for healing
and rests. The severely limited inventory and the large number of
enemies really encourages you to go incredibly slowly and defeat
every enemy. But, it's not fun enough to do. It feels pretty good
for about an hour, but after that it gets really aggravating, and
I feel like I want to just rush by.</p>

<p>Something I'm surprised I was annoyed by was the need to switch
weapons to fight different kinds of enemies. It just felt so
tedious to do, because you generally want to walk around with a
sword charge, only to go to the menu to change swords when you
see an enemy. It was particularly annoying that you can't turn
off the bracelet power once you get it, so you have to either use
MP (because it's so easy to accidentally charge to level 3 shots)
or only use level 1 (by turning off the power-up altogether.)</p>

<p>I'd say that the game is not bad, but it has been so out-done by
games like Secret of Mana that there's no reason to play this
older Action RPG (as if Mana is really much newer!) I was hoping a
little that this would be much more Action-y because it was
older. It is interesting for me to notice that as I get older I
like more action-based games, because they cut away all that fat
from RPGs that I used to love.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played tonight for about 20 minutes. I played two continues on
Ring Man's stage and couldn't get much past the Hippo. My kids
then took two continues and just stayed on the first screen
running around and climbing up the later and using the super
shot. It was cute.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
