<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-20T23:06:48-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/20/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I ended just before the final cut-off point to the final
bosses and end of the game. I finished the game today in about an
hour. Today as I started to play, I left the title screen on for a
while... it was very beautiful as the time of day changed.</p>

<p>I thought the end of the game was fun and crazy. It was so
incredibly Evangelion and so classically Japanese, like I said
before, but even more so given the ending---everyone you thought
was good is actually bad and everyone that was bad is really good,
and all that. I especially liked walking around in space and the
origin story given to Zanza. It was also neat how Dickson ended
up.</p>

<p>Total time: 26:36</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>In the end, I feel like this was a really interesting story and
world, but a pretty terrible game. The mechanics were just very
shallow and boring, lacking in meaningful choices. I think you
could do something with the concepts in the combat system, but
they didn't really do it. One thing that I reckon WoW does that
this game lacks is that because you need to assemble large groups
with varied skills, there is an interesting meta-process of doing
that, but it is still ultimately boring for the individual
players.</p>

<p>I heard so much about how amazing this game was and how it was so
great that Japanese developers were learning from the West, but I
feel like all the Western ideas here are bad ideas that I don't
want to see more of.</p>

<p>I don't think I can really recommend this game... maybe I would
just recommend watching some videos and reading about the story,
but I found the mechanics to be unbearably weak.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like four hours tonight. The ending of this game is
classic Japanese insanity where you fight God and conquer your
fate. The changing alliances and what not at the end of the game
are pretty crazy too. I like a lot of what went on and it is very
intriguing in its Evangelion-ness. Some of the boss battles are
getting to be very tedious slog fests.</p>

<p>Total time: 25:32</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/19/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played before dinner for like 10 minutes. I brought down the
Sandman three times, once per round, but died each of the two
matches. I'm getting better though!</p>

<p>Total time: 3:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play for like two hours this morning to entertain my kids so my
wife could sleep in. It was very interesting to be down on the
Mechonis foot and get to know what happened to Fiora. Her outfits
look very cool... very similar to KOS-MOS. Dickson is ridiculous
in his ability to be everyone instantly, despite being a level 25
NPC.</p>

<p>Later in the day, we played for another hour and had an epic fight
then went on a dumb fetch quest to get bomb parts. We played again
for just thirty minutes and did a little exploring, before
watching the first war scene and calling it quits for the night.</p>

<p>Total time: 21:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/18/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this while my kids watched for like 40 minutes. We
played up to the Fork Lift one. I had a really hard time with it
and the See Saw. I really enjoyed the Double Date one, it was
super cute. The first Remix was fun too.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
