<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-28T01:50:22-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a long drive today, so I played for almost four hours. I've
had lots of cute experiences in the game. I really like the towns
in this game... they feel much more fleshed out and real than
towns in most RPGs. I decided to marry Deborah because I think her
sprite is really cool and I thought she'd be funny. So far she has
been really hilarious with all her little comments. I like it a
lot. The wedding voes were really funny because they said "until
you stop getting resurrected at church when you die" instead of
"until death do you part"... thus acknowledging that the
characters really do die and get resurrected in the story. It was
really funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/23/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I made a lot of progress and saved the kingdom. It was
fun. I started exploring the new continent. I had a really hard
time with fighting the giant cat. I could tell there was some
trick but couldn't tell what it would be. It was annoying to have
no clue. I played for like two hours.</p>

<p>Total time: 8:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/22/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/22/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like three hours today at various times. I got
through the next few adventures and now I've escaped from the
slave camp and I'm trying to get Coburg back in order. I really
enjoy the story in this Dragon Quest. It does a really good job of
making you feel like your dad is really strong and cares about
you. It's neat. I feel like there's a lot of cute foreshadowing
going on too.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/21/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/21/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I really like the setup of the story: being a kid, hanging out
with your dad, etc. It's very adorable and heart-warming. I
especially like all the little jokes about how he can't read. The
game-play is exactly what you'd expect and fun.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We finished watching it.</p>

<p>The LP was done really really well. I appreciated
SuperGreatFriend's commentary as he went, livening up the slow
moments, like long combat sequences. He had some really funny
things too... like singing into the mic at the Galaxy of
Terror. Priceless! He was very thoughtful in other things, like
not showing cards with spoilers until the end, etc.</p>

<p>The game itself was really fascinating. The reveals at the end
were wild. As crazy as this game is in the beginning... it is SO
Japanese in the insanity that takes place at the end of the
game. Awesome.</p>

<p>I listened to the WAHP interview with SWERY again and found it
cool. I also noticed during the credits that there is a character
for every letter in the alphabet! Cool!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
