<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-09T23:13:41-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this afternoon for like an hour. I got up to Bald
Bull. During the fight with Soda Popinski that I won, I was in the
second round and had him down twice and he got me down for the
second time... I considered restarting, but didn't and won. Woot!</p>

<p>Later in the day I played for a bit more and got to
Mr. Sandman. He's really really hard. I've decided to put this as
"Scheduled" game and play it weekly until I beat him, rather than
burning a lot of time all at once.</p>

<p>I'm kind of appalled that I was able to get to the end so
quickly, but I know it will take a while to beat Sandman and
online I read that there is another round of fighting every enemy
during Title Defense. So it will be a fun experience, but not
really something you can binge on too much.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man X1 (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Mega-Man-X1--SNES--1993--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played again from the start for about an hour. This time I
beat Chill Penguin, then went against Flame Mammoth (because I
thought he'd be weak, but he wasn't), then we went to Sting
Chameleon's stage and got the Armor upgrade. I'm not sure if I
will use the password next time we play. Fighting the armor
upgrade guard was te----dious!</p>

<p>Total time: 1:28</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for an hour and a half-ish. We beat the game! The
final boss and the last rocket sequence was pretty tough and my
wife was getting very frustrated, but we eventually did it.</p>

<p>The Nintendo Channel clocks our total time at 20 hours and 52
minutes (I haven't been keeping track of our game play that long.)</p>

<p>We decided that the game is a lot more sloppy in many ways
compared to NSMBW, but that we had a lot of fun, especially once
we got infinite lives. We don't love the game enough to try to get
all the bonuses to unlock the hidden temple, so that's that.</p>

<p>I like platformers, but I like playing games with my wife more.</p>

<p>Time: 7:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment (N64, 2000) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Sin---Punishment--N64--2000--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Back in May, I bought a copy of S&amp;P for the N64 in Japan. On
Tuesday I bought a US N64 to play it on. Today, I got the
"GameBit" in the mail that I needed to region mod it to play
Japanese N64 games.</p>

<p>I started playing S&amp;P and it took a while to get used to the
controls again... especially because before I played on my arcade
stick (under an emulator) and now I was using the actual control
scheme. It felt a little strange but I started to get used to it
quickly.</p>

<p>I played about 14 minutes and got: 5,343,930 pts, 11m13s, and 531
enemies. I died at the final stage of the final boss of the first
level. I remember it taking a while to realize that I had to
shoot the glowing spot under water the first time too...</p>

<p>Time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this in the morning and got to Great Tiger. I had a
tough time with Bear Hugger before I realized that I could duck
the Bear Hug. I only fought one round against Great Tiger, so I'm
just learning his patterns. It is interesting how this game is
almost, but not quite, identical to the NES version. There are
some things that are better and more convenient (like Saves and
Retry in the middle of a match) but other than that it's just
tweaked on the edges. It's cool.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
