<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-12T22:37:15-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I've been taking a
break from games as I catch up on some work. I went up to the part
in the game where you are reunited with your kids after being a
statue and are looking for your wife. It was a really cool
sequence to be stone and then meet your kids. This game is just
sooo adorable.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago... I forget when... we played again, beat the first
temple and got some items in the world. My son really enjoys
watching it.</p>

<p>Today we played up to the boss in the Tower of Hera, but were
totally creamed. It is tough. I keep getting knocked off and then
his health is reset.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda: Link to the Past (SNES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Link-to-the-Past--SNES--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought my son might like this game, given how much he enjoyed
watching the beginning of Castlevania: SOTN. I also thought he
might be willing to play it because the controls are simpler. I
was right. He really enjoyed watching the beginning and then all
of sudden he said, "Dad, how do you move? How do you attack? Can I
try?" He explored the world a little and fought some enemies. He
started getting frustrated because he kept dying. His problem was
that he wouldn't move away from enemies when they came to attack
him. He would swing his sword while the enemies were on top of him
and this killed him eventually.</p>

<p>We got to the boss of the first temple, but I died during the
stomping part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/05/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The kids and I played this for a bit today. We did Needle Man and
couldn't do enough damage to the boss. Then we did Top Man, and
won. Then we did Hard Man (couldn't get past the second monkey)
and Gemini Man and then they got bored so we switched to a different
game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a long drive today, so I played for almost four hours. I've
had lots of cute experiences in the game. I really like the towns
in this game... they feel much more fleshed out and real than
towns in most RPGs. I decided to marry Deborah because I think her
sprite is really cool and I thought she'd be funny. So far she has
been really hilarious with all her little comments. I like it a
lot. The wedding voes were really funny because they said "until
you stop getting resurrected at church when you die" instead of
"until death do you part"... thus acknowledging that the
characters really do die and get resurrected in the story. It was
really funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
