<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-15T22:34:42-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xenoblade Chronicles (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Xenoblade-Chronicles--Wii--2012--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. The scenery was really
cool. It was awesome going through the swamp and the Bionis'
body. The visions that Schult it seeing now are very cool and I
can't wait to get to that area of the game. Dunban's new outfit
is neat too. I still think the battle system is terrible, and I
still think the world is exciting.</p>

<p>Total time: 11:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Mario All-Stars (SNES, 1993) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Super-Mario-All-Stars--SNES--1993--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played SMB1 in this for a while because my son wanted to see
some Mario. When I died and needed to continue in the World 2
castle, my son suggested that we move on to a different game. He
really enjoyed the water level in world 2.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Secret of Evermore (SNES, 1995)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Secret-of-Evermore--SNES--1995--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been telling my son the story of this game for a long time,
because he likes stories about dogs and exciting adventures by
boys. Today I suggested that he might like to see it. We played
for a bit. I forgot about how in the beginning you see the end of
the game and the various forms of the dog. Cool. We played
through to the bug boss of the pre-historic area, but I died. I
wasn't quick enough using items. I forgot that I wouldn't have a
checkpoint of some kind and we didn't save, but once. So, we
moved on to a different game.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:54</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rayman Origins (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Rayman-Origins--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son picked this game out because of its box art and it is in
my "new game queue". I'd been planning on playing it co-op with
my wife, but I couldn't dissuade him from wanting to check it
out. I've never played a Rayman game before, so I didn't know
what to expect other than that it is a platformer.</p>

<p>I found the world to be really cute and the art to be awesome.</p>

<p>I think the controls are really floaty and delayed (especially
the punches). The running doesn't feel quite right either. But
I'd say it is still on par with DKCR, and not totally terrible.</p>

<p>We played two levels. The first I played twice so I could get all
the stuff and the second I was one shiny thing away from the
second bonus. The collectathon in this game seems more fun that
the collectathons in DKCR and I'm not sure if I like them more or
less than NSMBW.</p>

<p>I couldn't figure out how to play multiplayer... maybe I just
needed to have two active controllers. Nor could I understand
what the difference between the characters were. I hope to play
it with my wife eventually, but I probably won't play again for a
while unless the kids request it.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Punch Out!! (Wii, 2009) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/15/Game--Punch-Out----Wii--2009--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this morning for a little bit... a couple rounds against
Mr. Sandman. I got a few hits in, but don't have a reliable
pattern down. I really let my kids down who were hoping for an
amazing display by Dad.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:17</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
