<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-09T15:40:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/08/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I finished getting As or above on every event in Pac-Man CE
DX. My ranking across the whole game is 5,100/245,281 or in the
top 2.07%. It's a really fun game. I think I like the normal mode
the most. The time trial is fun, but I think it's too easy to
cheese out and ignore the ghosts and just take shortcuts, so it
eliminates a bit of the unique fun of CE-DX. Such an awesome game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this for the first time tonight and my wife got a medal
on her first try at "Hole in One" (although she did watch me be
terrible at it for about 5 minutes.) Very fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The story took a bit of a depressing turn today. But it was a good
moment for the characters to come back from. Nothing particularly
exciting in the game happened though. I'm now at the part of the
game where it is possible to go to the final dungeon, but probably
not a good idea because I would be too weak. There are clearly a
lot of potential side-quests (the yellow stars on the map) that I
can go check out. I'll do a few.</p>

<p>The battling of the shadows, plus their ability to materialize for
super attacks that you ride on them during is very reminiscent of
the Eidolons in FF13. Weird.</p>

<p>023:15:05 --- Disc 3: Mechat Airship --- 33/33/31/32/31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/05/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/05/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight, although on the clock it
was only three. Since I was in Nene's fortress, I had a time limit
on myself and I pushed myself forward pretty fast. When I got to
the four robot boss fight... wow it was really hard. I probably
died 4 times. I was worried that I would have to quit the game
because when I fought around the area I was in, there were only a
few enemies and then there was no more AND I had a time limit. I
gave one more try and beat them just before I planned on giving
up. It was a frightening and annoying thought to have to quit,
although I don't think I would have really minded too
much... unfortunately. I looked at a FAQ for fight advice and it
suggested that I be at level 42... which I definitely am not.</p>

<p>As I play this game more, I'm liking Maru more and more. He's so
wacky and funny. Zola looks more and more like a tramp with every
day and her ridiculous headband is soooo <em>Snow</em>. Ugh.</p>

<p>In the final cut-scenes of the disc, Nene's mouth animations look
really weird and Nene is more and more of a jerk. Wow. What a
punk. He's not as pure evil on screen as Kefka was in FF6, but he
has the same quality where you just hate him. Shu is, of course,
super tough. I wonder where the game will go now the characters
have lost their magic (except for Shu)? Obviously they'll get them
back and save the day... but how?</p>

<p>Disc 2 was significantly short than Disc 1. 13.5 vs
about 7. Almost half as short.</p>

<p>020:55:56 --- Disc 3: Old Lady's House - 2F --- 31/31/30/29</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2007) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/04/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2007--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through two sequences tonight and started what I assume
will be the last part of this disc. The concept of the town that
had been imprisoned is kind of interesting. Nene's character---and
mainly his long history of bad-dudery---is starting to get more
interesting, although very unfulfilled from the part of the game.</p>

<p>I got all the skills for a few classes, so I've made my first
class changes. I spent some time looking through what the choices
are to make a plan for where I want the characters to end up. They
feel quite a bit weaker now that they've dropped levels. It was
annoying to not have Kluke for so long because of that power
difference.</p>

<p>019:09:18 --- Disc 2: Nene's Fortress - 1F Hallway --- 28/28/27/27/25</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
