<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-15T22:53:26-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour today and got a lot more S-ranks and
stuff.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 2,160/248,420 --- 0.86%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game as a prize from Call of Podcast for writing about
my game management system. It was on my to-buy list before that,
although I was planning on buying the PS3 version. The game looked
really beautiful and I really like Genki Rockets. I played Rez for
the Dreamcast and wasn't really blown away, but I thought that it
might be more interesting in a more modern form.</p>

<p>The game opens up with a really intriguing video and quickly shows
off its unique, beautiful world.</p>

<p>I played it for about an hour and half tonight. I beat the
first three levels on the first try, although I had to do each
twice to unlock the next level. I played the fourth level about
four times, but kept dying at the final form of the boss, because
it shoots so many tracer rounds.</p>

<p>I find the gameplay to be enjoyable and challenging, at least when
you get totally overwhelmed by bullets. I suppose I should get
better at using the screen clearing bombs. The addition of the
tracer rounds seems like it would be an insignificant change, but
it makes a huge difference compared to Rez.</p>

<p>I love the music, although I wish that there were more vocals,
like the actual Genki Rockets song. It may be that I'm not playing
well enough to unlock them though... on that note, I dislike how
it seems like I am doing the levels perfect (not getting hit,
getting mostly perfect octo-locks) but I'm only get three stars a
pop. It's weird.</p>

<p>I love that every level is totally different visually and aurally
from the others. This game is the perfect of a game that seems
like it was made on a totally different planet. I've played plenty
of Japanese games that do this, but most Western games lack that
kind of creativity.</p>

<p>I intend to keep trucking at it and beat. I haven't yet decided if
I will play through the hard mode or if I will just periodically
play through the whole game when I want to chill out to some rad
music, or show someone the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/14/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The wife and I watched two more episodes. The game continues to be
really funny. A little thing I really liked that we noticed today
was that the voice of York is different when he is hearing himself
talk than when the camera is from a third-person perspective. Very
subtle, but neat. Something I enjoy about the narrator guy is that
he talks so matter-of-factly about some of the strange stuff going
in the game. It adds to the absurdity.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I'm
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I'm on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I'll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but...</p>

<p>I can't remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I'm not compelled by this one at all. It's a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There's a
"blindside" system, but it's basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren't ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It's frustrating that
you can't really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there's no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you'll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You'll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it's
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don't think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I'm glad I've played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got another S-rank.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 3,144/248,092 --- 1.26%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
