<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-20T22:46:21-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Super Meat Boy (X360, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Super-Meat-Boy--X360--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another night of 5-19X. This level makes me hate the game.</p>

<p>Super Meat Boy is great when (a) a level has really good flow and
(b) the challenges are bite-sized, so that when you fail you don't
have to repeat long sequences of difficulty stuff.</p>

<p>Normal games can't be as hard as Super Meat Boy because they are
committed to long levels and don't give instant, infinite
respawns.</p>

<p>This level (and a few other levels) totally break the design of
the game. There are basically 5 totally independent challenges
that have nothing to do with one another and almost all of the
require you to stop moving and dodge, rather than having a flow
from one thing to the next.</p>

<p>(My point here is that a reductive
view of this issue would say that every jump is a unique
challenge. The difference is that running down a hallway in SMB is
a single coherent challenge because you must have the right flow
and tempo.)</p>

<p>Super Meat Boy is a great game when it is fulfilling its design
goals, but when it forgets them... it is horrifically bad.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this tonight. Last time I played, I could barely
get past the first level because it is so brutal and you need to
grind, but it's practically impossible. This time, I tried to use
a code that gave more hearts per heart icon you got, but it didn't
really help. I used a password that gave me more levels and that
made a big difference. The hardest part of the game was the third
fortress, because it was so complex of a labyrinth. It's a fun
game... a little too floaty jumps and the inability to scroll
backward is bit rough, but for an old game it has pretty decent
mechanics. Although it is a classic in my memory, it's systems
don't live up to being a real classic.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I used Amy exclusively and
beat the third challenge. I did really good on the third full
course tournament... until the 13th hole when I went from first to
last place by the end. Ouch.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about twenty minutes. I bought Amy and tried to do
the third challenge again. I ran out of batteries before I could
finish though.</p>

<p>Total time: 10:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Sin & Punishment: Star Successor (Wii, 2010) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/15/Game--Sin---Punishment--Star-Successor--Wii--2010--11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for another 20 minutes. I got the boss down to
about 750... much better than I've done before. Before the X-RGB
I hadn't got past 1500; after the X-RGB I got to 1200, and today
I did even better. I feel like the end is in sight.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
