<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T23:15:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Later in the day, I played for almost three hours.</p>

<p>I beat up to level 5. I find the game to be so much like LoZ but
bigger in ways that don't make it better.</p>

<p>There are some similar items (like the Rainbow Drop is the same as
the Ladder) and some unique ones (like the Glowing Moss). But
there's a lot that isn't there and what is added isn't great.</p>

<p>The levels are all a lot bigger, but they look too much the same
that they are extremely confusing and kind of frustrating. Same
with the various overworlds.</p>

<p>There are upgrades to your armor and weapon, but they don't really
feel much better because the enemies are getting stronger too. (In
contrast, in LoZ, the enemies in the overworld are all the same
and as you get stronger stuff, you see the same guys more and get
to thrash them.)</p>

<p>The bosses are huge and cool looking, but they take way too long
to kill once you've learned their pattern and can totally avoid
being hit.</p>

<p>Overall, the game just isn't as refined as LoZ. I got over the
problems with the combat with a little more attention, but I feel
like the rest of the game will just be a chore. I don't think I
will finish it.</p>

<p>I bet if I grew up with a TurboGrafx rather than a Nintendo, I
would love this game, but as it stands, it's just meh.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:05</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Neutopia (TG16, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/19/Game--Neutopia--TG16--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about a half an hour today on an emulator.</p>

<p>It's a strange game. It seems like it is trying to be Legend of
Zelda I, but it has tried to evolve, it seems. For instance, I
felt like inside every cave was a person just blathering on about
stuff that didn't matter. The combat feels a bit... off. It's
like it is very hard to line enemies up. In LTTP, since the sword
slices in an arc, it never really matters if you aren't lined up
perfectly. In LoZ, you do need to be straight, but I think the
enemies are guaranteed to be in a grid, so it is easy to hit
them. It's a strange thing to miss. It seems like the dungeons
are much more linear and I got to the end of one, but couldn't
beat the boss (after a ton of tries)... it seems to have way too
much health.</p>

<p>I will give it another session... but I'm not impressed.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:27</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Ninja-Gaiden-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this game tonight. I found it to be less
ridiculously hard than the first one because I found the powerups
and ninja power recharges to be more available. The environmental
hazards (wind, darkness, etc) were really rough. The cinema
sequences are way too long. I found confirmation in this
play-through of something that James Rolfe said in AVGN: you
forget that there is a health bar in this game, because you only
normally die by being whacked off platforms when you get
hit. It's so true. Also, the powerup that shoots fire diagonally
upwards is soooo good.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Batman (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/18/Game--Batman--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about two and half hours. A little more
than the final hour was spent on the last level trying to get up
the vertical passage with the gears. It was unbearably
brutalizing. If you could just shoot up or if the jump were a
little bit more controllable, I could have done it. But I decided
that I was interested in the ending that much.</p>

<p>Overall, this game is feels really great. The different weapons
are all useful and fun. The jumping is pretty nice and the
wall-hanging works much better than in Ninja Gaiden. Surprisingly
good!</p>

<p>Total time: 2:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/17/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Skull Man's stage tonight (my son is very
fascinated with his appearance.) It was a fun level and I managed
to get an E tank and lots of 1-UPs on it. I had 4 lives for the
boss fight but was totally destroyed. I feel like in these later
Mega Man games, it is impossible to beat bosses out of
order. It's a bit disappointing that it isn't as free, but it
doesn't detract that much from the experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
