<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Video Games | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/video-games/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-13T23:35:29-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I'm
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I'm on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I'll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but...</p>

<p>I can't remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I'm not compelled by this one at all. It's a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There's a
"blindside" system, but it's basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren't ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It's frustrating that
you can't really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there's no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you'll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You'll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it's
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don't think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I'm glad I've played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just got another S-rank.</p>

<p>New overall ranking: 3,144/248,092 --- 1.26%</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Pac-Man CE DX (X360, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Pac-Man-CE-DX--X360--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today and a few weeks ago, I improved my score a bit. I am now
3,526/248,092, in the top 1.42%. I still have a few modes that are
not all As. I plan on getting all As and then eventually Ss.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Deadly Premonition (X360, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/11/Game--Deadly-Premonition--X360--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We watched the next episode where he spends a lot of time at the
Milk Barn. I loved looking at each of the different products in
the store. There was more clear Japanese translations. It was also
funny to have him role-play as York a little bit. It's strange
that everyone talks about York's scar.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour tonight and mainly did story and
exploration stuff. I got the ability to go to other planets and
got to the medieval world. The game is okay so far. I haven't
really been captured by it. I'm not sure why. The combat system
doesn't seem as advanced as I'd like and a lot of the world is
pretty empty and samey. I'll keep playing, but I'm a bit sad I
haven't been totally won over by it.</p>

<p>Total: 3:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
