<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: El Shaddai: Ascension of the Metatron | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/el-shaddai-ascension-of-the-metatron/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-16T09:43:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: El Shaddai: Ascension of the Metatron (PS3, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/04/Game--El-Shaddai--Ascension-of-the-Metatron--PS3--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/04/Game--El-Shaddai--Ascension-of-the-Metatron--PS3--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just beat El Shaddai: Ascension of the Metatron. I pre-ordered
the game and I've been sitting on it waiting to put down Resonance
of Fate, which I've been playing for about a month, but it is
grinding me down.</p>

<p>I started this game on Thursday and beat it today. It was a pretty
fast game, but very memorable.</p>

<p>Mechanically, the game is a 3D action game with platforming
sequences and special 2D platforming levels. There is also a
single racing level. Every mechanical part of the game is
acceptable. The 2D platforming is very good in my opinion. The
racing sequence is better than a lot of racing sequences in games
(about as good as the racing sequence in my beloved Bayonetta.)
The 3D platforming kind of sucks, but I don't like 3D platforming
anyway. This game makes it a bit worse than normal because of the
crazy visuals, but ultimately it's pretty much okay. The 3D action
game doesn't have anywhere near the depth I'd like, but it does
its own thing and is successful at it.</p>

<p>The combat system is based on a Rock-Paper-Scissors system with
three different weapons that are more powerful versus another
weapon, etc. You can switch on a whim, instead you must steal a
weapon from an enemy. This creates a fun dynamic where you have to
plan out a battle in a split second by deciding which enemies to
attack in which order. It's simple and pretty fun and the weapons
all feel different. Overall, there's no major flaws in this part
of the game, but you wouldn't play it just for it. It does ensure
that this really is a game and not just a long cinematic-spotted
corridor. I think my only complaint about it is that you never
feel like the avatar is getting stronger in anyway, so combat in
the beginning of the game is almost exactly like combat at the
end. However, this isn't totally true because you as a player
advance and you can deal with more enemies, more variations,
etc.</p>

<p>Getting away from passable, interesting, but not spectacular
mechanics, this game really shines in the presentation
department. For example, there is absolutely no HUD and you don't
need it.</p>

<p>The most appropriate word for this game is "fantastic" in the
sense of inspring awe and bafflement at the world it creates.</p>

<p>The story centers on fallen angels who have created mini-paradises
for themselves and humans on the Earth. These paradises are
unimaginable. In most games, something looks good when it
simulates reality well, or when it gives you a well realized
vision. In El Shaddai, nothing really looks like anything you've
seen or thought of before and doesn't really seem like it should
either. There are sooo many crazy details. For example, as you
approach the angels' tower, there is lightly shimmering text on
the ground you're walking on. In other times, when you are in a
particularly angelic place, it is so bright that it hurts your
eyes and looks like nothing that could ever exist on Earth. It's
really quite amazing.</p>

<p>What is so much more amazing though is that each level of the game
looks nothing like any of the other levels. They are all
incredibly unique. Sometimes it even seems like the character
model is changing to better fit the new area. It's very bizarre
and interesting. The futuristic/racing world was particularly
different, but each was different in a special way.</p>

<p>The story is baffling. I can't tell if that's because of the
ancient Jewish origin or the Japanese interpretation. Either way,
it's baffling in a way that evokes interesting ideas and
feelings. There's something really cool about a world where
Lucifel, the pre-fallen Lucifer, talks to God on a cell phone and
wears designer jeans.</p>

<p>When you beat the game, it clearly challenges you to play it again
on harder difficulties and perform some feats, but I don't think
the game is mechanically appealing enough to actually do it. This
is definitely not a cine-game where you don't feel like you did
anything, but on the other hand, it's nowhere close to something
like Bayonetta or Ikaruga where you want to beat it on every
difficulty level and do everything it offers.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say this is a must player.</p>

<p>Best Reader: YOU</p>

<p>I like <a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2011/08/16/el-shaddai-ascension-of-the-metatron-review/">JC Fletcher's review</a>: "It's not fair to categorize the
weirdness as part and parcel of a Japanese game; this is more like
something that arrived fully formed from another planet." and "If
you want a game in which you battle nautilus-headed henchmen in an
underwater disco while a mute, dreadlocked fallen angel obscures
your view with his earnest dancing ... your dream has been
fulfilled."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
