<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Kid Icarus | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/kid-icarus/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T23:15:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this tonight. Last time I played, I could barely
get past the first level because it is so brutal and you need to
grind, but it's practically impossible. This time, I tried to use
a code that gave more hearts per heart icon you got, but it didn't
really help. I used a password that gave me more levels and that
made a big difference. The hardest part of the game was the third
fortress, because it was so complex of a labyrinth. It's a fun
game... a little too floaty jumps and the inability to scroll
backward is bit rough, but for an old game it has pretty decent
mechanics. Although it is a classic in my memory, it's systems
don't live up to being a real classic.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have very found memories of playing Kid Icarus a lot and
associate it with Metroid in my mind as one of those great NES
games with a system that modern games have kind of forgot. I
played it again recently and was utterly destroyed by it. The
cruelty of the games defies description: there is basically no way
to restore health during one of the long levels (except the
fortresses) and when you move from one level to another, you keep
however much health you had during the last one without bringing
it up to full, so you can get irreparably in the hole. Plus,
you need to grind to increase your maximum possible life. I got to
the first fortress and was destroyed. When I remember back to
being young and playing this, I seem to recall using a password to
get to the end a lot, so I tried that it was fun to play that
again, but I really wish I could play through the game proper.</p>

<p>Playing through that portion made me realize that it really isn't
anything like Metroid. In a sense, Metroid takes a run-n-gun
platformer (like Contra) and combines it with a Zelda-like item
upgrade and open world structure. In contrast, Kid Icarus
takes a run-n-gun platformer (like Contra) and adds just two
aspects of RPGs: item stores and grinding. Not the best things to
add, in my opinion.</p>

<p>I will play it again, but I'll move on to the next game for
now. I've realized that what I want to do is take a first pass at
all the older games that I remember or have heard so much about
and figure out which ones I really do want to invest some time
in. If the game is appealing enough, then I'll play through it
right then, otherwise I'll mark it down in my list to continue
with later. This game definitely makes the cut for the "play in
the future" list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
