<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: ESPgaluda II: Black Label | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/espgaluda-ii-black-label/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-15T06:06:40-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: ESPgaluda II: Black Label (X360, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--ESPgaluda-II--Black-Label--X360--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/28/Game--ESPgaluda-II--Black-Label--X360--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Late last year I got エスプガルーダII from someone on the SHMUPS
forum. I didn't start playing it every day until January, when I
stopped playing Mushi every day. My scores as of now are:
- ESPGaluda II - 360 Novice - Asagi: All-Clear. 217,480,251 points. #669 #hiscore #1cc
- ESPGaluda II - Black Label Novice - Seseri: All-Clear. 229,344,460 points. #938 #hiscore #1cc
- ESPGaluda II - Arrange - Tateha: Stage 2. 2,888,170 points. #1320 #hiscore
- ESPGaluda II - Omake! - Asagi: All-Clear. 496,851,202 points. #hiscore #1cc
- ESPGaluda II - 360 - Asagi: Stage 2. 1,615,157 points. #1675 #hiscore
- ESPGaluda II - 360 - Ageha: Stage 3. 12,034,604 points. #771 #hiscore</p>

<p>I was able to easily 1CC the easy modes, but I've been working on
the normal modes for some time.</p>

<p>The art in the game is very pretty, but not as fantastical as
Mushi. Most of the enemies are human (they leave blood stains on
the ground, eww) or normal military-looking things, which I find
kind of boring. Nevertheless, the art, given the style, is
great.</p>

<p>The music on the first level is AMAZING, but the music for the
rest of the game is just so-so.</p>

<p>The scoring system is interesting. Basically, you get gems and
gold. Killing enemies drops gems. You can use gems to slow down
time. When you destroy an enemy and time is slowed, then all their
bullets become gold. (If you try to slow down time, but don't have
gems, time speeds up. If you kill enemies in this mode, they drop
gold. Also, you are always getting points just for being in this
mode.) Now, time is slower for the bullets, but not the
characters, so by slowing down time you build up many bullets on
the screen and you can cash them all in for gold if you picked a
good time (where good time means you can kill the enemy.) This is
a really neat risk/reward system because you can spend gems to
make it easier to dodge or to get high scores; and, getting high
scores means there needs to be many bullets, and you need to
accurately gauge if you can kill the enemy with the number of gems
you have, otherwise all those bullets will need to be dodged.</p>

<p>While it is very interesting, I don't find the game as enjoyable
as Mushi. It doesn't have the same pace or something. I've played
it every day for about six months and I think I will play it much
less frequently, and spend more time with Mushi.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
