<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2012 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2012/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T00:21:19-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Lorax, by Dr. Seuss (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Movie--The-Lorax--by-Dr--Seuss--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Movie--The-Lorax--by-Dr--Seuss--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I took my son to this today. It was his first time going to a movie
theatre. We had a lot of fun. We had to sit in the very front row,
because he couldn't see over any of the other seats. I think I will
bring a booster in the future. We got popcorn and played arcade
games after too.</p>

<p>The movie was very well made with really neat visuals. The story
is, of course, anti-freedom and greatly misunderstands
capitalism. The Once-ler is not bad because he cuts down trees,
he's a bad businessman because he doesn't have a lasting business
strategy. He should have replanted as he cut them down. The Lorax
would like people to live in poverty and pain. O'Hare is the
classic business-as-murderous kind, which is absurd. My son and I
had a talk about the bad economics in the movie afterwards.</p>

<p>I read the Wikipedia page on the critical response. There's this
text:</p>

<p>David Edelstein: "the touch of their tufts was much softer than
silk and they had the sweet smell of fresh butterfly milk" -- and
[in the movie] Ted says, "Wow, what does that even mean?" and
Audrey says, "I know, right?" So one of the only lines that is from
the book, that does have Dr. Seuss' sublime whimsy, is basically
made fun of, or at least, dragged down to Earth."</p>

<p>What an idiot! Obviously Ted says that because they don't know what
silk or what butterflies are. They aren't making fun of the line!
It is a brilliant way of making fun of the emptiness of their lives
in Thneedville!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Mirror Mirror, starring Lily Collins (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Movie--Mirror-Mirror--starring-Lily-Collins--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/18/Movie--Mirror-Mirror--starring-Lily-Collins--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really awesome movie. The costumes and visuals were
amazing. The re-writing of the Snow White story was really
cool. Collins looked stunning. I loved the dance scene at the end
too. It was rad. The funny digs were neat too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Dark Knight Rises, directed by Christopher Nolan (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie--The-Dark-Knight-Rises--directed-by-Christopher-Nolan--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/11/Movie--The-Dark-Knight-Rises--directed-by-Christopher-Nolan--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cool movie. I thought they did a great job setting
up Cat Woman and Blake as interesting characters. I liked all the
tragedy and doubt that was part of the plot... it made it more
dramatic. It's also cool how they incorporated the
Bane-destroys-Batman storyline from the comic. All around there was
cool stuff. I'm glad that they allowed the ending to really be an
ending.</p>

<p>My only complaint is that Bane's voice was a little too hard to
understand in a few key moments... it made me want subtitles, which
of course you can't have in a theatre.</p>

<p>Despite Nolan's insistence that the movie is not anti-Occupy, I
think it very much is. It shows the commies for what they really
are: blood-thirsty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Lockout, starring Guy Pearce (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/10/Movie--Lockout--starring-Guy-Pearce--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun, fast-paced action movie. I liked how the world of
the future was very different, but there was no explanation of why
or how or in what way. It just looked really foreign, which was
pretty cool. The two lead villains were very crazy and
interesting. The main character, Snow, was very wise-cracking and
fun. Overall, the movie was a fun ride.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Avengers, directed by Joss Whedon (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/01/Movie--The-Avengers--directed-by-Joss-Whedon--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a great movie. Every character was very exciting and they
did a great job spreading out the interesting scenes for the
different characters. The only characters that weren't totally
awesome were Hawkeye and Black Widow, because they weren't really
super heroes... more "super spys" and that didn't seem to fit as
well. Also, I thought Hawkeye was a bit too shallow of a
character... the actor played him too "cool" and above-it-all.</p>

<p>There were some awesome jokes and funny moments. One of my
favourites was when Captain America, reacting to hearing that Thor
and Loki are gods, says, "Ma'am, there's only one God, and I don't
think He dresses like that." Not only was it delivered really well,
but it's such a great comment for his character as the epitome of
America.</p>

<p>Mark Ruffalo as the Hulk was great too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
