<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2012 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2012/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-25T23:32:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played twenty minutes of Monkey Watch today. I couldn't make it
out of the practice again. I was able to reliably hit the yellow
monkeys but couldn't get the purple ones at all. Not a single
time. This game is very frustrating. I'm doing terribly, but
it doesn't communicate to me in any way what I'm doing wrong. In
addition, I'm now blocked from doing any other of the
mini-games... even though they will definitely test different
rhythm skills than this one. I want to play this game and
experience more, but I can't. Argh.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:38</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gravity Rush (Vita, 2012) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Gravity-Rush--Vita--2012--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Gravity-Rush--Vita--2012--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It's been about a month since I've played this game and I'm not
really interested in trying it again. It's a cute concept and the
world is pretty interesting, but the controls and gameplay just
aren't compelling enough to last much longer than I've
played. It's too imprecise and the touch controls are
obnoxious. I almost feel like if this game were on PS3 I would
enjoy it a lot more. It also has a Portal-esque quality to it in
the way you move around (there aren't gravity puzzles, as far as
I've seen.)</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Green Lantern: Emerald Knights, by D.C. Comics (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/19/Movie--Green-Lantern--Emerald-Knights--by-D-C--Comics--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-19T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/19/Movie--Green-Lantern--Emerald-Knights--by-D-C--Comics--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We saw this movie advertised at the beginning of another and it
seemed pretty neat. The mythology of the Green Lantern world is
pretty cool (based on my knowledge from the live action movie) so
we decided to get it on Netflix. It was pretty bad. The plot is so
weak and most of the stories are tiny facades around a big fight
scene. The fight scenes aren't even that interesting, because the
rings are just used as laser cannons. One of the coolest things
about the Green Lanterns is their ability to make anything with
the ring, but that wasn't utilized very well. Overall, this was a
very disappointing movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/18/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours tonight. I used Amy exclusively and
beat the third challenge. I did really good on the third full
course tournament... until the 13th hole when I went from first to
last place by the end. Ouch.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Hot Shots Golf: World Invitational (Vita, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/17/Game--Hot-Shots-Golf--World-Invitational--Vita--2012--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about twenty minutes. I bought Amy and tried to do
the third challenge again. I ran out of batteries before I could
finish though.</p>

<p>Total time: 10:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
