<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2012 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2012/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-13T23:35:29-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Awakening, starring Kate Beckinsale (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Movie--Underworld--Awakening--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was the fasted paced and immediately insane movie. It's
practically equivalent to the insanity of the fourth Resident Evil
movie. The amount the world of the movies changes in the first five
minutes is unbelievable. Yet, they pack in lots of really
fascinating and sensible ideas and imagery. It's spectacular.</p>

<p>The story is interesting, although it is unclear why they would
need to be studying the hybrids, but whatever. The quality of the
Lycan models continues to improve, although their heads are still
not quite right. This movie removes all sympathy for the Lycans
that was in the background of the 1st and 3rd movies. It basically
does absolutely nothing for the mythology either. Perhaps it will
be more successful because of that, because you don't really need
to know anything about the previous movies to appreciate this
one. The mythological wankery only appeals to some, but this could
appeal to many.</p>

<p>The movie was noticeably more gory than previous movies. The only
time this bothered me was at the very beginning when Selene was
killing humans escaping. I don't mind gore when it is directed at
monsters or aliens, but humans shouldn't receive it. It is also
kind of uncharacteristic, because the previous movies have
established a vampire moral code that limits their consumption of
human blood.</p>

<p>I was surprised that Michael Corvin is basically not in the
movie. I was expecting him to come back and save the day in the
final fight after Selene had released him. (The actual ending
though, was supremely feminist, as the mother and daughter don't
really need help from the father, or men in general.) But I suppose
it was based on some contractual reason.</p>

<p>The Wikipedia page contains story information that I didn't get
from the movie. For example, the daughter's name is Eve and the
secret of the immortals was revealed to humans by the
doctor. Weird.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Rhythm Heaven Fever (Wii, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/06/Game--Rhythm-Heaven-Fever--Wii--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this for the first time tonight and my wife got a medal
on her first try at "Hole in One" (although she did watch me be
terrible at it for about 5 minutes.) Very fun.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Hunger Games, starring Jennifer Lawrence (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Movie--The-Hunger-Games--starring-Jennifer-Lawrence--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/23/Movie--The-Hunger-Games--starring-Jennifer-Lawrence--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I saw this on opening day, because my wife was going with some
friends and someone fell through, so I took the last ticket. I have
never read the books, so I don't really have opinions or
predilections about it. I thought the world was neat. They did a
good job showing the opulence of the people in the capitol, but I
don't think they really made the oppression disgusting enough. The
action was fun and she was pretty heroic---I found myself tearing
up a few times. I find the world to be pretty unbelievable
though. I don't understand how the people in the capitol could be
supportive of the oppression, when they don't seem to be kept in
the dark or otherwise "brainwashed" into thinking that they are
doing great things for the districts. Similarly, I don't understand
why they would not take better care of the districts or why the
districts would not have already gone on strike. The idea that this
could go on for 74 years strains credulity. I don't think Katniss
is a very consistent character. The movie communicated to me that
she was all about doing the right thing and would rather die than
not do that; yet, she doesn't do a whole lot against "the man". For
example, when she talks to Peter at night before the games start,
he says he wants to show that he is not "owned" and she agrees, but
says she'd like to go home. The way this scene plays out and how
she is so non-aggressive during the games said to me that she
really agreed with him. Yet, she never actually does anything to go
against them. Dying together at the end is a little bit like that,
but you get the impression that she knew they wouldn't let her do
it, and therefore it was an empty calculation rather than a
confident objection. Overall, I really enjoyed the movie, but I
felt like it could be more. My wife says that it is part one of a
trilogy and my wishes will come true in some way in the
future. That's fine... but... it's annoying when you need to know
something about the real world to appreciate a movie... when it
can't satisfy you on its own.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 2 (PS3, 2012) - Completion Times]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--25/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--25</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Episode    1: 000:00:00 (2012/01/31) - 002:47:03 (2012/01/31)
Episode    2: 002:47:03 (2012/01/31) - 004:56:03 (2012/02/01)
Episode   3a: 004:56:03 (2012/02/01) - 009:26:45 (2012/02/04)
Episode   3b: 009:26:45 (2012/02/04) - 012:47:25 (2012/02/04)
Episode    4: 012:47:25 (2012/02/04) - 027:40:05 (2012/02/12)
Episode    5: 027:40:05 (2012/02/12) - 034:01:46 (2012/02/16)
Episode Last: 034:01:46 (2012/02/16) - 036:27:04 (2012/02/16)
First win   : 036:27:04 (2012/02/16)
Second win  : 059:16:09 (2012/02/26)
Done        : 059:54:36 (2012/02/27)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 2 (PS3, 2012) - Thoughts about reviews]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--24/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/27/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--24</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://feeds.joystiq.com/~r/weblogsinc/joystiq/~3/J72px2lMtpU/">Joystiq</a> - He mentions some appalling music tracks: agree. He
doesn't like Chocobolina: I agree, but I also don't care. He
thought it was hard: I disagree. I don't think his review is very
deep.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.destructoid.com/review-final-fantasy-xiii-2-220373.phtml">Destructoid</a> - I like the review.</p>

<p><a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~r/kotaku/excerpts/~3/2gL3kyCtDGw/final-fantasy-xiii%2B2-the-kotaku-review">Kotaku</a> - Also like it</p>

<p><a href="http://www.reddit.com/r/JRPG/comments/p3cqr/final_fantasy_xiii2_edge_review/">Edge</a> - They agree it is too easy. I would say that it is mildly
satisfying to get 5 stars and that not giving any input won't get
you that.</p>

<p><a href="http://feedproxy.google.com/~r/GamasutraNews/~3/3OZ_bZ1jOrI/Questioning_the_vision_behind_Final_Fantasy_XIII2.php">Christian Nutt in Gamasutra</a> - His main critic is that the game is
far too reactionary and lacks its own vision. I agree with
this. The story didn't need to be told, which is why it comes out
of left field. But the engine could have been kept and given a new
vision, but I guess that would take too long?</p>

<p><a href="http://www.2d-x.com/the-final-fantasy-xiii-2-diaries-part-two/">2D-X Diaries</a> - I agree that Noel looks like Sorah and Alyssa looks
like Samus (and has ridiculous hot pants.)</p>

<p><a href="http://feeds.gawker.com/~r/kotaku/excerpts/~3/eq5Lmwvykds/in-case-you-skipped-final-fantasy-xiii-heres-a-breakdancing-recap-rap">Breaking Rap</a> - Amazing</p>

<p><a href="http://www.wethegamerz.com/2012/02/08/the-slots-of-serendipity-how-ffxiii-2-has-the-worst-minigame-ever/">Slots are the worst</a> - Yup</p>

<p><a href="http://www.joystiq.com/2012/02/15/do-japanese-rpgs-need-a-good-story/">Kat Bailey on Battle > Story</a> - Yup</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
