<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2012 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2012/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-06T06:53:51-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/04/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I showed my wife the awesome Wyzen fight and then did the next
two episodes. The "ending" was cool and the awesome arm-less
fight. This game is just sooo ridiculous. I can tell my wife is
kind of appalled at how insane it is. I love that about it.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Asura's Wrath (PS3, 2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Asura-s-Wrath--PS3--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought this game on the recommendation of the Giant Bomb
podcast. Tonight I played for a little less than two hours and
played through the first five episodes. This game is insane. I
love the over-the-top-ness. I love the TV show stylings. The
combat and shooting feel interesting and like I'm doing something,
although I get the impression that I can't lose and it's just a
matter of smashing enough until I can Burst, although I suppose I
could simply pay attention to my score at the end. So far, I think
it's a really unique and amazing experience.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Wrath of the Titans, starring Sam Worthington (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/01/Movie--Wrath-of-the-Titans--starring-Sam-Worthington--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This movie was fun, but definitely not as good as the first one. I
think the plot was much weaker and the cast was kind of thrown
together for no good reason---whereas the first one had a very
nice progression of how people joined the group.</p>

<p>Rosamund Pike was very beautiful, but it was very weird that the
actress from the previous movie was replaced and because she acted
so differently than the character before I didn't realize it was
supposed to be the same person.</p>

<p>Overall, I don't feel like the sequel was really necessary, which
is unfortunate, because I thought the first one was so good.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Tron: Legacy, starring Jeff Bridges (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/27/Movie--Tron--Legacy--starring-Jeff-Bridges--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/27/Movie--Tron--Legacy--starring-Jeff-Bridges--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a much better movie than the last one. I think my
favourite part of it was how it is basically the story of Catholic
theology: God enters the Void and creates Angels to assist Him in
creating perfection, but later finds (or creates) Humans, who are
imperfect, but have agency and can therefore grow and experience
love, but this upsets His chief Angel who fights against Him out of
jealousy. This particular story takes an approach very similar to
His Dark Materials, where God loses and someone has to come and
save him. The film is very cool throughout.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 13 2 (PS3, 2012) - DLC]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--26/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-13-2--PS3--2012--26</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I wrote in my calendar to check on the DLC about six months after
I beat the game, when presumably it would all have been
released. It has. I looked for information about it and almost
none of it seems interesting, except Lightning's episode. But, I
found that it only takes about 25 minutes (including cut-scenes)
and that's not worth 5 bucks, so I just watched it. The new ending
is neat. I'm excited for 13-3. I love this battle system so much
and I find the world to be really cool too. I hope it can be
efficient for them to produce, make them lots of money, and make
FF15 amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
