<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2012 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2012/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-17T08:05:33-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: John Carter, starring Taylor Kitsch (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie--John-Carter--starring-Taylor-Kitsch--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/12/Movie--John-Carter--starring-Taylor-Kitsch--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had heard a little about this movie when it came out, but nothing
really special. My parents wanted to watch a movie together and I
saw this on Amazon and suggested it.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the movie. It's very much unlike anything else in
its grand scheme. Maybe a little bit like Stargate. It takes a
little while to get started, but once it does, the pay-off is
great. I think what I like most about it is the way it spins a
world so well.</p>

<p>It makes me very interested in reading the series of books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: One for the Money, starring Katherine Heigl (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie--One-for-the-Money--starring-Katherine-Heigl--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/10/Movie--One-for-the-Money--starring-Katherine-Heigl--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My mom recommended this movie to us, as she has been reading the
series it is based on for a long time. I found the movie charming
and cute. It was a nice light mystery with some subtle romantic and
funny moments. It makes me interested in the books.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Amazing Spider-Man, starring Andrew Garfield (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--The-Amazing-Spider-Man--starring-Andrew-Garfield--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/06/Movie--The-Amazing-Spider-Man--starring-Andrew-Garfield--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I rarely see movies in the theatre, but I was very interested in
seeing this, so we took the opportunity of free babysitting and
went out.</p>

<p>I'm not a Spider-Man super-fan, but I am familiar with the comic
book mythos enough to really appreciate this movie.</p>

<p>I like the structure of the plot and I really like the interaction
of Gwen and Peter. In the Toby McGuire movies, they weren't
adorable enough together, but this movie does a good job of giving
them lots of awkward moments. I think Emma Stone really makes
it. She's got a beautiful face too, which is nice for all the
close-ups they give the couple.</p>

<p>I quite like the development of Pete's understanding of being
Spider-Man and I found the moment on the bridge to be really
emotional, as well as the crane scene.</p>

<p>I thought they did some good work establishing room to work in a
new franchise. There are cameos of The Daily Bugle, Peter's
technique of taking pictures for it, Flash, as well as the central
focus of Oscorp.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed the childishness of Peter: talking on his cell
phone, pranking on the villains, etc.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: This Means War, starring Reese Witherspoon (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/Movie--This-Means-War--starring-Reese-Witherspoon--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/20/Movie--This-Means-War--starring-Reese-Witherspoon--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a totally over the top movie. It's silly, kind of stupid,
but fun at the same time.</p>

<p>There are some funny moments and characters---like the way the CIA
teams act on the "case" and Lauren's friend Trish. The action
scenes are of the "super fast" type without much impact.</p>

<p>There a few moments of real romance---when FDR takes Lauren home or
when he's watching Titantic and the look on Tuck's ex-wife's face
at the end. The main problem with the romantic plot is that
everyone is being so dishonest with each other, there's no meaning
behind their actions.</p>

<p>But overall, I feel like a lot of the actors aren't really acting
together, just in the same room. It feels very
forced. (Particularly Trish actually, she's doesn't look at Lauren
enough when they're talking... it's very unnatural.)</p>

<p>Reese Witherspoon looks really good in the movie. However,
sometimes it feels like she's trying too hard to look
sexy... particularly in the sex scene with FDR. The way the
characters are connect to each other... it's like ballroom dancing
where FDR is the frame to show off her legs and stomach. Yet
another example of the unnaturalness in the movie.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Vow, starring Rachel McAdams and Channing Tatum (2012)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/17/Movie--The-Vow--starring-Rachel-McAdams-and-Channing-Tatum--2012--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very cute movie. There were a lot of cute moments. I
felt like the people in it were unrealistically mean to basically
everyone. I read the Wikipedia page and it talked about the real
couple was very religious and credit God for keeping them
together. It would have been nice to acknowledge that it
someway... but the couple in the movie weren't even married in a
church.</p>

<p>I think my favourite parts of the movie were the very subtle signs
of how much they loved each other. Such as rolling up the window
and the cat. Very cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
