<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Zelda II: The Adventures of Link | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/zelda-ii-the-adventures-of-link/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-04T23:17:08-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Zelda II: The Adventures of Link (NES, 1987)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/10/16/Game--Zelda-II--The-Adventures-of-Link--NES--1987--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/10/16/Game--Zelda-II--The-Adventures-of-Link--NES--1987--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Zelda II: The Adventure of Link over a few
nights. The first night I got familiar with the game and leveled a
bit. The next night I beat the first palace and explored up to the
second palace. I didn't play for a while and then I played again
tonight. I played through to the sixth palace and got to the
boss. I died in my first fight with the boss and decided to put
the game down for the night. However, when I reset the cart so
that I could save the SRAM on my PowerPak it said that there was a
fatal error and I couldn't backup the SRAM. When I turned it back
on, I had lost my save data.</p>

<p>I had one boss and the last dungeon between me and the end of the
game. I declare it a draw. Maybe I'll try again some day, but it
is so debilitating to have to redo so much.</p>

<p>I don't remember playing this game as much as the first Zelda when
I was younger. I remember the first palace and the general style
of the game very much, but I don't remember making a lot of
progress or being very attached to it. When I played through this
time, I thought it was fun.</p>

<p>It has a reputation for being very difficult. I thought it was
about the same difficulty, but there were some things that were
different enough to feel harder. For example, after losing all
your lives, you don't continue at the place where you are, you go
back to the start of the whole game and it may be a long walk
back. This feels quite frustrating. Another thing is that a lot of
the enemies are cheap NES mobs that soak up a lot of damage and
seem impossible to every really connect with (the many shield
enemies are like this.) Finally, there are
Castlevania-Medusea-esque floating heads that knock you off a jump
when you are going over lava pits. Arrggh. There are some things
that seem easier, like the opportunity to level and cast spells
and that you can easily get all your health/magic back outside a
dungeon.</p>

<p>I definitely enjoyed the game and it will be on my long-run
rotation.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
