<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Sherlock | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/sherlock/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-19T23:15:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 3 - The Reichenbach Fall]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-3---The-Reichenbach-Fall-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-3---The-Reichenbach-Fall-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a CRAZY episode. The whole plot line is pretty cool and
exciting, but I kind of wish there was more in it. For example,
Holmes doesn't defend himself at all, but it would great for him
to do so. I loved that he was in contempt of court, but we don't
know what he said. There were lots of clever moments like that. I
loved the way Moriarty explained that social engineering is more
effective than hacking. I thought the ending was far too obvious,
especially with regard to Holmes enlisting Molly's help. In that
respect it is obvious, but on the other hand it is ridiculous
that there's going to be an explanation for how he survived,
tricked the people at morgue (presumably Molly just did it?),
etc. I'm a bit pessimistic about where the show will go from
here. The ending is so "Mission Impossible" in its incredulity,
that I could imagine Moriarty not really being dead too. The show
has upped the stakes so much, it seems like they can't really go
back to pedestrian plots.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 2 - The Hounds of Baskerville]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-2---The-Hounds-of-Baskerville-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/14/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-2---The-Hounds-of-Baskerville-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a very interesting episode. I liked that it was a
"monster of the week" kind of episode and not an episode about
the epic story. It was neat that the interpersonal story of
James and Sherlock was explored so much as well.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 2 - Episode 1 - A Scandal in Belgravia]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-1---A-Scandal-in-Belgravia-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/12/Sherlock---Season-2---Episode-1---A-Scandal-in-Belgravia-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a fun episode. I liked the beginning and the montage of
sleuthing, especially the references to Holmes stories and how it
ended up being relevant for the larger story. The concept behind
The Woman was interesting and different, but I feel like time
moved way to quickly in this episode. It seems like almost 2
years of time passed, because the year they're texting, there's
the six months she's pretending to be dead, the months after the
break down, plus the two months she's actually dead, etc. It's a
bit unreasonable, because the time table of the earlier episodes
seemed much faster pace. I thought the advancement of some of
the extra characters was fun: Watson's girlfriends (although we
barely get a hint of why he'd be failing in love) and Molly. I
hope Sherlock shows Molly some love. This is a fun show, but I
get the impression that I'll be very annoyed that there won't be
any closure in the sixth episode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 1 - Episode 3 - The Great Game]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-3---The-Great-Game-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-3---The-Great-Game-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a really fascinating episode. I liked how there were
some many subplots and little stories. I think the Moriarty
character is really cool, but I thought the actor wasn't a good
choice. I expected someone older and more menacing
looking. Instead, this guy looks like an angry bully
kid. Hopefully as we see him more, he'll look more the part.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sherlock - Season 1 - Episode 2 - The Blind Banker]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-2---The-Blind-Banker-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/10/Sherlock---Season-1---Episode-2---The-Blind-Banker-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a neat episode, although I think the details of the
crime was not as interesting. Watching Sherlock be Sherlock was
very fun and I thought the introduction of the Sara character
was cute.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
