<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/dragon-quest-5-hand-of-the-heavenly-bride/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-15T02:01:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/17/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat the game today. (Although I used a 4x EXP and GOLD cheat so
I didn't have to grind. Luckily it did not make the game easy
really, it just saved time.) It was very cool. I like how
heart-warming and family-oriented the game is. It is also neat how
you go a grand tour of the world so you can revisit everyone. This
has been my favourite DQ so far. I really liked 4 a lot, but I
think this one was incredible. I almost want to say they're just
getting better, but I know that 9 is not as good as this.</p>

<p>Near the end of the game I developed an awesome strategy: have my
wife use the Sage Stone every round; use the main character and my
son to attack; and then use my daughter to buff/debuff and use
staves for other effects, including healing. It worked awesome.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.telebunny.net/toastywiki/index.php/Games/DragonQuestVHeavenlyHeartbreak">A great review</a>.</p>

<p>Total time: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/16/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/16/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a little more than three hours tonight as I watched
some YouTube videos. I made a lot of progress and had a lot of
fun. I got my wife back. It is really fun to have the whole family
together in the party now... even though my wife is much weaker
than the other party members. I'd like to keep her in just for
fun. There were some more adorable puns in the last section. I get
the feeling I'm basically done with the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 19:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/13/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had to wait around for a long time today, so I played for about
40 minutes. It took me a while to figure out what I needed to
do. I thought I couldn't use at the flying carpet because at first
it said I couldn't use it (because I was on a forest square). That
was annoying. I got the Magma Staff and now I'll try to get to the
fallen Zenithian Castle. I like how this game has so many
references to the last one.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:51</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/12/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I've been taking a
break from games as I catch up on some work. I went up to the part
in the game where you are reunited with your kids after being a
statue and are looking for your wife. It was a really cool
sequence to be stone and then meet your kids. This game is just
sooo adorable.</p>

<p>Total time: 15:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 5: Hand of the Heavenly Bride (DS, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/26/Game--Dragon-Quest-5--Hand-of-the-Heavenly-Bride--DS--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a long drive today, so I played for almost four hours. I've
had lots of cute experiences in the game. I really like the towns
in this game... they feel much more fleshed out and real than
towns in most RPGs. I decided to marry Deborah because I think her
sprite is really cool and I thought she'd be funny. So far she has
been really hilarious with all her little comments. I like it a
lot. The wedding voes were really funny because they said "until
you stop getting resurrected at church when you die" instead of
"until death do you part"... thus acknowledging that the
characters really do die and get resurrected in the story. It was
really funny.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:35</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
