<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Professor Layton and the Last Specter | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/professor-layton-and-the-last-specter/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:10-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did Puzzle 2 today, which was a classic example of what I love
and hate about these games. The puzzle was about how one picture
was different than three others. I initially answered wrong
because I selected the different one, rather than the three same
ones, because I didn't read the directions clear enough. Argh. It
should have said that I didn't select three rather than making me
answer wrong. Then, when I converted my answer (based on the
presence of what seemed to be a different un-movable object in the
background) and found out I was wrong. I tried a few different
logical (to me) ideas and was wrong. This made me frustrated like
there was going to be some out of nowhere explanation for the
similarities that I'd never have guessed. When the wrong reason
(standing still versus not) led to the right solution, it
described that the solution was really about the shadow of the
people in the photo to show the time... which made me happy again
because it was a reasonable explanation I could have thought of
but just didn't.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Professor Layton and the Last Specter (DS, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--Professor-Layton-and-the-Last-Specter--DS--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven't been doing puzzles for about two months, so I decided to
start again today. So far, the story is very intriguing and the
Emmy character is funny. Normally these games take a while to get
to interesting puzzles, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
