<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Child of Eden | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/child-of-eden/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-15T02:01:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/16/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for about an hour and beat the last two levels on
my first try (tonight, the second to last level took me about four
or five tries total.) The final level was basically a boss rush
plus a new boss at the end. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>I concurred with everything I said yesterday. This game is worth
everything I paid for it. ;) I would've probably been happy if I
paid $15 for it. I intend to gradually play through the levels
again on Hard and through the Challenge mode. Probably once a week
on Sunday. I enjoyed the game and it will be in the back of my
mind for a while, but it's not a revelation.</p>

<p>I wonder how it is with Kinect or Move?</p>

<p>Total time: 3:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Child of Eden (X360, 2011)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/15/Game--Child-of-Eden--X360--2011--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game as a prize from Call of Podcast for writing about
my game management system. It was on my to-buy list before that,
although I was planning on buying the PS3 version. The game looked
really beautiful and I really like Genki Rockets. I played Rez for
the Dreamcast and wasn't really blown away, but I thought that it
might be more interesting in a more modern form.</p>

<p>The game opens up with a really intriguing video and quickly shows
off its unique, beautiful world.</p>

<p>I played it for about an hour and half tonight. I beat the
first three levels on the first try, although I had to do each
twice to unlock the next level. I played the fourth level about
four times, but kept dying at the final form of the boss, because
it shoots so many tracer rounds.</p>

<p>I find the gameplay to be enjoyable and challenging, at least when
you get totally overwhelmed by bullets. I suppose I should get
better at using the screen clearing bombs. The addition of the
tracer rounds seems like it would be an insignificant change, but
it makes a huge difference compared to Rez.</p>

<p>I love the music, although I wish that there were more vocals,
like the actual Genki Rockets song. It may be that I'm not playing
well enough to unlock them though... on that note, I dislike how
it seems like I am doing the levels perfect (not getting hit,
getting mostly perfect octo-locks) but I'm only get three stars a
pop. It's weird.</p>

<p>I love that every level is totally different visually and aurally
from the others. This game is the perfect of a game that seems
like it was made on a totally different planet. I've played plenty
of Japanese games that do this, but most Western games lack that
kind of creativity.</p>

<p>I intend to keep trucking at it and beat. I haven't yet decided if
I will play through the hard mode or if I will just periodically
play through the whole game when I want to chill out to some rad
music, or show someone the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
