<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Metal Gear: Ghost Babel | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/metal-gear-ghost-babel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-06T22:28:09-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear: Ghost Babel (GBC, 2000)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/17/Game--Metal-Gear--Ghost-Babel--GBC--2000--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/17/Game--Metal-Gear--Ghost-Babel--GBC--2000--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid: Ghost Babel over the past three
days. This is a Game Boy Color game. At first, I assumed it would
basically be just like the first two Metal Gear games for the
MSX. It is, but it has clearly greatly evolved. This is the
perfect 2D Metal Gear. It makes me think (like I think for so many
series) how much better the series would be if it stuck in 2D but
got bigger, better, and more beautiful.</p>

<p>I'm amazed at how many of the mechanics from MGS they were able to
integrate into the game. For example, looking around walls is done
brilliantly. Tapping on walls works great. All the weapons
return. It's really a spectacular game. In some ways I'd say it is
better than MGS because many mechanics actually appear multiple
times. For example, there's really only one time you need to use
the Nikita Missiles in MGS (when you destroy the only electrical
panel in the game), but there are many instances in this
game. Same thing with the C4; there's one occurrences in MGS, but
many in this. I like the richness of that.</p>

<p>This game is technically linear and broken into stages, but in
many ways that is totally fine and a little inaccurate. It's a bit
inaccurate because there are many stages where you revisit areas
from previous stages (but that's a severe minority.) It's totally
fine because if you really break it down, MGS was linear too:
there is very sparse back-tracking. For example, once you go to
Otacon's lab, there's no reason to ever go back, even though you
could. This game just turns that admission into something enforced
by the game. Still though, each stage is really large and they
individually contain a lot of back-tracking. But really,
back-tracking (the need to go to old areas) and open world (the
technical ability to revisit old areas) are not valuable in and of
themselves. What is valuable is when the world feels "real" and
not artificial like a traditional stage-based game. This game
really makes the world feel real because of the way that things
connect and the size of the areas generally. In fact, I really see
a lot of this game in MGS4, which has a similar open-world
stage-based setup, where many areas have internal sections that
don't allow back-tracking.</p>

<p>I really want to think about this game as the basis for another 2D
Metal Gear-style game.</p>

<p>Here are the stats that I got:</p>

<p>Play Time: 02:56:07
Being Found: 001 times
Enemies: 000 killed
Rations: 008 used
Code Name: Spider</p>

<p>I was able to get such scores by using save states and always
restarting a room if I got caught. I don't feel this is cheating
because I still had to overcome the obstacle myself. It's really
an efficient way to do the traditional MGS Extreme mode where you
get a Game Over when you get caught. If I made an MGS-style game,
it would have this be an option and have it really stream-lined
(maybe Super Meat Boy streamlined.)</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
