<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Friday Night Lights | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/friday-night-lights/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-09T22:55:18-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Night Lights - Season 1 - Episode 2 - Eyes Wide Open]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-2---Eyes-Wide-Open-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-2---Eyes-Wide-Open-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We were curious how much of the documentary-style of the pilot
would continue to the show. It is very similar. I'm surprised
that in this episode they didn't show a football game. I get the
impression that every episode will be one week of time,
culminating in the game.</p>

<p>The "rally girl" thing was funny. And it was very sweet when
Jason got his treat even though he wasn't playing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday Night Lights - Season 1 - Episode 1 - Pilot]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-1---Pilot-0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/30/Friday-Night-Lights---Season-1---Episode-1---Pilot-0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife has been wanting to watch this show for a while, based on
the recommendation of her good friend. I can't think of that many
things that I care less about than football, so I've been
dragging my feet about watching it.</p>

<p>I found the first episode to be interesting. It is very
predictable in the plot development. The characters mostly play
to type, but they have a very real quality to them... like they
could be real people out there in a world that I know nothing
about (Texas, and Football.)</p>

<p>I really like the movie Varsity Blues and this is very
reminiscent of it. The small-town quaintness is cute and it is
interesting to learn about something I know nothing about.</p>

<p>I was very disappointed that no character in the show expressed
the idea that Jason's sacrifice was not worth it and that one
game or football itself is not worth ruining your life
over. Hopefully that will come up later.</p>

<p>I very much like the amount of faith in the show.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
