<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Mega Man 2 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/mega-man-2/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-02T22:22:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son wanted to see this played again today. We decided that my
wife would play (her first time) and she'd go against Metal
Man. It took her about 6 continues, but she eventually beat the
level. She used an E tank on the boss and got him on her first
try. Go team!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played through 6 Robot Masters today with my 3-year old son while
my wife slept. I love the lesson he is learning: "If you die, Dad,
just continue and try again... don't worry it's not too hard, you
can do it."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/09/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/09/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Mega Man 2 for the NES. I beat two bosses on
Monday, the rest of the bosses yesterday, and Dr. Wiley's Castle
today.</p>

<p>I remember playing this game a ton when I was a kid. But I don't
remember ever getting to Wiley's Castle, and especially not
through it. I'm kind of amazed that I was able to do it in such a
straight-forward way this week. I don't normally think of myself
as a super-gamer; maybe I'm just remembering it being harder than
it was? I'm not sure.</p>

<p>Something that struck me this time was how short a lot of the
levels were before the bosses. For instance, I love Bubble Man's
music, but I hardly heard it at all because I finished so fast. In
contrast, when I was a kid, I could never get past all the death
spikes on his stage, so I got really familiar with the music.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, the stages were so good, so fun. The bosses are
great. Man, this game is just a perfect little nugget. I don't
think there's anything that isn't polished just right. There are
challenges, but they can all be overcome with a little
practice.</p>

<p>This game is amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
