<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/shin-megami-tensei-devil-survivor/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Shin Megami Tensei: Devil Survivor (DS, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Devil-Survivor--DS--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/06/22/Game--Shin-Megami-Tensei--Devil-Survivor--DS--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started playing Devil Survivor in December 2009 and played it
regularly until the middle of January, then I got stuck on one
fight, so I played twice a week to progress without being numbed
by grinding. After I got through the battle in March, things
picked up and I played it regularly again. I've decided to stop
playing because I've been grinding to get past a battle for almost
two months with no end in sight.</p>

<p>The gameplay is great: it's a turn-based tactical role-playing
game with Dragon Quest-style fights when combatants encounter each
other on the field. I find real-time strategy games too frantic,
so I really enjoyed this system. There is a Pokemon-esque
"catch-them-all" with the demons that you can collect (apparently
this is common with all Megaten games, but it's the first I've
ever played.) There is incredibly deep customization with the
demon skills you can "crack".</p>

<p>The game got a lot easier for me once I understood how to use
all its systems. For the majority of the time I played, I didn't
realize what the fusion search option did. (It shows you all the
demons that you can potentially get by combining demons you have.)
Instead, I would search through combinations manually. Since that
was so tedious, I almost never did it. Once I understood search, I
did lots more fusing. Similarly, I didn't realize that you could
change a character's skills whenever you wanted. I thought you had
to crack them from an enemy and then you had that skill until it
was replaced. Once I realized that wasn't the case, I could tailor
my characters much better for the situation at hand.</p>

<p>The game is very skillful. Almost no battle will have a random
outcome if you plan your skill and demon configuration properly. I
really appreciate that.</p>

<p>However, there are a few key points where if you've done every
single battle before them and you've cracked every skill by doing
the free battles many times, you won't be high enough level to
beat the battle. So, your only option is to grind the free
battles. Unfortunately, grinding is extremely unproductive because
(1) a character on the field only gets EXP from the small battles
they participate in (rather than all the battles), (2) small
battles give minuscule amounts of EXP, and (3) free battles do not
give event EXP, which is typically very large. As an example, it
takes me about ten five to six minute battles to gain one level
for the Hero. The worst part is that there is typically only one
free battle available and it is almost exactly the same every time
you play it. Thus, you are not only grinding, which is boring, but
you are making the exact same moves every turn. I cannot fully
express how boring this is.</p>

<p>Overall, I really like this game and feel bad that I am giving
up, but it is a little too willing to waste my time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
