<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1957 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1957/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-16T09:43:49-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Atlas Shrugged, by Ayn Rand (1957) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/15/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I love the character of Ragnar! He's wicked cool.</p>

<p>I loved the whole deal with the tunnel and the engine. It's such a
perfect storm of stupidity, but she sells it so well!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Atlas Shrugged, by Ayn Rand (1957) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/13/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/13/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hank's relationships with Lillian and Dagny totally mirror his
philosophical development. Francisco makes the point to him that
the laws that he follows in business should be the same laws he
follows with men---meaning in the government or "public"
sector---namely that they should respect rights and be mutually
beneficial. Similarly, Lillian doesn't respect his rights and
actually wants their relationship to /not/ be beneficial because
then it is a sacrifice and thus "pure love". The idea is that it is
only loving to give things undeservedly, otherwise it is simply a
trade and there's no need for the concept of "love". In contrast,
Dagny wants to make a mutual beneficial "trade" and insists
upon. The concept of love is, therefore, basically just a name for
being willing to trade your whole self and let down your deepest
walls.</p>

<p>It makes me think of Hayek's comment that the laws of the market
would suffocate the family and the laws of the family would destroy
the market. I think there he is referring to trust and pooling
resources, not mutually beneficial interactions, though.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Atlas Shrugged, by Ayn Rand (1957) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/12/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-12T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/12/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I read the speech by Francisco at James' wedding and now I know
what everyone is talking about with the very long speaking
parts. That part, by the way, was pretty great. It's like the San
Sebastian mines, which I enjoyed but a million times more
vicious.</p>

<p>I think it is interesting at this point in the book that we really
don't know that much more than the characters but it's so obvious
to the reader that John Galt, the third student, it collecting
people to some place of freedom, but that hasn't occurred to the
main characters at all. Despite their being of monumental
intelligence.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Atlas Shrugged, by Ayn Rand (1957) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/11/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/11/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm now past Part I and the story is still pretty enthralling. I
still haven't got to the famous speeches that the characters give,
but there are always long dialogues. I wonder if I'm just
impervious to thinking they are too long?</p>

<p>Something I appreciate about the book is the development of the
relationship between Dagny and Rearden. I particularly like how
guilty Rearden feels about it, because I think it reinforces some
morals that I support. I also find it fascinating for Ayn Rand to
explore the concept of love's interaction with individualism and
self-esteem. I think it is pretty compelling. I must say though,
that I find the scenes between them too a-feminist. I'm kind of
amazed by it, actually, given how feminist the rest of the book is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Atlas Shrugged, by Ayn Rand (1957) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/10/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/10/Book--Atlas-Shrugged--by-Ayn-Rand--1957--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One thing with the dialogue in Atlas Shrugged is that it is often
so long without enough "he said"/"she said" that you lose track of
who is talking. It is a bit frustrating and one of the only
examples I can think of as "usability" problems with books.</p>

<p>For example, in this awesome dialogue from page 162, I'm not
totally sure the speakers are correct:</p>

<p>Dagny: "I keep thinking of what they told us in school about the
sun losing energy, growing colder each year. I remember wondering,
then, what it would be like in the last days of the world. I think
it would be . . . like this. Growing colder and things stopping."</p>

<p>Hank: "I never believed that story. I thought by the time the sun
was exhausted, men would find a substitute."</p>

<p>Dagny: "You did? Funny, I thought that, too."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
