<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/advance-wars-days-of-ruin/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-28T22:39:53-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin (DS, 2008) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/25/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On my flight back I beat the rest of the missions. They were
really, really hard. Brutally hard. Especially the one where you
couldn't build any new units. It was rough. This game has a really
good difficulty management system... in the beginning it is pretty
tough, but do-able and then near the middle to end it is insane,
but it's all the same rules. It's cool.</p>

<p>The story is totally absurd. But whatever. =)</p>

<p>Total Time: 18:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Advance Wars: Days of Ruin (DS, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/18/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/18/Game--Advance-Wars--Days-of-Ruin--DS--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I went on a long flight, so I started a new DS game.</p>

<p>A few years ago I played through the first DS Advance Wars game
and found it really enjoyable, so I decided to go through the next
one.</p>

<p>I played for about 11 hours on the flight! I can't believe my
battery lasted that long---but I did stop because it was about to
die. Then I played for another 2-ish hours while waiting for the
next flight and then on it.</p>

<p>I got about chapter 21, which appears to be about 80 or 90%
through the game. I only did the challenge levels in the very
beginning, but stopped once they outstripped my patience and
focused on the campaign levels.</p>

<p>The game is pretty much exactly the same as the last one. I don't
remember having the anti-tank guns or the bikes in the last game,
but I could be wrong. There's no "dual strike" anymore, which is
good because it was always a pain to look at the top screen too.</p>

<p>The game is very interesting in a way, because there's no
progression system. Although you are gradually given new units and
abilities, you don't have any input on that process, it's all
story based. In essence, each level is about defeating the enemy
with the endownment you've been given. Very similar to my ideas
for rougelike RPGs.</p>

<p>I had a few ridiculous battles. For example, mission 10 took like
73 rounds with an incredible slow push into their territory and
many failed blitz attempts. I won 12 by depleting the enemy's last
unit's gas after their fighter killed my last plan and I had
defeated all their ground units honestly. Mission 14 took a ton of
attempts, probably four or five, and ended up going into 47
rounds. Mission 17 took a little over an hour to beat. (Basic math
tells me that each mission has taken on average about 40 minutes.)
It's interesting how much mileage the game provides.</p>

<p>The story is ridiculous just like the last game but in like the
totally opposite direction. The first game I played was very "Rah
rah" about world and treated it (in the story) like a silly game
with no consequences. This game is all about the evils of war and
of humanity in general with the main characters being pure divine
beings of goodness and everyone else being totally
detestable. It's pretty absurd. If there were voice-acting, it
would be the worst. The situation they are in is actually really
similar to Battlestar Galactica, but if all the bad guys on that
show were the ones in charge and the people at the edges were
trying to be good. I'm tempted to not even watch the story scenes
they are so ridiculous, but I'm doing it anyways.</p>

<p>Total Time: 13:12</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
