<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Last Story | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/the-last-story/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-09T22:08:25-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/01/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the game tonight in about an hour. I did the Miasma
Cave, the last Arena season, and the fight against Therius. It was
a very sweet ending. Overall, I think this is one of the strongest
stories out of an RPG I've played. The ending is a little bit
tropey, but not incredibly and it really justifies the things that
are tropes. I was really affected by the relationship between Zael
and Calista. It felt as real as a movie. I really loved this
game. The combat system was really fun and challenging. I think
the next time I play I'll try not to get too powerful so the game
is a bit more challenging... but it was still good
anyways. Mistwalker keeps getting better and better.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 65
Total time: 30:09</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/30/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning I played for about an hour. I was surprised at how
quickly the new Jirall plot line was resolved. I was also very
sad that Calista was kidnapped. The game does a really good job
of making you feel really connected to and protective of
her. During the Jirall fight, I realized that I hadn't seen
Dagran in a long time... where is he?</p>

<p>After we got home from the day, I played again, all night (about
four hours, with some breaks for snacks, etc.) I basically beat
the game and got to the epilogue. The final sequences had some
really tough fights. I fought the final boss three times before
winning. The final reveal of the big bad was pretty intense. I
really liked the epilogue sequence with Calista's parents. It
seemed so appropriate for the couple to go on a little adventure
together before getting married. It's adorable. Calista's dress
was great too. I wish you could have her wear it during normal
gameplay. I feel like there's still a lot of stuff to do in the
game... people to talk to, weapons to continue upgrading,
etc. It's very strange. It's like the final sequence of Earthbound
or Dragon Warrior but amped to the max because there's so much to
do. It's exciting.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48 -> 56 -> 64
Total time: 28:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I advanced the story quite a bit. I feel like I'm in the closing
stages: I'm going to fight Zangurak, then send the Outsider back,
and live happily ever after with Calista. I thought her wedding
dress was very cute and I liked the resolution of the wedding
plot. In the game play, there's been a bit of a boss rush of sorts
where boss encounters similar to ones from earlier in the game
keep coming back. It's fun though. The fight next to the Outside
was pretty exciting and difficult. That whole sequence going down
the tunnel was very difficult---I think I died three times.</p>

<p>I accidentally used the Auto-Equip feature and all my outfits
changed. It was very painful to go back to dressing all the girls
how I like.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 48
Total time: 23:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/28/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for a short amount of time yesterday before going to
bed. I mainly just advanced the story. It turns out that Lavos is
behind Zael's power and the destruction of the world. Bummer. I'm
excited about a cute wedding scene.</p>

<p>TODO Go back to the mysterious island and go behind the entrance
where the Lvl 40 Cave Cougars are.</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Story (Wii, 2012) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/27/Game--The-Last-Story--Wii--2012--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I played for a lot. A new arena season was opened, so I
had a lot of fun playing it over and over so I could max out all
my currently available items, etc. I did it like seven times. In
addition to that, I did some story missions, including the
haunted mansion. The best part of that was Horace's ridiculous
comment about his wife afterwards. The stealth section escaping
from the castle was kind of odd, but worked as much as it needed
to. It was much better with Callista than with Zael alone. I'm
weirded out by Dagran being a sketch ball. I wonder where the
story is going. I presume that the Count is really the big bad in
some way, but maybe also I'll fight "The Outsider".</p>

<p>Zael Level: 42
Total time: 20:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
