<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-16T11:12:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Katniss destroying the Holo was pretty stupid.</p>

<p>Woah, Prim dying with the same trap that Gale was talking about.</p>

<p>Katniss awakening in a hospital and not really being involved in
capturing Snow is disappointing.</p>

<p>Snow's conversation with Katniss: very believable.</p>

<p>Appalling that Katniss would initiate more Hunger Games. Although,
since they never talked about it happening, I wonder if it did
given that Coin was killed?</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the books and thought they ended well. I thought
the second book and the first part of the third were the high
points for the series.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like the idea of the bargain between District 13 and the Capitol.</p>

<p>The militarism of District 13 is fascinating and reasonable, given
their past.</p>

<p>The books have always been a thin allegory for violence in media,
but having Katniss literally be a movie star is a bit
ridiculous. I'm glad that the characters realize this
too.</p>

<p>It's funny because when she's in the field, it's like she's in the
Games again, but the cameras are now obvious rather than hidden
everywhere.</p>

<p>The real moment of Katniss' catch phrase is totally epic. A little
teary.</p>

<p>The propaganda war is pretty brilliant and fits really well with
the media theme of the books.</p>

<p>I find the term "Mockingjay" used for Katniss incredibly silly and
aggravating.</p>

<p>Katniss' impassioned speech before she gets shot. :)</p>

<p>I have to admit, turning the raid on the Capitol into a recreation
of the Games is a clever way to stick to the formula.</p>

<p>I'm stopping for the day right when Peeta shows up in the
Capitol... tense!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The clock concept for the arena is clever.</p>

<p>The plot dump at the end of the book is pretty absurd, although
really, what else could she have done?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: The Hunger Games, by Suzanne Collins (2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--The-Hunger-Games--by-Suzanne-Collins--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The idea that the Muttations are really the tributes is
fascinating. The magic technology of the capital is pretty
interesting overall.</p>

<p>I finished the book today. As I said the other day, I find it to be
almost perfectly captured in the movie. That disappoints me a
little because I was hoping to learn more about the world from the
book.</p>

<p>I can't imagine how the other books could continue the style of
this one. The story can definitely move, there's no doubt about
that, but I'm not convinced that Collins could write a political
thriller.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/27/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The first chapters do a really good job of easily recapping what
happened in the last book as a reminder.</p>

<p>The concept of the Quarter Quell is so contrived for plot
purposes. It's as bad as Harry Potter where every year some huge
thing is revealed that couldn't possibly have been realistically
unmentioned before.</p>

<p>I thought that the tour around the districts would be a contrived
way to give the reader a tour. But I was wrong.</p>

<p>I teared up in the District 11 scene.</p>

<p>Wow, how contrived to get Katniss back in the arena, because
Collins has written her into a state of inability to do
anything. Naturally it will be her and Peeta again?</p>

<p>It is interesting that Katniss will have an advantage the second
time, because she and Peeta will the youngest, and presumably
un-softened by living in luxury as a victor.</p>

<p>Haymitch's story is great.</p>

<p>The amount of "food porn" in the books never gets old, strangely.</p>

<p>Katniss' private session with the Gamemakers :)</p>

<p>The pre-Games interviews were amazing.</p>

<p>The end of Part II is waaaay intense.</p>

<p>I feel like throughout the book Collins uses such sterile and bland
language to talk about Katniss' body. Yet, she seems to always be
doing it. We often hear about the showers and baths that Katniss
takes and when that happens she'll say she's "naked" or talk about
her "breasts" and most often she mentions her "underwear",
"underclothes", or "undergarment". It's particularly strange how
bland it is given the food orgies and descriptions of the Capitol
fashion we're so often given.</p>

<p>The whole second book is reminiscent of bad movie sequel that was
summarized in the production notes with one word: MORE. More
violence. More romance. More intrigue. More food. More. The book
has almost an identical structure and plot, but again, and a little
bit different, but bigger. Yet, it does a good job at it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
