<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-16T00:20:37-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-12T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/12/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been reading every day, but I haven't read anything I've felt
worth commenting on. It's a very interesting book. The Danish and
Italian sections were curious, but seem to end in a non-conclusion
because the ballet innovations there didn't drastically change
things. I'm excited about the transition to the Russian world.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/30/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This whole chapter seems to be about Marie Taglioni and she sounds
amazing.</p>

<p>If Vestris designed the steps that became modern ballet, she
figured out how to do them with the style expect of modern
ballerinas. She did everything that Vestris did, but she practiced
so long and hard to achieve the strength necessary to do it in an
"elegant" and "feminine" way. While the early dancers were
"sweaty" and "breathless" when they did them, she was
"angelic". She built this technique over 6 months after a failed
start in Vienna by working for 6 hours a day and holding poses for
100 seconds.</p>

<p>Her shoes are still extant and have been studied. While she
performed full pointe, she mainly held herself at full point and
did not dance on it. We know this because her shoes were not the
boxed and hard style that allows that. Instead, by looking at the
wearing at the shoes, it looks like she danced about half-way
between half-pointe and full-pointe. Her dancing was so powerful
that she used 2 or 3 shoes per performance.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/28/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/28/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just read one of the most interesting sections so far. It
discussed how in the 1820s, a ballet master named Vestris
dramatically changed the art.</p>

<p>He took the old three different genres of ballet and combined all
their steps into a new genre---that is modern ballet. This had lots
of big consequences. The old notation systems didn't work any
longer and weren't replaced because of the complexity of the new
dances.</p>

<p>The old style of practice was forgotten and replaced. Before, whole
dances were done continuously for practice, but after individual
steps were repeated dozens of times before going on to more
steps. The various steps were ranked in order of difficulty. For
example, in Vestris' notes it says there were 27 different kinds
of pirouettes.</p>

<p>In particular, the role of the male dancer changed a lot. Vestris
innovated the male dancer as acrobat doing many jumps and
turns. This was seen as very wild and distasteful. In addition,
the new style he came up with was perfected by women, so part of
his innovation led to male dancers becoming pariahs and not a
major part of ballet. In fact, in the mid 1800s, many male roles
were played by women! This is funny to me because a hundred years
before, the opposite was true.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/27/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/27/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The concept that Napolean had a major effect on the organization
of ballet companies and schools is really fascinating.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Apollo's Angels, by Jennifer Homans (2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/09/Book--Apollo-s-Angels--by-Jennifer-Homans--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It was very interesting to read about Nouverre and his ideas. I
like the expression that ballets should not be like "plays" but
should be like "paintings", because with the limited language of
pantomime, you can't express detailed, dynamic
stories... everything has to be very extreme and relatively static
to be understandable... like a painting.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
