<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-22T21:03:41-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: When You Reach Me, by Rebecca Stead (2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book--When-You-Reach-Me--by-Rebecca-Stead--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/22/Book--When-You-Reach-Me--by-Rebecca-Stead--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My wife read this book for book group (I think that's why) and
wanted me to as well. It was not the worst book ever, but I didn't
like it that much. My main problem with was the weakness of its
plot and its predictability. Practically nothing happens in it and
the characters are strong enough to carry a story where nothing
major happens. The slice of life isn't slicey enough because there
aren't even interesting vignettes about the girl's life. The
predictability is really bad. I was about half-way through the book
yesterday (long plane trip today) and I talked to my wife about it
and told her what I thought would happen... and I was exactly
correct on all counts. That's pretty bad. It's not even like a
standard romantic comedy where it is sticking to a formula, it's
just that the story is so cliche and obvious that there's basically
only one thing that <em>could</em> happen given the way she's set it up.</p>

<p>Maybe I'm begin too hard on a Young Adult book, but eh, it wasn't
for me.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Romeo & Juliet, by Shakespeare (1597) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/Book--Romeo---Juliet--by-Shakespeare--1597--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-03T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/03/Book--Romeo---Juliet--by-Shakespeare--1597--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finished it this morning. The last Act is definitely not as
memorable to me, but the last verse is very beautiful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Romeo & Juliet, by Shakespeare (1597)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Book--Romeo---Juliet--by-Shakespeare--1597--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Book--Romeo---Juliet--by-Shakespeare--1597--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started reading this because Ayame's class in school was. I
greatly enjoy it. The little poems in the first half are so cute
and clever. I'm now in Act III and I don't like it as much, but I
recognize its necessity for the tragedy of the first two Acts to be
realized. I just read Act III/Scene II and it is curious how
casually Juliet talks about having sex with Romeo that night to
seal their marriage.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Pride & Prejudice, by Jane Austen (1813)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/Book--Pride---Prejudice--by-Jane-Austen--1813--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/21/Book--Pride---Prejudice--by-Jane-Austen--1813--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started reading this before going to LA with Ayame in 2012/01
(probably the third week?) and finished on 2012/02/21. I had read
it before, when I was in college. I read more than half of the book
in the last three days of reading.</p>

<p>My favourite aspects of the book are how ridiculous Collins is, how
noble Darcy is at the end, and how struck Elizabeth is at the
realization of her past error.</p>

<p>I agree that basically nothing happens in the book, in terms of
"action", but where it really excels is in creating a world and a
set of characters that you feel like you truly know well. That's
what I like most about it... you feel like you are there and they
are real.</p>

<p>I find it so strange how preoccupied everyone is with everyone
else's income and how public it is. I don't think we can every
really understand what it was like to be in the gentry during that
era.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
