<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Books | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/books/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-24T09:34:45-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Good to Great: Why Some Companies Make the Leap... and Others Don't, by James C. Collins (2001) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Book--Good-to-Great--Why-Some-Companies-Make-the-Leap----and-Others-Don-t--by-James-C--Collins--2001--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/19/Book--Good-to-Great--Why-Some-Companies-Make-the-Leap----and-Others-Don-t--by-James-C--Collins--2001--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The stupidity continues: (pg 188) [The context is that the pioneers
don't often win in technology.] "Palm Computing did not pioneer the
personal digital assistant; Apple did" (and clearly Palm has won in
that industry.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>Overall, I was very unimpressed with the book. Almost 99% of the
book is: have standards and stick to them. Motherhood and apple
pie. The most interesting thing was not how "smart" the "great"
companies were, but how stupid their competitors were.</p>

<p>I have a very hard time applying it to my career, but I can't
really go into that.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Good to Great: Why Some Companies Make the Leap... and Others Don't, by James C. Collins (2001)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/Book--Good-to-Great--Why-Some-Companies-Make-the-Leap----and-Others-Don-t--by-James-C--Collins--2001--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/07/18/Book--Good-to-Great--Why-Some-Companies-Make-the-Leap----and-Others-Don-t--by-James-C--Collins--2001--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My initial assumption about this book is that it will be full of
trite junk anecdotes mixed with pseudo-scientific statistics. (N =
11!)</p>

<p>After reading the first 15 pages and learning of the research
methodology, I expect that they've been duped by the Black Swan
problem: they paid attention to the random successes and ignored
the large number of failures that implemented similar policies.</p>

<p>Pointed comments:</p>

<ul>
<li>(pg 5) "We believe that almost any organization can substantially
improve its stature and performance, perhaps even become great,
if it conscientiously applies the framework of ideas we've
uncovered."</li>
</ul>


<p>This sentence sounds like it says something meaningful, but
really it says nothing because if you fail after taking the
advice maybe you weren't "conscientious" enough and even then
they say "almost any" and make no promise about becoming
great. Not that I think they could, but they don't make very
large claims.</p>

<ul>
<li>(pg 7) One of the "companies" we should imitate is Fannie Mae!
Give me a break! The secret to success appears to be securing
government favour! You too can amass a net income of -16.9
billion USD ten years after becoming an example of a "Great"
company. I should throw the book out right now.</li>
</ul>


<p>Similarly, we have the wonderful, and bankrupt Circuit City.</p>

<ul>
<li>(pg 13) Lincoln is used as an example of a "humble" leader,
despite the atrocities he committed and dictatorial power he
seized. Nice.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/29/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Katniss destroying the Holo was pretty stupid.</p>

<p>Woah, Prim dying with the same trap that Gale was talking about.</p>

<p>Katniss awakening in a hospital and not really being involved in
capturing Snow is disappointing.</p>

<p>Snow's conversation with Katniss: very believable.</p>

<p>Appalling that Katniss would initiate more Hunger Games. Although,
since they never talked about it happening, I wonder if it did
given that Coin was killed?</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the books and thought they ended well. I thought
the second book and the first part of the third were the high
points for the series.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Mockingjay, by Suzanne Collins (2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Mockingjay--by-Suzanne-Collins--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I like the idea of the bargain between District 13 and the Capitol.</p>

<p>The militarism of District 13 is fascinating and reasonable, given
their past.</p>

<p>The books have always been a thin allegory for violence in media,
but having Katniss literally be a movie star is a bit
ridiculous. I'm glad that the characters realize this
too.</p>

<p>It's funny because when she's in the field, it's like she's in the
Games again, but the cameras are now obvious rather than hidden
everywhere.</p>

<p>The real moment of Katniss' catch phrase is totally epic. A little
teary.</p>

<p>The propaganda war is pretty brilliant and fits really well with
the media theme of the books.</p>

<p>I find the term "Mockingjay" used for Katniss incredibly silly and
aggravating.</p>

<p>Katniss' impassioned speech before she gets shot. :)</p>

<p>I have to admit, turning the raid on the Capitol into a recreation
of the Games is a clever way to stick to the formula.</p>

<p>I'm stopping for the day right when Peeta shows up in the
Capitol... tense!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Catching Fire, by Suzanne Collins (2009) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/28/Book--Catching-Fire--by-Suzanne-Collins--2009--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The clock concept for the arena is clever.</p>

<p>The plot dump at the end of the book is pretty absurd, although
really, what else could she have done?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
