<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Dragon Quest 9 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/dragon-quest-9/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-09T15:40:16-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Quest 9 (DS, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/08/Game--Dragon-Quest-9--DS--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/08/Game--Dragon-Quest-9--DS--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Dragon Quest IX on my Nintendo DS.</p>

<p>I played the first Dragon Warrior game when I was young and
watched a good friend of mine play through the other NES
games. Shortly before my house burned down, if I remember
correctly, I bought a PS2 Dragon Quest, but I never finished it
due to that. So, this is my first Dragon Quest game in a lonoong
time.</p>

<p>I guess I didn't finish this game either. I got to the very
last battle and was totally creamed. The disparity between the
second to last battle and the last battle was quite amazing---I
think I died in one round in the last battle. Obviously I could
have just grinded some more to give myself a chance and do it, but
at that point the "Time = Progress" equation of JRPGs was too
apparent to me and it wasn't worth it to continue. I explored a
few grottos, decided I wasn't going to finish the game, and
watched the ending on YouTube.</p>

<p>Mechanically, the game was pretty fun. The partner AI worked
really well, and was actually broken in a way: the AI could change
its commands based on what occurred earlier in the round, whereas
you as a player are not able to do that. The battles were pretty
difficult most of the time, which I enjoyed. The battle animations
were interesting for the first bit, but then they got really
tiring and I would just do sit-ups or something in between
rounds. Very boring.</p>

<p>The character progression system was fun---on the surface---it
was fun to allocate points and think about being different
classes. However, I made a lot of long run choices in my skill
allocation, despite not playing for the long-run, so I pretty much
ended the game with each character having one maxed weapon and
about 20/30 points in shield and 20/30 points in some other
skills. There was a period right before the end of the game when I
switched everyone's class and got to about 20th level with
everyone, but it was really tedious and not as exciting as I
hoped. I think if I really loved the game, then I would enjoy
leveling through each class, but as it is, I didn't love it enough
to really get into that.</p>

<p>I pretty much ignored the "quests" because after doing a few
the rewards were not very enticing and they were all painful to
contemplate. I didn't do any treasure maps before the end of the
game and did two after. Again, if I loved the game, I would like
the ability to go and fight tougher monsters, but since I don't
love the game, I'm not taking advantage of it.</p>

<p>I think if I knew people who wanted to play the game with me,
then I would have enjoyed continuing to play and experience those
other features, but they aren't really for the solo player I
typically am.</p>

<p>The other way it could have won me, I think, was if leveling
was easier, because then it would provide less tedium to
experience the full range of the character options. I've briefly
read online about milking metal slimes, but that sounds a bit much
for my taste.</p>

<p>Another area where I probably ruined the game for myself was
acquiring gold. I read about a technique to make profit with
alchemy and I spent a few hours getting an enormous amount of
money so I could buy whatever I wanted. That was really boring and
didn't really pay of either.</p>

<p>On areas other than mechanics, the game was really great.</p>

<p>I love the graphical style. It is pretty and it works really
well on the DS. I love how reactive a character's appearance is to
your equipment. I love the clever puns and enemy names. The story
is very cute and I love that each locale has its own personality
that you get into as you explore it. The plot is interesting and
the high-level concept of the world is also neat. It's funny how
close it goes to the JRPG cliché of fighting God, but skirts away
at the last minute. The music was fun.</p>

<p>Overall, I don't regret playing the game and I liked it a
lot. I can think of lots of ways it would have been better for me
personally, but I think it is perfectly fine for it to not be that
game, because I know how successful it was in Japan and how great
the other features are. I'll definitely play Dragon Quest
X.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
