<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ninja Gaiden | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/ninja-gaiden/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-19T22:50:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ninja Gaiden (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/23/Game--Ninja-Gaiden--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/23/Game--Ninja-Gaiden--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've just finished Ninja Gaiden for the NES. It was great to use
an authentic controller for it. It was also great to be able to
use save states because the game is so hard.</p>

<p>I really like the simple and straight-forward controls. I love
the arcade/shmup-like patterns and difficulties. Even though with
modern games, I loathe lame cut-scenes over boring stories, I find
them really entertaining in this game, because they are so
simplistic. The music and sound-effects overall are nice, in that
8-bit way.</p>

<p>For the first four acts (there are six), I limited myself to
one save state per screen. This was a significant challenge. When
I got to the fifth act, it was so tough that I was tempted by the
save states and used them after each obstacle. Each of the final
bosses (there are three) was defeated by using a save after each
hit I landed. Nevertheless, I feel very satisfied that I have been
able to get through the game, because even severely disadvantaging
it, it was very hard.</p>

<p>I'm looking forward to playing the sequel. If I play it again,
I will use save states much less to force myself to gain more
skill at the game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
