<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/castlevania-order-of-ecclesia/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-28T00:17:03-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania: Order of Ecclesia (DS, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/17/Game--Castlevania--Order-of-Ecclesia--DS--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2009-12-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2009/12/17/Game--Castlevania--Order-of-Ecclesia--DS--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing this. Castlevania... how do I love thee?
Let me count the ways:</p>

<p>The main character, Shanoa, is fascinating. It is a little old to
have a character that has lost their memory, but because the game
starts where she has her memory and then she loses it in the
prologue, it is much more believable and interesting. I love that
she is a such a powerful woman. She's beautiful, but IMHO in a
respectful way; she doesn't fit the typical sex-object stereotype
of video game women. (Yeah, she's wearing a backless dress, but
her long hair covers it up except when she's absorbing a glyph.)
The final sequence, after beating Dracula, is such beautiful
closure to her character.</p>

<p>The graphics are so fresh and fluid. Something most Castlevania
fans have to come to terms with is that the majority of the enemy
graphics are reused game to game. This game, however, is almost
entirely fresh. The backgrounds are amazingly vivid for the
DS. Shanoa is beautifully illustrated... I love the animation for
absorbing a glyph.</p>

<p>The scope of the game is so grand. Rather than a single map, it is
more like Portrait of Ruin, where there are many areas to travel
through. However, rather than a central hub map, there is an
overworld and most areas have a few entrances/exits... some
hidden. It did a very good job of making the world feel
real. That's something that I love about Castlevania games: in the
older games, the levels are sensibly connected and in the
post-SOTN games the map is huge and "makes sense". This game is
missing some of the backtracking and exploration from earlier
games, because the way areas are connected is generally linear;
but there are few areas that you revisit in the story and once you
unlock Dracula's Castle it is huge.</p>

<p>The combat is deep. I love all the different glyphs and glyph
unions. The combat system is fun to execute through the entire
game, because you are always getting more weapons and spells and
facing new /kinds/ of enemies.</p>

<p>The quests are actually fun! The quest system in Portrait of Ruin
was a little too tedious and boring, but these quests worked,
because they were a little more directed and you were likely to
run across one of the items requested as you progressed, so you
knew what to do to get everything. Thus, I completed them all.</p>

<p>The extra dungeons were a challenge, but not too insane! I don't
normally do the insane enemy rooms (like the Arena from Aria of
Sorrow), but I did do the Large Cavern, because I felt like the
rest of game's combat mechanics prepared you for dealing with so
many foes. In past games, I felt like the only way to beat them
was to grind an insane amount and get massive amounts of
potions. This game, I didn't really grind at all (I did a little
bit to get some of the more interesting glyph and item
drops---like Arma Felix, so cool!)</p>

<p>I recommend this game, no reservations!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
