<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Gran Turismo 5 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/gran-turismo-5/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-17T22:04:13-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/31/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I still need to get a gold on the Formula GT expert race (I
currently have a silver) and the rest of the special events. I've
decided to not do the A-Spec Endurance races at all, because they
are insulting. I tried doing the GT race this morning, but had
monkeys climbing all over me... which was very difficult.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/24/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I now have Silvers (or better) in every license test!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/08/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'd been working on IA-10 Silver for a loooong time and I just got
it after about a 40 minute session tonight. I ended in 2nd!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/27/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/27/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bought Gran Turismo 5 for Christmas for my dad and I. I'd never
really been super into a racing game before, although I played a
racing game for the SNES and I got a diddly wheel for the PS1 to
play Ridge Racer with. I remember going over Sean's house and
seeing his brother play Gran Turismo 1, but it's always been in my
periphery since then. I'd been hearing a lot about how awesome the
game was and how demanding it was of your skill, so I decided to
make it a new hobby. Due to the flood, it took until some time in
January to start playing regularly. After getting started with the
controller I decided that I needed a racing wheel and a stand for
it. That was a really good idea, because it made the game so much
more awesome.</p>

<p>From January to September, I played the game every day. For the
first two-ish months I would play for about an hour or so, but
after that I would just do one race/event per night. After
September, I've been playing every two-ish days. After getting up
to the Extreme series in Spec A, I switched to closing out all the
Spec B races. In each case, I would not proceed until I got a gold
on every event (although I delayed a pre-Extreme event because it
was very very difficult.) After closing out the Spec B, I went
back and finished the other Extreme events. My statistics right
now are:</p>

<p>A-Spec Level: 28
B-Spec Level: 40
Game Progress: 95 %
Current Credits: 13,585,072
Total Wins: 303
No. of Cars Owned: 135
Trophies Earned: 50 %
Total Distance Driven: 42,292.1 Miles
Licenses: S (Gold: 25; Silver: 8; Bronze: 27)</p>

<p>Right now, I only have one Spec A event in Extreme left... the
Formula GT races (which are incredibly difficult) and all the Spec
A Endurance races. Plus I'd like to go back and get gold in every
License test and I haven't done many Special Events.</p>

<p>However, I'm at the point where every task left in the game
(i.e. the 5% of the game that remains) is excruciatingly difficult
and often very time consuming. For example, each Formula GT race
takes about 30 minutes and you need to do six of them to win the
event. You can save the game in between races, but you can't
tackle the courses piecemeal. The Endurance races were incredibly
tedious even on Spec B (which is AI controlled)... I can't imagine
how horrible they would be in Spec A.</p>

<p>Given how much time I've played the game... obviously it is
amazing. I wish there were more of the average difficulty races,
because I'm now at the depressing stage of playing the game more
and more. Basically, I wish I could play the game for ever and
keep making incremental progress, whereas right now I feel like I
need to jump a really big wall.</p>

<p>Overall, my favourite thing about the game was the nice difficulty
curve that made you always feel like you were improving and the
general skill that I feel like I've acquired because of it. It's
almost like a shmup in a sense, because you have to gain personal
skill to do well. There were some awesome moments at the beginning
of the game when I was shaving milliseconds of trial times to get
a gold trophy. It was very satisfying to do. Sometimes though it
feels like you just need to get a better car to even have a chance
at certain races and it is hard to tell when that is. I think the
UI could be improved to give you some indication that your car is
very weak relative to the competition. Eventually I started using
a guide to recommend which cars to get... because there are so
many it is hard to decide what to buy at any one time.</p>

<p>The graphics and sound are amazing, as expected. The
side-of-the-road textures are really bad when you are going slow
(because you are terrible) but at the right speed they are
great. I had a little bit of screen tearing, but I get the feeling
it was something with my TV rather than the game. My favourite
tracks were the forest tracks where you got to see the interplay
of shadows and light. Very beautiful.</p>

<p>When I was doing Spec B at the end, I found the RPG side of the
game... getting credits and cars and upgrades to be strangely
satisfying. I can't reiterate enough how absurd the Endurance
races are. There are 9, 12, 24 hour, etc races. It is
ridiculous. I would leave the game on over night or all day to
just finish them once I knew I had a strong enough driver, car,
and pit-strategy to just win with no effort. I wish there were a
"Simulate until the end of the race" button. The worst was
grinding the XP to get to the final race. I was a little annoyed
that nothing happened when I beat every single Spec B race.</p>

<p>I will continue playing the game. The main question is whether I
keep pushing at the remaining 5% or if I select the part of the
game that I like and keep doing it over and over. Probably a
balance of the two. However, I don't think it would be possible
for me to actually play the whole game from the start again. Maybe
if they had some way of locking you out of certain driving assists
to have a different "difficulty" level, I would consider it. But
Gran Turismo 6.... probably :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gran Turismo 5 (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/01/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/09/01/Game--Gran-Turismo-5--PS3--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this regularly (once a day) and got almost every track
beat; and did get Gold on every Spec-B event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
