<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/chip-dale-rescue-rangers/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-25T23:32:10-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Chip & Dale Rescue Rangers (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Chip---Dale-Rescue-Rangers--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I beat three levels after about forty minutes of play. This game
is very similar to Super Mario Brothers 2. It's focused around
picking up blocks and throwing them, although you can throw them
in more directions in this game. The co-op play is a memorable
feature, although I played by myself.</p>

<p>The platforming is pretty good, but the hit detection against
projectiles and enemies is too imprecise... you can get hits
registered that look very far away from your character. This
annoyance combined with the extreme speed of a lot of the enemies
(particularly the flying ones) leads to a lot of frustration. The
boss of the third level is really vicious because it zooms across
the screen and drops two moving creatures that have big hit
boxes.</p>

<p>The first boss fight is super easy once you realize what you need
to do and is pretty bland. The third is more interesting, but
also flawed because you can't effective shot in mid-air because
you fall so quickly.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say this is a C+ NES platformer. It's not
horrific... it's certainly playable (unlike TMNT, for instance)
but it by no means enters the canon, and I don't feel it's really
worth my time. If I could have used a Game Genie code to get
infinite lives, I would have done it though and taken one screen
at a time. As it stands, the three lives per continue and three
continues barrier is too high for me to go through imperfect
mechanics.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
