<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Valkyria Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/valkyria-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-13T23:20:21-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (14)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/06/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--13</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today and finished the game. I got
As on the last few missions, which was pretty cool. I think I got
As on almost all of them, but I didn't load my Clear data, so I'm
not sure if it would say what my overall statistics were, etc.</p>

<p>It was a really cool game. The ending was sweet. There were so
pretty crazy revelations about the characters, the events were
suitably epic, and the final boss was intense. I particularly
liked the sequence at the end where they showed what each
character did after the war... especially the little vignette
about Welkin and Alicia and their baby girl :) So cute!</p>

<p>The combat in the game is really interesting too. I enjoyed both
the "stealth" missions and the other ones. It makes me think a lot
about how you'd make a game like this. (And in particular,
randomly generate levels for it.)</p>

<p>I saw that there were some DLC missions, but I don't think it is
worth it for me right now given my queue. I do like the game a
lot, but I feel like I've got the missions down to be a bit rote,
so it's mainly the story pushing me to do more.</p>

<p>It was interesting to compare my final in-game timer (25:08) to my
count (33:39), because it shows how much time was taken up by
mission attempts that ultimately failed and thus weren't counted
in the real total. Wow!</p>

<p>I highly recommend this game.</p>

<p>Total: 33:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (13)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--12/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--12</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today, split across watching a
movie. The battles were pretty tough. The once against Selvaria
was insane, because she dodges practically everything. I
eventually realized I should use a unit with the "Undodgeable
Shot" ability, then it was all over. The one where you have to
blow up the canyon walls, I kept doing it wrong because I didn't
realize there were two things to blow up to force it to
turn. D'oh. I wasted like 30 minutes because of that.</p>

<p>I can't believe that Welkin proposed to Alicia---he even had a
ring! This game is so grown up compared to other RPGs, especially
Japanese ones. The story is really cool, still.</p>

<p>Total: 30:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (12)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--11/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--11</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours today. I did a bunch of different
missions, all were done in a relatively "stealthy" style. It was
very hard though, but quite fun. The story is really interesting,
as I said. I was quite surprised by who shot Alicia. After the
next battle, I unlocked a few reports, which I am now going
through.</p>

<p>Total: 26:31</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (11)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--10/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/03/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--10</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about 33 minutes today and basically just learned
that Alicia really is a Valkyria and she's super tough. I lost the
battle pretty hard, because I did a stealth rush and couldn't
defend the forward base. Now that I know where the enemy will be,
I think I will try to pre-place Lancers behind the where the tanks
appear! We'll see tomorrow.</p>

<p>Total: 23:26</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a few more stealth style missions. The big battle in the
trenches was really different and dangerous, although I did it in
a stealth way. The bonus mission where you had to search through
all the grassy areas was pretty cool too.</p>

<p>The story is getting really neat and touching. I can't believe
they killed Isara, but I like the way you return to Bruhl as a way
to "avenge" her. The development of the idea of Alicia being a
Valkyria is really neat too. I wonder if it will just be in
cut-scenes or if she'll become some crazy new unit type? I feel
like the story is close to wrapping up, but there are a lot more
empty boxes in the R&amp;D area, so I suspect that it really isn't
that close to being done.</p>

<p>This is still an awesome game. The best part is probably the way
they are constantly developing and adding more and more to the
story and gameplay. It's very different than it was in the
beginning, but the path to here has made complete sense.</p>

<p>Total: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
