<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Valkyria Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/valkyria-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-30T00:46:00-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the "reports" I'd seen showing up were... how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service... I mean, the beach vacation... one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. The story battles are
getting pretty rough and un-cheese-able, which is really fun
because it forces me to try different things. I got a really bad
score in the second woodland battle, which was kinda sad, so I did
another skirmish so I could get the XP I missed. I really enjoyed
using the tank a lot in the woodland battle though.</p>

<p>Total: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/26/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three and half hours tonight. I spent a very
long time on the Desert Duel against the giant tank. There was a
lot of saving and reloading as I tried different techniques and
slowly got closer to victory. It was a really tough, complicated
fight. The stealth mission was pretty tough too; I kept making
stupid mistakes and trying to kill the soldier named "Ty the
Immortal"---I couldn't seem to land a killing hit on him... maybe
his name was a clue from the developers? I'm sad I didn't get an A
on that fight.</p>

<p>I think it is cool how the came is slowly becoming more
"fantastical" in its setting with the discovery at the ruins,
etc. It's neat because the earlier parts of the game are so
realistic-ish.</p>

<p>The battles tonight were especially fun because I couldn't cheese
them, so I had to really use all the options that were
available. Nevertheless, I had some pretty brutal strategies. For
example, in the desert fight, I was able to kill all the enemy
foot soldiers on the first round with my two snipers and
Rosie. Then I was able to take out all the gun turrets on the tank
in two rounds. Then it was just a matter of waiting around while
the radiators showed up. When Selvaria surprise attacked, Rosie
was right next to where her units appeared, so she was able to
kill every single one on the first round. Then Selvaria ignored
her and just ran past. It was pretty rad.</p>

<p>Total: 10:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/25/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two and half hours tonight. I did a whole bunch
of battles. The hardest was the Normal Skirmish that's like the
Woodland battle. It took me quite a few tries to get an A with
Alicia. Playing the game like this makes it like Metal Gear Solid
when you are trying to get a No Alert win. It's a very strange
optimization problem.</p>

<p>Total: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/24/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/24/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about two hours today. I replayed the first Skirmish
to get As, then I did the next two story battles (riverside and
bridge)---getting As both times, the first in one round, the
second in two---then did the next skirmish that is like the
riverside battle twice in a row (Easy then Normal) getting
one-round As as well. I spent a lot of time reading the background
material that is unlocking.</p>

<p>I'm using a really cheap technique because I want high rankings on
the battles. If I need to occupy an enemy camp (which is what
every battle has been since the Prologue), I blitz Alicia to the
base with the Defense/Evade Boost buffs active. Sometimes I need
to use a shock trooper to rush with her a little bit to destroy
the first few enemies. Sometimes I need to get the enemies out of
the base quickly, to occupy it, so I will either head shot them or
throw grenades to blow up the sandbags and/or launch them outside
the base boundaries. For the bridge battle, I was able to win in
two rounds without killing any enemies because my two grenades
launched them out. Near the end of the phase, each of her moves
barely got her closer at all, but I was able to use another
Ragnaid to survive the huge barrage of incoming fire.</p>

<p>I feel a little bad doing this exploit. Primarily because while
this gives my /characters/ the most experience; it gives me, the
/player/, the least experience. Hopefully there will be other
fights that have different objectives that will stress me
differently to get As. The main problem is that because I can't do
the story battles more than once, I feel pressure to get an A on
the first try, which leads to this ridiculous tactic. If I knew I
could try again, then I would just play it normally, then try
again for an A.</p>

<p>I have my first complaints about the game. They are pretty minor,
interface complaints, but I think it would make things a lot nicer
if they were fixed.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>You can't reset battles voluntary. If you die, you can restart
from the beginning of the battle, but you can't decide that
you've made a mistake and go back to the beginning. The only way
to do this is to make a hard save in Command mode and reload
it. This process is very cumbersome.</p></li>
<li><p>The game doesn't auto-save before battles. If you go into a
battle and die, you can restart from the beginning of the battle
without making a save yourself, but you are stuck with the
deployment decisions you originally made, which means you need
to make a hard save before every battle anyways in case you
don't put enough Lancers, etc.</p></li>
<li><p>The game doesn't give you battle statistics, like which
skirmishes you have A ranks on. I see a faded out Statistics
tab, that I will probably get in the future, but I don't see why
this is kept from me.</p></li>
<li><p>The game doesn't do a good job of helping you keep track of what
new content is available. For example, if there are new weapons
available for R&amp;D, there is no way to know that without going to
the HQ, then to R&amp;D, then to Weapons, then to the individual
kind of weapon. There should be an icon at every level of the
hierarchy that says something new is beneath that level. At
least with Book mode and some of the setting documents, it lists
which ones you have not read yet.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>So far I'm really like the story and the gameplay. It's a really
fun game!</p>

<p>Total: 4:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
