<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Valkyria Chronicles | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/valkyria-chronicles/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-03T00:18:44-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/02/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I did a few more stealth style missions. The big battle in the
trenches was really different and dangerous, although I did it in
a stealth way. The bonus mission where you had to search through
all the grassy areas was pretty cool too.</p>

<p>The story is getting really neat and touching. I can't believe
they killed Isara, but I like the way you return to Bruhl as a way
to "avenge" her. The development of the idea of Alicia being a
Valkyria is really neat too. I wonder if it will just be in
cut-scenes or if she'll become some crazy new unit type? I feel
like the story is close to wrapping up, but there are a lot more
empty boxes in the R&amp;D area, so I suspect that it really isn't
that close to being done.</p>

<p>This is still an awesome game. The best part is probably the way
they are constantly developing and adding more and more to the
story and gameplay. It's very different than it was in the
beginning, but the path to here has made complete sense.</p>

<p>Total: 22:53</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/01/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I had a very busy but ultimately unproductive day with a lot of
wasted effort, so I played games rather later to feel some
accomplishment. I played for about 2 hours. I got through all of
chapter 11 and did the skirmish that opened up three times (Easy,
Normal, Normal)... all As (2 rounds!)... to get enough money to
buy everything. The beach battle was pretty scary, but I was able
to do it in 2 rounds with only 2 restarts. It was pretty cool to
have a few "stealth" levels.</p>

<p>Total: 20:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I finished the 10th chapter tonight... the tank battle through the
city was pretty awesome, although I didn't understand how the
lifts would work, so I tried to bunch all the characters together
before having them ride it... but of course they went one at a
time. Very annoying. I wanted to keep playing tonight, but decided
not to. I wanted to because I'm curious about what Zaka will be
like... do I really get another vehicle? I'm running really low on
money too, so I think I need to play skirmishes a few times to get
capital to buy the rest of the available upgrades.</p>

<p>Total: 18:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/29/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Another three hours. Today I did a few battles and I realized what
the "reports" I'd seen showing up were... how you have to go back
in Book Mode to the report. I watched all of them. The
fan-service... I mean, the beach vacation... one was funny. The
battles are becoming quite diverse. The one where you take the
tank through the city was pretty cool, as was the one were you had
to cut off the armored car.</p>

<p>Total: 16:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyria Chronicles (PS3, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/27/Game--Valkyria-Chronicles--PS3--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about three hours tonight. The story battles are
getting pretty rough and un-cheese-able, which is really fun
because it forces me to try different things. I got a really bad
score in the second woodland battle, which was kinda sad, so I did
another skirmish so I could get the XP I missed. I really enjoyed
using the tank a lot in the woodland battle though.</p>

<p>Total: 13:30</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
