<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vanquish | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/vanquish/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-10T23:35:31-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Vanquish (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/02/07/Game--Vanquish--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/02/07/Game--Vanquish--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing Vanquish. Amazing.</p>

<p>After playing Bayonetta, I was convinced that Platinum Games
were one of the greatest game companies ever. On paper, I'd never
have bought Vanquish, but when I saw that it was made by Platinum,
I had to try it.</p>

<p>I don't think I've ever really played a third-person
shooter. I've played third-person platform games with a little
shooting---like Musashi and Tomb Raider. I think the closest I've
come is Parasite Eve on the PS1. I've certainly never played
anything in the modern "cover-based" shooter genre. But, oh man,
this game is amazing.</p>

<p>I love the cover aspect of it. It makes it feel very "real" and
gives an odd rhythm to the extreme excitement of being in the open
and the ability to relax a little behind cover. The game can
become very methodical, and I like that.</p>

<p>I really enjoyed that you were traveling with a "squad" most of
the time. Even though the AIs revealed that they didn't really do
anything (they never seemed to ever kill any enemies.) It was
still fun to have them around, interacting with you and the
environment. It was a nice way to have stupid dialogue in between
action too.</p>

<p>The game is rated M. Like Bayonetta, though, there is basically
no violence against humans---just robots. So, it is not offensive
to me. The few times (in cinematics) when there is human violence,
it is quite tame. The language is pretty bad though---however, I
listened to it in Japanese and for me personally, reading a swear
has SOOOO much less impact that hearing one, so I wasn't bothered
at all.</p>

<p>I can't believe I'm saying this, but this game is actually
faster paced than Bayonetta. It is so fast sometimes, that I
actually got a little sick playing the game and had to take
breathers. =) I'm an old fart, I guess. The amount of attention
and speed the game takes is so exhausting. Some nights, I would
schedule three hours or so to play, but I had to stop after two
because I was just so tired in the head with the crazy action. I
loved it though.</p>

<p>There are some funny little details in the game. For example,
you can surprise some robots who are dancing on their
break. Another detail: there's a soldier that you save in the
beginning, and the game goes out of its way to show you later on
how he gets shot shortly afterwards---as if it is saying how
fruitless your action was.</p>

<p>The most frustrating part of the game were a few of the "cheap"
one-hit kills. For example, if you don't destroy a robot all the
way, it will chase you and explode, killing you in one hit. There
are a few enemies that shoot lasers that kill in one hit. This is
most frustrating when they are behind you and you don't see them
power it up. But, the number one most frustrating thing is the
"Unknown" enemy. This thing is death. It can instantly kill you if
you let it get close at all. I could only kill them by spamming
EMPs and using the melee Disc Launcher attack---over and
over. Yikes.</p>

<p>I played on Normal difficulty and never used a Checkpoint---I
effectively "1cc'd" the game. Here are my stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Normal
Total Score: 265,740
Space Score: 9740
Mission Time: 5:33:33
Cover Usage: 33.99%
Distance Traveled: 34488
Munitions Fired: 32927
Deaths: 0
Confirmed Friendlies K.I.A.: 589
Wounded Friendlies Assisted: 35
Confirmed Kills: 960
Pangloss Statues Destroyed: 25
Developers Destroyed: 77</p>

<p>I wish I could've kept track of the total time I played. (The
"Mission Time" is the amount of time in all the final, completed
runs of levels.) I would guess that my actual play time was three
or four times more than that, because I had to repeat so many
levels so many times to get a perfect run. However, I never played
anything more times than necessary to get passed.</p>

<p>While when I beat Bayonetta, I immediately played through EVERY
difficulty level and got EVERY item; with Vanquish I don't feel
the need to totally destroy it and do everything. Maybe it is
because I have some other games waiting to be
played... nevertheless, I love this game! I will definitely play
it again in the next year at the next difficulty level.</p>

<p>Hoorah!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
