<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-21T19:11:25-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Duck Tales (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Duck-Tales--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today and gave it another chance. This time, it was a
total breeze. I did die in the Amazon after spending $300k, which
was really painful, but I realized that if you just hold bounce
next to the statue, guys come and die under you without a chance
of getting hurt. This was totally boring and stupid (it took
a few minutes), but it wasn't horrific. After that, there was no
more grinding. The whole game was really short... just about an
hour from start to finish. The best part was the unique challenge
of not being able to directly jump on enemies and the way you
sometimes needed to whack things with your cane. (For example,
the mummy ducks in the mansion where fun to fight when you had to
whack their ball &amp; chain.)</p>

<p>Overall, the game was fun... good music, cute monsters... and
it's classic in a certain sense, but I don't feel it is worth
replaying, because it is sooo easy.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Clash at Demonhead (NES, 1989) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Clash-at-Demonhead--NES--1989--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Clash-at-Demonhead--NES--1989--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played again today and gave a bigger chance. I was able to
accomplish somethings, including killing one of the bosses. I
still think the core gameplay is really sloppy---the hit boxes
are bad, the shot control isn't great, and the interface is
pretty whack. But, I can see why some people might have loved it
when it was released. I'm done with it though.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:40</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this tonight. Last time I played, I could barely
get past the first level because it is so brutal and you need to
grind, but it's practically impossible. This time, I tried to use
a code that gave more hearts per heart icon you got, but it didn't
really help. I used a password that gave me more levels and that
made a big difference. The hardest part of the game was the third
fortress, because it was so complex of a labyrinth. It's a fun
game... a little too floaty jumps and the inability to scroll
backward is bit rough, but for an old game it has pretty decent
mechanics. Although it is a classic in my memory, it's systems
don't live up to being a real classic.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda (Second Quest) (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost a year ago, I beat the first quest of Legend of Zelda. I'd
never really played the second quest, but I knew it existed, so
after doing Castlevania II, I decided to knock it out.</p>

<p>I played for about 2 hours and 15 minutes and got up to level 4
and had about 9 hearts and other stuff from the overworld. It was
very painful to gather all the money. I decided that I wanted to
buy the arrows and wanted to try the Money Making Game trick, but
I needed to plug in the second controller. I was scared of
accidentally bumping the NES and causing it to glitch, so I
figured I'd save first. I stupidly didn't realize that when you
do "Continue" it doesn't also save, so I just held down RESET,
saved the SRAM on my PowerPak, and rebooted. And thus I deleted
all my progress. Ouch.</p>

<p>I decided to play again, but with a Game Genie code to give me
more access to money, so I wouldn't have to do the rupee grinding
like I did the first time. It took about one hour to get back to
where I was before. Then another 2 and a half to win. 3:34 total.</p>

<p>This version of the game is much more difficult. There are parts
where you almost have to play it like a stealth game because you
are so limited in your ability to take damage.</p>

<p>I like that the maps are rearranged, but since I used online maps,
it didn't really matter... I don't have the patience to make my
own tools to do mapping for myself. I would never look at a map in
game like Castlevania (one of the Metroid-style ones) because the
in-game map system is so good. A game like Legend of Zelda that
had a really good map like there, maybe with the ability to make
notes like in Etrian Odyssey. That would be cool and you could
probably randomly generate the maps to have infinite fun. I wonder
if it would be too much like Sudoku though (in the sense that you
would always start off by trying to find the Blue Ring and then
the Candle, etc, etc.)</p>

<p>I liked the final message: "You are great. You have an amazing
wisdom and power."</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:34
Total time: 5:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania 2 (NES, 1987) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this game today using a walkthrough, maps, and
an infinite lives/hearts code. I feel like the hearts code was
essential so I didn't have to grind. The lives code didn't seem
to make much of a difference, because the game is pretty easy
(re: Egoraptor's dissection of its layout problems.) The
walkthrough and maps were definitely essential because it is so
confusing and backwards. I feel like there wasn't really anything
valuable in this game, although the mechanics felt good, but it
just wasn't anywhere near as challenging as Castlevania 1.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
