<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-10T23:35:53-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like an hour and half today. I got to stage 15, which
was a really hard part. There were many moments that were
atrociously difficult---basically anything with Fleamen or Medusa
Heads.</p>

<p>The Frankenstein's Monster boss was particularly tough, at least
until I beat the entire level perfectly and kept the Holy Water
the whole time so I could blast him with it. There are many
moments in the game that feel so unfair unless you never died to
get there. It's similar to a lot of old shmups where if you die
and loss all your power ups, you're basically toast.</p>

<p>The part I got to, where there's Medusa Heads and an Axe Knight
seems totally unfair. But it's super satisfying to beat a level in
this game. It's a bit frustrating that there are no passwords and
I have to work all the way back the next time I want to play. Cry.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/06/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/06/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today at the request of my kids. I got to the horrific
part in the second level where you are trying to get passed the
Medusa heads and platforming. The kids had a lot of fun before
that trying to play and attacking the ghouls &amp; bats. It was cute.</p>

<p>I think I will play it again.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:19</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we've been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Little Nemo: The Dream Master (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Little-Nemo--The-Dream-Master--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/16/Game--Little-Nemo--The-Dream-Master--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have this cartridge and my son thinks the box art is cool. We
played today for a little and I beat the first level... which I
haven't done any of the last four or five times he's wanted to
see the game. I feel like it's a pretty brutal game, because most
animals (and Nemo) have no offense abilities.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 5 (NES, 1992)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Mega-Man-5--NES--1992--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/08/19/Game--Mega-Man-5--NES--1992--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I play this while my son watched today. I spent twenty minutes
going through Stone Man's stage. I got to him and was doing pretty
well, but the Mega Buster wasn't powerful enough against him. The
spinning things are the worst... they crowd you and you can't
shoot them while they are touching you. It stinks, you have to
draw them away and then jump n shoot them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
