<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-23T23:41:16-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles 2: Arcade (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles-2--Arcade--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles-2--Arcade--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game sooo much when I was a kid. I enjoyed
beat-em-ups and this one in particular to play with friends.</p>

<p>I played tonight for the whole first level and then died on the
boss. It was incredibly rote and there weren't even exciting
graphics or satisfying punching like in Streets of Rage. I feel
like this genre of game is so easy to replace with better
versions that put all the old ones to shame.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Street Fighter 2010 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Street-Fighter-2010--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Street-Fighter-2010--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for maybe 10 rounds. Each time I could barely
register a few hits on the target. It's an incredibly bizarre
game. It's kind of a 2D platforming action game, but with an
incredibly small arena and horrific controls. Definitely not a
winner.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:08</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: S.C.A.T.: Special Cybernetic Attack Team (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--S-C-A-T---Special-Cybernetic-Attack-Team--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--S-C-A-T---Special-Cybernetic-Attack-Team--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game until the boss of the third stage. I used one
continue on the first stage getting to know the systems; I used
another at the beginning of stage two and stage three; then I got
to the boss of stage three and died. Stage three was incredibly
painful on the eyes because the background scroll so much.</p>

<p>The game was a very competent shooter from that era, with the
standard complaints for someone that loves CAVE. The idea that you
are person is kind of cute and the rotating options are neat
too. But, the game doesn't have enough distinctive to feel
special.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:21</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Little Nemo: The Dream Master (NES, 1990) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Little-Nemo--The-Dream-Master--NES--1990--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Little-Nemo--The-Dream-Master--NES--1990--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this game for about 30 minutes. It took me 5 minutes to
get passed level 1, then I spent the rest of the time in the next
level. I got no keys at all and could barely make any progress.</p>

<p>This game is so brutal. Nemo can't really jump over enemies, even
if he has stunned them with candy. Most of the animals have no
ability to hurt the enemies. It's so hard but you have no ways to
deal with it. It's not fun, despite the concept being great and
the general premise of turning into lots of different animals
sounds like it would be great. But, it doesn't follow through
enough.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Gun-Nac (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Gun-Nac--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/23/Game--Gun-Nac--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this and got to Area 5 on one continue. (There are 8
levels.) My score was 1,997,270 points. This is one of those old
shmups (I think of them as of the "Solider" archetype) where if
you die then you are totally screwed because you lose all your
power-ups. In this round, but Area 3, I had literally everything
you could get (there's a store to buy stuff and it tells you when
there isn't anything to get), and was stomping on everything. But
then I lost it at the end of Area 4, then spammed bombs on the
boss and then spent a few continues trying and failing to get
past Area 5.</p>

<p>There were a lot of cute graphics... really weird stuff but not
"cute" like Parodius, more just bizarre. That was fun to look at,
but the mechanics weren't worth trying again.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:36</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
