<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-10T23:02:19-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda (Second Quest) (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost a year ago, I beat the first quest of Legend of Zelda. I'd
never really played the second quest, but I knew it existed, so
after doing Castlevania II, I decided to knock it out.</p>

<p>I played for about 2 hours and 15 minutes and got up to level 4
and had about 9 hearts and other stuff from the overworld. It was
very painful to gather all the money. I decided that I wanted to
buy the arrows and wanted to try the Money Making Game trick, but
I needed to plug in the second controller. I was scared of
accidentally bumping the NES and causing it to glitch, so I
figured I'd save first. I stupidly didn't realize that when you
do "Continue" it doesn't also save, so I just held down RESET,
saved the SRAM on my PowerPak, and rebooted. And thus I deleted
all my progress. Ouch.</p>

<p>I decided to play again, but with a Game Genie code to give me
more access to money, so I wouldn't have to do the rupee grinding
like I did the first time. It took about one hour to get back to
where I was before. Then another 2 and a half to win. 3:34 total.</p>

<p>This version of the game is much more difficult. There are parts
where you almost have to play it like a stealth game because you
are so limited in your ability to take damage.</p>

<p>I like that the maps are rearranged, but since I used online maps,
it didn't really matter... I don't have the patience to make my
own tools to do mapping for myself. I would never look at a map in
game like Castlevania (one of the Metroid-style ones) because the
in-game map system is so good. A game like Legend of Zelda that
had a really good map like there, maybe with the ability to make
notes like in Etrian Odyssey. That would be cool and you could
probably randomly generate the maps to have infinite fun. I wonder
if it would be too much like Sudoku though (in the sense that you
would always start off by trying to find the Blue Ring and then
the Candle, etc, etc.)</p>

<p>I liked the final message: "You are great. You have an amazing
wisdom and power."</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:34
Total time: 5:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania 2 (NES, 1987) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--Castlevania-2--NES--1987--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through this game today using a walkthrough, maps, and
an infinite lives/hearts code. I feel like the hearts code was
essential so I didn't have to grind. The lives code didn't seem
to make much of a difference, because the game is pretty easy
(re: Egoraptor's dissection of its layout problems.) The
walkthrough and maps were definitely essential because it is so
confusing and backwards. I feel like there wasn't really anything
valuable in this game, although the mechanics felt good, but it
just wasn't anywhere near as challenging as Castlevania 1.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:57</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mike Tyson's Punch-Out!! (NES, 1987) (15)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--14/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/03/Game--Mike-Tyson-s-Punch-Out----NES--1987--14</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played this today for a little more than half and hour. I sped
through up to Soda Popinski, although Bald Bull got me once and
Piston Honda got me another time. This game is so fun. I also
played it with my new XRGB Framemeister... so beautiful!</p>

<p>Total time: 0:37</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-27T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/27/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This morning we played for a bit more than an hour and beat the
game. I played through all of Wily's Fortress three times. The
first time I got stuck on the level before the triplicator
because I ran out of energy for the Rush Jet. The second time I
got to Wily but after continuing I didn't have any E-tanks or any
of the weapons I needed to kill him. The third time I won. It was
a brutal fight and I got really good at getting through the
fortress. I think this is a great game. Mega Man 2 is awesome,
but this is great too.</p>

<p>Total time: 5:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 3 (NES, 1990) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/26/Game--Mega-Man-3--NES--1990--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played today for a little more than thirty minutes. We got to
the final boss rush, but I didn't have enough skill to beat them,
and then when I got to the continue screen I accidentally
selected "Stage Select" rather than "Continue" so was put back at
the beginning of Wily's Castle. In frustration, I quit. I
understand why this option is there---so you can gave E
tanks. But I was very annoyed that it was default and it took so
long to restart the game back to where I was.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
