<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: NES | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/nes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-15T02:01:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/05/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played tonight for about 20 minutes. I played two continues on
Ring Man's stage and couldn't get much past the Hippo. My kids
then took two continues and just stayed on the first screen
running around and climbing up the later and using the super
shot. It was cute.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 4 (NES, 1991)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/02/Game--Mega-Man-4--NES--1991--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this today for 30 minutes at the request of my son. He
loves Mega Man a lot and always wants to play one. He's very
interested in fighting Skull Man, but I went Toad -> Bright ->
Pharaoh and then died during Ring Man's stage.</p>

<p>Something I dislike about Mega Man is the three lives system. On
a single level, it is a good idea, because it requires you to get
some mastery, rather than just sacrificing life to go
forward. The problem is that when you beat a boss on your last
life, the next level you start off with only the one life. This
encourages you to commit suicide at the start of the next level
(because there's no disadvantage to doing that... you keep your E
Tanks and all your equipment.) I don't like it when games have an
optimal strategy that is (a) un-fun, (b) trivial to execute, and
(c) trivial to have just programmed out of the game.</p>

<p>In any case, this game has lots of clever concepts in its
platforming.</p>

<p>In Toad Man's stage, the rain's ability to push you is very
challenging and the rushing water is also interesting. Fighting
the Giant Snail on the water-ridden platform was very nerve
racking.</p>

<p>In Bright Man's stage, the jumping grasshoppers were cool
(although really out of place) and the enemies that shut-out the
lights when you hit them was pretty crazy. The sequence before the
boss door where you had to jump from falling/sliding platform to
the next one while the light-putter-outers where moving around and
firing. It was nuts.</p>

<p>In Pharaoh Man's stage, the platforms then when you jump on them
start moving and then fall was cool. It was particularly
challenging because the next platform would shot at you just
before you were supposed to jump on to it and if you didn't jump
early enough, you would be shocked and fall to your death.</p>

<p>In Ring Man's stage (what I've seen so far), I like the platforms
that shift from side to side as you walk across them. In one
sequence if you dropped beneath one you could get a large health
charge, but you had to jump back up quickly or else you'd be
stuck. It's a great idea.</p>

<p>This game is a very creative Mega Man game that really does
something quite different every stage, rather than executing the
same set of mechanics really well. (It's not that I think the
normal Mega Man style is bad, but this is neat.) I've heard a lot
of griping about the charged shot, but I don't find it to be so
powerful that I have to keep it charged all the time (and thus
slow down the action.) Whenever I've done that, I think it has
hurt me more than it helped.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:33</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Crystalis (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/01/Game--Crystalis--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I remember playing this game as a kid and thinking it was cool. I
just remember that it is an Action RPG. I played today for an
hour with my son and we beat the first dungeon. It's very
fun. There's a little too much grinding... I feel like I can't
move forward and search, but I have to consciously try to get
money and EXP. But, it's fun. The charge shot is essential for
staying out of harm, but it makes you less flexible, so it's a
nice mechanic to put you in stressful situations.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Adventures of Lolo 2 (NES, 1990)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/25/Game--Adventures-of-Lolo-2--NES--1990--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today I played through this whole game... throughout the day... a
total of seven hours and eleven minutes! Woah! This is a great
game. I love these escape puzzle games.</p>

<p>There are fifty puzzles, so each took an average of eight minutes,
but I'd say most were either really short... like one or two
tries... or very long. I had to seek hints about five times. The
ones that were the hardest were ones where you need to push a
block half a tile, or cover a monster spawning location with a
block so it would appear somewhere else, or where you need really
precise timing. The biggest problem with the game is when Lolo
gets stuck on edges of the grid. Nevertheless, It's a lot of fun
to play.</p>

<p>The graphics are simple and to the point, but super adorable. I
love the way Lolo runs.</p>

<p>My son had fun helping me and giving me advice during the game.</p>

<p>There's not much more to say about it, but it's very enjoyable.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:11</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles (NES, 1989)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-24T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/24/Game--Teenage-Mutant-Ninja-Turtles--NES--1989--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played three rounds and got to the boss of the first area both
times. This game is ridiculously bad. The controls are terrible
and basic mechanics are broken. For example, there's no period of
invulnerability when you get hit and you get stunlocked in
place. There were times when I missed a jump, landed on an enemy,
and slowly lost all my health as I couldn't move away.</p>

<p>I remember playing this game as a kid, but I don't remember every
getting past the first stage. I guess I never will.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
