<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2005 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2005/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-08-26T17:56:12-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Book: Joseph Smith: Rough Stone Rolling: A Cultural Biography of Mormonism's Founder, by Richard L. Bushman (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/Book--Joseph-Smith--Rough-Stone-Rolling--A-Cultural-Biography-of-Mormonism-s-Founder--by-Richard-L--Bushman--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/06/08/Book--Joseph-Smith--Rough-Stone-Rolling--A-Cultural-Biography-of-Mormonism-s-Founder--by-Richard-L--Bushman--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In my third or fourth time reading the book, I enjoyed it just as
much as past times. It was one of the first books I ever read about
<em>REDACTED</em>ism, so it defined my thinking in many ways. On this most
recent reading, I noticed that many things I find particularly
interesting were only discussed very briefly. Despite being
incredibly long, on one hand it is a tiny thimble-full of what you
could learn about Joseph Smith and early <em>REDACTED</em>ism.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: The Baxter, starring Michael Showalter (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--The-Baxter--starring-Michael-Showalter--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/05/Movie--The-Baxter--starring-Michael-Showalter--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very funny movie. It magnifies standard romantic comedy
cliches to a whole new level and is almost a "reductio ad absurdum"
of the concept of a "Baxter". I quite enjoyed it. Michelle Williams
was adorable in it, too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Shinobi - Heart Under Blade, starring Yukie Nakama (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/Movie--Shinobi---Heart-Under-Blade--starring-Yukie-Nakama--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/Movie--Shinobi---Heart-Under-Blade--starring-Yukie-Nakama--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This an intense movie. It has a very surreal fighting choreography
style that is reminiscent of Crouching Tiger but much more
crazy. Each of the shinobi have very diverse and interesting
"arts". I love how the main characters seem like the wimps the
whole movie until they are finally forced to fight and they have
The Real Ultimate Power. It's very cool. The movie is also
incredibly sad and emotional; it is fittingly tragic for a Romeo &amp;
Juliet-like story. I love the resolve of Oboro at the end. She's
super tough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Pride & Prejudice, starring Kiera Knightley (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Movie--Pride---Prejudice--starring-Kiera-Knightley--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Movie--Pride---Prejudice--starring-Kiera-Knightley--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Watching this movie so soon after reading the book was very
interesting to see what was changed, redacted, and otherwise
re-arranged. It's an amazing movie and totally does justice to the
story in the perfect time format.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid (PSP, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Metal Gear Acid for the PSP.</p>

<p>This game is utterly insane in concept. It is a turn-based
tactical game based on the Metal Gear world, with collectible card
game elements. You need to read the Wikipedia page's (linked
above) gameplay discussion to possibly understand how it
works. After playing it through, it is brilliant. I can't believe
how great it is.</p>

<p>I love the gameplay. It is so deep. The final battle is
particularly epic.</p>

<p>The art is beautiful. There is some great 2D art, in addition to
the cool 3D in the game, but the 2D is definitely a lot better.</p>

<p>The story and characters are great and really "fit" in the Metal
Gear universe, even though it is a gaiden.</p>

<p>One of my favourite things in retrospect was the opening movie
that was an "action" video, but using the card-mechanics of the
whole game, so it felt really awkward and off-kilter, but in an
endearing way.</p>

<p>I found that the stealth-gameplay was pretty weak and it was
really optimized for combat, but I think that's appropriate for
the gameplay since that's where it really shines.</p>

<p>I think it would have a lot of replay value, although I never
played any level again, although I definitely died a lot and had
to make many attempts on some levels. In all, the game took me
19:55:01 on Normal difficulty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
