<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2005 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2005/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-04-24T21:44:04-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Shinobi - Heart Under Blade, starring Yukie Nakama (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/Movie--Shinobi---Heart-Under-Blade--starring-Yukie-Nakama--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/21/Movie--Shinobi---Heart-Under-Blade--starring-Yukie-Nakama--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This an intense movie. It has a very surreal fighting choreography
style that is reminiscent of Crouching Tiger but much more
crazy. Each of the shinobi have very diverse and interesting
"arts". I love how the main characters seem like the wimps the
whole movie until they are finally forced to fight and they have
The Real Ultimate Power. It's very cool. The movie is also
incredibly sad and emotional; it is fittingly tragic for a Romeo &amp;
Juliet-like story. I love the resolve of Oboro at the end. She's
super tough.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Pride & Prejudice, starring Kiera Knightley (2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Movie--Pride---Prejudice--starring-Kiera-Knightley--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/02/22/Movie--Pride---Prejudice--starring-Kiera-Knightley--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Watching this movie so soon after reading the book was very
interesting to see what was changed, redacted, and otherwise
re-arranged. It's an amazing movie and totally does justice to the
story in the perfect time format.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid (PSP, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/11/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid--PSP--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I recently played through Metal Gear Acid for the PSP.</p>

<p>This game is utterly insane in concept. It is a turn-based
tactical game based on the Metal Gear world, with collectible card
game elements. You need to read the Wikipedia page's (linked
above) gameplay discussion to possibly understand how it
works. After playing it through, it is brilliant. I can't believe
how great it is.</p>

<p>I love the gameplay. It is so deep. The final battle is
particularly epic.</p>

<p>The art is beautiful. There is some great 2D art, in addition to
the cool 3D in the game, but the 2D is definitely a lot better.</p>

<p>The story and characters are great and really "fit" in the Metal
Gear universe, even though it is a gaiden.</p>

<p>One of my favourite things in retrospect was the opening movie
that was an "action" video, but using the card-mechanics of the
whole game, so it felt really awkward and off-kilter, but in an
endearing way.</p>

<p>I found that the stealth-gameplay was pretty weak and it was
really optimized for combat, but I think that's appropriate for
the gameplay since that's where it really shines.</p>

<p>I think it would have a lot of replay value, although I never
played any level again, although I definitely died a lot and had
to make many attempts on some levels. In all, the game took me
19:55:01 on Normal difficulty.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence (PS2, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/31/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-3--Subsistence--PS2--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/31/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-3--Subsistence--PS2--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Metal Gear Solid 3: Subsistence over three days
from the 28th to the 30th. My stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Normal
Play time: 19:14:20
Save: 12 times
Continue: 18 times
Alert Phase: 51 times
Humans Killed: 97 people
Seriously Injured: 129 times
Total Damage: 29 life bars.
Life Medicine Used: 0 times.
Plants &amp; Animals Captured: 11 kinds
Meals Eaten: 28 meals
Special Item: Not used
Title: Iguana</p>

<p>I have a lot of good things to say about this game, but I have a
few bad things and comments on the above stats.</p>

<p>First, I didn't use any life medicine, because I never realized
what it did. I guess it was like a traditional ration from the
earlier games. I'm not sure how I missed the instructions that
they did that, but I totally ignored them the whole game. It
probably would've made a few things easier if I hadn't. D'oh!</p>

<p>Next, I played on Normal, because there was no "Game Over if
Spotted" on any mode except European Extreme, which I don't have
the fortitude for. This made me really mad, because I find the
game mechanically weak unless you have to sneak, but implementing
that mode yourself with saves, reloads, etc is waaay to tedious to
actually do. As such, I think my enjoyment of the game suffered a
lot. I don't think I can think of any areas of the game that I got
through without alerting the guards. That means that I tried to
sneak, failed, and just ran past them frantically until I got to
the next cut-scene (which stopped the alert) or found somewhere to
hide, but then I'd just do it again. Thus, the game was basically
totally broken for me. The only mechanics I really did were the
combat mechanics during boss fights, which I've mentioned many
times before, I really don't like. The biggest problem though is
that by not having to do areas many times until I got them right,
I really only saw most areas for a few minutes (and in a rush at
that.) Therefore, the scenery of the game didn't have time to sink
in and create a lasting memory for me. I think that's really
annoying. I almost want to play it again on EE, but then my sanity
checks and I have no desire to go through the horrible combat. I
wish Kojima Productions would realize that the sneaking and the
combat difficulty can be separated. Bummer.</p>

<p>Finally, the game very inelegantly gave me the RPG-7 after a
cut-scene where Snake used it, even though I had never found it up
to that point in the game. Snake just talks about having it, then
uses it, and then I have access to it. Generally these games are
good at forcing you to get things like that, I'm surprised they
missed this one.</p>

<p>On to the praise... Most of my praise for the game focuses on
its unique story and setting.</p>

<p>A few gameplay things... Since the setting is low-tech, I really
enjoy the need to heal yourself, eat food, etc. It makes
everything feel so much more real and impacting. It's hard to
express just how that is. This game is a lot more linear than the
previous two MGS games, although very similar in linearity to the
Game Boy Color game I really liked. Basically, there are one-way
doors that lock you from going back in the world. This makes
things constantly feel fresh and new. It works really well in the
story as well, because you are not exploring one area like the
previous games, but you are pushing forward through a jungle to a
base and then to the escape. In a similar way, some of the
fundamental formulas of Metal Gear are really broken off in this
game. The biggest, I think, is that the game does not feel
"puzzley", but rather the challenges come about very
organically. For example, there's always been a token mine-field
that you must pass through that you are notified about, but in
this game mines appear very organically where they sensibly
should, and no one warns you about it. Another example is the lack
of remote controlled missile puzzles, etc. A lot of the same
elements are in this game, but they feel much more real and less
abstract, which is great. Overall, I'd say that I would prefer
more Metal Gear games like this, in particular, with the low-tech,
organic worlds.</p>

<p>On a technical level, there are some great aspects. First, the
music and ambient sound is out of the park amazing. The jungle
sounds like a jungle. Second, the areas are huge and impressive,
not the tiny corridors and rooms from previous games. The models
are nice and the art direction controls the exposure of their
flaws. Third, the first-person view jokes are great.</p>

<p>The best part of the game though, as I said before, is the setting
and story.</p>

<p>I love the opening James-Bond-style movie.</p>

<p>There are many times when characters will quote people from
earlier games that fill the same role as them. For example, Naked
Snake quotes Big Boss (himself) from MG2:SS and Solid Snake from
MGS1 (although I guess in the second case that would imply that
Big Boss had a big influence on Solid and gave him that idea.)</p>

<p>The whole development of Revolver Ocelot is amazing. The subtle
reveals when he is first introduced that he is one and the same;
the relationship between him and Naked; the "origin" story they
setup; and the best part---the post-credits reveal that harkens
back to MGS1 and lays a huge foundational mystery for the whole
series. If there weren't so many other amazing characters, Ocelot
would've been the star.</p>

<p>In general, all the characters have really great moments that
reveal who their characters are. The characters serve really well
to reinforce the setting's believably and put you in the time
period. I especially like the constant chatter about old movies on
the radio.</p>

<p>But in the end, the game totally sold me on the amazing heroism of
Naked Snake and The Boss. They are so honorable and amazing,
self-sacrificing heroes. I know it sounds cheesy, but it makes me
so proud of people and touches my heart that such pure virtues are
conceivable. When Big Boss was honoring The Boss at the end, it
gave me chills and brought some tears to my eyes. I'm especially a
sucker for tragedy and it hit the spot there too. Another part I
loved the heroism of was when EVA and Snake are about to go off
towards the end of the game and the Metal Gear theme slowly starts
to play... amazing.</p>

<p>I found the philosophy of the game great too. Especially The
Boss's speech about how enemies don't really exist, because we're
all human beings and can connect on that level.</p>

<p>This has hands down the best "ending sequence" of any Metal
Gear. Not just the scenes after you can play, but the whole final
sequence of getting to the end---basically from planting the bombs
to the end. It is so epic and awesome.</p>

<p>What a game. I will play it again some day.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: WarioWare: Touched! (DS, 2005)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/31/Game--WarioWare--Touched---DS--2005--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/12/31/Game--WarioWare--Touched---DS--2005--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through WarioWare: Touched! and had a chance with all of
the games. It is really fun, just like /WarioWare: Smooth Moves/
for the Wii.</p>

<p>This is the perfect game for someone with ADD, especially once
you unlock the Megamix and can sit on one screen and go through
the whole variety of games. I really enjoyed the retro games, but
I was a little annoyed when the control was really different than
the original game, because I felt stupid being so bad at them
initially. I thought the mic-based games were all very lazy and
easily the worst part of the game. my wife and I played the
Ping-Pong game, which was an incredibly clever use of the dual
screens of the DS.</p>

<p>Overall, I enjoyed the game a lot; I'll keep it around to play
whenever I need something quick to fool around with.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
