<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/star-ocean-the-last-hope-international/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-16T11:12:13-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/13/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played another 30-ish minutes of the game. I decided that I'm
not interested enough in this game to play it. The story seems
fine, maybe a bit cliche. The interesting thing to me was the
setting of the intro movie, which was abandoned pretty instantly
and now I'm on random medieval planet (like the first three
games.) I'll ignore a boring story if the gameplay is awesome,
but...</p>

<p>I can't remember what the combat system was like for the third
game (I remember liking it, but I feel like it was similar to
this) but I'm not compelled by this one at all. It's a cross
between way too easy and way too frustrating. For example, most
battles can be won by simply pressing X over and over. There's a
"blindside" system, but it's basically impossible to use when you
are ganged up on, and when you aren't ganged up on, you can just
time your attacks to never need to dodge. It's frustrating that
you can't really use it well. The targeting system is really
frustrating because it never seems to go where you want and
there's no way to lock on to a target. The field is really bad,
because sometimes you'll run at an enemy from behind, but the hit
detection is off, so you end up getting them from the side and you
get a Surprise attack, even though you clearly snuck up on them
from behind. Argh! The controls in combat are really laggy with
hidden timers or something. This is the worst when it comes to
jumping. You'll hit the button and then have a noticeable delay
before the jump happens.</p>

<p>The game aspires to feel like a third-person action game, but it's
not good enough at it to make the comparison a good thing. It
pales in comparison to Bayonetta. I don't think I have the time
and interest to play 50 hours (the median time on
HowLongToBeat.com) of something that is not totally amazing.</p>

<p>I'm glad I've played tri-Ace games released after this, because I
can imagine that if I played this on release, I would be skeptical
of their ability to continue to deliver hits. But, Resonance of
Fate was amaaaazing, so tri-Ace still has it.</p>

<p>So long, Star Ocean.</p>

<p>Total: 4:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/10/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour tonight and mainly did story and
exploration stuff. I got the ability to go to other planets and
got to the medieval world. The game is okay so far. I haven't
really been captured by it. I'm not sure why. The combat system
doesn't seem as advanced as I'd like and a lot of the world is
pretty empty and samey. I'll keep playing, but I'm a bit sad I
haven't been totally won over by it.</p>

<p>Total: 3:42</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/09/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about an hour and a half tonight. I did one adventure
and boss fight, learning a bit more about the world and the alien
races you can interact with. I found the combat to be a bit
weird. When I was controlling Edge, I was finding it very hard to
be successful and dodge attacks. It feels like it should control
more like an action game, but the animations and cool-downs
between the usability of actions are very long, so it feels
strangely sluggish, despite otherwise moving at a pretty fast
pace. I found the amount of health items and the distance to the
"Inn" to be pretty grueling. I felt like there were quite a few
times were I was almost going to die because of trying to preserve
healing items. The boss was pretty tough, but I felt like I got
into a nice stride with it. I healed right before I killed it,
because I felt like the battle was going to keep going on for a
long time.</p>

<p>In a small way I've been introduced to something I find very scary
about Star Ocean games: the item invention and harvesting
system. There's just so many options to explore, it can be really
overwhelming.</p>

<p>I think doing one "episode" per night will be a pretty good rate
for this game.</p>

<p>Total: 2:39</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I'm looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don't really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It's the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful, although a little bit of the time
I felt like I was losing because I couldn't target the thing I
wanted. The graphics are pretty good, although the characters are
verrry anime-y and from some angles their clothes really clash
with their faces. (For example, the guy on the computer screen
that Edge talks to.) The controls are responsive.  Although the
camera controls are a little too "tight" for my taste so far. I
got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I think the
problem is that the world is so "bright" that it's hard to notice
something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of the time was
spent in videos, so I don't really have a good feel for the game
yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
