<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/star-ocean-the-last-hope-international/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-08T22:23:39-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Star Ocean: The Last Hope International (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/05/08/Game--Star-Ocean--The-Last-Hope-International--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've played the first and third Star Ocean games and really
enjoyed them. I generally like everything that tri-Ace does, so
I'm looking forward to this game. I like the idea of the enhanced
PS3 version, but I don't really know anything about the game or
about what is enhanced about this release.</p>

<p>--</p>

<p>I played for about an hour in my first session. The concept of the
world is pretty cool. It's the first Star Ocean I can think of
that has Earth as a real place. I wonder if it is supposed to be
in the same continuity as the other games? The gameplay seems like
it will be cool. The battle system tutorial was incredibly
complicated and I did during the battle three times before
winning. That makes me hopeful. The graphics are pretty good,
although the camera controls are a little too "tight" for my taste
so far. I got a little stuck walking around in the space ship. I
think the problem is that the world is so "bright" that it's hard
to notice something you can bump into. Anyways, the majority of
the time was spent in videos, so I don't really have a good feel
for the game yet.</p>

<p>Total: 1:03</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
