<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PC | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/pc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-29T22:13:59-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Desktop Dungeons (PC, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/02/Game--Desktop-Dungeons--PC--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/07/02/Game--Desktop-Dungeons--PC--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I've been playing Desktop Dungeons every few days for about two
months. I was able to get through the normal mode easily with the
Fighter and the advanced version of the Fighter, but I haven't
been able to with any other classes---I've tried the next Fighter
and the Thief, mainly the Thief. I feel like the game's random
creation engine is flawed and creates un-beatable dungeons. For
example, in the last one I did, I beat every enemy and was only
level 8, but the boss is always level 10 and indestructible. I've
decided to stop playing because of this... I gave it many chances,
but every play session is becoming too rote. Initially, I thought
it was very cool because it flet like a roguelike, but was very
bite-sized. I think the idea is still good, but needs to be
refined.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Portal (PC, 2007)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/06/Game--Portal--PC--2007--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-05-06T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/05/06/Game--Portal--PC--2007--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Portal over
the last little bit. The game is really clever and unique. The
puzzles were nothing quite like I've experienced before and the
story is clever. I love the idea that you break out of a puzzle
game and use your skills "against" the game in the "real
world".</p>

<p>Definitely a great and memorable game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Machinarium (PC, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/07/Game--Machinarium--PC--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-05-07T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/05/07/Game--Machinarium--PC--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week or so, I've played through Machinarium, a Flash
game available on many platforms---I played on the Mac.</p>

<p>It was a very enjoyable point-and-click adventure game. I
haven't played one of those in a while, so it was very fresh for
me. The graphics were beautiful, to a totally stunning degree. The
puzzles were interesting without being opaque or infuriating. (The
only annoyances were the Tic-Tac-Toe game and the bad top-down
shooting/exploration mini-game at the end---it was bad because the
controls were horrible.) My favourite puzzles were the many
Sokoban variants, particularly the one in the Arcade and the
string of beads.</p>

<p>I got the game <a href="http://www.indiegames.com/blog/2010/04/machinarium_for_mac_free_today.html">for free</a>, so it was totally worth it. It costs <a href="http://www.macgamestore.com/detail.php?ProductID=1287">$20</a>
and I'd say it is worth closer to $15.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: VVVVVV (PC, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/26/Game--VVVVVV--PC--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/26/Game--VVVVVV--PC--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Saturday, Sunday and this morning I played through VVVVVV, by
Terry Cavanagh.</p>

<p>This is a puzzle platformer with beautiful retro
audio-visuals. You can move left, right, and "flip" on to the
ceiling (or floor if you were on the ceiling.) This simple
mechanical system is used to a brilliant degree in the level
design. Some areas were incredibly frustrating, but incredibly
satisfying as well. My best experience was getting the "hardest"
trinket in the game, the one in /Doing Things the Hard Way/ (every
room has a clever name.) Here's a video of someone else doing it:
<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch#!v=4CtiY5D6HCs&amp;feature=related">YouTube</a>.</p>

<p>Here are my end-game stats:</p>

<p>Trinkets Found: Twelve of Twenty
Game Time: 3:46:19</p>

<p>Total Flips: 4995
Total Deaths: 2189</p>

<p>Hardest Room (with 261 deaths):
Veni</p>

<p>Here's another look at the statistics: 226 minutes. 22 flips
per minute. 9.7 deaths per minute.</p>

<p>I definitely recommend it! You can play on pretty much anything
that has Flash, so it's easy to play.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Cave Story (PC, 2004)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/17/Game--Cave-Story--PC--2004--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-04-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/04/17/Game--Cave-Story--PC--2004--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past few days, I've played through Cave Story on the
PC. (It has recently been re-released in an updated form for
WiiWare.)</p>

<p>It has a very unique and fun mix of Mega Man, Metroid, and
Adventure-style game play. I played through the "Hard" version of
the game where you get Booster 2.0 and I played through the "Hell"
final area as well.</p>

<p>I highly recommend it. It is free to download and it's very
fun. It inspires me to work more often on my game ideas.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
