<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1988 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1988/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-20T22:55:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Xexyz (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Xexyz--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-12-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/12/16/Game--Xexyz--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about 15 minutes today. This is one of those
older NES games with really spotty controls but lots of
interesting ideas, that really doesn't work super well. On the
first level you have to wander around a whole bunch of screens
looking for which star block to shoot five times to open a secret
door. I didn't find the controls and mechanics very appealing, so
I think that's it for me.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:14</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Wonder Boy in Monster Land (SMS, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Wonder-Boy-in-Monster-Land--SMS--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for about an hour today. I used an emulator and
couldn't resist save states. In the beginning, I worked my way
through on my own, using saves at each screen. I had no sense of
what the items would do, so I didn't really buy any. After a
while, I looked at a walkthrough (which basically just recommended
which items to buy) and learned that I missed a few essential
hidden items. I restarted and made it to stage 4 following the
guide. I went away to eat, paused, and when I came back, the game
had reset itself.</p>

<p>This game looks and sounds really good, especially for its
age. It's cute and has some interesting mechanics. I think of it
as a lot like Zelda 2, but with a less interesting combat system,
sloppier mechanics, and a more advanced inventory system. I found
the jumps to feel really wrong and the combat delays to be pretty
painful. The inventory system, once you realize what things are,
is neat.</p>

<p>Overall, I'd say that this is a pretty amazing game for its age,
but that a lot about it works against it. The biggest problem is
the lack of continues. The game is too deep on a customization
level to make sense as an arcade game. I presume that later
version of the game change this, because they were designed for
consoles. Secondly, the sprites are a bit too big and they make
it hard to see what's going on. Third, the jumps and fighting
don't feel quite right.</p>

<p>I won't play this, but I'm excited to investigate other games in
this series.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:52</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Alien Crush (TG16, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Alien-Crush--TG16--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-22T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/22/Game--Alien-Crush--TG16--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played this for a while today on an emulator. This game is
gorgeous and amazingly detailed. I love the "living" board
concept and it works really well. The hit detection on the bottom
on the paddles seems a bit off, but it's not too hard to get used
to.</p>

<p>I got a 1.3 mil score and my dad got 4.7 mil. It was fun to pass
the game back and forth. But, for me, there's not enough of a
carrot to chase after, because I don't really have a good concept
of what scores are possible and most of my deaths felt random &amp;
weren't learning experiences.</p>

<p>I enjoy the game a lot, although I'm not sure how much I
like <em>this</em> game and how much I just like pinball. In any case,
the problem with the game is the amount of friction it takes to
setup and play for how long would be optimal. I can imagine
playing this for 10 minutes at a time, but it would take at least
5 to get everything ready to play it. This game (with what is
available today to be entertained with) needs some external
scheduling and a speedy front-end.</p>

<p>Total time: 0:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Final Fantasy 2 (NES, 1988)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-2--NES--1988--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/21/Game--Final-Fantasy-2--NES--1988--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played tonight for two and half hours. I found it unbearable. I
couldn't find any codes, so I decided to use the exploits with
canceling commands. That was actually a bad idea because it meant
I couldn't effectively do the "hit yourself" trick to get HP and
MP. The next big problem was that I couldn't do that because I
didn't have enough money to pay for the inn to heal after I used
all my MP. The thing that is so annoying about this game is that
you don't feel like you're getting anything from battles. At
least in Dragon Quest, you are making progress. In this, I feel
like I was either cheating or wasting my time. In the average
random battle, I would barely make 10 GP, but I needed around 100
to 200 to use the inn and then over 400 to pay for a spell. I'm
curious about the story, but I'll have to play one of the
re-releases that put in a traditional experience system.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:24</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we've been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
