<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1988 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1988/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-08T22:46:33-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/29/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today my son wanted to play this real bad rather than Mega Man X
(which we've been playing for a while.) So we did it. We played
through the whole game. I got stuck pretty bad on the Wily
Machine, but other than that I walked through the game pretty
easily. I happened to choose a really nice order for the levels
so I had a lot of good items and weapons during the levels. It
was really fun to go through the whole game.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:44</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/17/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My son wanted to see this played again today. We decided that my
wife would play (her first time) and she'd go against Metal
Man. It took her about 6 continues, but she eventually beat the
level. She used an E tank on the boss and got him on her first
try. Go team!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Mega Man 2 (NES, 1988) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/11/Game--Mega-Man-2--NES--1988--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Played through 6 Robot Masters today with my 3-year old son while
my wife slept. I love the lesson he is learning: "If you die, Dad,
just continue and try again... don't worry it's not too hard, you
can do it."</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 3 (NES, 1988) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/28/Game--Dragon-Warrior-3--NES--1988--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/28/Game--Dragon-Warrior-3--NES--1988--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through Dragon Warrior 3 over the past week and a half.</p>

<p>My opinions on this game are very similar to DW1 and DW2. This
much more mechanically strong that DW2 but not as much of a leap
as DW2 was over DW1. I enjoyed the class changing system.</p>

<p>I used anti-grinding Game Genie codes to limit the amount I had to
do it---one gave me more XP and the other more GP. The combat
system gets pretty old, especially with random monsters. Fighting
the bosses is typically really fun.</p>

<p>I also played with a guide, so I didn't have to figure out where I
needed to go myself, but I got the impression that it was much
less obscure than DW2, but not as clear as even a SNES-era game.</p>

<p>For these two reasons, I definitely didn't get a true DW3
experience, although I'm willing to bet that I wouldn't want that
experience. Instead, I just enjoyed the story.</p>

<p>The connection to the other games is easily the coolest part of
this and really comes out of nowhere, but makes complete sense
after the fact. I thought it was also really cool how you run into
your father right at the end. It's really neat.</p>

<p>I'm looking forward to the first truly played DW game.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior 3 (NES, 1988) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/28/Game--Dragon-Warrior-3--NES--1988--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/01/28/Game--Dragon-Warrior-3--NES--1988--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Baramos is hard. And beat me the first time. Going to the world of
DW1 is rad. Seeing your dad at the end is cool.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
