<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 3D Dot Game Heroes | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/3d-dot-game-heroes/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-20T23:12:02-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: 3D Dot Game Heroes (PS3, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/02/09/Game--3D-Dot-Game-Heroes--PS3--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/02/09/Game--3D-Dot-Game-Heroes--PS3--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I just finished playing 3D Dot Game Heroes.</p>

<p>I played for three nights. The first night I just started the
game and fooled around. The next night I got up to the Aqua temple
(7/15ths through the game). The next night (tonight) I got to the
end of the Aqua temple and the game crashed as I was leaving the
temple and I lost all my progress for the night. I do not tolerate
bugs like this, so I'm not interested in continuing the game.</p>

<p>There were some things I liked about this game: the quirky
graphics are very fun, especially the way that modern particle,
liquid, and reflection effects are used to accentuate the visuals;
the gigantic sword is cool; the core Zelda 1 gameplay is fun.</p>

<p>However, there are a few things I did not like: the movement is
not grid-based, so it is very easy to get slightly ajar from
enemies (who do move in a grid) and miss them when not powered up
despite standing in front of them; similarly, it is pretty easy to
get stuck on a corner for the same reason; the world is large (it
is the size of Zelda 3) but it feels really empty (there is a
Zelda 1 amount of stuff); and, obviously, the game breaking
bug.</p>

<p>Now that I've decided to drop it, I looked at the GameFAQs
page. It talks a lot about side quests and extra swords, etc, that
you can get. That sounds like it would be fun and add
replayability, but these things seem really buried in the
nose-to-the-grind-stone gameplay. I didn't notice many hooks
during my play-through of half the game. I'm sure if the game
wasn't broken, though, I'd want to stick around and do some of
them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
