<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Donkey Kong Country Returns | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/donkey-kong-country-returns/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-07T22:16:20-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-09T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/09/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Today we played for an hour and a half-ish. We beat the game! The
final boss and the last rocket sequence was pretty tough and my
wife was getting very frustrated, but we eventually did it.</p>

<p>The Nintendo Channel clocks our total time at 20 hours and 52
minutes (I haven't been keeping track of our game play that long.)</p>

<p>We decided that the game is a lot more sloppy in many ways
compared to NSMBW, but that we had a lot of fun, especially once
we got infinite lives. We don't love the game enough to try to get
all the bonuses to unlock the hidden temple, so that's that.</p>

<p>I like platformers, but I like playing games with my wife more.</p>

<p>Time: 7:58</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/08/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for an hour and beat the first three levels of
World 8. There was a normal platforming level (although it had
lots of breaking platforms), then a rocket level, then a mine-cart
level. The rocket levels are so terrible because they are just
memorization mazes with an awful control scheme. It was
annoying. But eventually I got in the zone and did it. I think my
wife was a bit mad because she kept trying and dying every other
time.</p>

<p>Time: 6:22</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (8)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played for about two hours and beat the rest of the factory
levels. We discovered a way to grind for balloons but decided not
to. We traded our time for just using a cheat code that gives
infinite balloons. It's amazing how much more fun the game is
now, because we can play a little less cautiously and give my
wife more opportunities to do the difficult platforming sequences
where she used to just climb on my back. I think that might be
why we liked Mario so much more, because the Desert Life grind is
so effective.</p>

<p>Time: 5:13</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/03/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We tried to play again tonight and only beat one factory level
then decided to try to grind for balloons, but there's no good
opportunities to, so we gave up that for a bit and did something
else.</p>

<p>Time: 3:02</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Donkey Kong Country Returns (Wii, 2010) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/09/02/Game--Donkey-Kong-Country-Returns--Wii--2010--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We played a few levels tonight and finished Area 6. I found a lot
of the levels to be really difficult to have two people, because
they use forced scrolling and the timed barrel jumps, which
require a lot more synchronization than is reasonable between two
people. Overall, the game seems to have multiplayer as an after
thought, especially with the varied capabilities of the two
players. The boss of Area 6 was very exciting to beat with my
wife, we were yelling and jumping out of our seats as we
recognized tells of the boss.</p>

<p>Time: 2:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
