<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1986 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1986/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-06-07T22:53:07-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior (NES, 1986) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--Dragon-Warrior--NES--1986--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/22/Game--Dragon-Warrior--NES--1986--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I listened to the <a href="http://www.crunkgames.com/?p%3D380">Crunk Games</a> Dragon Quest special and Alex said
something really funny about Dragon Quest. He said something like,
"Dragon Quest is quintessentially Japanese because it is based on
the premise that success comes from putting in the hours of time,
not acquiring skill." They then discussed how Japanese people love
lines and have many meaningless "put in the hours" work and study
experiences. I've heard this before, but it is interesting to hear
it discussed as a fundamental feature of Dragon Quest: anyone can
beat it no matter how good they are. I actually think a lot of
modern games are like that, and that's what I don't like about
them.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Dragon Warrior (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/Game--Dragon-Warrior--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/03/15/Game--Dragon-Warrior--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched the <a href="http://retrowaretv.com/16-bit-gems-rise-of-the-rpg-a-history/">16-Bit Gems - Rise of the RPG: A History</a> documentary
and was blown away by how amazing Dragon Quest is when compared to
previous games. It really is a huge leap ahead.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Valkyrie no BÅken: Toki no Kagi Densetsu (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Valkyrie-no-B-ken--Toki-no-Kagi-Densetsu--NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Valkyrie-no-B-ken--Toki-no-Kagi-Densetsu--NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I got this game when I ordered my AV Famicom from Japan. I
immediately tried it but it seems to be corrupted or something
because both the actual cart and the ROM (through my PowerPak)
have all sorts of graphical glitches. Reading the Wikipedia page
makes it sound intriguing, but I can't try it.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have very found memories of playing Kid Icarus a lot and
associate it with Metroid in my mind as one of those great NES
games with a system that modern games have kind of forgot. I
played it again recently and was utterly destroyed by it. The
cruelty of the games defies description: there is basically no way
to restore health during one of the long levels (except the
fortresses) and when you move from one level to another, you keep
however much health you had during the last one without bringing
it up to full, so you can get irreparably in the hole. Plus,
you need to grind to increase your maximum possible life. I got to
the first fortress and was destroyed. When I remember back to
being young and playing this, I seem to recall using a password to
get to the end a lot, so I tried that it was fun to play that
again, but I really wish I could play through the game proper.</p>

<p>Playing through that portion made me realize that it really isn't
anything like Metroid. In a sense, Metroid takes a run-n-gun
platformer (like Contra) and combines it with a Zelda-like item
upgrade and open world structure. In contrast, Kid Icarus
takes a run-n-gun platformer (like Contra) and adds just two
aspects of RPGs: item stores and grinding. Not the best things to
add, in my opinion.</p>

<p>I will play it again, but I'll move on to the next game for
now. I've realized that what I want to do is take a first pass at
all the older games that I remember or have heard so much about
and figure out which ones I really do want to invest some time
in. If the game is appealing enough, then I'll play through it
right then, otherwise I'll mark it down in my list to continue
with later. This game definitely makes the cut for the "play in
the future" list.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Ikari Warriors (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Ikari-Warriors--NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/11/20/Game--Ikari-Warriors--NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I tried to play Ikari Warriors on my Famicom. I wanted to play it
because I've heard it talked about some many times. But it was
excruciatingly slow. I couldn't tell if it was the fault of my
PowerPak or the normal behavior, but when I looked at videos
online, it didn't seem like it was normally faster. It reminded me
a little bit of Iron Tank, which I remember liking.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
