<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 1986 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/1986/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-24T22:50:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Kid Icarus (NES, 1986) (2)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/20/Game--Kid-Icarus--NES--1986--1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played and beat this tonight. Last time I played, I could barely
get past the first level because it is so brutal and you need to
grind, but it's practically impossible. This time, I tried to use
a code that gave more hearts per heart icon you got, but it didn't
really help. I used a password that gave me more levels and that
made a big difference. The hardest part of the game was the third
fortress, because it was so complex of a labyrinth. It's a fun
game... a little too floaty jumps and the inability to scroll
backward is bit rough, but for an old game it has pretty decent
mechanics. Although it is a classic in my memory, it's systems
don't live up to being a real classic.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:47</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Legend of Zelda (Second Quest) (NES, 1986)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-04T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/04/Game--The-Legend-of-Zelda--Second-Quest---NES--1986--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Almost a year ago, I beat the first quest of Legend of Zelda. I'd
never really played the second quest, but I knew it existed, so
after doing Castlevania II, I decided to knock it out.</p>

<p>I played for about 2 hours and 15 minutes and got up to level 4
and had about 9 hearts and other stuff from the overworld. It was
very painful to gather all the money. I decided that I wanted to
buy the arrows and wanted to try the Money Making Game trick, but
I needed to plug in the second controller. I was scared of
accidentally bumping the NES and causing it to glitch, so I
figured I'd save first. I stupidly didn't realize that when you
do "Continue" it doesn't also save, so I just held down RESET,
saved the SRAM on my PowerPak, and rebooted. And thus I deleted
all my progress. Ouch.</p>

<p>I decided to play again, but with a Game Genie code to give me
more access to money, so I wouldn't have to do the rupee grinding
like I did the first time. It took about one hour to get back to
where I was before. Then another 2 and a half to win. 3:34 total.</p>

<p>This version of the game is much more difficult. There are parts
where you almost have to play it like a stealth game because you
are so limited in your ability to take damage.</p>

<p>I like that the maps are rearranged, but since I used online maps,
it didn't really matter... I don't have the patience to make my
own tools to do mapping for myself. I would never look at a map in
game like Castlevania (one of the Metroid-style ones) because the
in-game map system is so good. A game like Legend of Zelda that
had a really good map like there, maybe with the ability to make
notes like in Etrian Odyssey. That would be cool and you could
probably randomly generate the maps to have infinite fun. I wonder
if it would be too much like Sudoku though (in the sense that you
would always start off by trying to find the Blue Ring and then
the Candle, etc, etc.)</p>

<p>I liked the final message: "You are great. You have an amazing
wisdom and power."</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:34
Total time: 5:46</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/21/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I decided to beat this game today. I used a cheat code to give
infinite lines, so I didn't need to worry about continues and
replaying sections over and over (at least, until I got passed
them once, or in the case of the stage before a boss battle, more
times.) However, even with that, I was able to get to
Frankenstein's in 3 lives. I took another three to get to stage
15 (the stage that ends in Death.) I did all that in about 30
minutes. I played the stage before Death for about 25 minutes
before church. Then I had a very NES moment and left the system
running while I was at church.</p>

<p>When I got back, I played Death's sequence over and over again
for an hour and a half. Eventually I decided to focus on not
losing any life at all during the hallway with the two axe
knights and the brutal Medusa heads, by willingly sacrificing
lots of hearts. This turned out to be a good move and I gradually
improved. It took maybe three times of getting to Death with full
health before I defeated him. It was awesome.</p>

<p>It only took about 15 minutes to get to Dracula after that. It
took another hour and a half before I beat Dracula. It got to the
point where I could get passed the first form without taking any
damage pretty reliably, but then I had to work on my moves to
fight the second form. Eventually I decided to try the potion
rather than the cross, because the cross didn't seem to do much
damage. This was an awesome move. The potion doesn't do any
damage, but it stunlocks him so he can't move. Provided I didn't
have the double shot, I was able to lay into him for two hits,
then stun, then repeat. I was triumphant!</p>

<p>Altogether, I beat the game in about four hours. It felt so good
to do it. Even though I used a code, it was a pretty weak code
because I had to do everything. It's a good example about what
I'd like games to do---be like spaced repetition systems (like
Anki), have me do a stage until I can beat it reliably, then move
on, but don't show me something that is now easy (or moderate,
but with random swings all the time.)</p>

<p>I'm very glad I gave this game a chance. Initially, the controls
felt so gross, but now I really love their unique stickiness.</p>

<p>Cycle time: 3:58
Total time: 6:59</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/13/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/13/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played two times today. The first time for about 45 minutes and
I got to Stage 9. I found it incredibly difficult to get past the
bone pillars... I just couldn't get the rhythm I needed to
destroy their fireballs. It was brutal.</p>

<p>I played again latter in the day for 30 minutes and got to
Stage 11. I found it very hard that time to get past the flea men
being dropped from the eagles. This game is so hard. I don't like
that I can't restart at where I was, but I appreciate that I have
to get good at the whole game to win.</p>

<p>Total time: 3:01</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Castlevania (NES, 1986) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/10/Game--Castlevania--NES--1986--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for like an hour and half today. I got to stage 15, which
was a really hard part. There were many moments that were
atrociously difficult---basically anything with Fleamen or Medusa
Heads.</p>

<p>The Frankenstein's Monster boss was particularly tough, at least
until I beat the entire level perfectly and kept the Holy Water
the whole time so I could blast him with it. There are many
moments in the game that feel so unfair unless you never died to
get there. It's similar to a lot of old shmups where if you die
and loss all your power ups, you're basically toast.</p>

<p>The part I got to, where there's Medusa Heads and an Axe Knight
seems totally unfair. But it's super satisfying to beat a level in
this game. It's a bit frustrating that there are no passwords and
I have to work all the way back the next time I want to play. Cry.</p>

<p>Total time: 1:45</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
