<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: The Last Remnant | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/the-last-remnant/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-24T22:50:51-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (7)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--6/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/18/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours today. I went through one dungeon
and got to a really hard boss fight. I've been on a pattern of try
the boss then go back to the beginning of the dungeon fighting
dudes and back so I can gain some levels and try again. I think
I've had about 5 or 6 loops so far. It's pretty brutal too because
there's a medium difficulty boss battle before it that you have to
go through, so each failing boss fight takes about 10 minutes.</p>

<p>I've been talking with my wife about some of the stupid stuff in
this game. The biggest problem with it is the lack of agency in
almost every aspect of the game.</p>

<ul>
<li><p>Each unit has specific skills, like Smash II or Restore III, but
you don't get to choose what skills will actually be
used. Instead, you choose between a few "baskets" of
attacks. For example, you might have the option "<em>REDACTED</em>ge" which
has your five guys just do basic attacks and then you'll also
have "Attack 'em hard, man" which has two of your guys do two
seemingly random physical attacks. There's no option to just
determine what your units will do.</p></li>
<li><p>It's not even possible for you to always choose each type of
basket. For example, generally there is a (1) no AP basket, (2)
physical AP basket, (3) magic AP basket, (4) healing AP basket,
and (5) hexing/buffing basket. Each one sometimes has a second
variant that uses much more AP. However, it's not the case that
on any given round you can choose between any of the baskets. I
have no idea what algorithm it is using to determine what I am
allowed to do. This is most frustrating with healing. Suppose I
have 2k HP and I'm fighting something that I know can do 1.2k
damage sometimes. If I get hit and get knocked down past 1.5k,
I'd like to heal as insurance for the eventually big one. Last
Remnant does not allow this. It only gives you the ability to
heal (and other teams to heal you) when you are really low, for
some unknown definition of really low. In this case, it's too
late. It is almost like the FF13 Paradigm system where all the
characters are AI controlled and you aren't allowed to switch to
any Paradigm whenever you want.</p></li>
<li><p>Outside of combat, there's a similar lack of agency in the
character progression system. You have a whole bunch of
characters, but not one of them gives you the ability to decide
what skills they will learn as they progress. Rush (the main
character) can sometimes choose between two options after a
battle, but you don't really have any perspective on this
decision and it's very micro. Some of the leaders will ask you
whether to focus on physical or magical attacks, but
repercussions of this are pretty vague. You can't change the
equipment on your characters, except for the main one, but you
almost never need to do it (it seems) because there's rarely
anything better than what you have or will find in a dungeon in
a little bit.</p></li>
</ul>


<p>Despite these big game play problems, I find the core idea pretty
interesting and it's tempting to keep playing and grind through it,
but I'm beginning to think it's just not worth given the many other
great games that are available.</p>

<p>I find the story to be pretty intriguing and original. The
production values are pretty bad in a lot of places and some of the
micro-story bits are pretty lame, but it's a reasonable package.</p>

<p>I feel real bad putting down games and not playing them to
completion, but I just can't get behind such flawed game play.</p>

<p>I was having a discussion with someone the other day about what
makes good game play and I stated three things:</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Intuition</em></li>
</ul>


<p>The challenge of the game should require some inexplicable skill
that can't be feasibly turned into an algorithm by
humans. Tic-Tac-Toe is flawed in this way. A shmup is super easy
to imagine (algorithm: dodge bullets when they get close), but
it's basically impossible to succeed with such a system. Most
strategy and role-playing games can get too close to the edge of
easy to axiomatize. Games that /require/ memorization are some of
the worst offenders on this category by going in the opposite
direction from Tic-Tac-Toe; rather than having a deeply
algorithmic structure, they lack any coherence at all, so you
must resort to pure memorization.</p>

<p>The Last Remnant is pretty good in this camp, I think, but the
place where the choice enters in is pretty weak---primarily in
what order your unions attack what enemy unions and to a lesser
extent how much AP you spend on any turn.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Fairness</em></li>
</ul>


<p>When you fail, it should be clear to you that it is your
fault. This doesn't mean you should know what to do to succeed,
but rather you should believe that you did something wrong. For
example, Super Mario Brothers is very good with this, except on
the ZX Spectrum, where the lack of scrolling forced you to do
blind jumps.</p>

<p>The Last Remnant is very bad on this category because it's lack
of player agency makes you always feel like it was the RNG that
killed you and not your lack of ability/planning/strategy/etc.</p>

<ul>
<li><em>Precision</em></li>
</ul>


<p>A complement of Fairness is Precision, which means that you the
burden to communicate your intentions should be reasonable. Mario
is practically perfect here, because there is basically no delay
between your choice and the action and the set of actions (jump,
move, etc) is perfectly matched by the mechanism of choice (the
buttons on the controller.) Many games with complicated control
schemes violate the Precision principle. Many games have bad
input lag and other problems that stand in the way of
precision. Some games seem to violate Precision---like Street
Fighter, where we could imagine a 3DS style menu of the super
attacks, rather than the high-execution challenge abilities---but
some how do not, because the commands are tight and seem to flow
out of other actions you are doing anyways, and are coupled with
general tightness and precision. Sometimes a game consciously
makes the control harder as part of the challenge... DDR is
easier with four buttons that you can control with your fingers,
for example; but this is difficulty design decision to balance
and generally pushes the game from the abstract realm (the
screen) to the physical realm (dancing).</p>

<p>The Last Remnant's lack of Fairness almost entirely comes from
its lack of Precision. It is not possible for you to choose your
actions, so you know you should heal but the game prevents
you. It's not necessarily the case that lack of Precision leads
to lack of Fairness... the NES Castlevania games are very chunky
in their control, but somehow maintain Fairness.</p>

<p>So I guess I've decided to abandon The Last Remnant. I just read
the Wikipedia summary of the story and it sounds like it would
have been cool to experience, but it's not worth the suffering. I'm
glad I played it enough to feel like I really understand the
mechanics and gave them a chance, but I think my conscious will be
clear on abandoning the game.</p>

<p>Total time: 16:06</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (6)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--5/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/17/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I played for about four and a half hours and finished two
or three areas, then got to a big boss fight with the Conqueror's
army at the Nest of Eagles. I died twice. So I decided to do a few
sidequests and come back. After doing two, I tried again and died
right away. I tried one more time and this time the RNG was on my
side and I got two Gae Bolg attacks from David in a row, took out
all the plebs and could focus on the two boss characters. I barely
won, however, with some pretty crazy luck. It was fun to face such
odds and win, but the game feels totally unfair with your lack of
control.</p>

<p>The cinematic fight between Emma and the Conqueror was really
awesome. I can't believe how poorly they introduced and explained
the Emmy character, although I'm glad I'd at least run into her
before.</p>

<p>Total time: 12:20</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (5)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--4/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/16/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for 1:38 tonight and just got through one area. There
were a few tough enemies that got me in trouble. I'm in an area
now with just one person in my group and it's quite hard to go at
the battles in a way that lets me survive. Kind of fun. I'm
looking forward to getting the ability to have more units and
unions in my party. It will be fun to organize a big group, I
think.</p>

<p>Total time: 7:48</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (4)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--3/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/15/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--3</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played for about four hours tonight after putting kids to
bed. The game is growing on me quite a bit. I find the story to be
very interesting. It's not cliche and not over the top. Although
it does move a little slow.</p>

<p>I'm finding the battle system to be more fun as I think a little
hard as I direct each union to attack. Occasionally I am close to
death, so I feel like it is a little difficult, although I haven't
died since I restarted.</p>

<p>I made it through a bunch more areas (I'm about to go under the
temple) and had a lot of combat on the way. One thing I dislike
about the game is how poorly it communicates your character
progression. There is no summary level that you can look at
it. Instead after each fight, some characters increase some stats
based on something (use? I don't know.) It's almost like in FF13
where you get bonuses in very small steps, but here you don't see
the global path so you don't get that reptilian enjoyment of
increasing numbers.</p>

<p>When I got to a new city, Elysion, I explored all over but lost
track of the plot. I couldn't find the trigger that would bring me
to the next segment, so I thought I might have to do a mandatory
"side" quest. This sent me to a whole bunch of new places... kind
of a hole... that turned out to be unnecessary. But on the way I
got to see something cool: the world map is sensibly connected,
because in an area next to a big city, I could see a feature of
the city in the background. That was a nice touch.</p>

<p>Total time: 6:10</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: The Last Remnant (X360, 2008) (3)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--2/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-14T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/14/Game--The-Last-Remnant--X360--2008--2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This afternoon I played for 2:15 and got far past where I was
before. I still feel the same way about most parts of the game,
but the battle system is feeling a bit more strategic, if less
active or involved than other similar systems. The story is pretty
interesting... the concept of remnants is neat. They're basically
totally unique high magic items in a low magic world. The voice
acting in this game is totally atrocious though. It would be much
better to just turn if off and/or have Japanese.</p>

<p>In the combat setup of unions, units, etc I feel like I'm just
making random decisions though. There are so many different
numbers and combinations, I don't understand how to optimize it,
so I'm just getting by.</p>

<p>Total time: 2:15</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
