<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: PSP | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/psp/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-02T19:55:43-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Peace Walker (PSP, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Peace-Walker--PSP--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/08/01/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Peace-Walker--PSP--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I started on the July 12th and beat the main game on the 19th. I
continued playing the optional content until today. I did all the
extra "Search" missions, but I didn't want to invest the time to
do every other mission to unlock the /Final/ mission. (So I
watched it on YouTube.) In the end, I cleared 86 missions in
36:22:53.</p>

<p>I thought the game was amazing. It's beautiful and the controls
actually feel really nice (unlike Portable Ops, where the controls
were atrocious.) The story is really cool too. The main thing I
didn't like about the game is how a lot of the extra content
revolved around incredibly difficult boss fights. (It was about
half that and half stealth missions... which were all really
fun.)</p>

<p>I thought the pace of unlocking new content was really nice. A big
problem with some games like this is that you feel drowned in the
number of possible options. This has a nice slow drip that feels
rewarding to unlock more. Eventually though, it became too much
for me when there were so many combat missions on the docket.</p>

<p>There were many funny in-jokes in the Metal Gear Universe that I
enjoyed.</p>

<p>The biggest problem with the game though was the disgusting Che
worship. Ugh.</p>

<p>Highly recommended.</p>

<p>I have now played and beat every Metal Gear game that has been
released!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid 2: Digital Graphic Novel (PSP, 2008)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/25/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2008--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-25T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/25/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid-2--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2008--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched the Metal Gear Solid 2: Digital Graphic Novel. It was
really cool. The changed the flow of the story a lot and a lot of
the details for the adventure, but it got to the same place. It
was neat, and a good reminder before playing MGS4 (which I am
doing right now.)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through Metal
Gear Solid: Portable Ops.</p>

<p>I really liked that this is a canonical game and features Naked
Snake. I find his character really fascinating.</p>

<p>In general, I found the gameplay great. The controls on the PSP
were really hard to work with, so I played on Easy. I find that
very interesting, because the first three Metal Gear Solid games
had fixed cameras. If this game were just made in that style, then
the lack of a second analog stick on the PSP would not have been a
problem. I found it very painful.</p>

<p>The recruiting and squad concept was interesting, but ultimately
very unfulfilling for me. I want to play as Snake. I only used
other people in one boss fight where Snake died and then when I
wanted to get a box closer to capture someone.</p>

<p>The comic book style cutscenes in this game were really great. I
think they looked better than MGS1 cut-scenes, so I don't feel
like it was a cop-out.</p>

<p>The storyline revelations were very cool and the general concept
for the action was rad. I found that the game had the same great
Metal Gear themes, even though it was portable.</p>

<p>Great game!</p>

<p>Stats:
Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 11:25
Times Saved: 8
Restarts: 18
Times Alert Mode Triggered: 76
Humans Killed: 41
Comrades Secured: 53
Comrades Killed: 16
Codename: Scorpion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Half-Minute Hero (PSP, 2009)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/21/Game--Half-Minute-Hero--PSP--2009--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/21/Game--Half-Minute-Hero--PSP--2009--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played Half-Minute Hero after hearing a lot about it from blogs,
etc for a long time.</p>

<p>It is definitely a really unique and quirky game. I can see why
people would love it for its freshness, but after playing through
about half-a-dozen stages and seeing where it was going, it lost
my attention and I wasn't interested in doing more.</p>

<p>I think the problem I had with it was that I had very little input
into what happened in the game. You only control the character in
the broadest way: what area they are in and what they buy. You
don't really impact combat at all. I wonder if you could have a
game like this, where combat was INCREDIBLY fast(-paced), but
still have a lot of player involvement. I think something like the
FF13 system is the right direction. Also, I've thought a lot about
RPGs that are mechanically based on fighting games for similar
inspiration.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Flying Hamster (PSP, 2010)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/21/Game--Flying-Hamster--PSP--2010--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/21/Game--Flying-Hamster--PSP--2010--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played The Flying Hamster on the PSP.</p>

<p>Another bad shmup for all the typical reasons. It is absurdly cute
though. I may want to try to play it again just from its
cuteness. Probably not though... not enough time to play games
that aren't amazing.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
