<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2006 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2006/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-11-23T07:26:34-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Casino Royale, starring Daniel Craig (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is such an amazing movie. The whole story-arc of Vesper is so
powerful and heart-breaking. The first half of the film has so
many super high energy exciting parts... like the opening and the
airport. The film has lots of great lines and funny parts... like
at the country club and between Bond and Vesper. This is really great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Vitus, starring Teo Gheorghiu (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Movie--Vitus--starring-Teo-Gheorghiu--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Movie--Vitus--starring-Teo-Gheorghiu--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very cool movie. I didn't really have any expectations
for it and in the beginning (when Vitus is unhappy) I was
beginning to get really annoyed at the movie, but when it changes
and gets a new plot... man it's awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn't seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It's a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through Metal
Gear Solid: Portable Ops.</p>

<p>I really liked that this is a canonical game and features Naked
Snake. I find his character really fascinating.</p>

<p>In general, I found the gameplay great. The controls on the PSP
were really hard to work with, so I played on Easy. I find that
very interesting, because the first three Metal Gear Solid games
had fixed cameras. If this game were just made in that style, then
the lack of a second analog stick on the PSP would not have been a
problem. I found it very painful.</p>

<p>The recruiting and squad concept was interesting, but ultimately
very unfulfilling for me. I want to play as Snake. I only used
other people in one boss fight where Snake died and then when I
wanted to get a box closer to capture someone.</p>

<p>The comic book style cutscenes in this game were really great. I
think they looked better than MGS1 cut-scenes, so I don't feel
like it was a cop-out.</p>

<p>The storyline revelations were very cool and the general concept
for the action was rad. I found that the game had the same great
Metal Gear themes, even though it was portable.</p>

<p>Great game!</p>

<p>Stats:
Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 11:25
Times Saved: 8
Restarts: 18
Times Alert Mode Triggered: 76
Humans Killed: 41
Comrades Secured: 53
Comrades Killed: 16
Codename: Scorpion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Digital Graphic Novel (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/17/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/17/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched the Metal Gear Solid: Digital Graphic Novel. It isn't a
game, but it is on the PSP. It's a really cool motion comic. The
art style is beautiful and it is an interesting way to experience
Metal Gear, but it does drop a lot. In particular, it doesn't give
you the feeling of tense enemy avoidance or the patience that the
game requires. But it is really neat.</p>

<p>I really liked the way they translated Psycho Mantis' abilities to
the form, because you can't really recreate the controller
gimmicks. But what they did was cool.</p>

<p>I'm interested in watching the second graphic novel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
