<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2006 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2006/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-12-15T02:01:23-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Casino Royale, starring Daniel Craig (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-11-16T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/11/16/Movie--Casino-Royale--starring-Daniel-Craig--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is such an amazing movie. The whole story-arc of Vesper is so
powerful and heart-breaking. The first half of the film has so
many super high energy exciting parts... like the opening and the
airport. The film has lots of great lines and funny parts... like
at the country club and between Bond and Vesper. This is really great.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Vitus, starring Teo Gheorghiu (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Movie--Vitus--starring-Teo-Gheorghiu--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/10/31/Movie--Vitus--starring-Teo-Gheorghiu--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is a very cool movie. I didn't really have any expectations
for it and in the beginning (when Vitus is unhappy) I was
beginning to get really annoyed at the movie, but when it changes
and gets a new plot... man it's awesome.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn't seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It's a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2006) (10)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2006--9/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-11T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/11/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2006--9</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I played through the rest of the game... meaning the final
optional dungeon and final dungeon tonight. I started to notice a
lot of chunky frame rate moments, strangely.</p>

<p>The end of the game was satisfying in a lot of ways. I got to the
power level where there was a lot of flexibility and fun in
planning the skill combinations, so I could create brutal
combos. The story wrapped up in a fun way too, with a few good
twists there at the end. The final bosses were not very hard
though.</p>

<p>Overall, I found the game on par. It wasn't particularly special:
the combat system was simple, the story was okay, and the skill
system didn't really flourish until the end. But, there also
wasn't anything really bad about it. The worst thing was probably
the plainness and the fact that a lot of the dungeons were very
samey because of small prop counts.</p>

<p>I don't think I would recommend the game to anymore, because there
are much better options. But obviously I didn't dislike it enough
to quit.</p>

<p>038:36:12 --- Clear --- 63/61/62/61</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Blue Dragon (X360, 2006) (9)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/10/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2006--8/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-10T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/10/Game--Blue-Dragon--X360--2006--8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Tonight I did a few more sidequests, including the Sea
Cube. During that I got a lot of class upgrades and had fun
picking out skill configurations. These side bosses are pretty
tough. There's one (the Ghost Yeet) that I can't survive more than
a round against.</p>

<p>The Devee Dance of Love was pretty funny. Stonesaurus is very
hard, but eventually I just used a strong Guard shadow and got
him. The boss music vocal track gets really old.</p>

<p>Before bed I wanted to finish a podcast, so I did a tiny bit of SP
grinding in the Underground River against the Kelolons.</p>

<p>I hope to do the last sidequest tomorrow night and finish that
night or the next.</p>

<p>030:47:16 --- Disc 3: Mechat Airship --- 50/50/49/49/50</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
