<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: 2006 | MECHAkunEX Media Diary]]></title>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/categories/2006/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-05-29T23:20:54-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[MECHAkunEX@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Movie: Underworld: Evolution, starring Kate Beckinsale (2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2012/04/30/Movie--Underworld--Evolution--starring-Kate-Beckinsale--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I thought that I hadn't seen this movie, but actually I have. Given
when it came out, I think I saw it in the theatres during grad
school. I would often go to the movie theater by myself on boring
nights/afternoons.</p>

<p>I think the production quality on the movie is significantly higher
and the fights are a lot more interesting. They did a good job
introducing new characters that were different. I like the
development of the mythology. Kate Beckinsale continues to look
amazing and she seems to be wearing a slightly different cat-suit.
The monsters look a little less like Buffy villains, but still a
little bit cheesy.</p>

<p>The plot feels a lot simpler, more like a roller-coaster ride where
the characters are chased from one place to the next without much
time for mystery or real plot development. It's a bit more of a
standard action movie in that regard, and I think it suffers
compared to the last for it. The cast of meaning characters is a
lot smaller with most (such as Corvinus and Tanis) really only have
one scene. The high point of the movie is probably the set of
flashbacks scenes.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Portable Ops (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/24/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Portable-Ops--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Over the past week, I played through Metal
Gear Solid: Portable Ops.</p>

<p>I really liked that this is a canonical game and features Naked
Snake. I find his character really fascinating.</p>

<p>In general, I found the gameplay great. The controls on the PSP
were really hard to work with, so I played on Easy. I find that
very interesting, because the first three Metal Gear Solid games
had fixed cameras. If this game were just made in that style, then
the lack of a second analog stick on the PSP would not have been a
problem. I found it very painful.</p>

<p>The recruiting and squad concept was interesting, but ultimately
very unfulfilling for me. I want to play as Snake. I only used
other people in one boss fight where Snake died and then when I
wanted to get a box closer to capture someone.</p>

<p>The comic book style cutscenes in this game were really great. I
think they looked better than MGS1 cut-scenes, so I don't feel
like it was a cop-out.</p>

<p>The storyline revelations were very cool and the general concept
for the action was rad. I found that the game had the same great
Metal Gear themes, even though it was portable.</p>

<p>Great game!</p>

<p>Stats:
Difficulty: Easy
Play Time: 11:25
Times Saved: 8
Restarts: 18
Times Alert Mode Triggered: 76
Humans Killed: 41
Comrades Secured: 53
Comrades Killed: 16
Codename: Scorpion</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Solid: Digital Graphic Novel (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/17/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-17T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/17/Game--Metal-Gear-Solid--Digital-Graphic-Novel--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I watched the Metal Gear Solid: Digital Graphic Novel. It isn't a
game, but it is on the PSP. It's a really cool motion comic. The
art style is beautiful and it is an interesting way to experience
Metal Gear, but it does drop a lot. In particular, it doesn't give
you the feeling of tense enemy avoidance or the patience that the
game requires. But it is really neat.</p>

<p>I really liked the way they translated Psycho Mantis' abilities to
the form, because you can't really recreate the controller
gimmicks. But what they did was cool.</p>

<p>I'm interested in watching the second graphic novel.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: Metal Gear Acid 2 (PSP, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/16/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid-2--PSP--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-16T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2011/06/16/Game--Metal-Gear-Acid-2--PSP--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After loving Metal Gear Acid so much, I played Metal Gear
Acid 2.</p>

<p>The opening movie of this was amazing.</p>

<p>The gameplay makes the last game feel like the first Dragon Quest:
there are so many ways the new interface is cleaner, easier, more
fluid, etc. I really like the improvements. The new gameplay
mechanics (like linkages and cover fire) where interesting, but
didn't really make it different. But I'm fine with that, because I
just wanted more game. (The blinding mechanic was definitely new,
but very annoying.)</p>

<p>The game gives you cards in a different order from the last game
and I generally felt the weapon power-level was higher initially,
although the support cards had the same path.</p>

<p>I really liked the cell-shaded style of the 3D graphics.</p>

<p>The game does an absurd jiggling animation with the female
characters. It is ridiculous.</p>

<p>This game seems even more combat focused than the last
game. Whereas in the last game, there were many traversal levels
where combat was the best approach, in this game there are many
straight-out combat missions. This game also feels like it has a
lot less time in between boss encounters. I also noticed that
there weren't really any "puzzle" levels, like before.</p>

<p>One thing that was close to a puzzle was the train level. It was
really cool to coax enemies into the path of the train and get
them squashed. Woo!</p>

<p>I did a little bit of grinding to get good cards, but I also made
some really stupid decks to get through some levels with a
challenge; both were fun.</p>

<p>The ending was very neat in its cinematic-ness, but the game in
general (and the bosses in particular) was a lot easier.</p>

<p>This game probably has more replay value because of the special
missions, but I didn't do any.</p>

<p>Here are my final stats:</p>

<p>Difficulty: Normal
Play Time: 14:24:20
Cost: 4395
Found: 45
Kills: 73
Total Damage: 15035
Clear Count: 1
Cards Collected: 41 (I don't know what this means... maybe in the stages?)</p>

<p>I hope there will be an Acid 3.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Game: New Super Mario Brothers (DS, 2006)]]></title>
    <link href="http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/30/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers--DS--2006--0/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://MECHAkunEX.github.com/blog/2010/11/30/Game--New-Super-Mario-Brothers--DS--2006--0</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>On the plane ride back from New England for Thanksgiving, I beat
New Super Mario Brothers for the Nintendo DS.</p>

<p>I started playing the game in August 2009 on a trip to Oregon
for a wedding, but I hit a wall in my progress after the second
tower in World 6. It was very frustrating, so I only played it
occasionally (less than monthly), basically whenever I was bored
and had a few moments. On the ride out to Boston this year, I did
exactly that. And again as I was sitting around with my family one
night. Then. I beat the level! I played regularly the rest of the
trip and by the flight home, I'd beaten it.</p>

<p>Most of my opinion of the game revolve around the last World
and my painful experience with the progress wall. Obviously it is
very frustrating not to make any progress. I think the biggest
problem was that even when I could beat a level, you are
restricted from saving until after a tower or castle, so you had
to have a successful string and a long time to play to make
progress. NSMBW solved this problem with the Quick Save system,
although I see no reason to not have Save anywhere unlocked from
the beginning. The final level's maze was really frustrating---I
made it there over 10 times and tried different patterns over and
over again, running out of time and then lives each time, before
looking it up online (which was a miracle, because I was on a
plane.)</p>

<p>I thought the physics in the game after more off than NSMBW. I
thought that the additional power-ups were mostly all dumb.</p>

<p>But, I love platformers and Mario in particular, so it was
really fun, especially when you're on a roll.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
